<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">22110294</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1790-8019</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2011</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Hippokratia</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Hippokratia</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sarcopenia: An emphasis on occlusion training and dietary protein.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>132</StartPage><EndPage>137</EndPage><MedlinePgn>132-7</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Demographics reveal that the world's population aged 60 years and older will triple from 600 million in 2000 to more 2 billion by the year 2050. To remain independent and healthy, an important factor to consider is the maintenance of skeletal muscle, as the elderly seem to become prone to a progressive loss of skeletal muscle with aging, termed sarcopenia. Interventions should focus on resistance training and optimal nutrition. Low intensity occlusion training may provide a mode of resistance training more applicable to the elderly, due to the lower loads used. Furthermore, an emphasis must be placed on high quality protein adequately distributed throughout the day to maximize protein synthesis. The use of drug therapy may be of some benefit, but it appears exercise and diet likely plays a more prominent role in the preservation of muscle mass and strength than administration of synthetic hormones.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Loenneke</LastName><ForeName>J P</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pujol</LastName><ForeName>T J</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Greece</Country><MedlineTA>Hippokratia</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101296613</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1108-4189</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">atrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood occlusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dietary protein</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">growth hormone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">review</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22110294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3209675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Koopman R, van Loon LJ. Aging, exercise, and muscle protein metabolism. J Appl Physiol. 2009;106:2040&#x2013;2048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19131471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mourtzakis M, Bedbrook M. Muscle atrophy in cancer: a role for nutrition and exercise. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2009;34:950&#x2013;956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19935858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holloszy JO. Exercise-induced increase in muscle insulin sensitivity. J Appl Physiol. 2005;99:338&#x2013;343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16036907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helge JW, Biba TO, Galbo H, Gaster M, Donsmark M. Muscle triacylglycerol and hormone-sensitive lipase activity in untrained and trained human muscles. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2006;97:566&#x2013;572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16767439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahlin K, Mogensen M, Bagger M, Fernstrom M, Pedersen PK. The potential for mitochondrial fat oxidation in human skeletal muscle influences whole body fat oxidation during low-intensity exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2007;292:E223&#x2013;230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16926382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosy-Westphal A, Reinecke U, Schlorke T, Illner K, Kutzner D, Heller M, et al. Effect of organ and tissue masses on resting energy expenditure in underweight, normal weight and obese adults. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 2004;28:72&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14647174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera WR, Hughes VA, Fielding RA, Fiatarone MA, Evans WJ, Roubenoff R. Aging of skeletal muscle: a 12-yr longitudinal study. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88:1321&#x2013;1326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10749826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera WR, Hughes VA, Lutz KJ, Evans WJ. A cross-sectional study of muscle strength and mass in 45- to 78-yr-old men and women. J Appl Physiol. 1991;71:644&#x2013;650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1938738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iannuzzi-Sucich M, Prestwood KM, Kenny AM. Prevalence of sarcopenia and predictors of skeletal muscle mass in healthy, older men and women. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2002;57:M772&#x2013;777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12456735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenny AM, Dawson L, Kleppinger A, Iannuzzi-Sucich M, Judge JO. Prevalence of sarcopenia and predictors of skeletal muscle mass in nonobese women who are long-term users of estrogenreplacement therapy. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2003;58:M436&#x2013;440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12730253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolland Y, Lauwers-Cances V, Cournot M, Nourhashemi F, Reynish W, Riviere D, et al. Sarcopenia, calf circumference, and physical function of elderly women: a cross-sectional study. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2003;51:1120&#x2013;1124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12890076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan BK, Marshall LM, Winters KM, Faulkner KA, Schwartz AV, Orwoll ES. Incident fall risk and physical activity and physical performance among older men: the Osteoporotic Fractures in Men Study. Am J Epidemiol. 2007;165:696&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17194749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orr R, de Vos NJ, Singh NA, Ross DA, Stavrinos TM, Fiatarone-Singh MA. Power training improves balance in healthy older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2006;61:78&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16456197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metter EJ, Talbot LA, Schrager M, Conwit R. Skeletal muscle strength as a predictor of all-cause mortality in healthy men. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2002;57:B359&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12242311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty TJ, Brown WF. The estimated numbers and relative sizes of thenar motor units as selected by multiple point stimulation in young and older adults. Muscle Nerve. 1993;16:355&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8455648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty TJ, Brown WF. Age-related changes in the twitch contractile properties of human thenar motor units. J Appl Physiol. 1997;82:93&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9029203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roos MR, Rice CL, Vandervoort AA. Age-related changes in motor unit function. Muscle Nerve. 1997;20:679&#x2013;690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9149074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosek DJ, Kim JS, Petrella JK, Cross JM, Bamman MM. Efficacy of 3 days/wk resistance training on myofiber hypertrophy and myogenic mechanisms in young vs. older adults. J Appl Physiol. 2006;101:531&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16614355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welle S, Thornton C, Statt M. Myofibrillar protein synthesis in young and old human subjects after three months of resistance training. Am J Physiol. 1995;268:E422&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7900788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dangin M, Boirie Y, Guillet C, Beaufrere B. Influence of the protein digestion rate on protein turnover in young and elderly subjects. J Nutr. 2002;132:3228S&#x2013;3233S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12368423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dangin M, Guillet C, Garcia-Rodenas C, Gachon P, Bouteloup-Demange C, Reiffers-Magnani K, et al. The rate of protein digestion affects protein gain differently during aging in humans. J Physiol. 2003;549:635&#x2013;644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2342962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12665610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsanos CS, Kobayashi H, Sheffield-Moore M, Aarsland A, Wolfe RR. A high proportion of leucine is required for optimal stimulation of the rate of muscle protein synthesis by essential amino acids in the elderly. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2006;291:E381&#x2013;387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16507602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morley JE. Anorexia, sarcopenia, and aging. Nutrition. 2001;17:660&#x2013;663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11448592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murton AJ, Constantin D, Greenhaff PL. The involvement of the ubiquitin proteasome system in human skeletal muscle remodelling and atrophy. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2008;1782:730&#x2013;743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18992328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhaff PL, Karagounis LG, Peirce N, Simpson EJ, Hazell M, Layfield R, et al. Disassociation between the effects of amino acids and insulin on signaling, ubiquitin ligases, and protein turnover in human muscle. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2008;295:E595&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2536736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18577697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guillet C, Auguste P, Mayo W, Kreher P, Gascan H. Ciliary neurotrophic factor is a regulator of muscular strength in aging. J Neurosci. 1999;19:1257&#x2013;1262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6786012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9952403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delbono O. Neural control of aging skeletal muscle. Aging Cell. 2003;2:21&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12882331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narici MV, Maffulli N. Sarcopenia: characteristics, mechanisms and functional significance. Br Med Bull. 2010;95:139&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20200012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dirks AJ, Leeuwenburgh C. The role of apoptosis in age-related skeletal muscle atrophy. Sports Med. 2005;35:473&#x2013;483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15974633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trifunovic A, Wredenberg A, Falkenberg M, Spelbrink JN, Rovio AT, Bruder CE, et al. Premature ageing in mice expressing defective mitochondrial DNA polymerase. Nature. 2004;429:417&#x2013;423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15164064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brose A, Parise G, Tarnopolsky MA. Creatine supplementation enhances isometric strength and body composition improvements following strength exercise training in older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2003;58:11&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12560406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferri A, Scaglioni G, Pousson M, Capodaglio P, Van HoeckeJ, Narici MV. Strength and power changes of the human plantar flexors and knee extensors in response to resistance training in old age. Acta Physiol Scand. 2003;177:69&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12492780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera WR, Hughes VA, Krivickas LS, Kim SK, Foldvari M, Roubenoff R. Strength training in older women: early and late changes in whole muscle and single cells. Muscle Nerve. 2003;28:601&#x2013;608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14571463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Takazawa H, Sato Y, Takebayashi S, Tanaka Y, Ishii N. Effects of resistance exercise combined with moderate vascular occlusion on muscular function in humans. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88:2097&#x2013;2106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10846023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita S, Abe T, Drummond MJ, Cadenas JG, Dreyer HC, Sato Y, et al. Blood flow restriction during low-intensity resistance exercise increases S6K1 phosphorylation and muscle protein synthesis. J Appl Physiol. 2007;103:903&#x2013;910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17569770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lexell J. Ageing and human muscle: observations from Sweden. Can J Appl Physiol. 1993;18:2&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8471991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ACSM American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams MA, Haskell WL, Ades PA, Amsterdam EA, Bittner V, Franklin BA, et al. Resistance exercise in individuals with and without cardiovascular disease: 2007 update: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association Council on Clinical Cardiology and Council on Nutrition, Physical Activity, and Metabolism. Circulation. 2007;116:572&#x2013;584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17638929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Holwerda AM, Selby KC, West DW, Staples AW, Cain NE, et al. Resistance exercise volume affects myofibrillar protein synthesis and anabolic signalling molecule phosphorylation in young men. J Physiol. 2010;588:3119&#x2013;3130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2956949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20581041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Pujol TJ. The Use of Occlusion Training to Produce Muscle Hypertrophy. Strength Cond J. 2009;31:77&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Kearns CF, Sato Y. Muscle size and strength are increased following walk training with restricted venous blood flow from the leg muscle, Kaatsu-walk training. J Appl Physiol. 2006;100:1460&#x2013;1466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16339340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madarame H, Neya M, Ochi E, Nakazato K, Sato Y, Ishii N. Cross-transfer effects of resistance training with blood flow restriction. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40:258&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18202577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Sato Y, Ishii N. Effects of resistance exercise combined with vascular occlusion on muscle function in athletes. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;86:308&#x2013;314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11990743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Tsuruta T, Ishii N. Cooperative effects of exercise and occlusive stimuli on muscular function in low-intensity resistance exercise with moderate vascular occlusion. Jpn J Physiol. 2004;54:585&#x2013;592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15760491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Fujita S, Ogasawara R, Sato Y, Abe T. Effects of lowintensity bench press training with restricted arm muscle blood flow on chest muscle hypertrophy: a pilot study. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20618358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumide T, Sakuraba K, Sawaki K, Ohmura H, Tamura Y. Effect of resistance exercise training combined with relatively low vascular occlusion. J Sci Med Sport. 2009;12:107&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18083635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karabulut M, Abe T, Sato Y, Bemben MG. The effects of low-intensity resistance training with vascular restriction on leg muscle strength in older men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;108:147&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19760431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Wilson GJ, Wilson JM. A Mechanistic Approach to Blood Flow Occlusion. Int J Sports Med. 2010;31:1&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19885776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Nakamura Y, Aruga S, Onda T, Miyazaki S, Ishii N. Rapid increase in plasma growth hormone after low-intensity resistance exercise with vascular occlusion. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88:61&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10642363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry CS, Glynn EL, Drummond MJ, Timmerman KL, Fujita S, Abe T, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise stimulates mTORC1 signaling and muscle protein synthesis in older men. J Appl Physiol. 2010;108:1199&#x2013;1209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2867530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20150565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houston DK, Nicklas BJ, Ding J, Harris TB, Tylavsky FA, Newman AB, et al. Dietary protein intake is associated with lean mass change in older, community-dwelling adults: the Health, Aging, and Body Composition (Health ABC) Study. Am J Clin Nutr. 2008;87:150&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18175749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pepersack T, Corretge M, Beyer I, Namias B, Andr S, Benoit F, et al. Examining the effect of intervention to nutritional problems of hospitalised elderly: a pilot project. J Nutr Health Aging. 2002;6:306&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12474019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe RR, Miller SL. The recommended dietary allowance of protein: a misunderstood concept. JAMA. 2008;299:2891&#x2013;2893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18577734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton LE, Layman DK, Bunpo P, Anthony TG, Brana DV, Garlick PJ. The leucine content of a complete meal directs peak activation but not duration of skeletal muscle protein synthesis and mammalian target of rapamycin signaling in rats. J Nutr. 2009;139:1103&#x2013;1109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19403715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton LE, Wilson GJ. Optimal protein intake to maximize muscle protein synthesis. Examinations of optimal meal protein intake and frequency for athletes. Agro Food Ind High-Tech. 2009;20:54&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millward DJ, Layman DK, Tome D, Schaafsma G. Protein quality assessment: impact of expanding understanding of protein and amino acid needs for optimal health. Am J Clin Nutr. 2008;87:1576S&#x2013;1581S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18469291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paddon-Jones D, Sheffield-Moore M, Zhang XJ, Volpi E, Wolf SE, Aarsland A, et al. Amino acid ingestion improves muscle protein synthesis in the young and elderly. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2004;286:E321&#x2013;328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14583440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Symons TB, Sheffield-Moore M, Wolfe RR, Paddon-Jones D. A moderate serving of high-quality protein maximally stimulates skeletal muscle protein synthesis in young and elderly subjects. J Am Diet Assoc. 2009;109:1582&#x2013;1586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3197704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19699838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohe J, Low JF, Wolfe RR, Rennie MJ. Latency and duration of stimulation of human muscle protein synthesis during continuous infusion of amino acids. J Physiol. 2001;532:575&#x2013;579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11306673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Castro JM. Circadian rhythms of the spontaneous meal pattern, macronutrient intake, and mood of humans. Physiol Behav. 1987;40:437&#x2013;446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3628541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell WW, Leidy HJ. Dietary protein and resistance training effects on muscle and body composition in older persons. J Am Coll Nutr. 2007;26:696S&#x2013;703S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18187436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryall JG, Schertzer JD, Lynch GS. Cellular and molecular mechanisms underlying age-related skeletal muscle wasting and weakness. Biogerontology. 2008;9:213&#x2013;228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18299960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khosla S, Melton LJ, 3rd, Atkinson EJ, O'Fallon WM, Klee GG, Riggs BL. Relationship of serum sex steroid levels and bone turnover markers with bone mineral density in men and women: a key role for bioavailable estrogen. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1998;83:2266&#x2013;2274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9661593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morley JE, Kaiser F, Raum WJ, Perry HM, 3rd, Flood JF, Jensen J, et al. Potentially predictive and manipulable blood serum correlates of aging in the healthy human male: progressive decreases in bioavailable testosterone, dehydroepiandrosterone sulfate, and the ratio of insulin-like growth factor 1 to growth hormone. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1997;94:7537&#x2013;7542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC23857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9207127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha-Hikim I, Cornford M, Gaytan H, Lee ML, Bhasin S. Effects of testosterone supplementation on skeletal muscle fiber hypertrophy and satellite cells in community-dwelling older men. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2006;91:3024&#x2013;3033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16705073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha-Hikim I, Taylor WE, Gonzalez-Cadavid NF, Zheng W, Bhasin S. Androgen receptor in human skeletal muscle and cultured muscle satellite cells: up-regulation by androgen treatment. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2004;89:5245&#x2013;5255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15472231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaap LA, Pluijm SM, Smit JH, van Schoor NM, Visser M, Gooren LJ, et al. The association of sex hormone levels with poor mobility, low muscle strength and incidence of falls among older men and women. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 2005;63:152&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16060908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waters DL, Yau CL, Montoya GD, Baumgartner RN. Serum Sex Hormones, IGF-1, and IGFBP3 Exert a Sexually Dimorphic Effect on Lean Body Mass in Aging. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2003;58:648&#x2013;652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12865482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermann M, Berger P. Hormonal changes in aging men: a therapeutic indication? Exp Gerontol. 2001;36:1075&#x2013;1082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11404052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zadik Z, Chalew SA, McCarter RJ, Jr, Meistas M, Kowarski AA. The influence of age on the 24-hour integrated concentration of growth hormone in normal individuals. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1985;60:513&#x2013;516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3972964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sotiropoulos A, Ohanna M, Kedzia C, Menon RK, Kopchick JJ, Kelly PA, et al. Growth hormone promotes skeletal muscle cell fusion independent of insulin-like growth factor 1 up-regulation. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2006;103:7315&#x2013;7320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1456062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16670201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadakis MA, Grady D, Black D, Tierney MJ, Gooding GA, Schambelan M, et al. Growth hormone replacement in healthy older men improves body composition but not functional ability. Ann Intern Med. 1996;124:708&#x2013;716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8633830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehrnborg C, Rosen T. Physiological and pharmacological basis for the ergogenic effects of growth hormone in elite sports. Asian J Androl. 2008;10:373&#x2013;383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18385899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borst SE. Interventions for sarcopenia and muscle weakness in older people. Age Ageing. 2004;33:548&#x2013;555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15385272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boonen S, Rosen C, Bouillon R, Sommer A, McKay M, Rosen D, et al. Musculoskeletal effects of the recombinant human IGF-I/IGF binding protein-3 complex in osteoporotic patients with proximal femoral fracture: a double-blind, placebo-controlled pilot study. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2002;87:1593&#x2013;1599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11932288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>