<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41276779</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2199-1170</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine - open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Intermittent Hypoxia Protocols on Physical Performance in Trained and Untrained Individuals: An Umbrella Review of Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>145</StartPage><MedlinePgn>145</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">145</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40798-025-00933-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Intermittent hypoxia (IH) has emerged as a promising strategy to enhance physical performance by eliciting adaptive responses across cardiovascular, respiratory, and muscular systems. Various IH protocols have been applied in both trained and untrained individuals to improve aerobic capacity, strength, and repeated sprint ability. However, the growing number of systematic reviews and meta-analyses (SRs/MAs) has led to heterogeneous conclusions due to variability in populations, protocols, and outcome measures. This umbrella review aimed to synthesize and critically appraise the available SRs/MAs on the effects of IH protocols on physical performance across different fitness levels.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A systematic search, aligned with the PRIOR (Preferred Reporting Items for Overviews of Reviews) guidelines, was conducted across seven electronic databases (PubMed/MEDLINE, Web of Science, Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews, Scopus, Embase, PsycINFO, and SciELO) from inception to June 2025. Eligible studies included systematic reviews (SRs) with or without meta-analyses (MAs) or network meta-analyses (NMAs) evaluating the effects of intermittent hypoxia protocols on physical performance. Methodological quality was assessed using the AMSTAR-2 tool.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 22 systematic reviews (14 with meta-analyses, 3 with network meta-analyses) analyzing 487 primary studies and 5,333 participants were included. Intermittent hypoxia (IH) protocols improved both aerobic and anaerobic performance, as well as muscular strength. Live high-train low (LHTL) and live low-train high (LLTH) protocols consistently enhanced V&#x307;O&#x2082;max, especially when combined with sea-level training. Anaerobic-focused strategies like repeated sprint training in hypoxia (RSH) and RSH induced by voluntary hypoventilation at low lung volume (RSH-VHL) led to improvements in sprint-fatigue resistance and glycolytic capacity. Intermittent hypoxic interval training (IHIT) and high-intensity interval training (HIIT) under hypoxia showed robust aerobic benefits. However, the magnitude of these effects varied depending on the type of protocol, training status, and hypoxic dose.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">IH is an effective and adaptable strategy to improve aerobic and anaerobic performance, as well as to enhance muscle strength and hypertrophy. These benefits often occur without consistent hematological changes. Future studies should focus on individualized approaches, standardization of terminology, and precise quantification of both hypoxic exposure and training load to optimize outcomes and ensure reproducibility.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="REVIEW REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This overview was registered on the International Database of Systematic Review Protocols (PROSPERO ID: CRD42024465481).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boulares</LastName><ForeName>Ayoub</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-5728-9801</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory Mobility, Aging &amp; Exercise-ER20296, Faculty of Sport Sciences-STAPS, University of Poitiers, Poitiers, France. ayoub.boulares@univ-poitiers.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dupuy</LastName><ForeName>Olivier</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7273-8272</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory Mobility, Aging &amp; Exercise-ER20296, Faculty of Sport Sciences-STAPS, University of Poitiers, Poitiers, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology and Physical Activity Sciences (EKSAP), Faculty of Medicine, University of Montreal, Montreal, QC, H3T 1J4, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bragazzi</LastName><ForeName>Nicola Luigi</ForeName><Initials>NL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8409-868X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory for Industrial and Applied Mathematics (LIAM), Department of Mathematics and Statistics, York University, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Nutrition Unit (HNU), Department of Food and Drugs, Medical School, University of Parma, Parma, 43125, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Anthropology Biosphere and Healing Systems, United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) Chair, University of Genoa, Genoa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pichon</LastName><ForeName>Aur&#xe9;lien</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2772-9232</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory Mobility, Aging &amp; Exercise-ER20296, Faculty of Sport Sciences-STAPS, University of Poitiers, Poitiers, France. aurelien.pichon@univ-poitiers.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101662568</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2198-9761</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Altitude training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Elites</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypoxic training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intermittent hypoxia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Subelites athletes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41276779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12640890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-025-00933-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40798-025-00933-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Dempsey JA, Morgan BJ. Humans In Hypoxia: A Conspiracy Of Maladaptation?! Physiology (Bethesda). 2015;30:304&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4491526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26136544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss JW, Tamisier R, Liu Y. Sympathoexcitation and arterial hypertension associated with obstructive sleep apnea and Cyclic intermittent hypoxia. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2015;119:1449&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00315.2015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26251511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navarrete-Opazo A, Mitchell GS. Therapeutic potential of intermittent hypoxia: a matter of dose. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2014;307:R1181&#x2013;1197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00208.2014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4315448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25231353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabrese EJ, Mattson MP. How does hormesis impact biology, toxicology, and medicine? NPJ Aging Mech Dis. 2017;3:13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41514-017-0013-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5601424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28944077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard O, Brocherie F, Goods PSR, Millet GP. An updated panorama of living Low-Training high Altitude/Hypoxic methods. Front Sports Act Living. 2020;2:26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2020.00026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7739748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33345020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet GP, Roels B, Schmitt L, Woorons X, Richalet JP. Combining hypoxic methods for peak performance. Sports Med. 2010;40:1&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11317920-000000000-00000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20020784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feriche B, Garc&#xed;a-Ramos A, Morales-Artacho AJ, Padial P. Resistance training using different hypoxic training strategies: a basis for hypertrophy and muscle power development. Sports Med Open. 2017;3:12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-017-0078-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5357242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28315193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard O, Koehle MS, MacInnis MJ, Guenette JA, Koehle MS, Verges S et al. Comments on Point:Counterpoint: Hypobaric hypoxia induces/does not induce different responses from normobaric hypoxia. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2012;112:1788&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3785185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22589492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet GP, Faiss R, Pialoux V. Last word on Point: Counterpoint: Hypobaric hypoxia induces different responses from normobaric hypoxia. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2012;112:1795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22589493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mounier R, Brugniaux JV. Last word on counterpoint: hypobaric hypoxia does not induce different physiological responses from Normobaric hypoxia. J Appl Physiol. 2012;112:1796&#x2013;1796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00355.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22589494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrendt T, Bielitzki R, Behrens M, Herold F, Schega L. Effects of intermittent Hypoxia&#x2013;Hyperoxia on Performance- and Health-Related outcomes in humans: A systematic review. Sports Med - Open. 2022;8:70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-022-00450-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9156652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35639211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine BD, Stray-Gundersen J. Living high-training low: effect of moderate-altitude acclimatization with low-altitude training on performance. J Appl Physiol (1985). 1997;83:102&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1997.83.1.102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9216951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mollard P, Woorons X, Letournel M, Lamberto C, Favret F, Pichon A, et al. Determinants of maximal oxygen uptake in moderate acute hypoxia in endurance athletes. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;100:663&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-007-0457-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17534646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weibel ER, Taylor CR, Hoppeler H. The concept of symmorphosis: a testable hypothesis of structure-function relationship. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1991;88:10357&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.88.22.10357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC52927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1946456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundby C, Millet GP, Calbet JA, B&#xe4;rtsch P, Subudhi AW. Does &#x2018;altitude training&#x2019; increase exercise performance in elite athletes? Br J Sports Med. 2012;46:792&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2012-091231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22797528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robach P, Lundby C. Is live high-train low altitude training relevant for elite athletes with already high total hemoglobin mass? Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2012;22:303&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2012.01457.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22612361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundby C, Robach P. Does altitude training increase exercise performance in elite athletes? Exp Physiol. 2016;101:783&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP085579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27173805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wehrlin JP, Marti B, Hall&#xe9;n J. Hemoglobin mass and aerobic performance at moderate altitude in elite athletes. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2016;903:357&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-4899-7678-9_24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27343108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garvican LA, Saunders PU, Pyne DB, Martin DT, Robertson EY, Gore CJ. Hemoglobin mass response to simulated hypoxia blinded by noisy measurement? J Appl Physiol (1985). 2012;112:1797&#x2013;8. author reply 1799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00212.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22589495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet GP, Chapman RF, Girard O, Brocherie F. Is live high-train low altitude training relevant for elite athletes? Flawed analysis from inaccurate data. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53:923&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-098083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29247024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean BD, Gore CJ, Kemp J. Application of &#x2018;Live Low-Train high&#x2019; for enhancing normoxic exercise performance in team sport athletes. Sports Med. 2014;44:1275&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0204-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24849544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard O, Brocherie F, Millet GP. Effects of Altitude/Hypoxia on Single- and Multiple-Sprint performance: A comprehensive review. Sports Med. 2017;47:1931&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0733-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28451905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brocherie F, Millet GP, Hauser A, Steiner T, Rysman J, Wehrlin JP, et al. Live high-Train low and high hypoxic training improves Team-Sport performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47:2140&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25668402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrendt T, Bielitzki R, Behrens M, Jahns L-M, Boersma M, Schega L. Acute psycho-physiological responses to submaximal constant-load cycling under intermittent hypoxia-hyperoxia vs. hypoxia-normoxia in young males. PeerJ. 2024;12:e18027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.18027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11457877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39376227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sazontova TG, Bolotova AV, Bedareva IV, Kostina NV, Arkhipenko YV. Adaptation to Intermittent Hypoxia/Hyperoxia Enhances Efficiency of Exercise Training. In: Xi L, Serebrovskaya TV, editors. Intermittent Hypoxia and Human Diseases [Internet]. London: Springer; 2012 [cited 2023 Sep 7]. pp. 191&#x2013;205. Available from: 10.1007/978-1-4471-2906-6_16</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrendt T, Bielitzki R, Behrens M, Glazachev OS, Schega L. Effects of intermittent Hypoxia-Hyperoxia exposure prior to aerobic cycling exercise on physical and cognitive performance in geriatric Patients-A randomized controlled trial. Front Physiol. 2022;13:899096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.899096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9178199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35694402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollock M, Fernandes RM, Pieper D, Tricco AC, Gates M, Gates A, et al. Preferred reporting items for overviews of reviews (PRIOR): a protocol for development of a reporting guideline for overviews of reviews of healthcare interventions. Syst Rev. 2019;8:335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13643-019-1252-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6929355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31870434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kugley S, Wade A, Thomas J, Mahood Q, J&#xf8;rgensen A-MK, Hammerstr&#xf8;m K, et al. Searching for studies: a guide to information retrieval for Campbell systematic reviews. Campbell Syst Reviews. 2017;13:1&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4073/cmg.2016.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gusenbauer M, Haddaway NR. Which academic search systems are suitable for systematic reviews or meta-analyses? Evaluating retrieval qualities of Google Scholar, PubMed, and 26 other resources. Res Synth Methods. 2020;11:181&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jrsm.1378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7079055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31614060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haddaway NR, Collins AM, Coughlin D, Kirk S. The role of Google scholar in evidence reviews and its applicability to grey literature searching. PLoS ONE. 2015;10:e0138237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0138237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4574933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26379270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioannidis JPA. Integration of evidence from multiple meta-analyses: a primer on umbrella reviews, treatment networks and multiple treatments meta-analyses. CMAJ. 2009;181:488&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1503/cmaj.081086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2761440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19654195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirvalidze M, Abbadi A, Dahlberg L, Sacco LB, Calder&#xf3;n-Larra&#xf1;aga A, Morin L. Estimating pairwise overlap in umbrella reviews: considerations for using the corrected covered area (CCA) index methodology. Res Synth Methods. 2023;14:764&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jrsm.1658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37501239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bougioukas KI, Diakonidis T, Mavromanoli AC, Haidich A-B, ccaR. A package for assessing primary study overlap across systematic reviews in overviews. Res Synth Methods. 2023;14:443&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jrsm.1610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36369993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shea BJ, Reeves BC, Wells G, Thuku M, Hamel C, Moran J, et al. AMSTAR 2: a critical appraisal tool for systematic reviews that include randomised or non-randomised studies of healthcare interventions, or both. BMJ. 2017;358:j4008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.j4008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5833365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28935701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uzun A-B, Iliescu MG, Stanciu L-E, Ionescu E-V, Ungur RA, Ciortea VM, et al. Effectiveness of intermittent Hypoxia-Hyperoxia therapy in different pathologies with possible metabolic implications. Metabolites. 2023;13:181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/metabo13020181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9961389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36837800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Z, Yang S, Li C, Xie X, Wang Y. The effects of intermittent hypoxic training on the aerobic capacity of exercisers: a systemic review and meta-analysis. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2023;15:174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-023-00784-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10731756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38115083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lancaster K, Smart N. Live-High Train-Low altitude training on maximal oxygen consumption in athletes: A systematic review and Meta-Analysis. Int J Sports Sci Coaching. 2012;7:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1260/1747-9541.7.1.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benavente C, Schoenfeld BJ, Padial P, Feriche B. Efficacy of resistance training in hypoxia on muscle hypertrophy and strength development: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2023;13:3676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-30808-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9985626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36871095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albertus-C&#xe1;mara I, Ferrer-L&#xf3;pez V, Mart&#xed;nez-Gonz&#xe1;lez-Moro I. The effect of Normobaric hypoxia in Middle- and/or Long-Distance runners. Syst Rev Biology (Basel). 2022;11:689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9138601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35625417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamonales JM, Rojas-Valverde D, V&#xe1;squez J, Mart&#xed;nez-Guardado I, Azofeifa-Mora C, S&#xe1;nchez-Ure&#xf1;a B, et al. An update to a comprehensive assessment of the methods and effectiveness of resistance training in Normobaric hypoxia for the development of strength and muscular hypertrophy. Appl Sci. 2023;13:1078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app13021078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brocherie F, Girard O, Faiss R, Millet GP. Effects of Repeated-Sprint training in hypoxia on Sea-Level performance: A Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. 2017;47:1651&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0685-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28194720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seitz H, Preissler E, Catal&#xe1;-Lehnen P, Weitl M. Effects of the &#x2018;live low-train high&#x2018; method on variables of endurance capacity. A systematic review. Dtsch Z Sportmed. 2020;71:43&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5960/dzsm.2019.413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zelenovic M, Kontro T, Stojanovic T, Alexe DI, Bozic D, Aksovic N, et al. Effects of repeated sprint training in hypoxia on physical performance among athletes: A systematic review. Int J Morphol. 2021;39:1625&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4067/S0717-95022021000601625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Campo DJ, Scott BR, Alcaraz PE, Rubio-Arias JA. The efficacy of resistance training in hypoxia to enhance strength and muscle growth: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;18:92&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2017.1388850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29045191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng X, Zhao L, Chen Y, Wang Z, Lu H, Wang C. Optimal type and dose of hypoxic training for improving maximal aerobic capacity in athletes: a systematic review and Bayesian model-based network meta-analysis. Front Physiol [Internet]. 2023 [cited 2025 Jan 7];14. Available from: https://www.frontiersin.org/journals/physiology/articles/10.3389/fphys.2023.1223037/full</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10513096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37745240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng X, Chen Y, Yan T, Lu H, Wang C, Zhao L. Effects of various living-low and training-high modes with distinct training prescriptions on sea-level performance: A network meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2024;19:e0297007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0297007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11025749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38635743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Q, Kong Z, Zou L, Chapman R, Shi Q, Nie J. Comparative efficacy of various hypoxic training paradigms on maximal oxygen consumption: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. J Exerc Sci Fit. 2023;21:366&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jesf.2023.09.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10580050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37854170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westmacott A, Sanal-Hayes NEM, McLaughlin M, Mair JL, Hayes LD. High-Intensity interval training (HIIT) in hypoxia improves maximal aerobic capacity more than HIIT in normoxia: A systematic Review, Meta-Analysis, and Meta-Regression. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:14261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph192114261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9658399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36361141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deb SK, Brown DR, Gough LA, Mclellan CP, Swinton PA, Andy Sparks S, et al. Quantifying the effects of acute hypoxic exposure on exercise performance and capacity: A systematic review and meta-regression. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;18:243&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2017.1410233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29220311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamlin MJ, Lizamore CA, Hopkins WG. The effect of natural or simulated altitude training on High-Intensity intermittent running performance in Team-Sport athletes: A Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48:431&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0809-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29129021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pr&#xe9;cart C, Bouten J, Woorons X, Fornasier-Santos C, Millet GP, Brocherie F. Repeated-Sprint training in hypoxia induced by voluntary hypoventilation at low lung volume: A Meta-analysis. Sports Med Open. 2025;11:55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-025-00853-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12084195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40377793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonetti DL, Hopkins WG, Kilding AE. High-intensity Kayak performance after adaptation to intermittent hypoxia. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2006;1:246&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.1.3.246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19116438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu C-J, Tsai S-C, Liao Y-H, Chen C-Y, Wu K-C. Exploring the potential benefits of interventions when addressing simulated altitude hypoxia during male cyclist sports: A systematic review. Appl Sci. 2024;14:3091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app14073091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fentaw S, Tadesse T, Birhanu Z. Methodological and aerobic capacity adaptations of high-intensity interval training at different altitudes in distance runners: A comprehensive meta&#x2010;analysis. Physiol Rep. 2025;13:e70349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.70349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12045700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40312262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonetti DL, Hopkins WG. Sea-level exercise performance following adaptation to hypoxia: a meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2009;39:107&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200939020-00002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19203133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coates AM, Joyner MJ, Little JP, Jones AM, Gibala MJ. A perspective on High-Intensity interval training for performance and health. Sports Med. 2023;53:85&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-023-01938-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10721680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37804419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batacan RB, Duncan MJ, Dalbo VJ, Tucker PS, Fenning AS. Effects of high-intensity interval training on cardiometabolic health: a systematic review and meta-analysis of intervention studies. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:494&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27797726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montero D, Lundby C. Effects of exercise training in hypoxia versus normoxia on vascular health. Sports Med. 2016;46:1725&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0570-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27286988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verges S, Chacaroun S, Godin-Ribuot D, Baillieul S. Hypoxic conditioning as a new therapeutic modality. Front Pediatr. 2015;3:58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fped.2015.00058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4476260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26157787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gore CJ, Clark SA, Saunders PU. Nonhematological mechanisms of improved sea-level performance after hypoxic exposure. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39:1600&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0b013e3180de49d3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17805094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt W, Prommer N. Impact of alterations in total hemoglobin mass on VO 2max. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2010;38:68&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JES.0b013e3181d4957a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20335738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts AC, Reeves JT, Butterfield GE, Mazzeo RS, Sutton JR, Wolfel EE et al. Altitude and beta-blockade augment glucose utilization during submaximal exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985). 1996;80:605&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8929605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faiss R, Raberin A, Brocherie F, Millet GP. Repeated-sprint training in hypoxia: A review with 10 years of perspective. J Sports Sci. 2025;43:2164&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2024.2416821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39445500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasai N, Kojima C, Sumi D, Takahashi H, Goto K, Suzuki Y. Impact of 5 days of sprint training in hypoxia on performance and muscle energy substances. Int J Sports Med. 2017;38:983&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0043-117413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28965346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey DP, Joyner MJ. Compensatory vasodilatation during hypoxic exercise: mechanisms responsible for matching oxygen supply to demand. J Physiol. 2012;590:6321&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2012.242396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3533194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22988134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilegaard H, Domino K, Noland T, Juel C, Hellsten Y, Halestrap AP, et al. Effect of high-intensity exercise training on lactate/H&#x2009;+&#x2009;transport capacity in human skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol. 1999;276:E255&#x2013;261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9950784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet G, Bentley DJ, Roels B, Mc Naughton LR, Mercier J, Cameron-Smith D. Effects of intermittent training on anaerobic performance and MCT transporters in athletes. PLoS ONE. 2014;9:e95092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0095092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4010422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24797797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatterer H, Philippe M, Menz V, Mosbach F, Faulhaber M, Burtscher M. Shuttle-run sprint training in hypoxia for youth elite soccer players: a pilot study. J Sports Sci Med. 2014;13:731&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4234940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25435763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desplanches D, Hoppeler H, Linossier MT, Denis C, Claassen H, Dormois D, et al. Effects of training in normoxia and Normobaric hypoxia on human muscle ultrastructure. Pflugers Arch. 1993;425:263&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00374176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8309787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woorons X, Mollard P, Pichon A, Duvallet A, Richalet J-P, Lamberto C. Prolonged expiration down to residual volume leads to severe arterial hypoxemia in athletes during submaximal exercise. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2007;158:75&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resp.2007.02.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17434347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto Y, Takei Y, Mutoh Y, Miyashita M. Delayed appearance of blood lactate with reduced frequency breathing during exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1988;57:462&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00417994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3135187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faiss R, L&#xe9;ger B, Vesin J-M, Fournier P-E, Eggel Y, D&#xe9;riaz O, et al. Significant molecular and systemic adaptations after repeated sprint training in hypoxia. PLoS ONE. 2013;8:e56522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0056522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3577885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23437154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woorons X, Faucher C, Dufour SP, Brocherie F, Robach P, Connes P, et al. Hypoventilation training including maximal end-expiratory breath holding improves the ability to repeat high-intensity efforts in elite judo athletes. Front Physiol. 2024;15:1441696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2024.1441696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11467534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39397858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc1;lvarez-Herms J, Juli&#xe0;-S&#xe1;nchez S, Gatterer H, Blank C, Corbi F, Pag&#xe8;s T, et al. Anaerobic training in hypoxia: A new approach to stimulate the rating of effort perception. Physiol Behav. 2016;163:37&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.physbeh.2016.04.035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27126970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karayigit R, Ramirez-Campillo R, Yasli BC, Gabrys T, Benesova D, Esen O. High dose of acute Normobaric hypoxia does not adversely affect sprint interval Training, cognitive performance and heart rate variability in males and females. Biology (Basel). 2022;11:1463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9598265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36290367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warnier G, Benoit N, Naslain D, Lambrecht S, Francaux M, Deldicque L. Effects of sprint interval training at different altitudes on cycling performance at Sea-Level. Sports (Basel). 2020;8:148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports8110148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7698804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33217937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gore CJ, Sharpe K, Garvican-Lewis LA, Saunders PU, Humberstone CE, Robertson EY et al. Altitude training and haemoglobin mass from the optimised carbon monoxide rebreathing method determined by a meta-analysis. 2013 [cited 2025 Jun 16]; Available from: https://bjsm.bmj.com/content/47/Suppl_1/i31#ref-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3903147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24282204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen P, Siebenmann C, D&#xed;az V, Lundby C. Red cell volume expansion at altitude: a meta-analysis and Monte Carlo simulation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45:1767&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31829047e5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23502972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rusko HK, Tikkanen HO, Peltonen JE. Oxygen manipulation as an ergogenic aid. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2003;2:233&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00149619-200308000-00011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12834580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark SA, Quod MJ, Clark MA, Martin DT, Saunders PU, Gore CJ. Time course of haemoglobin mass during 21 days live high:train low simulated altitude. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;106:399&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-009-1027-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19294411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundby C, Robach P. Performance enhancement: what are the physiological limits? Physiol (Bethesda). 2015;30:282&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26136542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson EY, Saunders PU, Pyne DB, Aughey RJ, Anson JM, Gore CJ. Reproducibility of performance changes to simulated live high/train low altitude. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42:394&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181b34b57</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19927018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siebenmann C, Robach P, Jacobs RA, Rasmussen P, Nordsborg N, Diaz V, et al. Live high&#x2013;train low using Normobaric hypoxia: a double-blinded, placebo-controlled study. J Appl Physiol. 2012;112:106&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00388.2011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22033534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millet GP, Brocherie F. Hypoxic training is beneficial in elite athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2020;52:515&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31939914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siebenmann C, Dempsey JA. Hypoxic training is not beneficial in elite athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2020;52:519&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31939915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mollard P, Woorons X, Letournel M, Cornolo J, Lamberto C, Beaudry M, et al. Role of maximal heart rate and arterial O2 saturation on the decrement of VO2max in moderate acute hypoxia in trained and untrained men. Int J Sports Med. 2007;28:186&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2006-924215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17024632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>