<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">27244884</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2018</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1949-2553</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>23</Issue><PubDate><Year>2016</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Oncotarget</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Oncotarget</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Thigh muscle size and vascular function after blood flow-restricted elastic band training in older women.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>33595</StartPage><EndPage>33607</EndPage><MedlinePgn>33595-607</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.18632/oncotarget.9564</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We examined the effect of elastic band training with blood flow restriction (BFR) on thigh muscle size and vascular function in older women. Older women were divided into three groups: low-intensity elastic band BFR training (BFR-Tr, n = 10), middle- to high-intensity elastic band training (MH-Tr, n = 10), and no training (Ctrl, n = 10) groups. BFR-Tr and MH-Tr groups performed squat and knee extension exercises using elastic band, 2 days/week for 12 weeks. During BFR-Tr exercise session, subjects wore pressure cuffs around the most proximal region of both thighs. The following measurements were taken before (pre) and 3-5 days after (post) the final training session: MRI-measured muscle cross-sectional area (CSA) at mid-thigh, maximum voluntary isometric contraction (MVIC) of knee extension, central systolic blood pressure (c-SBP), central-augmentation index (c-AIx), cardio-ankle vascular index testing (CAVI), ankle-brachial pressure index (ABI). Quadriceps muscle CSA (6.9%) and knee extension MVIC (13.7%) were increased (p &lt; 0.05) in the BFR-Tr group, but not in the MH-Tr and the Ctrl groups. Regarding c-SBP, c-AIx, CAVI and ABI, there were no changes between pre- and post- results among the three groups. Elastic band BFR training increases thigh muscle CSA as well as maximal muscle strength, but does not decrease vascular function in older women.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yasuda</LastName><ForeName>Tomohiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Medicine, University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Seirei Christopher University, Shizuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Toho University, Chiba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fukumura</LastName><ForeName>Kazuya</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Medicine, University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tomaru</LastName><ForeName>Takanobu</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Toho University, Chiba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakajima</LastName><ForeName>Toshiaki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate School of Medicine, University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Heart Center, Dokkyo Medical University Hospital, Tochigi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016430">Clinical Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Oncotarget</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101532965</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1949-2553</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012039" MajorTopicYN="N">Regional Blood Flow</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055948" MajorTopicYN="N">Sarcopenia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="Y">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013848" MajorTopicYN="N">Thigh</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000098" MajorTopicYN="N">blood supply</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gerotarget</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">arterial stiffness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sarcopenia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vascular occlusion</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Our department (University of Tokyo) was funded by KAATSU Japan Co., Ltd. This study used equipment manufactured by the KAATSU Japan Co., Ltd.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2015</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2016</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2018</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27244884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5085105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/oncotarget.9564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">9564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Haykowsky MJ, Brubaker PH, Morgan TM, Kritchevsky S, Eggebeen J, Kitzman DW. Impaired aerobic capacity and physical functional performance in older heart failure patients with preserved ejection fraction: role of lean body mass. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med. Sci. 2013;68:968&#x2013;975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3712362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23525477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visser M, Goddpaster BH, Kritchevsky SB, Newman AB, Nevitt M, Rubin SM, Simonsick EM, Harris TB. Muscle mass, muscle strength, and muscle fat infiltration as predictors of incident mobility limitations in well-functioning older persons. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med. Sci. 2005;60:324&#x2013;333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15860469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiatarone MA, Marks EC, Ryan ND, Meredith CN, Lipsitz LA, Evans WJ. High-intensity strength training in nonagenarians. Effects on skeletal muscle. JAMA. 1990;263:3029&#x2013;3034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2342214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frontera WR, Meredith CN, O_Reilly KP, Knuttgen HG, Evans WJ. Strength conditioning in older men: skeletal muscle hypertrophy and improved function. J Appl Physiol. 1988;64:1038&#x2013;1044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3366726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Suetta C, Caserotti P, Magnusson SP, Kjaer M. Role of the nervous system in sarcopenia and muscle atrophy with aging: strength training as a countermeasure. Scand J Med Sci. Sports. 2010;20:49&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20487503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro F, Teixeira F, Brochado G, Oliveira J. Impact of low cost strength training of dorsi- and plantar flexors on balance and functional mobility in institutionalized elderly people. Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2009;9:75&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19260983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zion AS, De Meersman R, Diamond BE, Bloomfield DM. A home-based resistance-training program using elastic bands for elderly patients with orthostatic hypotension. Clin Auton Res. 2003;13:286&#x2013;292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12955554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikesky A, Topp R, Wigglesworth J, Harsha DM, Edwards J. Efficacy of a home based training program for older adults using elastic tubing. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1994;69:316&#x2013;320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7851367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colado JC, Triplett NT. Effects of a short-term resistance program using elastic bands vs. weight machines for sedentary middle-aged women. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22:1441&#x2013;1448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18714245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Nakamura Y, Aruga S, Onda T, Miyazaki S, Ishii N. Rapid increase in plasma growth hormone after low-intensity resistance exercise with vascular occlusion. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88:61&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10642363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Yasuda T, Midorikawa T, Sato Y, Kearns CF, Inoue K, Koizumi K, Ishii N. Skeletal muscle size and circulating IGF-1 are increased after two weeks of twice daily &#x201c;KAATSU&#x201d; resistance training. Int. J. Kaatsu Training Res. 2005;1:6&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Rourke M. Arterial stiffness, systolic blood pressure, and logical treatment of arterial hypertension. Hypertension. 1990;15:339&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2180816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monahan KD, Tanaka H, Dinenno FA, Seals DR. Central arterial compliance is associated with age- and habitual exercise-related differences in cardiovagal baroreflex sensitivity. Circulation. 2001;104:1627&#x2013;1632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyachi M, Donato AJ, Yamamoto K, Takahashi K, Gates PE, Moreau KL, Tanaka H. Greater age-related reductions in central arterial compliance in resistance-trained men. Hypertension. 2003;41:130&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12511542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyachi M, Kawano H, Sugawara J, Takahashi K, Hayashi K, Yamazaki K, Tabata I, Tanaka H. Unfavorable effects of resistance training on central arterial compliance: a randomized intervention study. Circulation. 2004;110:2858&#x2013;2863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15492301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey DP, Pierce GL, Howe KS, Mering MC, Braith RW. Effect of resistance training on arterial wave reflection and brachial artery reactivity in normotensive postmenopausal women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;100:403&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17394009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rakobowchuk M, McGowan CL, de Groot PC, Bruinsma D, Hartman JW, Phillips SM, MacDonald MJ. Effect of whole body resistance training on arterial compliance in young men. Exp Physiol. 2005;90:645&#x2013;651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15849230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahs CA, Rossow LM, Thiebaud RS, Loenneke JP, Kim D, Abe T, Beck TW, Feeback DL, Bemben DA, Bemben MG. Vascular adaptations to low-load resistance training with and without blood flow restriction. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114:715&#x2013;724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24375201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozaki H, Yasuda T, Ogasawara R, Sakamaki-Sunaga M, Naito H, Abe T. Effects of high-intensity and blood flow-restricted low-intensity resistance training on carotid arterial compliance: role of blood pressure during training sessions. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113:167&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22618304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Fukumura K, Fukuda T, Uchida Y, Iida H, Meguro M, Sato Y, Yamasoba T, Nakajima T. Muscle size and arterial stiffness after blood flow-restricted low-intensity resistance training in older adults. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24:799&#x2013;806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23730848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyatani M, Kanehisa H, Azuma K, Kuno S, Fukunaga T. Site-related differences in muscle loss with aging: a cross sectional survey on the muscle thickness in Japanese men and Age-related muscle loss in Japanese adults 150 women aged 20 to 79 years. Int J Sport Health Sci. 2003;1:34&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Sakamaki M, Yasuda T, Bemben MG, Kondo M, Kawakami Y, Fukunaga T. Age related, site-specific muscle loss in 1507 Japanese men and women aged 20 to 95 years. Journal of Sports Science and Medicine. 2011;10:145&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3737910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiebaud RS, Loenneke JP, Fahs CA, Rossow LM, Kim D, Abe T, Anderson MA, Young KC, Bemben DA, Bemben MG. The effects of elastic band resistance training combined with blood flow restriction on strength, total bone-free lean body mass and muscle thickness in postmenopausal women. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2013;33:344&#x2013;352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23701116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrella JK, Kim JS, Mayhew DL, Cross JM, Bamman MM. Potent myofiber hypertrophy during resistance training in humans is associated with satellite cell-mediated myonuclear addition: a cluster analysis. J Appl Physiol. 2008;104:1736&#x2013;1742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18436694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen JL, Aagaard P, Bech RD, Nygaard T, Hvid LG, Wernbom M, Suetta C, Frandsen U. Proliferation of myogenic stem cells in human skeletal muscle in response to low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction. J Physiol. 2012;590:4351&#x2013;4361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3473290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22802591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Fahs CA, Rossow LM, Abe T, Bemben MG. The anabolic benefits of venous blood flow restriction training may be induced by muscle cell swelling. Med Hypotheses. 2012;78:151&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22051111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Loenneke JP, Thiebaud RS, Abe T. Effects of low-intensity blood flow restricted concentric or eccentric training on muscle size and strength. PLoS One. 2012;12:e52843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3534116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23300795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Abe T, Brechue WF, Iida H, Takano H, Meguro K, Kurano M, Fujita S, Nakajima T. Venous blood gas and metabolite response to low-intensity muscle contractions with external limb compression. Metabolism. 2010;59:1510&#x2013;1519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20199783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller U, Szinnai G, Bilz S, Berneis K. Effects of changes in hydration on protein, glucose and lipid metabolism in man: impact on health. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2003;57(Suppl 2):S69&#x2013;S74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14681716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millar ID, Barber MC, Lomax MA, Travers MT, Shennan DB. Mammary protein synthesis is acutely regulated by the cellular hydration state. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 1997;230:351&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9016782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nigam A, Mitchell GF, Lambert J, Tardif JC. Relation between conduit vessel stiffness (assessed by tonometry) and endothelial function (assessed by flow-mediated dilatation) in patients with and without coronary heart disease. Am J Cardiol. 2003;92:395&#x2013;399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12914868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark BC, Manini TM, Hoffman RL, Williams PS, Guiler MK, Knutson MJ, McGlynn ML, Kushnick MR. Relative safety of 4 weeks of blood flow-restricted resistance exercise in young, healthy adults. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2011;21:653&#x2013;662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6152804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21917016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakajima T, Kurano M, Iida H, Takano H, Oonuma H, Morita T, Meguro K, Sato Y, Nagata T, KATTSU Training Group Use and safety of KAATSU training: Results of a national survey. Int. J. KAATSU Training Res. 2006;2:5&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagally KM, Robertson RJ. Construct validity of the OMNI resistance exercise scale. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20:252&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16686549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greig CA, Young A, Skelton DA, Pippet E, Butler FM, Mahmud SM. Exercise studies with elderly volunteers. Age Ageing. 1994;23:185&#x2013;189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8085501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Japanese Society of Hypertension Guidelines for Management of Hypertension (JSH 2014) Hypertens Res. 2014;37:253&#x2013;392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24705419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page P, Labbe A, Topp RV. Clinical force production of thera-band elastic bands. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2000;30:A47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Ogasawara R, Sakamaki M, Ozaki H, Sato Y, Abe T. Combined effects of low-intensity blood flow restriction training and high-intensity resistance training on muscle strength and size. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111:2525&#x2013;2533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21360203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozaki H, Sakamaki M, Yasuda T, Fujita S, Ogasawara R, Sugaya M, Nakajima T, Abe T. Increases in thigh muscle volume and strength by walk training with leg blood flow reduction in older participants. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2010;66:257&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20974731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wathen D. Load Assignment. In: Baechle TR, editor. Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 1994. pp. 435&#x2013;439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takazawa K, Kobayashi H, Shindo N, Tanaka N, Yamashina A. Relationship between radial and central arterial pulse wave and evaluation of central aortic pressure using the radial arterial pulse wave. Hypertens Res. 2007;30:219&#x2013;228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17510503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takase H, Dohi Y, Kimura G. Distribution of central blood pressure values estimated by Omron HEM-9000AI in the Japanese general population. Hypertens Res. 2013;36:50&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22895062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirai K, Otsuka K, Takata M. A novel blood pressure independent arterial wall stiffness parameter: cardio-ankle vascular index (CAVI) J Atheroscler Thromb. 2006;13:101&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16733298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. 2nd. Hillsdale, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates Inc; 1988. pp. 19&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>