<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">29985221</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2018</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Recent Advancements in Our Understanding of the Ergogenic Effect of Respiratory Muscle Training in Healthy Humans: A Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2665</StartPage><EndPage>2676</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2665-2676</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002730</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Shei, R-J. Recent advancements in our understanding of the ergogenic effect of respiratory muscle training in healthy humans: a systematic review. J Strength Cond Res 32(9): 2674-2685, 2018-Respiratory muscle training (RMT) has been shown to be an effective ergogenic aid for sport performance. Respiratory muscle training has been documented to improve performance in a wide range of exercise modalities including running, cycling, swimming, and rowing. The physiological effects of RMT that may explain the improvements in performance have been proposed to include diaphragm hypertrophy, muscle fiber-type switching, improved neural control of the respiratory muscles, increased respiratory muscle economy, attenuation of the respiratory muscle metaboreflex, and decreases in perceived breathlessness and exertion. This review summarizes recent studies on the ergogenicity and mechanisms of RMT since 2013 when the topic was last systematically reviewed. Recent evidence confirms the ergogenic effects of RMT and explores different loading protocols, such as concurrent exercise and RMT (i.e., "functional" RMT). These studies suggest that adapting new training protocols may have an additive improvement effect, but evidence of the efficacy of such an approach is conflicting thus far. Other recent investigations have furthered our understanding of the mechanisms underpinning RMT-associated improvements in performance. Importantly, changes in ventilatory efficiency, oxygen delivery, cytokine release, motor recruitment patterns, and respiratory muscle fatigue resistance are highlighted as potential mechanistic factors linking RMT with performance improvements. It is suggested that future investigations focus on development of sport-specific RMT loading protocols, and that further work be undertaken to better understand the mechanistic basis of RMT-induced performance improvements.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shei</LastName><ForeName>Ren-Jay</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary, Allergy, and Critical Care Medicine, and Gregory Fleming James Cystic Fibrosis Research Center, Department of Medicine, University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>T32 HL105346</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054874" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletic Performance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001945" MajorTopicYN="Y">Breathing Exercises</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018763" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012132" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory Muscles</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Conflict of Interest</b>. R-J.S. declares no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29985221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS970698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6105530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aliverti A. The respiratory muscles during exercise. Breathe. 2016;12:165&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4933622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27408635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amann M, Pegelow DF, Jacques AJ, Dempsey JA. Inspiratory muscle work in acute hypoxia influences locomotor muscle fatigue and exercise performance of healthy humans. Am J Physiol - Reg Integr Comp Physiol. 2007;293:R2036&#x2013;R2045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17715180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Archiza B, Andaku DK, Caruso FCR, Bonjorno JC, Oliveira CRd, Ricci PA, Amaral ACd, Mattiello SM, Libardi CA, Phillips SA, Arena R, Borghi-Silva A. Effects of inspiratory muscle training in professional women football players: a randomized sham-controlled trial. J Sport Sci. 2018;36:771&#x2013;780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28622081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey SJ, Romer LM, Kelly J, Wilkerson DP, DiMenna FJ, Jones AM. Inspiratory muscle training enhances pulmonary O2 uptake kinetics and high-intensity exercise tolerance in humans. J Appl Physiol. 2010;109:457&#x2013;468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20507969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell GJ, Game A, Jones R, Webster T, Forbes SC, Syrotuik D. Inspiratory and expiratory respiratory muscle training as an adjunct to concurrent strength and endurance training provides no additional 2000 m performance benefits to rowers. Res Sports Med. 2013;21:264&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23777381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernardi E, Melloni E, Mandolesi G, Uliari S, Grazzi G, Cogo A. Respiratory muscle endurance training improves breathing pattern in triathletes. Ann Sports Med Res. 2014;1:1003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brilla LR, Kauffman TH. Effect of inspiratory muscle training and core exercise training on core functional tests. J Exerc Physiol. 2014;17:12&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cafarelli E. Peripheral contributions to the perception of effort. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1982;14:382&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7154894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caine, McConnell Development and evaluation of a pressure threshold inspiratory muscle trainer for use in the context of sports performance. Sports Engineering. 2000;3:149&#x2013;159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatham K, Baldwin J, Griffiths H, Summers L, Enright S. Inspiratory muscle training improves shuttle run performance in healthy subjects. Physiotherapy. 1999;85:676&#x2013;683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cybulska A, Drobnik P. An assessment of the impact of special training of inspiratory muscles in a fitness classes programme on physical capacity of 20&#x2013;25-year-old women. Baltic J Health Physical Activity. 2015;7:37&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dempsey JA, Amann M, Harms CA, Wetter TJ. Respiratory system limitations to performance in the healthy athlete: some answers, more questions! Deutsche Zeitschrift f&#xfc;r Sportmedizin. 2012;63:157&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dempsey JA, Romer L, Rodman J, Miller J, Smith C. Consequences of exercise-induced respiratory muscle work. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2006;151:242&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16616716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downey AE, Chenoweth LM, Townsend DK, Ranum JD, Ferguson CS, Harms CA. Effects of inspiratory muscle training on exercise responses in normoxia and hypoxia. Respir Physiol Neurobio. 2007;156:137&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16996322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards AM. Respiratory muscle training extends exercise tolerance without concomitant change to peak oxygen uptake: physiological, performance and perceptual responses derived from the same incremental exercise test. Respirology. 2013;18:1022&#x2013;1027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23600609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enright SJ, Unnithan VB, Heward C, Withnall L, Davies DH. Effect of high-intensity inspiratory muscle training on lung volumes, diaphragm thickness, and exercise capacity in subjects who are healthy. Phys Ther. 2006;86:345&#x2013;354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16506871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faghy MA, Brown PI. Preloaded time trial to assess load carriage performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28:3354&#x2013;3362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24910952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faghy MA, Brown PI. Thoracic load carriage-induced respiratory muscle fatigue. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114:1085&#x2013;1093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24526164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faghy MA, Brown PI. Training the inspiratory muscles improves running performance when carrying a 25 kg thoracic load in a backpack. Eur J Sport Sci. 2016;16:585&#x2013;594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26274785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faghy MA, Brown PI. Whole-body active warm-up and inspiratory muscle warm-up do not improve running performance when carrying thoracic loads. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2017;42:810&#x2013;815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28288302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairbarn MS, Coutts KC, Pardy RL, McKenzie DC. Improved respiratory muscle endurance of highly trained cyclists and the effects on maximal exercise performance. Int J Sports Med. 1991;12:66&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2030063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Granados J, Gillum TL, Castillo W, Christmas KM, Kuennen MR. &#x201c;Functional&#x201d; respiratory muscle training during endurance exercise causes modest hypoxemia but overall is well tolerated. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30:755&#x2013;762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26340471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guy JH, Edwards AM, Deakin GB. Inspiratory muscle training improves exercise tolerance in recreational soccer players without concomitant gain in soccer-specific fitness. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28:483&#x2013;491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23722111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>HajGhanbari B, Yamabayashi C, Buna TR, Coelho JD, Freedman KD, Morton TA, Palmer SA, Toy MA, Walsh C, Sheel AW, Reid WD. Effects of respiratory muscle training on performance in athletes: a systematic review with meta-analyses. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27:1643&#x2013;1663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22836606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harms CA, Babcock MA, McClaran SR, Pegelow DF, Nickele GA, Nelson WB, Dempsey JA. Respiratory muscle work compromises leg blood flow during maximal exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1997;82:1573&#x2013;1583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9134907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harms CA, Wetter TJ, McClaran SR, Pegelow DF, Nickele GA, Nelson WB, Hanson P, Dempsey JA. Effects of respiratory muscle work on cardiac output and its distribution during maximal exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1998;85:609&#x2013;618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9688739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Held HE, Pendergast DR. The effects of respiratory muscle training on respiratory mechanics and energy cost. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2014;200:7&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24816143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helfer S, Quackenbush J, Fletcher M, Pendergast DR. Respiratory Muscle Training and Exercise Endurance at Altitude. Aerosp Med Hum Perform. 2016;87:704&#x2013;711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27634605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellyer NJ, Folsom IA, Gaz DV, Kakuk AC, Mack JL, Ver Mulm JA. Respiratory muscle activity during simultaneous stationary cycling and inspiratory muscle training. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29:3517&#x2013;3522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26584054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holm P, Sattler A, Fregosi R. Endurance training of respiratory muscles improves cycling performance in fit young cyclists. BMC Physiol. 2004;4:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC419707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15132753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang CH, Martin AD, Davenport PW. Effect of inspiratory muscle strength training on inspiratory motor drive and RREP early peak components. J Appl Physiol. 2003;94:462&#x2013;468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12391135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Illi SK, Held U, Frank I, Spengler CM. Effect of respiratory muscle training on exercise performance in healthy individuals. Sports Med. 2012;42:707&#x2013;724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22765281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson BD, Babcock MA, Suman OE, Dempsey JA. Exercise-induced diaphragmatic fatigue in healthy humans. J Physiol. 1993;460:385&#x2013;405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1175219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8487201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson M, Sharpe G, Brown P. Inspiratory muscle training improves cycling time-trial performance and anaerobic work capacity but not critical power. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;101:761&#x2013;770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17874123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapus J. Effects of inspiratory muscle training on inspiratory muscle strength and sprint swimming performance in young female and male swimmers. Kinesiologia Slovenica. 2013;19:53&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilding A, Brown S, McConnell A. Inspiratory muscle training improves 100 and 200 m swimming performance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;108:505&#x2013;511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19841931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leddy JJ, Limprasertkul A, Patel S, Modlich F, Buyea C, Pendergast DR, Lundgren CEG. Isocapnic hyperpnea training improves performance in competitive male runners. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;99:665&#x2013;676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17242946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemaitre F, Coquart JB, Chavallard F, Castres I, Mucci P, Costalat G, Chollet D. Effect of Additional Respiratory Muscle Endurance Training in Young Well-Trained Swimmers. J Sports Sci Med. 2013;12:630&#x2013;638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3873652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24421721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lomax M, Kapus J, Brown PI, Faghy M. Impact of weekly swimming training distance on the ergogenicity of inspiratory muscle training in well trained youth swimmers. J Strength Cond Res. Publish Ahead of Print, Post-Acceptance November 21, 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31344014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lomax M, Massey HC, House JR. Inspiratory muscle training effects on cycling during acute hypoxic exposure. Aerosp Med Hum Perform. 2017;88:544&#x2013;549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28539142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McConnell AK. Respiratory muscle training as an ergogenic aid. J Exerc Sci Fit. 2009;7:S18&#x2013;S27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McConnell AK. CrossTalk opposing view: Respiratory muscle training does improve exercise tolerance. J Physiol. 2012;590:3397&#x2013;3398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3547251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22855045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEntire SJ, Smith JR, Ferguson CS, Brown KR, Kurti SP, Harms CA. The effect of exercise training with an additional inspiratory load on inspiratory muscle fatigue and time-trial performance. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2016;230:54&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27195511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMahon ME, Boutellier U, Smith RM, Spengler CM. Hyperpnea training attenuates peripheral chemosensitivity and improves cycling endurance. J Exp Biol. 2002;205:3937&#x2013;3943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12432015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menezes KKP, Nascimento LR, Ada L, Polese JC, Avelino PR, Teixeira-Salmela LF. Respiratory muscle training increases respiratory muscle strength and reduces respiratory complications after stroke: a systematic review. J Physiother. 2016;62:138&#x2013;144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27320833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mickleborough T, Stager J, Chatham K, Lindley M, Ionescu A. Pulmonary adaptations to swim and inspiratory muscle training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;103:635&#x2013;646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18478253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mickleborough TD, Nichols T, Lindley MR, Chatham K, Ionescu AA. Inspiratory flow resistive loading improves respiratory muscle function and endurance capacity in recreational runners. Scan J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20:458&#x2013;468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19558387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills DE, Johnson MA, McPhilimey MJ, Williams NC, Gonzalez JT, Barnett YA, Sharpe GR. The effects of inspiratory muscle training on plasma interleukin-6 concentration during cycling exercise and a volitional mimic of the exercise hyperpnea. J Appl Physiol. 2013;115:1163&#x2013;1172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23887901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills DE, Johnson MA, McPhilimey MJ, Williams NC, Gonzalez JT, Barnett YA, Sharpe GR. Influence of oxidative stress, diaphragm fatigue, and inspiratory muscle training on the plasma cytokine response to maximum sustainable voluntary ventilation. J Appl Physiol. 2014;116:970&#x2013;979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24557794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishchenko V, Sawczyn S, Cybulska A, Pasek M. Special Training of Inspiratory Muscles in Fitness Activities and Exercise Capacity in Young Women. Hum Mov. 2017:46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan DW, Kohrt WM, Bates BJ, Skinner JS. Effects of respiratory muscle endurance training on ventilatory and endurance performance of moderately trained cyclists. Int J Sports Med. 1987;08:88&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3596882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noakes TD. Fatigue is a brain-derived emotion that regulates the exercise behavior to ensure the protection of whole body homeostasis. Front Physiol. 2012;3:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3323922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22514538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oueslati F, Berriri A, Boone J, Ahmaidi S. Respiratory muscle strength is decreased after maximal incremental exercise in trained runners and cyclists. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2018;248:25&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29155334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozmen T, Gunes GY, Ucar I, Dogan H, Gafuroglu TU. Effect of respiratory muscle training on pulmonary function and aerobic endurance in soccer players. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2017;57:507&#x2013;513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28399624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel MS, Hart N, Polkey MI. CrossTalk proposal: Training the respiratory muscles does not improve exercise tolerance. J Physiol. 2012;590:3393&#x2013;3395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3547250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22855044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porcari JP, Probst L, Forrester K, Doberstein S, Foster C, Cress ML, Schmidt K. Effect of wearing the elevation training mask on aerobic capacity, lung function, and hematological variables. J Sports Sci Med. 2016;15:379&#x2013;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4879455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27274679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramsook AH, Koo R, Molgat-Seon Y, Dominelli PB, Syed N, Ryerson CJ, Sheel AW, Guenette JA. Diaphragm recruitment increases during a bout of targeted inspiratory muscle training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48:1179&#x2013;1186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26795460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramsook AH, Molgat-Seon Y, Schaeffer MR, Wilkie SS, Camp PG, Reid WD, Romer LM, Guenette JA. Effects of inspiratory muscle training on respiratory muscle electromyography and dyspnea during exercise in healthy men. J Appl Physiol. 2017;122:1267&#x2013;1275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5451532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28255085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raux M, Demoule A, Redolfi S, Morelot-Panzini C, Similowski T. Reduced phrenic motoneuron recruitment during sustained inspiratory threshold loading compared to single-breath loading: A twitch interpolation study. Front Physiol. 2016;7:537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5102887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27891099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raux M, Tyvaert L, Ferreira M, Kindler F, Bardinet E, Karachi C, Morelot-Panzini C, Gotman J, Pike GB, Koski L, Similowski T. Functional magnetic resonance imaging suggests automatization of the cortical response to inspiratory threshold loading in humans. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2013;189:571&#x2013;580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23994177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riganas CS, Vrabas IS, Christoulas K, Mandroukas K. Specific inspiratory muscle training does not improve performance or VO2max levels in well trained rowers. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2008;48:285&#x2013;292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18974712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romer LM, Haverkamp HC, Amann M, Lovering AT, Pegelow DF, Dempsey JA. Effect of acute severe hypoxia on peripheral fatigue and endurance capacity in healthy humans. Am J Physiol - Reg Integr Comp Physiol. 2007;292:R598&#x2013;R606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16959862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romer LM, McConnell AK, Jones DA. Inspiratory muscle fatigue in trained cyclists: effects of inspiratory muscle training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34:785&#x2013;792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11984296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salazar-Mart&#xed;nez E, Gatterer H, Burtscher M, Naranjo Orellana J, Santalla A. Influence of inspiratory muscle training on ventilatory efficiency and cycling performance in normoxia and hypoxia. Front Physiol. 2017;8:133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5340768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28337149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sales ATdN, Fregonezi GAdF, Ramsook AH, Guenette JA, Lima INDF, Reid WD. Respiratory muscle endurance after training in athletes and non-athletes: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Phys Ther Sport. 2016;17:76&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26626464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segizbaeva MO, Timofeev NN, Donina ZA, Kur&#x2019;yanovich EN, Aleksandrova NP. Effects of Inspiratory Muscle Training on Resistance to Fatigue of Respiratory Muscles During Exhaustive Exercise. In: Pokorski M, editor. Body Metab Exerc. Cham: Springer International Publishing; 2015. pp. 35&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25248344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheel AW. Respiratory muscle training in healthy individuals. Sports Med. 2002;32:567&#x2013;581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12096930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheel AW, Derchak PA, Morgan BJ, Pegelow DF, Jacques AJ, Dempsey JA. Fatiguing inspiratory muscle work causes reflex reduction in resting leg blood flow in humans. J Physiol. 2001;537:277&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11711580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shei R-J. Respiratory muscle training and aquatic sports performance. J Sports Sci Med. 2018;17:161&#x2013;162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5844203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29535590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shei R-J, Chapman RF, Gruber AH, Mickleborough TD. Respiratory effects of thoracic load carriage exercise and inspiratory muscle training as a strategy to optimize respiratory muscle performance with load carriage. Springer Sci Rev. 2017;5:49&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5884160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29630067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shei R-J, Chapman RF, Gruber AH, Mickleborough TD. Inspiratory muscle training improves exercise capacity with thoracic load carriage. Physiol Rep. 2018;6:e13558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5805854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29424007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shei R-J, Lindley MR, Chatham K, Mickleborough TD. Effect of flow-resistive inspiratory loading on pulmonary and respiratory muscle function in sub-elite swimmers. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2016;56:392&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25503711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shei R-J, Paris HLR, Wilhite DP, Chapman RF, Mickleborough TD. The role of inspiratory muscle training in the management of asthma and exercise-induced bronchoconstriction. Phys Sportsmed. 2016;44:327&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27094568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smart NA, Giallauria F, Dieberg G. Efficacy of inspiratory muscle training in chronic heart failure patients: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Cardiol. 2013;167:1502&#x2013;1507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22560934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonetti DA, Wetter TJ, Pegelow DF, Dempsey JA. Effects of respiratory muscle training versus placebo on endurance exercise performance. Respir Physiol. 2001;127:185&#x2013;199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11504589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St Croix CM, Morgan BJ, Wetter TJ, Dempsey JA. Fatiguing inspiratory muscle work causes reflex sympathetic activation in humans. J Physiol. 2000;529:493&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2270191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11101657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong TK, McConnell AK, Lin H, Nie J, Zhang H, Wang J. &#x201c;Functional&#x201d; inspiratory and core muscle training enhances running performance and economy. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30:2942&#x2013;2951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25162653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner LA, Tecklenburg-Lund SL, Chapman RF, Shei R-J, Wilhite DP, Mickleborough TD. The effect of inspiratory muscle training on respiratory and limb locomotor muscle deoxygenation during exercise with resistive inspiratory loading. Int J Sports Med. 2016;37:598&#x2013;606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27191210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner LA, Tecklenburg-Lund SL, Chapman RF, Stager JM, Wilhite DP, Mickleborough TD. Inspiratory muscle training lowers the oxygen cost of voluntary hyperpnea. J Appl Physiol. 2012;112:127&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21979803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Va&#x161;&#xed;&#x10d;kov&#xe1; J, Neumannov&#xe1; K, Svozil Z. The effect of respiratory muscle training on fin-swimmers&#x2019; performance. J Sports Sci Med. 2017;16:521&#x2013;526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5721182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29238252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volianitis S, McConnell AK, Koutedakis Y, McNaughton L, Backx K, Jones DA. Inspiratory muscle training improves rowing performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:803&#x2013;809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11323552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walterspacher S, Pietsch F, Walker DJ, R&#xf6;cker K, Kabitz H-J. Activation of respiratory muscles during respiratory muscle training. Respir Physiol Neurobiol. 2018;247:126&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29037769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witt JD, Guenette JA, Rupert JL, McKenzie DC, Sheel AW. Inspiratory muscle training attenuates the human respiratory muscle metaboreflex. J Physiol. 2007;584:1019&#x2013;1028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2277000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17855758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C-Y, Yang T-Y, Lo P-Y, GUo L-Y. Effects of respiratory muscle training on exercise performance in tennis players. Med Sport. 2017;70:318&#x2013;327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wylegala J, Pendergast D, Gosselin L, Warkander D, Lundgren CG. Respiratory muscle training improves swimming endurance in divers. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;99:393&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17165052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>