<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">30524717</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2048-8505</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2018</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical kidney journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Kidney J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Chronic kidney disease: considerations for monitoring skeletal muscle health and prescribing resistance exercise.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>822</StartPage><EndPage>831</EndPage><MedlinePgn>822-831</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/ckj/sfy054</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Skeletal muscle wasting has gained interest as a primary consequence of chronic kidney disease (CKD) due to the relationship between skeletal muscle mass, mortality and major adverse cardiovascular events in this population. The combination of reductions in physical function, skeletal muscle performance and skeletal muscle mass places individuals with CKD at greater risk of sarcopenia. Therefore the monitoring of skeletal muscle composition and function may provide clinical insight into disease progression. Dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry and bioelectrical impedance analysis are frequently used to estimate body composition in people with CKD within clinical research environments, however, their translation into clinical practice has been limited. Proxy measures of skeletal muscle quality can be obtained using diagnostic ultrasound, providing a cost-effective and accessible imaging modality to aid further clinical research regarding changes in muscle composition. Clinicians and practitioners should evaluate the strengths and limitations of the available technology to determine which devices are most appropriate given their respective circumstances. Progressive resistance exercise has been shown to improve skeletal muscle hypertrophy of the lower extremities, muscular strength and health-related quality of life in end-stage renal disease, with limited evidence available in CKD predialysis. Fundamental principles (i.e. specificity, overload, variation, reversibility, individuality) can be used in the development of more advanced programs focused on improving specific neuromuscular and functional outcomes. Future research is needed to determine the applicability of skeletal muscle monitoring in clinical settings and the feasibility and efficacy of more advanced resistance exercise approaches in those with CKD predialysis.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gollie</LastName><ForeName>Jared M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1066-7389</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Muscle Morphology, Mechanics and Performance Laboratory, Human Performance Research Unit, Clinical Research Center, Veterans Affairs Medical Center, Washington, DC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Human Function, and Rehabilitation Sciences, School of Medicine &amp; Health Sciences, George Washington University, Washington, DC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harris-Love</LastName><ForeName>Michael O</ForeName><Initials>MO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Muscle Morphology, Mechanics and Performance Laboratory, Human Performance Research Unit, Clinical Research Center, Veterans Affairs Medical Center, Washington, DC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise and Nutritional Sciences, Milken Institute School of Public Health, George Washington University, Washington, DC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Geriatrics and Extended Care Service/Research Service, Veterans Affairs Medical Center, Washington, DC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patel</LastName><ForeName>Samir S</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Renal Service, Veterans Affairs Medical Center, Washington, DC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, School of Medicine &amp; Health Sciences, George Washington University, Washington, DC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Argani</LastName><ForeName>Sholey</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Renal Service, Veterans Affairs Medical Center, Washington, DC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, School of Medicine &amp; Health Sciences, George Washington University, Washington, DC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, School of Medicine, Uniform Services University of the Health Sciences, Bethesda, MD, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>IK2 RX001854</GrantID><Acronym>RX</Acronym><Agency>RRD VA</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UL1 TR000101</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UL1 TR001409</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2018</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Kidney J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101579321</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2048-8505</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CKD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pre-dialysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ultrasonography</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2018</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2018</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30524717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6275456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ckj/sfy054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">sfy054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Levin A, Tonelli M, Bonventre J. et al. Global kidney health 2017 and beyond: a roadmap for closing gaps in care, research, and policy. Lancet 2017; 390: 1888&#x2013;1917</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28434650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster AC, Nagler EV, Morton RL. et al. Chronic kidney disease. Lancet 2017; 389: 1238&#x2013;1252</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27887750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Workeneh BT, Mitch WE.. Review of muscle wasting associated with chronic kidney disease. Am J Clin Nutr 2010; 91: 1128S&#x2013;1132S</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20181807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang XH, Mitch WE.. Mechanisms of muscle wasting in chronic kidney disease. Nat Rev Nephrol 2014; 10: 504&#x2013;516</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4269363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24981816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avin KG, Moorthi RN.. Bone is not alone: the effects of skeletal muscle dysfunction in chronic kidney disease. Curr Osteoporos Rep 2015; 13: 173&#x2013;179</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4860015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25691218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Hellberg M, Svensson P. et al. Sarcopenia and relationships between muscle mass, measured glomerular filtration rate and physical function in patients with chronic kidney disease stages 3&#x2013;5. Nephrol Dial Transplant 2018; 33: 342&#x2013;348</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28340152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harada K, Suzuki S, Ishii H. et al. Impact of skeletal muscle mass on long-term adverse cardiovascular outcomes in patients with chronic kidney disease. Am J Cardiol 2017; 119: 1275&#x2013;1280</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28215411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen I, Ross R.. Linking age-related changes in skeletal muscle mass and composition with metabolism and disease. J Nutr Health Aging 2005; 9: 408&#x2013;419</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16395513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheema B, Abas H, Smith B. et al. Progressive Exercise for Anabolism in Kidney Disease (PEAK): a randomized, controlled trial of resistance training during hemodialysis. J Am Soc Nephrol 2007; 18: 1594&#x2013;601</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17409306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delgado C, Shieh S, Grimes B. et al. Association of self-reported frailty with falls and fractures among patients new to dialysis. Am J Nephrol 2015; 42: 134&#x2013;140</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4596065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26381744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gould DW, Graham-Brown MP, Watson EL. et al. Physiological benefits of exercise in pre-dialysis chronic kidney disease: exercise in chronic kidney disease. Nephrology 2014; 19: 519&#x2013;527</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24899042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheema BS, Chan D, Fahey P. et al. Effect of progressive resistance training on measures of skeletal muscle hypertrophy, muscular strength and health-related quality of life in patients with chronic kidney disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 2014; 44: 1125&#x2013;1138</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24696049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan D, Cheema BS.. Progressive resistance training in end-stage renal disease: systematic review. Am J Nephrol 2016; 44: 32&#x2013;45</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27355619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacKinnon HJ, Feehally J, Smith AC.. A review of the role of exercise and factors affecting its uptake for people with chronic kidney disease (CKD) not requiring renal replacement therapy. Pril (Makedon Akad Nauk Umet Odd Med Nauki) 2015; 36: 37&#x2013;46</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26076773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA.. Fundamentals of resistance training: progression and exercise prescription. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2004; 36: 674&#x2013;688</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15064596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. National Chronic Kidney Disease Fact Sheet, 2017. Atlanta, GA: US Department of Health and Human Services, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, 2017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massy Z, Drueke T.. Adynamic bone disease is a predominant bone pattern in early stages of chronic kidney disease. J Nephrol 2017; 30: 629&#x2013;34</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28405928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klarenbach SW, Tonelli M, Chui B. et al. Economic evaluation of dialysis therapies. Nat Rev Nephrol 2014; 10: 644&#x2013;652</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25157840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanholder R, Annemans L, Brown E. et al. Reducing the costs of chronic kidney disease while delivering quality health care: a call to action. Nat Rev Nephrol 2017; 13: 393&#x2013;409</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28555652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumeister SE, B&#xf6;ger CA, Kr&#xe4;mer BK. et al. Effect of chronic kidney disease and comorbid conditions on health care costs: a 10-year observational study in a general population. Am J Nephrol 2010; 31: 222&#x2013;229</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20068286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris A, Cooper BA, Li JJ. et al. Cost-effectiveness of initiating dialysis early: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Kidney Dis 2011; 57: 707&#x2013;715</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21349618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas SS, Mitch WE.. Mechanisms stimulating muscle wasting in chronic kidney disease: the roles of the ubiquitin-proteasome system and myostatin. Clin Exp Nephrol 2013; 17: 174&#x2013;182</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3628947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23292175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vega A, Abad S, Mac&#xed;as N. et al. Low lean tissue mass is an independent risk factor for mortality in patients with stages 4 and 5 non-dialysis chronic kidney disease. Clin Kidney J 2017; 10: 170&#x2013;175</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5381238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28396734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrero JJ, Chmielewski M, Axelsson J. et al. Muscle atrophy, inflammation and clinical outcome in incident and prevalent dialysis patients. Clin Nutr 2008; 27: 557&#x2013;564</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18538898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honda H, Qureshi AR, Axelsson J. et al. Obese sarcopenia in patients with end-stage renal disease is associated with inflammation and increased mortality. Am J Clin Nutr 2007; 86: 633&#x2013;638</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17823427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desmeules S, Levesque R, Jaussent I. et al. Creatinine index and lean body mass are excellent predictors of long-term survival in haemodiafiltration patients. Nephrol Dial Transplant 2004; 19: 1182&#x2013;1189</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14993499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McIntyre CW, Selby NM, Sigrist M. et al. Patients receiving maintenance dialysis have more severe functionally significant skeletal muscle wasting than patients with dialysis-independent chronic kidney disease. Nephrol Dial Transplant 2006; 21: 2210&#x2013;2216</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16504974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang XH, Hu Z, Klein JD. et al. Decreased miR-29 suppresses myogenesis in CKD. J Am Soc Nephrol 2011; 22: 2068&#x2013;76</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3231783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21965375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcus RL, LaStayo PC, Ikizler TA. et al. Low physical function in maintenance hemodialysis patients is independent of muscle mass and comorbidity. J Ren Nutr 2015; 25: 371&#x2013;375</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4469499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25836339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansen KL, Doyle J, Sakkas GK. et al. Neural and metabolic mechanisms of excessive muscle fatigue in maintenance hemodialysis patients. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 2005; 289: R805&#x2013;R813</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15905222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiraki K, Yasuda T, Hotta C. et al. Decreased physical function in pre-dialysis patients with chronic kidney disease. Clin Exp Nephrol 2013; 17: 225&#x2013;231</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22911116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis MI, Fournier M, Wang H. et al. Metabolic and morphometric profile of muscle fibers in chronic hemodialysis patients. J Appl Physiol 2012; 112: 72&#x2013;78</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3290422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22016372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roshanravan B, Robinson-Cohen C, Patel KV. et al. Association between physical performance and all-cause mortality in CKD. J Am Soc Nephrol 2013; 24: 822&#x2013;830</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3636794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23599380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurella Tamura M, Covinsky KE, Chertow GM. et al. Functional status of elderly adults before and after initiation of dialysis. N Engl J Med 2009; 361: 1539&#x2013;1547</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2789552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19828531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moorthi RN, Avin KG.. Clinical relevance of sarcopenia in chronic kidney disease. Curr Opin Nephrol Hypertens 2017; 26: 219&#x2013;228</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5860815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28198733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Androga L, Sharma D, Amodu A. et al. Sarcopenia, obesity, and mortality in US adults with and without chronic kidney disease. Kidney Int Rep 2017; 2: 201&#x2013;211</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5399775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28439567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza VAd, Oliveira D, Barbosa SR. et al. Sarcopenia in patients with chronic kidney disease not yet on dialysis: analysis of the prevalence and associated factors. PLoS One 2017; 12: e0176230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5407780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28448584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira RA, Cordeiro AC, Avesani CM. et al. Sarcopenia in chronic kidney disease on conservative therapy: prevalence and association with mortality. Nephrol Dial Transplant 2015; 30: 1718&#x2013;1725</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25999376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isoyama N, Qureshi AR, Avesani CM. et al. Comparative associations of muscle mass and muscle strength with mortality in dialysis patients. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 2014; 9: 1720&#x2013;1728</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4186520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25074839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean RR, Kiel DP.. Developing consensus criteria for sarcopenia: an update. J Bone Miner Res 2015; 30: 588&#x2013;592</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25735999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Baeyens JP, Bauer JM. et al. Sarcopenia: European consensus on definition and diagnosis: report of the European Working Group on Sarcopenia in Older People. Age Ageing 2010; 39: 412&#x2013;423</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2886201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20392703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley RN, Wang C, Ishani A. et al. Kidney function and sarcopenia in the united states general population: NHANES III. Am J Nephrol 2007; 27: 279&#x2013;286</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17440263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J-K, Choi SR, Choi MJ. et al. Prevalence of and factors associated with sarcopenia in elderly patients with end-stage renal disease. Clin Nutr 2014; 33: 64&#x2013;68</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23631844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrero JJ, Johansen KL, Lindholm B. et al. Screening for muscle wasting and dysfunction in patients with chronic kidney disease. Kidney Int 2016; 90: 53&#x2013;66</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27157695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymsfield SB, Gonzalez MC, Lu J. et al. Skeletal muscle mass and quality: evolution of modern measurement concepts in the context of sarcopenia. Proc Nutr Soc 2015; 74: 355&#x2013;366</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25851205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodpaster BH, Thaete FL, Kelley DE.. Composition of skeletal muscle evaluated with computed tomography. Ann N Y Acad Sci 2000; 904: 18&#x2013;24</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10865705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>John SG, Sigrist MK, Taal MW. et al. Natural history of skeletal muscle mass changes in chronic kidney disease stage 4 and 5 patients: an observational study. PLoS One 2013; 8: e65372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3669290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23741490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansen KL, Shubert T, Doyle J, Soher B, Sakkas GK, Kent-Braun JA.. Muscle atrophy in patients receiving hemodialysis: effects on muscle strength, muscle quality, and physical function. Kidney Int 2003; 63: 291&#x2013;297</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12472795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segura-Ort&#xed; E, Gordon PL, Doyle JW. et al. Correlates of physical functioning and performance across the spectrum of kidney function. Clin Nurs Res 2018; 27: 579&#x2013;596</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28114792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper C, Fielding R, Visser M. et al. Tools in the assessment of sarcopenia. Calcif Tissue Int 2013; 93: 201&#x2013;210</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3744387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23842964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckinx F, Landi F, Cesari M. et al. Pitfalls in the measurement of muscle mass: a need for a reference standard: measurement of muscle mass. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 2018; 9: 269&#x2013;278</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5879987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29349935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fosb&#xf8;l M&#xd8;, Zerahn B.. Contemporary methods of body composition measurement. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 2015; 35: 81&#x2013;97</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24735332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bredella MA, Ghomi RH, Thomas BJ. et al. Comparison of DXA and CT in the assessment of body composition in premenopausal women with obesity and anorexia nervosa. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2010; 18: 2227&#x2013;2233</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3607308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20111013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toomey CM, McCormack WG, Jakeman P.. The effect of hydration status on the measurement of lean tissue mass by dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry. Eur J Appl Physiol 2017; 117: 567&#x2013;574</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28204901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyle UG, Piccoli A, Pichard C.. Body composition measurements: interpretation finally made easy for clinical use. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care 2003; 6: 387&#x2013;393</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12806211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walter-Kroker A, Kroker A, Mattiucci-Guehlke M. et al. A practical guide to bioelectrical impedance analysis using the example of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Nutr J 2011; 10: 1&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3110108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21510854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris-Love MO, Adams B, Hernandez HJ. et al. Disparities in the consequences of sarcopenia: implications for African Americans veterans. Front Physiol 2014; 5: 250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4083180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25071595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez H, Obamwonyi G, Harris-Love M.. Physical therapy considerations for chronic kidney disease and secondary sarcopenia. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 2018; 3: 1&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5784851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29376141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares V, Avelar IS de, Andrade SR de S. et al. Body composition of chronic renal patients: anthropometry and bioimpedance vector analysis. Rev Lat Am Enfermagem 2013; 21: 1240&#x2013;1247</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24402340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen JLT, Godfrey S, Ng TT. et al. Effect of intra-dialytic, low-intensity strength training on functional capacity in adult haemodialysis patients: a randomized pilot trial. Nephrol Dial Transplant 2010; 25: 1936&#x2013;1943</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2902890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20100734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castaneda C, Gordon PL, Uhlin KL. et al. Resistance training to counteract the catabolism of a low-protein diet in patients with chronic renal insufficiency. A randomized controlled trial. Ann Intern Med 2001; 135: 965&#x2013;976</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11730397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris-Love MO, Monfaredi R, Ismail C. et al. Quantitative ultrasound: measurement considerations for the assessment of muscular dystrophy and sarcopenia. Front Aging Neurosci 2014; 6: 172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4094839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25071570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landi F, Liperoti R, Russo A. et al. Sarcopenia as a risk factor for falls in elderly individuals: results from the ilSIRENTE study. Clin Nutr 2012; 31: 652&#x2013;658</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22414775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodpaster BH, Carlson CL, Visser M. et al. Attenuation of skeletal muscle and strength in the elderly: the health ABC study. J Appl Physiol 2001; 90: 2157&#x2013;2165</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11356778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheema B, Abas H, Smith B. et al. Randomized controlled trial of intradialytic resistance training to target muscle wasting in ESRD: the Progressive Exercise for Anabolism in Kidney Disease (PEAK) study. Am J Kidney Dis 2007; 50: 574&#x2013;584</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17900457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pillen S, Tak RO, Zwarts MJ. et al. Skeletal muscle ultrasound: correlation between fibrous tissue and echo intensity. Ultrasound Med Biol 2009; 35: 443&#x2013;446</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19081667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris-Love MO, Seamon BA, Teixeira C. et al. Ultrasound estimates of muscle quality in older adults: reliability and comparison of photoshop and imagej for the grayscale analysis of muscle echogenicity. PeerJ 2016; 4: e1721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4768702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26925339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akima H, Hioki M, Yoshiko A. et al. Intramuscular adipose tissue determined by T1-weighted MRI at 3T primarily reflects extramyocellular lipids. Magn Reson Imaging 2016; 34: 397&#x2013;403</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26743430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail C, Zabal J, Hernandez HJ. et al. Diagnostic ultrasound estimates of muscle mass and muscle quality discriminate between women with and without sarcopenia. Front Physiol 2015; 6: 302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4625057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26578974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukumoto Y, Ikezoe T, Yamada Y. et al. Skeletal muscle quality assessed from echo intensity is associated with muscle strength of middle-aged and elderly persons. Eur J Appl Physiol 2012; 112: 1519&#x2013;1525</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21847576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi MV, Atherton PJ, Reeves ND. et al. Architectural, functional and molecular responses to concentric and eccentric loading in human skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol 2014; 210: 642&#x2013;654</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24387247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narici M, Franchi M, Maganaris C.. Muscle structural assembly and functional consequences. J Exp Biol 2016; 219: 276&#x2013;284</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26792340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>English C, Fisher L, Thoirs K.. Reliability of real-time ultrasound for measuring skeletal muscle size in human limbs in vivo: a systematic review. Clin Rehabil 2012; 26: 934&#x2013;944</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22324054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klauser AS, Peetrons P.. Developments in musculoskeletal ultrasound and clinical applications. Skeletal Radiol 2010; 39: 1061&#x2013;1071</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19730857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Loenneke JP, Thiebaud RS.. Morphological and functional relationships with ultrasound measured muscle thickness of the lower extremity: a brief review. Ultrasound 2015; 23: 166&#x2013;173</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4760590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27433253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obst SJ, Boyd R, Read F. et al. Quantitative 3-D ultrasound of the medial gastrocnemius muscle in children with unilateral spastic cerebral palsy. Ultrasound Med Biol 2017; 43: 2814&#x2013;2823</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28967503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walton JM, Roberts N, Whitehouse GH.. Measurement of the quadriceps femoris muscle using magnetic resonance and ultrasound imaging. Br J Sports Med 1997; 31: 59&#x2013;64</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1332478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9132215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heiwe S, Jacobson SH.. Exercise training for adults with chronic kidney disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2011; 10: CD003236</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10183198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21975737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barcellos FC, Santos IS, Umpierre D. et al. Effects of exercise in the whole spectrum of chronic kidney disease: a systematic review. Clin Kidney J 2015; 8: 753&#x2013;765</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4655802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26613036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castaneda C, Gordon PL, Parker RC. et al. Resistance training to reduce the malnutrition-inflammation complex syndrome of chronic kidney disease. Am J Kidney Dis 2004; 43: 607&#x2013;616</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15042537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson EL, Greening NJ, Viana JL. et al. Progressive resistance exercise training in CKD: a feasibility study. Am J Kidney Dis 2015; 66: 249&#x2013;257</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25533601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson EL, Viana JL, Wimbury D. et al. The effect of resistance exercise on inflammatory and myogenic markers in patients with chronic kidney disease. Front Physiol 2017; 8: 541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5532513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28804461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansen KL. Effects of resistance exercise training and nandrolone decanoate on body composition and muscle function among patients who receive hemodialysis: a randomized, controlled trial. J Am Soc Nephrol 2006; 17: 2307&#x2013;2314</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16825332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song W-J, Sohng K-Y.. Effects of progressive resistance training on body composition, physical fitness and quality of life of patients on hemodialysis. J Korean Acad Nurs 2012; 42: 947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23377590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong J, Sundell MB, Pupim LB. et al. The effect of resistance exercise to augment long-term benefits of intradialytic oral nutritional supplementation in chronic hemodialysis patients. J Ren Nutr 2011; 21: 149&#x2013;159</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2947559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20580251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR. et al. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2011; 43: 1334&#x2013;1359</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21694556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansen KL, Painter P.. Exercise in individuals with CKD. Am J Kidney Dis 2012; 59: 126&#x2013;134</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3242908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22113127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smart NA, Williams AD, Levinger I. et al. Exercise &amp; Sports Science Australia (ESSA) position statement on exercise and chronic kidney disease. J Sci Med Sport 2013; 16: 406&#x2013;411</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23434075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roshanravan B, Gamboa J, Wilund K.. Exercise and CKD: skeletal muscle dysfunction and practical application of exercise to prevent and treat physical impairments in CKD. Am J Kidney Dis 2017; 69: 837&#x2013;852</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5441955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28427790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. ACSM&#x2019;s Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription, Tenth Edition. Philadelphia: Wolters Kluwer, 2018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2009; 41: 687&#x2013;708</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borde R, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Granacher U.. Dose&#x2013;response relationships of resistance training in healthy old adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 2015; 45: 1693&#x2013;1720</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4656698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26420238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Sen A, Gordon PM.. Influence of resistance exercise on lean body mass in aging adults: a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2011; 43: 249&#x2013;258</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2995836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20543750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Rhea MR, Sen A. et al. Resistance exercise for muscular strength in older adults: a meta-analysis. Ageing Res Rev 2010; 9: 226&#x2013;237</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2892859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20385254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steib S, Schoene D, Pfeifer K.. Dose-response relationship of resistance training in older adults: a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2010; 42: 902&#x2013;914</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19996996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid KF, Fielding RA.. Skeletal muscle power: a critical determinant of physical functioning in older adults. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 2012; 40: 4&#x2013;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3245773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22016147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid KF, Martin KI, Doros G. et al. Comparative effects of light or heavy resistance power training for improving lower extremity power and physical performance in mobility-limited older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 2015; 70: 374&#x2013;380</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4351393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25199912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straight CR, Lindheimer JB, Brady AO. et al. Effects of resistance training on lower-extremity muscle power in middle-aged and older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Sports Med 2016; 46: 353&#x2013;364</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26545362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris-Love MO, Seamon BA, Gonzales TI. et al. Eccentric exercise program design: a periodization model for rehabilitation applications. Front Physiol 2017; 8: 112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5322206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28280471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorenz DS, Reiman MP, Walker JC.. Periodization: current review and suggested implementation for athletic rehabilitation. Sports Health Multidiscip Approach 2010; 2: 509&#x2013;518</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3438871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23015982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunanan AJ, DeWeese BH, Wagle JP. et al. The general adaptation syndrome: a foundation for the concept of periodization. Sports Med Auckl NZ 2018; 48: 787&#x2013;797</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29307100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>