<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37399886</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2213-2961</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of sport and health science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Sport Health Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Time to consider the potential role of alternative resistance training methods in cancer management?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>715</StartPage><EndPage>725</EndPage><MedlinePgn>715-725</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jshs.2023.06.007</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2095-2546(23)00062-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Exercise has emerged as fundamental therapeutic medicine in the management of cancer. Exercise improves health-related outcomes, including quality of life, neuromuscular strength, physical function, and body composition, and it is associated with a lower risk of disease recurrence and increased survival. Moreover, exercise during or post cancer treatments is safe, can ameliorate treatment-related side effects, and may enhance the effectiveness of chemotherapy and radiation therapy. To date, traditional resistance training (RT) is the most used RT modality in exercise oncology. However, alternative training modes, such as eccentric, cluster set, and blood flow restriction are gaining increased attention. These training modalities have been extensively investigated in both athletic and clinical populations (e.g., age-related frailty, cardiovascular disease, type 2 diabetes), showing considerable benefits in terms of neuromuscular strength, hypertrophy, body composition, and physical function. However, these training modes have only been partially or not at all investigated in cancer populations. Thus, this study outlines the benefits of these alternative RT methods in patients with cancer. Where evidence in cancer populations is sparse, we provide a robust rationale for the possible implementation of certain RT methods that have shown positive results in other clinical populations. Finally, we provide clinical insights for research that may guide future RT investigations in patients with cancer and suggest clear practical applications for targeted cancer populations and related benefits.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023. Production and hosting by Elsevier B.V.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bettariga</LastName><ForeName>Francesco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Medicine Research Institute, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, WA 6027, Australia; School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, WA 6027, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bishop</LastName><ForeName>Chris</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>London Sport Institute, School of Science and Technology, Middlesex University, London, NW4 4BT, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taaffe</LastName><ForeName>Dennis R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Medicine Research Institute, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, WA 6027, Australia; School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, WA 6027, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Galv&#xe3;o</LastName><ForeName>Daniel A</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Medicine Research Institute, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, WA 6027, Australia; School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, WA 6027, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maestroni</LastName><ForeName>Luca</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>London Sport Institute, School of Science and Technology, Middlesex University, London, NW4 4BT, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Newton</LastName><ForeName>Robert U</ForeName><Initials>RU</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Medicine Research Institute, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, WA 6027, Australia; School of Medical and Health Sciences, Edith Cowan University, Joondalup, WA 6027, Australia; School of Human Movement and Nutrition Sciences, University of Queensland, St. Lucia, QLD 4067, Australia. Electronic address: r.newton@ecu.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>China</Country><MedlineTA>J Sport Health Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101606001</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2213-2961</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003924" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009369" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood flow restriction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cluster set</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eccentric training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37399886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10658316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2023.06.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2095-2546(23)00062-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization . World Health Organization; Geneva: 2014. Global status report on noncommunicable diseases 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobelo F, Stoutenberg M, Hutber A. The exercise is medicine global health initiative: A 2014 update. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48:1627&#x2013;1633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24759911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>6th ed. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; Philadelphia, PA: 2000. American College of Sports Medicine. ACSM's guidelines for exercise testing and prescription.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Momma H, Kawakami R, Honda T, Sawada SS. Muscle-strengthening activities are associated with lower risk and mortality in major non-communicable diseases: A systematic review and meta-analysis of cohort studies. Br J Sports Med. 2022;56:755&#x2013;763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9209691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35228201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung H, Ferlay J, Siegel RL, et al. Global cancer statistics 2020: Globocan estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2021;71:209&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33538338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ligibel JA, Bohlke K, May AM, et al. Exercise, diet, and weight management during cancer treatment: ASCO guideline. J Clin Oncol. 2022;40:2491&#x2013;2507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35576506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes SC, Newton RU, Spence RR, Galv&#xe3;o DA. The Exercise and Sports Science Australia position statement: Exercise medicine in cancer management. J Sci Med Sport. 2019;22:1175&#x2013;1199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31277921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell KL, Winters-Stone KM, Wiskemann J, et al. Exercise guidelines for cancer survivors: Consensus statement from international multidisciplinary roundtable. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51:2375&#x2013;2390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8576825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31626055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz KH, Campbell AM, Stuiver MM, et al. Exercise is medicine in oncology: Engaging clinicians to help patients move through cancer. CA Cancer J Clin. 2019;69:468&#x2013;484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7896280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31617590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedenreich CM, Neilson HK, Farris MS, Courneya KS. Physical activity and cancer outcomes: A precision medicine approach. Clin Cancer Res. 2016;22:4766&#x2013;4775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27407093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt K, Vogt L, Thiel C, J&#xe4;ger E, Banzer W. Validity of the six-minute walk test in cancer patients. Int J Sports Med. 2013;34:631&#x2013;636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23444095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Rodriguez EJ, Sanchez-Gomez C, Mendez-Sanchez R, et al. Multimodal physical exercise and functional rehabilitation program in oncological patients with cancer-related fatigue&#x2014;A randomized clinical trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20:4938. doi: 10.3390/ijerph20064938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph20064938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10049732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36981846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Unciti M, Palacios Samper N, M&#xe9;ndez-Sandoval S, Idoate F, Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez-Santos J. Effect of combining impact-aerobic and strength exercise, and dietary habits on body composition in breast cancer survivors treated with aromatase inhibitors. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20:4872. doi: 10.3390/ijerph20064872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph20064872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10049091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36981785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newton RU, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Spry N, et al. Exercise mode specificity for preserving spine and hip bone mineral density in prostate cancer patients. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51:607&#x2013;614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30395051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang DW, Fairey AS, Boul&#xe9; NG, Field CJ, Wharton SA, Courneya KS. A randomized trial of the effects of exercise on anxiety, fear of cancer progression and quality of life in prostate cancer patients on active surveillance. J Urol. 2022;207:814&#x2013;822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35179044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bland KA, Zadravec K, Landry T, Weller S, Meyers L, Campbell KL. Impact of exercise on chemotherapy completion rate: A systematic review of the evidence and recommendations for future exercise oncology research. Crit Rev Oncol Hematol. 2019;136:79&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30878132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Adams K, Cafarelli E, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34:364&#x2013;380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11828249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: Guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43:1334&#x2013;1359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21694556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x10c;retnik K, Ple&#x161;a J, Kozinc &#x17d;, L&#xf6;fler S, &#x160;arabon N. The effect of eccentric vs. traditional resistance exercise on muscle strength, body composition, and functional performance in older adults: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Front Sports Act Living. 2022;4:873718. doi: 10.3389/fspor.2022.873718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2022.873718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9045400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35498525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suchomel T, Wagle J, Douglas J, et al. Implementing eccentric resistance training&#x2014;Part 1: A brief review of existing methods. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2019;4:38. doi: 10.3390/jfmk4020038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk4020038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7739257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33467353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoppeler H. Moderate load eccentric exercise: A distinct novel training modality. Front Physiol. 2016;7:483. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2016.00483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2016.00483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5110564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27899894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latella C, Peddle-McIntyre C, Marcotte L, Steele J, Kendall K, Fairman CM. Strengthening the case for cluster set resistance training in aged and clinical settings: Emerging evidence, proposed benefits and suggestions. Sports Med. 2021;51:1335&#x2013;1351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33983613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krzysztofik M, Wilk M, Wojda&#x142;a G, Go&#x142;a&#x15b; A. Maximizing muscle hypertrophy: A systematic review of advanced resistance training techniques and methods. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019;16:4897. doi: 10.3390/ijerph16244897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph16244897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6950543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31817252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbalho M, Rocha AC, Seus TL, Raiol R, Del Vecchio FB, Coswig VS. Addition of blood flow restriction to passive mobilization reduces the rate of muscle wasting in elderly patients in the intensive care unit: A within-patient randomized trial. Clin Rehabil. 2019;33:233&#x2013;240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30246555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairman CM, Owens OL, Kendall KL, et al. Study protocol: Investigating the feasibility of a hybrid delivery of home-based cluster set resistance training for individuals previously treated for lung cancer. Pilot Feasibility Stud. 2022;8:102. doi: 10.1186/s40814-022-01065-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40814-022-01065-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9114285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35585562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaStayo PC, Marcus RL, Dibble LE, Smith SB, Beck SL. Eccentric exercise versus usual-care with older cancer survivors: The impact on muscle and mobility&#x2013;An exploratory pilot study. BMC Geriatr. 2011;11:5. doi: 10.1186/1471-2318-11-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2318-11-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3038910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21272338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaStayo PC, Larsen S, Smith S, Dibble L, Marcus R. The feasibility and efficacy of eccentric exercise with older cancer survivors: A preliminary study. J Geriatr Phys Ther. 2010;33:135&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3018757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21155509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wooten SV, Fleming RYD, Wolf JS, et al. Prehabilitation program composed of blood flow restriction training and sports nutrition improves physical functions in abdominal cancer patients awaiting surgery. Eur J Surg Oncol. 2021;47:2952&#x2013;2958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34092455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigaran A, Howden EJ, Foulkes S, et al. Prescribing exercise in early-stage breast cancer during chemotherapy: A simple periodized approach to align with the cyclic phases of chemotherapy. J Strength Cond Res. 2022;36:2934&#x2013;2941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36135037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winters-Stone KM, Leo MC, Schwartz A. Exercise effects on hip bone mineral density in older, post-menopausal breast cancer survivors are age dependent. Arch Osteoporos. 2012;7:301&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3533253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23225299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klijn P, van Keimpema A, Legemaat M, Gosselink R, van Stel H. Nonlinear exercise training in advanced chronic obstructive pulmonary disease is superior to traditional exercise training. A randomized trial. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2013;188:193&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23449691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikseresht M, Agha-Alinejad H, Azarbayjani MA, Ebrahim K. Effects of nonlinear resistance and aerobic interval training on cytokines and insulin resistance in sedentary men who are obese. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28:2560&#x2013;2568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24662224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinton PS, Nigh P, Thyfault J. Effectiveness of resistance training or jumping-exercise to increase bone mineral density in men with low bone mass: A 12-month randomized, clinical trial. Bone. 2015;79:203&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4503233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26092649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westcott WL. Resistance training is medicine: Effects of strength training on health. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2012;11:209&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22777332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser B, Schobersberger W. Evidence for resistance training as a treatment therapy in obesity. J Obes. 2011;2011:482564. doi: 10.1155/2011/482564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2011/482564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2931407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shailendra P, Baldock KL, Li LSK, Bennie JA, Boyle T. Resistance training and mortality risk: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Prev Med. 2022;63:277&#x2013;285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35599175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGovern A, Mahony N, Mockler D, Fleming N. Efficacy of resistance training during adjuvant chemotherapy and radiation therapy in cancer care: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Support Care Cancer. 2022;30:3701&#x2013;3719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34993651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padilha CS, Marinello PC, Galv&#xe3;o DA, et al. Evaluation of resistance training to improve muscular strength and body composition in cancer patients undergoing neoadjuvant and adjuvant therapy: A meta-analysis. J Cancer Surviv. 2017;11:339&#x2013;349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28054255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser B, Steindorf K, Wiskemann J, Ulrich CM. Impact of resistance training in cancer survivors: A meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45:2080&#x2013;2090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23669878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf8;nbro S. The effect of progressive resistance training on lean body mass in post-treatment cancer patients &#x2013; A systematic review. Radiother Oncol. 2014;110:71&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24060169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson ED, Wagoner CW, Anderson T, Battaglini CL. The independent effects of strength training in cancer survivors: A systematic review. Curr Oncol Rep. 2016;18:31. doi: 10.1007/s11912-016-0511-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11912-016-0511-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27025505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J. The effects of resistance training on muscular strength and hypertrophy in elderly cancer patients: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci. 2022;11:194&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9068528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33592324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isner-Horobeti ME, Dufour SP, Vautravers P, Geny B, Coudeyre E, Richard R. Eccentric exercise training: Modalities, applications and perspectives. Sports Med. 2013;43:483&#x2013;512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23657934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyldahl RD, Olson T, Welling T, Groscost L, Parcell AC. Satellite cell activity is differentially affected by contraction mode in human muscle following a work-matched bout of exercise. Front Physiol. 2014;5:485. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2014.00485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2014.00485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4263080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25566087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MO Harris-Love, Gollie JM, Keogh JWL. Eccentric exercise: Adaptations and applications for health and performance. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol. 2021;6:96. doi: 10.3390/jfmk6040096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfmk6040096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8628948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34842737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen PA, Dechet CB, Porucznik CA, LaStayo PC. Comparing eccentric resistance exercise in prostate cancer survivors on and off hormone therapy: A pilot study. PM R. 2009;1:1019&#x2013;1024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19942188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo JS, Yang HC, Lee JM, Kim MS, Park EC, Chung SH. The association of physical function and quality of life on physical activity for non-small cell lung cancer survivors. Support Care Cancer. 2020;28:4847&#x2013;4856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31980896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin WK, Song S, Jung SY, et al. The association between physical activity and health-related quality of life among breast cancer survivors. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2017;15:132. doi: 10.1186/s12955-017-0706-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12955-017-0706-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5493872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28666465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buffart LM, Kalter J, Sweegers MG, et al. Effects and moderators of exercise on quality of life and physical function in patients with cancer: An individual patient data meta-analysis of 34 RCTs. Cancer Treat Rev. 2017;52:91&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28006694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groen WG, Naaktgeboren WR, van Harten WH, et al. Physical fitness and chemotherapy tolerance in patients with early-stage breast cancer. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2022;54:537&#x2013;542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8920022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34961754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piraux E, Caty G, Aboubakar Nana F, Reychler G. Effects of exercise therapy in cancer patients undergoing radiotherapy treatment: A narrative review. SAGE Open Med. 2020;8 doi: 10.1177/2050312120922657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2050312120922657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7301662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32595968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azevedo PHSM, Oliveira MGD, Schoenfeld BJ. Effect of different eccentric tempos on hypertrophy and strength of the lower limbs. Biol Sport. 2022;39:443&#x2013;449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8919893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35309524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julian V, Thivel D, Miguet M, et al. Eccentric cycling training improves health-related quality of life in adolescents with obesity. Obes Facts. 2020;13:548&#x2013;559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7802461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33190133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kudiarasu C, Rohadhia W, Katsura Y, Koeda T, Singh F, Nosaka K. Eccentric-only versus concentric-only resistance training effects on biochemical and physiological parameters in patients with type 2 diabetes. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2021;13:162. doi: 10.1186/s13102-021-00384-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-021-00384-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8686274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34930480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roig M, Shadgan B, Reid WD. Eccentric exercise in patients with chronic health conditions: A systematic review. Physiother Can. 2008;60:146&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2792816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20145778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis R, Shields N, Lim K, Dodd KJ. Eccentric exercise in adults with cardiorespiratory disease: A systematic review. Clin Rehabil. 2015;29:1178&#x2013;1197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25758944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruddy KJ, Patel SR, Higgins AS, Armenian SH, Herrmann J. Cardiovascular health during and after cancer therapy. Cancers (Basel) 2020;12:3737. doi: 10.3390/cancers12123737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers12123737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7763346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33322622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winters-Stone KM, Horak F, Jacobs PG, et al. Falls, functioning, and disability among women with persistent symptoms of chemotherapy-induced peripheral neuropathy. J Clin Oncol. 2017;35:2604&#x2013;2612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5549452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28586243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kon M, Tanabe K, Lee H, Kimura F, Akimoto T, Kono I. Eccentric muscle contractions induce greater oxidative stress than concentric contractions in skeletal muscle. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2007;32:273&#x2013;281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17486169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatebayashi D, Himori K, Yamada R, Ashida Y, Miyazaki M, Yamada T. High-intensity eccentric training ameliorates muscle wasting in colon 26 tumor-bearing mice. PLoS One. 2018;13:e0199050. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0199050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0199050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5997314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29894511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardee JP, Mangum JE, Gao S, et al. Eccentric contraction-induced myofiber growth in tumor-bearing mice. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2016;120:29&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4698440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26494443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardee JP, Fix DK, Koh HJ, Wang X, Goldsmith EC, Carson JA. Repeated eccentric contractions positively regulate muscle oxidative metabolism and protein synthesis during cancer cachexia in mice. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2020;128:1666&#x2013;1676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7311684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32407241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez AM, Hoffman JR, Stout JR, Fukuda DH, Willoughby DS. Intramuscular anabolic signaling and endocrine response following resistance exercise: Implications for muscle hypertrophy. Sports Med. 2016;46:671&#x2013;685.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26666743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anjanappa M, Corden M, Green A, et al. Sarcopenia in cancer: Risking more than muscle loss. Tech Innov Patient Support Radiat Oncol. 2020;16:50&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7769854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33385074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolland Y, Abellan van Kan G, Gillette-Guyonnet S, Vellas B. Cachexia versus sarcopenia. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2011;14:15&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21076295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Burgess SJ, Stone MH. Cluster training: Theoretical and practical applications for the strength and conditioning professional. Prof Strength Cond. 2008;12:12&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawton TW, Cronin JB, Lindsell RP. Effect of interrepetition rest intervals on weight training repetition power output. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20:172&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16503678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gie&#x3b2;sing J, Fisher J, Steele J, Rothe F, Raubold K, Eichmann B. The effects of low-volume resistance training with and without advanced techniques in trained subjects. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2016;56:249&#x2013;258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25303171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moir GL, Graham BW, Davis SE, Guers JJ, Witmer CA. Effect of cluster set configurations on mechanical variables during the deadlift exercise. J Hum Kinet. 2013;39:15&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3916933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24511337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latella C, Teo WP, Drinkwater EJ, Kendall K, Haff GG. The acute neuromuscular responses to cluster set resistance training: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2019;49:1861&#x2013;1877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6851217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31506904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rosell D, Aagaard P, et al. Time course of recovery from resistance exercise with different set configurations. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34:2867&#x2013;2876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30036284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mor&#xe1;n-Navarro R, P&#xe9;rez CE, Mora-Rodr&#xed;guez R, et al. Time course of recovery following resistance training leading or not to failure. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117:2387&#x2013;2399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28965198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tufano JJ, Brown LE, Haff GG. Theoretical and practical aspects of different cluster set structures: A systematic review. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31:848&#x2013;867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27465625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collado-Mateo D, Lav&#xed;n-P&#xe9;rez AM, Pe&#xf1;acoba C, et al. Key factors associated with adherence to physical exercise in patients with chronic diseases and older adults: An umbrella review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:2023. doi: 10.3390/ijerph18042023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18042023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7922504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33669679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halperin I, Emanuel A. Rating of perceived effort: Methodological concerns and future directions. Sports Med. 2020;50:679&#x2013;687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31745731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez-Campillo R, Alvarez C, Garc&#xec;a-Hermoso A, et al. High-speed resistance training in elderly women: Effects of cluster training sets on functional performance and quality of life. Exp Gerontol. 2018;110:216&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29909049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias RKN, Penna EM, Noronha ASN, et al. Cluster-sets resistance training induce similar functional and strength improvements than the traditional method in postmenopausal and elderly women. Exp Gerontol. 2020;138:111011. doi: 10.1016/j.exger.2020.111011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2020.111011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32592830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro-Torres O, de Sousa AFM, Iglesias-Soler E, et al. Lower cardiovascular stress during resistance training performed with inter-repetition rests in elderly coronary patients. Medicina (Kaunas) 2020;56:264. doi: 10.3390/medicina56060264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/medicina56060264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7353896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32481634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savina S, Zaydiner B. Cancer-related fatigue: Some clinical aspects. Asia Pac J Oncol Nurs. 2019;6:7&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6287376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30599009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner LI, Cella D. Fatigue and cancer: Causes, prevalence and treatment approaches. Br J Cancer. 2004;91:822&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2409868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15238987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell SA. Cancer-related fatigue: State of the science. PM R. 2010;2:364&#x2013;383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20656618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baillot A, Chenail S, Barros Polita N, et al. Physical activity motives, barriers, and preferences in people with obesity: A systematic review. PLoS One. 2021;16 doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0253114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0253114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8221526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34161372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott BR, Loenneke JP, Slattery KM, Dascombe BJ. Exercise with blood flow restriction: An updated evidence-based approach for enhanced muscular development. Sports Med. 2015;45:313&#x2013;325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25430600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, Hughes L, Warmington S, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise: Considerations of methodology, application, and safety. Front Physiol. 2019;10:533. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2019.00533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2019.00533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6530612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31156448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larkin KA, Macneil RG, Dirain M, Sandesara B, Manini TM, Buford TW. Blood flow restriction enhances post-resistance exercise angiogenic gene expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44:2077&#x2013;2083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3633075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22677927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Garzon M, Cantarero-Villanueva I, Leger&#xe9;n-Alvarez M, et al. Prevention of chemotherapy-induced peripheral neuropathy with PRESIONA, a therapeutic exercise and blood flow restriction program: A randomized controlled study protocol. Phys Ther. 2022;102:pzab282. doi: 10.1093/ptj/pzab282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/pzab282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35079838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraz RB, Gualano B, Rodrigues R, et al. Benefits of resistance training with blood flow restriction in knee osteoarthritis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2018;50:897&#x2013;905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29266093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DePhillipo NN, Kennedy MI, Aman ZS, Bernhardson AS, O'Brien LT, LaPrade RF. The role of blood flow restriction therapy following knee surgery: Expert opinion. Arthroscopy. 2018;34:2506&#x2013;2510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30077275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker BS, Stannard MS, Duren DL, Cook JL, Stannard JP. Does blood flow restriction therapy in patients older than age 50 result in muscle hypertrophy, increased strength, or greater physical function? A systematic review. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2020;478:593&#x2013;606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7145054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31860546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vechin FC, Libardi CA, Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o MS, et al. Low-intensity resistance training with partial blood flow restriction and high-intensity resistance training induce similar changes in skeletal muscle transcriptome in elderly humans. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2019;44:216&#x2013;220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30001503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubota A, Sakuraba K, Koh S, Ogura Y, Tamura Y. Blood flow restriction by low compressive force prevents disuse muscular weakness. J Sci Med Sport. 2011;14:95&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21035395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubota A, Sakuraba K, Sawaki K, Sumide T, Tamura Y. Prevention of disuse muscular weakness by restriction of blood flow. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40:529&#x2013;534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18379217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson SJ, Hussain SR. A review on the mechanisms of blood-flow restriction resistance training-induced muscle hypertrophy. Sports Med. 2015;45:187&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25249278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Newton RU, Taaffe DR, Winster-Stone K, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Buffart LM. Moderators of resistance-based exercise programs' effect on sarcopenia-related measures in men with prostate cancer previously or currently undergoing androgen deprivation therapy: An individual patient data meta-analysis. J Geriatr Oncol. 2023;14:101535. doi: 10.1016/j.jgo.2023.101535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jgo.2023.101535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37229882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cognetti DJ, Sheean AJ, Owens JG. Blood flow restriction therapy and its use for rehabilitation and return to sport: Physiology, application, and guidelines for implementation. Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil. 2022;4:e71&#x2013;e76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8811521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35141538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu JB, Raj VS, Guo Y. A guide to inpatient cancer rehabilitation: Focusing on patient selection and evidence-based outcomes. PM R. 2017;9(Suppl.2):S324&#x2013;S334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5736373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28942907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu JB, Lee J, Tran KB, et al. Symptom burden and functional gains in a cancer rehabilitation unit. Int J Ther Rehabil. 2015;22:517&#x2013;523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4768746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26929772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Johns SA, Theobald D, Wu J, Tu W. Somatic symptoms in cancer patients trajectory over 12 months and impact on functional status and disability. Support Care Cancer. 2013;21:765&#x2013;773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3543758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22941116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batalik L, Winnige P, Dosbaba F, Vlazna D, Janikova A. Home-based aerobic and resistance exercise interventions in cancer patients and survivors: A systematic review. Cancers (Basel) 2021;13:1915. doi: 10.3390/cancers13081915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers13081915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8071485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33921141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun L. Effects of blood flow restriction training on anthropometric and blood lipids in overweight/obese adults: Meta-analysis. Front Physiol. 2022;13:1039591. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2022.1039591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.1039591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9745437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36523558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Fukumura K, Uchida Y, et al. Effects of low-load, elastic band resistance training combined with blood flow restriction on muscle size and arterial stiffness in older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2015;70:950&#x2013;958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24917178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Fukumura K, Iida H, Nakajima T. Effects of detraining after blood flow-restricted low-load elastic band training on muscle size and arterial stiffness in older women. Springerplus. 2015;4:348. doi: 10.1186/s40064-015-1132-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40064-015-1132-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4502052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26191475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madarame H, Kurano M, Fukumura K, Fukuda T, Nakajima T. Haemostatic and inflammatory responses to blood flow-restricted exercise in patients with ischaemic heart disease: A pilot study. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2013;33:11&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23216760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Paulsen G, Nilsen TS, Hisdal J, Raastad T. Contractile function and sarcolemmal permeability after acute low-load resistance exercise with blood flow restriction. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112:2051&#x2013;2063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21947453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umbel JD, Hoffman RL, Dearth DJ, Chleboun GS, Manini TM, Clark BC. Delayed-onset muscle soreness induced by low-load blood flow-restricted exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2009;107:687&#x2013;695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19727801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sieljacks P, Matzon A, Wernbom M, Ringgaard S, Vissing K, Overgaard K. Muscle damage and repeated bout effect following blood flow restricted exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116:513&#x2013;525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26645685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen JL, Aagaard P, Prokhorova TA, et al. Blood flow restricted training leads to myocellular macrophage infiltration and upregulation of heat shock proteins, but no apparent muscle damage. J Physiol. 2017;595:4857&#x2013;4873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5509865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28481416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soultati A, Mountzios G, Avgerinou C, et al. Endothelial vascular toxicity from chemotherapeutic agents: Preclinical evidence and clinical implications. Cancer Treat Rev. 2012;38:473&#x2013;483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21982720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandner CR, May AK, Clarkson MJ, Warmington SA. Reported side-effects and safety considerations for the use of blood flow restriction during exercise in practice and research. Tech Orthop. 2018;33:1. doi: 10.1097/BTO.0000000000000259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BTO.0000000000000259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolnick N, Kimbrell K, Cerqueira MS, Weatherford B, Brandner C. Perceived barriers to blood flow restriction training. Front Rehabil Sci. 2021;2:697082. doi: 10.3389/fresc.2021.697082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fresc.2021.697082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9397924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36188864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng AH, Ngo-Huang A, Vidal M, et al. Exercise barriers and adherence to recommendations in patients with cancer. JCO Oncol Pract. 2021;17:e972&#x2013;e981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33739853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes DC, Ellefsen S, Baar K. Adaptations to endurance and strength training. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med. 2018;8 doi: 10.1101/cshperspect.a029769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/cshperspect.a029769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5983157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28490537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleather D. Independently Published; UK: 2021. Force: The biomechanics of training.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagle JP, Taber CB, Cunanan AJ, et al. Accentuated eccentric loading for training and performance: A review. Sports Med. 2017;47:2473&#x2013;2495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28681170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasso JP, Eves ND, Christensen JF, Koelwyn GJ, Scott J, Jones LW. A framework for prescription in exercise-oncology research. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2015;6:115&#x2013;124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4458077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26136187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>