<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">31567839</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Static and Dynamic Stretching Performed Before Resistance Training on Muscle Adaptations in Untrained Men.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3050</StartPage><EndPage>3055</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3050-3055</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003283</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Ferreira-J&#xfa;nior, JB, Benine, RPC, Chaves, SFN, Borba, DA, Martins-Costa, HC, Freitas, EDS, Bemben, MG, Vieira, CA, and Bottaro, M. Effects of static and dynamic stretching performed before resistance training on muscle adaptations in untrained men. J Strength Cond Res 35(11): 3050-3055, 2021-This study evaluated the effects of dynamic and static stretching (SS) performed before resistance training on biceps femoris hypertrophy and knee flexor strength gains in untrained young men. Forty-five untrained young men (age, 21.2 &#xb1; 0.5 years; mass, 72.2 &#xb1; 5.6 kg; height, 178 &#xb1; 1 cm) were randomly assigned to 1 of the 3 groups: (a) 80 seconds of SS (n = 14); (b) 80 seconds of dynamic stretching (DS, n = 13); or (c) control group (CON, n = 18) in which subjects performed no stretching before exercise. Both SS and DS were performed before resistance exercise. Resistance training consisted of 4 sets of 8-12 repetition maximum of seated leg curl exercise 2 days per week for 8 weeks, with a period of at least 48 hours between sessions. Unilateral biceps femoris muscle thickness (MT) and maximal isometric strength (MIS) of the knee flexors were measured 1 week before training and 1 week after the last training session. There were significant increases in MIS (SS = 13.9 &#xb1; 10.3 kgf; DS = 10.2 &#xb1; 13.1 kgf; CON = 12.7 &#xb1; 7.6 kgf; p &lt; 0.05) and MT (SS = 6.0 &#xb1; 3.5 mm; DS = 6.7 &#xb1; 4.1 mm; CON = 5.7 &#xb1; 3.0 mm; p &lt; 0.05) with no significant differences across groups (p &gt; 0.05). Additionally, all groups demonstrated moderate effect sizes for MIS (1.27-1.4), and DS was the only group that had a large effect size for MT increases (DS = 2.18; SS = 1.35; CON = 0.92). In conclusion, 80 seconds of SS and DS did not induce any additional muscular adaptations to resistance training in untrained young men.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2019 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferreira-J&#xfa;nior</LastName><ForeName>Jo&#xe3;o B</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Federal Institute of Sudeste of Minas Gerais, Campus Rio Pomba, MG, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benine</LastName><ForeName>Ricardo P C</ForeName><Initials>RPC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Federal Institute of Sudeste of Minas Gerais, Campus Rio Pomba, MG, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaves</LastName><ForeName>Suene F N</ForeName><Initials>SFN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Federal Institute of Sudeste of Minas Gerais, Campus Rio Pomba, MG, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Borba</LastName><ForeName>Diego A</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Movement Science, State University of Minas Gerais, Campus Ibirit&#xe9;, MG, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martins-Costa</LastName><ForeName>Hugo C</ForeName><Initials>HC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais, Belo Horizonte, MG, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Freitas</LastName><ForeName>Eduardo D S</ForeName><Initials>EDS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Exercise Science, University of Oklahoma, Norman, Oklahoma.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bemben</LastName><ForeName>Michael G</ForeName><Initials>MG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Exercise Science, University of Oklahoma, Norman, Oklahoma.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vieira</LastName><ForeName>Carlos A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Federal University of Goi&#xe1;s, Goiania, GO, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bottaro</LastName><ForeName>Martim</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Bras&#xed;lia, Bras&#xed;lia, DF, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000070633" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hamstring Muscles</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Stretching Exercises</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31567839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202111000-00011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bacurau RFP, De Assis Monteiro G, Ugrinowitsch C, et al. Acute effect of a ballistic and a static stretching exercise bout on flexibility and maximal strength. J Strength Cond Res 23: 304&#x2013;308, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandy WD, Irion JM. The effect of time on static stretch on the flexibility of the hamstring muscles. Phys Ther 74: 845&#x2013;852, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barroso R, Tricoli V, Dos Santos Gil S, Ugrinowitsch C, Roschel H. Maximal strength, number of repetitions, and total volume are differently affected by static-, ballistic-, and proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation stretching. J Strength Cond Res 26: 2432&#x2013;2437, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck TW. The importance of a priori sample size estimation in strength and conditioning research. J Strength Cond Res 27: 2323&#x2013;2337, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behm DG, Blazevich AJ, Kay AD, McHugh M. Acute effects of muscle stretching on physical performance, range of motion, and injury incidence in healthy active individuals: A systematic review. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 41: 1&#x2013;11, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bemben MG. Use of diagnostic ultrasound for assessing muscle size. J Strength Cond Res 16: 103&#x2013;108, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borges Bastos CL, Miranda H, Vale RG, et al. Chronic effect of static stretching on strength performance and basal serum IGF-1 levels. J Strength Cond Res 27: 2465&#x2013;2472, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan SP, Hong Y, Robinson PD. Flexibility and passive resistance of the hamstrings of young adults using two different static stretching protocols. Scand J Med Sci Sport 11: 81&#x2013;86, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa PB, Ryan ED, Herda TJ, et al. Acute effects of static stretching on peak torque and the hamstrings-to-quadriceps conventional and functional ratios. Scand J Med Sci Sports 23: 38&#x2013;45, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutinho EL, Gomes ARS, Fran&#xe7;a CN, Oishi J, Salvini TF. Effect of passive stretching on the immobilized soleus muscle fiber morphology. Braz J Med Biol Res 37: 1853&#x2013;1861, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira DV, Ferreira-J&#xfa;nior JB, Soares SRS, et al. Chest press exercises with different stability requirements result in similar muscle damage recovery in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 31: 71&#x2013;79, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas SR, Andrade RJ, Nordez A, Mendes B, Mil-Homens P. Acute muscle and joint mechanical responses following a high-intensity stretching protocol. Eur J Appl Physiol 116: 1519&#x2013;1526, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, Bottaro M. Effects of training attendance on muscle strength of young men after 11 weeks of resistance training. Asian J Sports Med 4: 101&#x2013;106, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handel M, Horstmann T, Dickhuth HH, G&#xfc;lch RW. Effects of contract-relax stretching training on muscle performance in athletes. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 76: 400&#x2013;408, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaggers JR, Swank AM, Frost KL, Lee CD. The acute effects of dynamic and ballistic stretching on vertical jump height, force, and power. J Strength Cond Res 22: 1844&#x2013;1849, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Junior RM, Berton R, de Souza TMF, Chacon-Mikahil MPT, Cavaglieri CR. Effect of the flexibility training performed immediately before resistance training on muscle hypertrophy, maximum strength and flexibility. Eur J Appl Physiol 117: 767&#x2013;774, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokkonen J, Nelson AG, Eldredge C, Winchester JB. Chronic static stretching improves exercise performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc 39: 1825&#x2013;1831, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokkonen J, Nelson AG, Tarawhiti T, Buckingham P, Winchester JB. Early-phase resistance training strength gains in novice lifters are enhanced by doing static stretching. J Strength Cond Res 24: 502&#x2013;506, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leite T, de Souza Teixeira A, Saavedra F, et al. Influence of strength and flexibility training, combined or isolated, on strength and flexibility gains. J Strength Cond Res 29: 1083&#x2013;1088, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall PWM, Cashman A, Cheema BS. A randomized controlled trial for the effect of passive stretching on measures of hamstring extensibility, passive stiffness, strength, and stretch tolerance. J Sci Med Sport 14: 535&#x2013;540, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oba K, Samukawa M, Nakamura K, et al. Influence of constant torque stretching at different stretching intensities on flexibility and mechanical properties of plantar flexors. J Strength Cond Res 35: 709&#x2013;714, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onishi H, Yagi R, Oyama M, et al. EMG-angle relationship of the hamstring muscles during maximum knee flexion. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 12: 399&#x2013;406, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page P. Current concepts in muscle stretching for exercise and rehabilitation. Int J Sports Phys Ther 7: 109&#x2013;119, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papadopoulos G, Siatras T, Kellis S. The effect of static and dynamic stretching exercises on the maximal isokinetic strength of the knee extensors and flexors. Isokinet Exerc Sci 13: 285&#x2013;291, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Alvar BA, Evetovich TK, et al. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sport Exerc 41: 687&#x2013;708, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR. Determining the magnitude of treatment effects in strength training research through the use of the effect size. J Strength Cond Res 18: 918&#x2013;920, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodacki AL, Souza RM, Ugrinowitsch C, Cristopoliski F, Fowler NE. Transient effects of stretching exercises on gait parameters of elderly women. Man Ther 14: 167&#x2013;172, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanada K, Kearns CF, Midorikawa T, Abe T. Prediction and validation of total and regional skeletal muscle mass by ultrasound in Japanese adults. Eur J Appl Physiol 96: 24&#x2013;31, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The mechanisms of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 24: 2857&#x2013;2872, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B, Krieger J, et al. Resistance training volume enhances muscle hypertrophy but not strength in trained men. Med Sci Sport Exerc 51: 94&#x2013;103, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 35: 1073&#x2013;1082, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Effects of low- vs. High-load resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy in well-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 29: 2954&#x2013;2963, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekir U, Arabaci R, Akova B, Kadagan SM. Acute effects of static and dynamic stretching on leg flexor and extensor isokinetic strength in elite women athletes. Scand J Med Sci Sport 20: 268&#x2013;281, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim&#xe3;o R, Lemos A, Salles B, et al. The influence of strength, flexibility, and simultaneous training on flexibility and strength gains. J Strength Cond Res 25: 1333&#x2013;1338, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stauber WT, Miller GR, Grimmett JG, Knack KK. Adaptation of rat soleus muscles to 4 wk of intermittent strain. J Appl Physiol 77: 58&#x2013;62, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas S, Reading J, Shephard RJ. Revision of the physical activity readiness questionnaire (PAR-Q). Can J Sport Sci 17: 338&#x2013;345, 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres EM, Kraemer WJ, Vingren JL, et al. Effects of stretching on upper-body muscular performance. J Strength Cond Res 22: 1279&#x2013;1285, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winchester JB, Nelson AG, Kokkonen J. A single 30-s stretch is sufficient to inhibit maximal voluntary strength. Res Q Exerc Sport 80: 257&#x2013;261, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winett RA, Carpinelli RN. Potential health-related benefits of resistance training. Prev Med 33: 503&#x2013;513, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worrell TW, Smith TL, Winegardner J. Effect of hamstring stretching on hamstring muscle performance. J Orthop Sport Phys Ther 20: 154&#x2013;159, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamaguchi T, Ishii K, Yamanaka M, Yasuda K. Acute effects of dynamic stretching exercise on power output during concentric dynamic constant external resistance leg extension. J Strength Cond Res 21: 1238&#x2013;1244, 2007.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>