<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">29204323</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2167-8359</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>5</Volume><PubDate><Year>2017</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PeerJ</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PeerJ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ability to predict repetitions to momentary failure is not perfectly accurate, though improves with resistance training experience.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e4105</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e4105</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e4105</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7717/peerj.4105</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>'Repetitions in Reserve' (RIR) scales in resistance training (RT) are used to control effort but assume people accurately predict performance <i>a priori</i> (i.e. the number of possible repetitions to momentary failure (MF)). This study examined the ability of trainees with different experience levels to predict number of repetitions to MF. One hundred and forty-one participants underwent a full body RT session involving single sets to MF and were asked to predict the number of repetitions they could complete before reaching MF on each exercise. Participants underpredicted the number of repetitions they could perform to MF (Standard error of measurements [95% confidence intervals] for combined sample ranged between 2.64 [2.36-2.99] and 3.38 [3.02-3.83]). There was a tendency towards improved accuracy with greater experience. Ability to predict repetitions to MF is not perfectly accurate among most trainees though may improve with experience. Thus, RIR should be used cautiously in prescription of RT. Trainers and trainees should be aware of this as it may have implications for the attainment of training goals, particularly muscular hypertrophy.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Steele</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Health, and Social Sciences, Southampton Solent University, Southampton, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Endres</LastName><ForeName>Andreas</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sport Science, University of Koblenz-Landau, Landau, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fisher</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Health, and Social Sciences, Southampton Solent University, Southampton, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gentil</LastName><ForeName>Paulo</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Education and Dance, Federal University of Goias, Goi&#xe2;nia, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giessing</LastName><ForeName>J&#xfc;rgen</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sport Science, University of Koblenz-Landau, Landau, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PeerJ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101603425</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2167-8359</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fitness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Program evaluation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Strength</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare there are no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29204323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5712461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.4105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">4105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abbiss CR, Peiffer JJ, Meeusen R, Skorski S. Role of ratings of perceived exertion during self-paced exercise: what are we actually measuring? Sports Medicine. 2015;45:1235&#x2013;1243. doi: 10.1007/s40279-015-0344-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0344-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26054383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barcelos LC, Nunes PR, De Souza LR, De Oliviera AA, Furlanetto R, Marocolo M, Orsatti FL. Low-load resistance training promotes muscular adaptation regardless of vascular occlusion, load, or volume. European Journal of Applied Physiology. 2015;115:1559&#x2013;1568. doi: 10.1007/s00421-015-3141-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-015-3141-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25731927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutts AJ, Murphy AJ, Dascombe BJ. Effect of direct supervision of a strength coach on measures of muscular strength and power in young rugby league players. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2004;18:316&#x2013;323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15142000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Jessee MB, Mattocks KT, Mouser JG, Counts BR, Buckner SL, Loenneke JP. Training to fatigue: the answer for standardization when assessing muscle hypertrophy? Sports Medicine. 2016;47(6):1021&#x2013;1027. doi: 10.1007/s40279-016-0633-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0633-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27677915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsangedy HM, Krause MP, Krinski K, Alves RC, Hsin Nery Chao C, Da Silva SG. Is the self-selected resistance exercise intensity by older women consistent with the American College of Sports Medicine guidelines to improve muscular fitness? Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2013;27:1877&#x2013;1884. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182736cfa.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182736cfa</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23792939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farup J, De Paoli F, Bjerg K, Riis S, Ringgard S, Vissing K. Blood flow restricted and traditional resistance training performed to fatigue produce equal muscle hypertrophy. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine and Science in Sports. 2015;25:754&#x2013;763. doi: 10.1111/sms.12396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25603897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher JP, Blossom D, Steele J. A comparison of volume equated knee extensions to failure, or not to failure, upon rating of perceived exertion and strength adaptations. Applied, Physiology, Nutrition, and Metabolism. 2016;41:168&#x2013;174. doi: 10.1139/apnm-2015-0421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2015-0421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26789094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher JP, Carlson L, Steele J. The effects of breakdown set resistance training on muscular performance and body composition in young males and females. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2015;30:1425&#x2013;1432. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26439789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher JP, Carlson L, Steele J, Smith D. The effects of pre-exhaustion, exercise order, and rest intervals in a full-body resistance training intervention. Applied, Physiology, Nutrition, and Metabolism. 2014;39:1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1139/apnm-2014-0162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2014-0162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25092528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Farrow J, Steele J. Acute fatigue, and perceptual responses to resistance exercise. Muscle and Nerve. 2017;56(6):E141&#x2013;E146. doi: 10.1002/mus.25645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.25645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28321881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Ironside M, Steele J. Heavier- and lighter-load resistance training to momentary failure produce similar increases in strength with differing degrees of discomfort. Muscle and Nerve. 2016;56(4):797&#x2013;803. doi: 10.1002/mus.25537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.25537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28006852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Steele J, Smith D. Evidence-based resistance training recommendations for muscular hypertrophy. Medicina Sportiva. 2013;17:217&#x2013;235. doi: 10.5604/17342260.1081302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5604/17342260.1081302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Steele J, Smith J, Bruce-Low S. Evidence based resistance training recommendations. Medicina Sportiva. 2011;15:147&#x2013;162. doi: 10.2478/v10036-011-0025-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/v10036-011-0025-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P., Bottaro M. Influence of supervision ratio on muscle adaptations to resistance training in nontrained subjects. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2010;24:639&#x2013;643. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181ad3373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181ad3373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19661830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giessing J, Eichmann B, Steele J, Fisher J. A comparison of low volume &#x2018;high-intensity-training&#x2019; and high volume traditional resistance training methods on muscular performance, body composition, and subjective assessments of training. Biology of Sport. 2016a;33:241&#x2013;249. doi: 10.5604/20831862.1201813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5604/20831862.1201813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4993139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27601778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giessing J, Fisher J, Steele J, Rothe F, Raubold K, Eichmann B. The effects of low volume resistance training with and without advanced techniques in trained participants. Journal of Sports Medicine and Physical Fitness. 2016b;56(3):249&#x2013;258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25303171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glass SC, Stanton DR. Self-selected resistance training intensity in novice weightlifters. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2004;18:324&#x2013;327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15142014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Cobley S, Favies T, Michael S, Halaki M. Accuracy in estimating repetitions to failure during resistance exercise. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2016;31(8):2162&#x2013;2168. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27787474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Johnson NA, Halaki M, Chow C. A novel scale to assess resistance-exercise effort. Journal of Sports Sciences. 2012;30:1405&#x2013;1413. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2012.710757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2012.710757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22873691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms ER, Brown SR, Cross MR, Storey A, Cronin J, Zourdos M. Self-rated accuracy of rating of perceived exertion-based load prescription in powerlifters. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2017;31(10):2938&#x2013;2943. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28933716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms ER, Cronin J, Storey A, Zourdos M. Application of the repetitions in reserve-based rating of perceived exertion scale for resistance training. Strength and Conditioning Journal. 2016;38:42&#x2013;49. doi: 10.1519/SSC.0000000000000218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/SSC.0000000000000218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4961270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27531969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiscock DJ, Dawson B, Donnelly CJ, Peeling P. Muscle activation, blood lactate, and perceived exertion responses to changing resistance training programming variables. European Journal of Sport Science. 2016;16:536&#x2013;544. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2015.1071880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2015.1071880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26267339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiscock DJ, Dawson B, Peeling P. Perceived exertion responses to changing resistance training programming variables. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2015;29:1564&#x2013;1569. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25436635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollander DB, Duran RJ, Trynicki JL, Larock D, Castracane VD, Hebert EP, Kraemer RR. RPE, pain, and physiological adjustment to concentric and eccentric contractions. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2003;35:1017&#x2013;1025. doi: 10.1249/01.MSS.0000069749.13258.4E.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000069749.13258.4E</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12783051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollander DB, Kilpatrick MW, Ramadan ZG, Reeves GV, Francois M, Blakeney A, Castracane VD, Kraemer RR. Load rather than contraction type influences rate of perceived exertion and pain. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2008;22:1184&#x2013;1193. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31816a8bc2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31816a8bc2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18545190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG. Measures of Reliability in Sports Medicine and Science. Sports Medicine. 2000;30:1&#x2013;15. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200030010-00001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200030010-00001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10907753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG. Spreadsheets for analysis of validity and reliability. Sportscience. 2015;19:36&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo-Gabarren M, Gonzalez De Txbarri Exposito R, Garcia-pallares J, Sanchez-Medina J, De Villarreal ES, Izquierdo M. Concurrent endurance and strength training not to failure optimises performance gains. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2010;42:1191&#x2013;1199. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181c67eec.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181c67eec</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19997025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcora S. Perception of effort during exercise is independent of afferent feedback from skeletal muscles, heart, and lungs. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2009;106:2060&#x2013;2062. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.90378.2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.90378.2008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18483166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzetti SA, Kraemer WJ, Volek JS, Dunca ND, Ratamess NA, Gomez AL, Newton RU, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Fleck SJ. The influence of direct supervision of resistance training on strength performance. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise. 2000;32:1175&#x2013;1184. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200006000-00023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200006000-00023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10862549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Oikawa SY, Wavell CG, Mazara N, McGlory C, Quadrilatero J, Baechler BL, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Neither load nor systemic hormones determine resistance training-mediated hypertrophy or strength gains in resistance-trained young men. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2016;121:129&#x2013;138. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00154.2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00154.2016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4967245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27174923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pritchett RC, Green JM, Wickwire PJ, Pritchett KL, Kovacs MS. Acute and session RPE responses during resistance training: bouts to failure at 60% and 90% of 1RM. South African Journal of Sports Medicine. 2009;21:23&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Faigenabum AD, Hoffman JR, Kang J. Self-selected resistance training intensity in healthy women: the influence of a personal trainer. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2008;22:103&#x2013;111. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31815f29cc.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31815f29cc</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18296962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sampson JA, Groeller H. Is repetition failure critical for the development of muscle hypertrophy and strength? Scandinavian Journal of Medicine and Science in Sports. 2016;26:375&#x2013;383. doi: 10.1111/sms.12445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25809472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn DI, Krieger JW. Effect of repetition duration during resistance training on muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Medicine. 2015;45:577&#x2013;585. doi: 10.1007/s40279-015-0304-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0304-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25601394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Peterson MD, Ogborn D, Contreras B, Sonmez GT. Effects of low- versus high-load resistance training on muscle strength and hypertrophy in well-trained men. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2015;29:2954&#x2013;2963. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25853914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Wilson JM, Lowery RP, Krieger JW. Muscular adaptations in low-versus high-load resistance training: a meta-analysis. European Journal of Sport Science. 2016;16:1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2014.989922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2014.989922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25530577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimano T, Kraemer WJ, Spiering BA, Volek JS, Hatfield DL, Silvestre R, Vingren JL, Fragala MS, Maresh CM, Fleck SJ, Newton RU, Spreuwenberg LP, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Relationship between the number of repetitions and selected percentages of one repetition maximum in free weight exercises in trained and untrained men. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2006;20:819&#x2013;823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17194239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva VL, Azevedo AP, Cordeiro JP, Duncan MJ, Cholewa JM, Siqueira-Filho MA, Zanchi NE, Guimaraes-Ferreira L. Effects of exercise intensity on perceived exertion during multiple sets of bench press to volitional failure. Journal of Trainology. 2014;3:41&#x2013;46. doi: 10.17338/trainology.3.2_41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17338/trainology.3.2_41</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smirnaul BDPC. Sense of effort and other unpleasant sensations during exercise: clarifying concepts and mechanisms. British Journal of Sports Medicine. 2012;46:308&#x2013;311. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.2010.071407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2010.071407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20584757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J. Intensity; in-ten-si-ty; noun. 1. Often used ambiguously within resistance training. 2. Is it time to drop the term altogether? British Journal of Sports Medicine. 2014;48:1586&#x2013;1588. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2012-092127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2012-092127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23403526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J, Fisher J, Giessing J, Gentil P. Clarity in reporting terminology and definitions of set end points in resistance training. Muscle and Nerve. 2017a;56(3):368&#x2013;374. doi: 10.1002/mus.25557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.25557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28044366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J, Fisher J, McGuff D, Bruce-Low S, Smith D. Resistance training to momentary muscular failure improves cardiovascular fitness in humans: a review of acute physiological responses and chronic physiological adaptations. Journal of Exercise Physiology. 2012;15(3):53&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J, Fisher J, McKinnon S, McKinnon P. Differentiation between perceived effort and discomfort during resistance training in older adults: reliability of trainee ratings of effort and discomfort, and reliability and validity of trainer ratings of trainee effort. Journal of Trainology. 2017b;6(1):1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.17338/trainology.6.1_1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17338/trainology.6.1_1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele J, Fisher J, Skivington M, Dunn C, Arnold J, Tew G, Batterham AM, Nunan D, O&#x2019;Driscoll JM, Mann S, Beedie C, Jobson S, Smith D, Vigotsky A, Phillips S, Estabrooks P, Winett R. A higher effort-based paradigm in physical activity and exercise for public health: making the case for a greater emphasis on resistance training. BMC Public Health. 2017c;17:300. doi: 10.1186/s12889-017-4209-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-017-4209-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5382466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28381272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zourdos MC, Klemp A, Dolan C, Quiles JM, Schau KA, Jo E, Helms E, Esgro B, Duncan S, Garcia-Merino Blanco R. Novel resistance training-specific rating of perceived exertion scale measuring repetitions in reserve. Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research. 2016;30:267&#x2013;275. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000001049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26049792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>