<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38773002</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2199-1170</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine - open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Potential Moderators of the Effects of Blood Flow Restriction Training on Muscle Strength and Hypertrophy: A Meta-analysis Based on a Comparison with High-Load Resistance Training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>58</StartPage><MedlinePgn>58</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">58</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40798-024-00719-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">While it has been examined whether there are similar magnitudes of muscle strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low-load resistance training combined with blood-flow restriction training (BFR-RT) and high-load resistance training (HL-RT), some important potential moderators (e.g., age, sex, upper and lower limbs, frequency and duration etc.) have yet to be analyzed further. Furthermore, training status, specificity of muscle strength tests (dynamic versus isometric or isokinetic) and specificity of muscle mass assessments (locations of muscle hypertrophy assessments) seem to exhibit different effects on the results of the analysis. The role of these influencing factors, therefore, remains to be elucidated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this meta-analysis was to compare the effects of BFR- versus HL-RT on muscle adaptations, when considering the influence of population characteristics (training status, sex and age), protocol characteristics (upper or lower limbs, duration and frequency) and test specificity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Studies were identified through database searches based on the following inclusion criteria: (1) pre- and post-training assessment of muscular strength; (2) pre- and post-training assessment of muscular hypertrophy; (3) comparison of BFR-RT vs. HL-RT; (4) score&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;4 on PEDro scale; (5) means and standard deviations (or standard errors) are reported or allow estimation from graphs. In cases where the fifth criterion was not met, the data were requested directly from the authors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The main finding of the present study was that training status was an important influencing factor in the effects of BFR-RT. The trained individuals may gain greater muscle strength and hypertrophy with BFR-RT as compared to HL-RT. However, the results showed that the untrained individuals experienced similar muscle mass gains and superior muscle strength gains in with HL-RT compared to BFR-RT.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Compared to HL-RT, training status is an important factor influencing the effects of the BFR-RT, in which trained can obtain greater muscle strength and hypertrophy gains in BFR-RT, while untrained individuals can obtain greater strength gains and similar hypertrophy in HL-RT.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geng</LastName><ForeName>Yu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-3985-6100</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Jiyang College of Zhejiang A&amp;F University, Zhuji, 311800, People's Republic of China. gengyu@zafu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Xueping</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Shanghai University of Sport, Shanghai, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, School of Medicine, Shaoxing University, Zhejiang, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Meng</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physical Education, Huzhou University, Zhejiang, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101662568</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2198-9761</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood flow restriction training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High-load resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Protocol characteristics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Test specificity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Training effect</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Training status</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Yu Geng, Xueping Wu, Yong Zhang and Meng Zhang declare that they have no conflict of interests relevant to the content of this review.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38773002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11109065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-024-00719-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40798-024-00719-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Wilson JM, Lowery RP, Krieger JW. Muscular adaptations in low- versus high-load resistance training: a meta-analysis. Eur J Sport Sci. 2016;16:1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2014.989922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2014.989922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25530577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Ratamess NA. Fundamentals of resistance training: progression and exercise prescription. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2004;36:674&#x2013;688. doi: 10.1249/01.MSS.0000121945.36635.61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000121945.36635.61</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15064596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos GER, Luecke TJ, Wendeln HK, Toma K, Hagerman FC, Murray TF, et al. Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2002;88:50&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1007/s00421-002-0681-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-002-0681-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12436270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott B, Loenneke J, Slattery K, Dascombe B. Exercise with blood flow restriction: an updated evidence-based approach for enhanced muscular development. Sports Med. 2015;45:313&#x2013;325. doi: 10.1007/s40279-014-0288-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0288-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25430600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pignanelli C, Petrick HL, Keyvani F, Heigenhauser GJF, Quadrilatero J, Holloway GP, et al. Low-load resistance training to task failure with and without blood flow restriction: muscular functional and structural adaptations. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2020;318:R284&#x2013;R295. doi: 10.1152/ajpregu.00243.2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00243.2019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7052604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31823670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes L, Paton B, Rosenblatt B, Gissane C, Patterson SD. Blood flow restriction training in clinical musculoskeletal rehabilitation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:1003&#x2013;1011. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2016-097071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2016-097071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28259850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slysz J, Stultz J, Burr JF. The efficacy of blood flow restricted exercise: a systematic review &amp; meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport. 2016;19:669&#x2013;675. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2015.09.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2015.09.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26463594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Wilson JM, Marin PJ, Zourdos MC, Bemben MG. Low intensity blood flow restriction training: a meta-analysis. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112:1849&#x2013;1859. doi: 10.1007/s00421-011-2167-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-011-2167-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21922259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karabulut M, Abe T, Sato Y, Bemben MG. The effects of low-intensity resistance training with vascular restriction on leg muscle strength in older men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;108:147&#x2013;155. doi: 10.1007/s00421-009-1204-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-009-1204-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19760431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Komuro T, Ishiguro N, Tsunoda N, Sato Y, Ishii N, et al. Effects of low-load resistance training with vascular occlusion on the mechanical properties of muscle and tendon. J Appl Biomech. 2006;22:112&#x2013;119. doi: 10.1123/jab.22.2.112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jab.22.2.112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16871002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Ogasawara R, Sakamaki M, Ozaki H, Sato Y, Abe T. Combined effects of low-intensity blood flow restriction training and high-intensity resistance training on muscle strength and size. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111:2525&#x2013;2533. doi: 10.1007/s00421-011-1873-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-011-1873-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21360203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin-Hernandez J, Marin PJ, Menendez H, Ferrero C, Loenneke JP, Herrero AJ. Muscular adaptations after two different volumes of blood flow-restricted training. Scand J Med Sci SPORTS. 2013;23:e114&#x2013;e120. doi: 10.1111/sms.12036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.12036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23278841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vechin FC, Libardi CA, Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o MS, Damas FR, Lixandr&#xe3;o ME, Berton RPB, et al. Comparisons between low-intensity resistance training with blood flow restriction and high-intensity resistance training on quadriceps muscle mass and strength in elderly. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29:1071&#x2013;1076. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000000703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25264670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark BC, Manini TM, Hoffman RL, Williams PS, Guiler MK, Knutson MJ, et al. Relative safety of 4 weeks of blood flow-restricted resistance exercise in young, healthy adults. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2011;21:653&#x2013;662. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01100.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01100.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6152804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21917016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurentino GC, Ugrinowitsch C, Roschel H, Aoki MS, Soares AG, Neves M, Jr, et al. Strength training with blood flow restriction diminishes myostatin gene expression. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44:406&#x2013;412. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e318233b4bc.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318233b4bc</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21900845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozaki H, Yasuda T, Ogasawara R, Sakamaki-Sunaga M, Naito H, Abe T. Effects of high-intensity and blood flow-restricted low-intensity resistance training on carotid arterial compliance: role of blood pressure during training sessions. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113:167&#x2013;174. doi: 10.1007/s00421-012-2422-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-012-2422-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22618304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellefsen S, Hammarstrom D, Strand TA, Zacharoff E, Whist JE, Rauk I, et al. Blood flow-restricted strength training displays high functional and biological efficacy in women: a within-subject comparison with high-load strength training. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2015;309:R767&#x2013;R779. doi: 10.1152/ajpregu.00497.2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00497.2014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4666930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26202071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Zhao Z, Wang M, Chen C, Wei W, Liang Y. Effect of 4 weeks KAATSU training on body composition and maximum strength of male handball players. China Sport Sci Technol. 2019;55:37&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Che T, Li Z, Yang T, Chen Z, Wang S. Effects of six-week low intensity KAATSU training combined with high intensity resistance training on core area and lower limb muscle strength in adolescent female wrestlers. J Cap Univ Phys Educ Sports. 2022;34:333&#x2013;341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandr&#xe3;o M, Ugrinowitsch C, Berton R, Vechin F, Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o M, Damas F, et al. Magnitude of muscle strength and mass adaptations between high-load resistance training versus low-load resistance training associated with blood-flow restriction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48:361&#x2013;378. doi: 10.1007/s40279-017-0795-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0795-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29043659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xf8;nfeldt BM, Lindberg Nielsen J, Mieritz RM, Lund H, Aagaard P. Effect of blood-flow restricted vs heavy-load strength training on muscle strength: systematic review and meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2020;30:837&#x2013;848. doi: 10.1111/sms.13632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32031709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrell PA, Joyner MJ, Caiozzo VJ. In: American College of Sports Medicine, editors. ACSM&#x2019;s advanced exercise physiology. 2nd ed. Philadelphia: Wolters Kluwer Health/Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG. Neural adaptation to strength training. In: Komi PV, editor. Strength power sport. Oxford: Blackwell Science Ltd; 2003. pp. 281&#x2013;314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vissing K, Groennebaek T, Wernbom M, Aagaard P, Raastad T. Myocellular adaptations to low-load blood flow restricted resistance training. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2020;48:180&#x2013;187. doi: 10.1249/JES.0000000000000231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JES.0000000000000231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32658044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill EC, Housh TJ, Keller JL, Smith CM, Anders JV, Schmidt RJ, et al. Patterns of responses and time-course of changes in muscle size and strength during low-load blood flow restriction resistance training in women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2021;121:1473&#x2013;1485. doi: 10.1007/s00421-021-04627-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-021-04627-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33638690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornsen T, Wernbom M, Kirketeig A, Paulsen G, Samnoy L, Baekken L, et al. Type 1 muscle fiber hypertrophy after blood flow-restricted training in powerlifters. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51:288&#x2013;298. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000001775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30188363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacin A, Strazar K. Frequent low-load ischemic resistance exercise to failure enhances muscle oxygen delivery and endurance capacity. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2011;21:E231&#x2013;E241. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01260.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0838.2010.01260.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21385216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centner C, Jerger S, Lauber B, Seynnes O, Friedrich T, Lolli D, et al. Low-load blood flow restriction and high-load resistance training induce comparable changes in patellar tendon properties. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2022;54:582&#x2013;589. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34772900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner SL, Jessee MB, Mattocks KT, Mouser JG, Counts BR, Dankel SJ, et al. Determining strength: a case for multiple methods of measurement. Sports Med. 2017;47:193&#x2013;195. doi: 10.1007/s40279-016-0580-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0580-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27380100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verhagen AP, de Vet HCW, de Bie RA, Kessels AGH, Boers M, Bouter LM, et al. The delphi list: a criteria list for quality assessment of randomized clinical trials for conducting systematic reviews developed by Delphi consensus. J Clin Epidemiol. 1998;51:1235&#x2013;1241. doi: 10.1016/S0895-4356(98)00131-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0895-4356(98)00131-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10086815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JPT, Rothstein HR, editors. Introduction to meta-analysis. Chichester: Wiley; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckner SL, Jessee MB, Dankel SJ, Mattocks KT, Mouser JG, Bell ZW, et al. Blood flow restriction does not augment low force contractions taken to or near task failure. Eur J Sport Sci. 2020;20:650&#x2013;659. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2019.1664640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2019.1664640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31486720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centner C, Lauber B, Seynnes OR, Jerger S, Sohnius T, Gollhofer A, et al. Low-load blood flow restriction training induces similar morphological and mechanical Achilles tendon adaptations compared with high-load resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 2019;127:1660&#x2013;1667. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00602.2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00602.2019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31725362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook SB, LaRoche DP, Villa MR, Barile H, Manini TM. Blood flow restricted resistance training in older adults at risk of mobility limitations. Exp Gerontol. 2017;99:138&#x2013;145. doi: 10.1016/j.exger.2017.10.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2017.10.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5660944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28987643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook SB, Scott BR, Hayes KL, Murphy BG. Neuromuscular adaptations to low-load blood flow restricted resistance training. J Sports Sci Med. 2018;17:66&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5844210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29535579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davids CJ, Naess TC, Moen M, Cumming KT, Horwath O, Psilander N, et al. Acute cellular and molecular responses and chronic adaptations to low-load blood flow restriction and high-load resistance exercise in trained individuals. J Appl Physiol. 2021;131:1731&#x2013;1749. doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00464.2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00464.2021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34554017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lemos Muller CH, Ramis TR, Ribeiro JL. Effects of low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction on the perceived exertion, muscular resistance and endurance in healthy young adults. Sport Sci Health. 2019;15:503&#x2013;510. doi: 10.1007/s11332-019-00536-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11332-019-00536-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zanardini Fernandes D, M&#xfc;ller Reis Weber V, Amaral da Silva MP, de Lima Stavinski NG, Campos de Oliveira LE, Casoto Tracz EH, et al. Effects of blood flow restriction training on handgrip strength and muscular volume of young women. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2020;15:901&#x2013;909. doi: 10.26603/ijspt20200901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26603/ijspt20200901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7727424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33344006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jessee MB, Buckner SL, Mouser JG, Mattocks KT, Dankel SJ, Abe T, et al. Muscle adaptations to high-load training and very low-load training with and without blood flow restriction. Front Physiol. 2018;9:1448. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2018.01448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2018.01448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6198179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30386254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SJ, Sherk VD, Bemben MG, Bemben DA. Effects of short-term, low-intensity resistance training with vascular restriction on arterial compliance in untrained young men. Int J KAATSU Train Res. 2009;5:1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.3806/ijktr.5.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3806/ijktr.5.1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D, Loenneke JP, Ye X, Bemben DA, Beck TW, Larson RD, et al. Low-load resistance training with low relative pressure produces muscular changes similar to high-load resistance training. Muscle Nerve. 2017;56:E126&#x2013;E133. doi: 10.1002/mus.25626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.25626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28224640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Lang JA, Pilania N, Franke WD. Effects of blood flow restricted exercise training on muscular strength and blood flow in older adults. Exp Gerontol. 2017;99:127&#x2013;132. doi: 10.1016/j.exger.2017.09.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2017.09.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28986234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korkmaz E, Donmez G, Uzuner K, Babayeva N, Torgutalp SS, Ozcakar L. Effects of blood flow restriction training on muscle strength and architecture. J Strength Cond Res. 2022;36:1396&#x2013;1403. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32287091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laswati H, Sugiarto D, Poerwandari D, Pangkahila JA, Kimura H. Low-Intensity exercise with blood flow restriction increases muscle strength without altering hsCRP and Fibrinogen levels in healthy subjects. Chin J Physiol. 2018;61:188&#x2013;195. doi: 10.4077/CJP.2018.BAG567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4077/CJP.2018.BAG567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29962179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Letieri RV, Teixeira AM, Furtado GE, Lamboglia CG, Rees JL, Gomes BB. Effect of 16 weeks of resistance exercise and detraining comparing two methods of blood flow restriction in muscle strength of healthy older women: a randomized controlled trial. Exp Gerontol. 2018;114:78&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1016/j.exger.2018.10.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2018.10.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30391274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libardi CA, Chacon-Mikahil MPT, Cavaglieri CR, Tricoli V, Roschel H, Vechin FC, et al. Effect of concurrent training with blood flow restriction in the elderly. Int J Sports Med. 2015;36:395&#x2013;399. doi: 10.1055/s-0034-1390496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0034-1390496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25700103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandrao ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Laurentino G, Libardi CA, Aihara AY, Cardoso FN, et al. Effects of exercise intensity and occlusion pressure after 12 weeks of resistance training with blood-flow restriction. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2015;115:2471&#x2013;2480. doi: 10.1007/s00421-015-3253-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-015-3253-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26323350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luebbers PE, Witte EV, Oshel JQ, Butler MS. Effects of practical blood flow restriction training on adolescent lower-body strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33:2674&#x2013;2683. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29084094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>May AK, Russell AP, Della Gatta PA, Warmington SA. Muscle adaptations to heavy-load and blood flow restriction resistance training methods. Front Physiol. 2022 doi: 10.3389/fphys.2022.837697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2022.837697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8850930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35185627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendonca GV, Vila-Ch&#xe3; C, Teod&#xf3;sio C, Goncalves AD, Freitas SR, Mil-Homens P, et al. Contralateral training effects of low-intensity blood-flow restricted and high-intensity unilateral resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2021;121:2305&#x2013;2321. doi: 10.1007/s00421-021-04708-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-021-04708-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33982187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morley WN, Ferth S, Debenham MIB, Boston M, Power GA, Burr JF. Training response to 8 weeks of blood flow restricted training is not improved by preferentially altering tissue hypoxia or lactate accumulation when training to repetition failure. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2021;46:1257&#x2013;1264. doi: 10.1139/apnm-2020-1056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2020-1056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33930277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramis TR, de Muller CHL, Boeno FP, Teixeira BC, Rech A, Pompermayer MG, et al. Effects of traditional and vascular restricted strength training program with equalized volume on isometric and dynamic strength, muscle thickness, electromyographic activity, and endothelial function adaptations in young adults. J Strength Cond Res. 2020;34:689&#x2013;698. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30063556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharifi S, Monazzami A, Nikousefat Z, Heyrani A, Yari K. The acute and chronic effects of resistance training with blood flow restriction on hormonal responses in untrained young men: a comparison of frequency. Cell Mol Biol. 2020;66:1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.14715/cmb/2019.66.1.1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14715/cmb/2019.66.1.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32359376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiromaru FF, de Painelli VS, Silva-Batista C, Longo AR, Lasevicius T, Schoenfeld BJ, et al. Differential muscle hypertrophy and edema responses between high-load and low-load exercise with blood flow restriction. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2019;29:1713&#x2013;1726. doi: 10.1111/sms.13516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31281989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sousa JBC, Neto GR, Santos HH, Ara&#xfa;jo JP, Silva HG, Cirilo-Sousa MS. Effects of strength training with blood flow restriction on torque, muscle activation and local muscular endurance in healthy subjects. Biol Sport. 2017;34:83&#x2013;90. doi: 10.5114/biolsport.2017.63738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/biolsport.2017.63738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5377566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28416903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugiarto D, Andriati A, Laswati H, Kimura H. Comparison of the increase of both muscle strength and hypertrophy of biceps brachii muscle in strengthening exercise with low-intensity resistance training with and without the application of blood flow restriction and high-intensity resistance training. Bali Med J. 2017;6:251&#x2013;257. doi: 10.15562/bmj.v6i2.496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15562/bmj.v6i2.496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira EL, de Painelli VS, Schoenfeld BJ, Silva-Batista C, Longo AR, Aihara AY, et al. Perceptual and neuromuscular responses adapt similarly between high-load resistance training and low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction. J Strength Cond Res. 2022;36:2410&#x2013;2416. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33306591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiebaud RS, Loenneke JP, Fahs CA, Rossow LM, Kim D, Abe T, et al. The effects of elastic band resistance training combined with blood flow restriction on strength, total bone-free lean body mass and muscle thickness in postmenopausal women. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2013;33:344&#x2013;352. doi: 10.1111/cpf.12033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cpf.12033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23701116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanghua LI, Zhiyun LIU. Biomechanical study on influence of different resistance training combined with blood flow restriction methods on leg muscle volume. J Southwest China Norm Univ Nat Sci Ed. 2020;45:111&#x2013;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Yu S, Lou H, Wang Y. Effect of KAATSU resistance training on body limb circumference, maximum strength and agility of college student male tennis players. Fujian Sports Sci Technol. 2022;41:49&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Li Z, Wei W, Zhao Z, Chen C, Huang J. Empirical study of KAATSU training effect on lower limb of male elite handball player. China Sport Sci Technol. 2019;55:30&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Ye J, Wu J. The effect of blood flow restriction with different intensities of strength training on muscle strength and explosive jump performance. Sichuan Sports Sci. 2022;41:29&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kataoka R, Vasenina E, Hammert WB, Ibrahim AH, Dankel SJ, Buckner SL. Muscle growth adaptations to high-load training and low-load training with blood flow restriction in calf muscles. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2022;122:623&#x2013;634. doi: 10.1007/s00421-021-04862-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-021-04862-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34981201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Sherk VD, Bemben MG, Bemben DA. Effects of short term low intensity resistance training with blood flow restriction on bone markers and muscle cross-sectional area in young men. Int J Exerc Sci. 2012;5:136&#x2013;147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centner C, Jerger S, Lauber B, Seynnes O, Friedrich T, Lolli D, et al. Similar patterns of tendon regional hypertrophy after low-load blood flow restriction and high-load resistance training. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2023;33:848&#x2013;856. doi: 10.1111/sms.14321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36703264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araujo Pess&#xf4;a DE, K, Cholewa JM, Sousasilva R, Xia Z, Zagatto AM, Lancha-Jr AH, , et al. Does beta-alanine supplementation potentiate muscle performance following 6 weeks of blood flow restriction or traditional resistance training? Int J Exerc Sci. 2023;16:999&#x2013;1011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10464749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37650035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horiuchi M, Stoner L, Poles J. The effect of four weeks blood flow restricted resistance training on macro- and micro-vascular function in healthy, young men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2023;123:2179&#x2013;2189. doi: 10.1007/s00421-023-05230-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-023-05230-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37245196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Judd K, Morales C, White M, Wilkie K, Faller J, Ives SJ. The effects of accessory blood flow restriction training on muscle size and strength in division III soccer athletes: a preliminary ecological study. Int J Exerc Sci. 2023;16:1244&#x2013;1256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10824293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38288384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reece TM, Godwin JS, Strube MJ, Ciccone AB, Stout KW, Pearson JR, et al. Myofiber hypertrophy adaptations following 6 weeks of low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction in untrained males and females. J Appl Physiol Bethesda Md. 1985;2023(134):1240&#x2013;1255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10190928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37022967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sousa-Silva R, Cholewa JM, Pess&#xf4;a KDA, Xia Z, Lauver JD, Rossi FE, et al. Creatine supplementation combined with blood flow restriction training enhances muscle thickness and performance: a randomized, placebo-controlled, and double-blind study. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2023;48:417&#x2013;426. doi: 10.1139/apnm-2022-0209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2022-0209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36812477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Atakan MM, Acar B, Xiong R, Peng L. Effects of 4-week low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction on muscle strength and left ventricular function in young swimmers: a pilot randomized trial. J Hum Kinet. 2023;87:63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10407315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37559761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukic I, Van Hooren B, Ramos AG, Helms ER, McGuigan MR, Tufano JJ. The effects of set structure manipulation on chronic adaptations to resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med Auckl NZ. 2021;51:1061&#x2013;1086. doi: 10.1007/s40279-020-01423-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01423-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33417154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JPT, Rothstein HR. A basic introduction to fixed-effect and random-effects models for meta-analysis. Res Synth Methods. 2010;1:97&#x2013;111. doi: 10.1002/jrsm.12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jrsm.12</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26061376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. 2003;327:557&#x2013;560. doi: 10.1136/bmj.327.7414.557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.327.7414.557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2017;35:1073&#x2013;1082. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2016.1210197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2016.1210197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27433992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Takazawa H, Sato Y, Takebayashi S, Ishii N. Effects of resistance exercise combined with moderate vascular occlusion on muscular function in humans. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88:2097. doi: 10.1152/jappl.2000.88.6.2097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.2000.88.6.2097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10846023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coe R. It&#x2019;s the effect size, stupid what effect size is and why it is important. In: Annual conference of the British educational research association. England: University of Exeter; 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA. ACSM&#x2019;s foundations of strength training and conditioning. Philadelphia: Wolters Kluwer Health/Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakkinen K, Komi PV, Alen M, Kauhanen H. EMG, muscle fibre and force production characteristics during a 1 year training period in elite weight-lifters. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1987;56:419&#x2013;427. doi: 10.1007/BF00417769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00417769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3622485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe T, Kawamoto K, Yasuda T, Kearns CF, Midorikawa T, Sato Y. Eight days KAATSU-resistance training improved sprint but not jump performance in collegiate male track and field athletes. Int J KAATSU Train Res. 2005;1:19&#x2013;23. doi: 10.3806/ijktr.1.19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3806/ijktr.1.19</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denadai BS, Oliveira F, Camarda S, Ribeiro L, Greco CC. Effects of low-load resistance training with blood flow restriction on muscle size and strength of professional soccer players with muscle imbalance. Int J Appl Exerc Physiol. 2017;6:7&#x2013;13. doi: 10.22631/ijaep.v6i4.194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22631/ijaep.v6i4.194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. Potential mechanisms for a role of metabolic stress in hypertrophic adaptations to resistance training. Sports Med Auckl. 2013;43:179&#x2013;194. doi: 10.1007/s40279-013-0017-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-013-0017-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23338987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchateau J, Stragier S, Baudry S, Carpentier A. Strength training: in search of optimal strategies to maximize neuromuscular performance. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2021;49:2&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1249/JES.0000000000000234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JES.0000000000000234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33044332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kon M, Ikeda T, Homma T, Suzuki Y. Effects of low-intensity resistance exercise under acute systemic hypoxia on hormonal responses. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26:611&#x2013;617. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182281c69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3182281c69</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22310510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishimura A, Sugita M, Kato K, Fukuda A, Sudo A, Uchida A. Hypoxia increases muscle hypertrophy induced by resistance training. Int J SPORTS Physiol Perform. 2010;5:497&#x2013;508. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.5.4.497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.5.4.497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21266734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christiansen D, Murphy RM, Bangsbo J, Stathis CG, Bishop DJ. Increased FXYD1 and PGC-1&#x3b1; mRNA after blood flow-restricted running is related to fibre type-specific AMPK signalling and oxidative stress in human muscle. Acta Physiol Oxf Engl. 2018;223:e13045. doi: 10.1111/apha.13045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apha.13045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5969286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29383885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Burgomaster KA, Schofield LM, Gibala MJ, Sale DG, Phillips SM. Neuromuscular adaptations in human muscle following low intensity resistance training with vascular occlusion. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2004;92:399&#x2013;406. doi: 10.1007/s00421-004-1072-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-004-1072-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15205956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Nakamura Y, Aruga S, Onda T, Miyazaki S, Ishii N. Rapid increase in plasma growth hormone after low-intensity resistance exercise with vascular occlusion. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88:61&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1152/jappl.2000.88.1.61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.2000.88.1.61</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10642363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Brechue W, Fujita T, Shirakawa J, Sato Y, Abe T. Muscle activation during low-intensity muscle contractions with restricted blood flow. J Sports Sci. 2009;27:479&#x2013;489. doi: 10.1080/02640410802626567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640410802626567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19253083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauver JD, Cayot TE, Rotarius T, Scheuermann BW. The effect of eccentric exercise with blood flow restriction on neuromuscular activation, microvascular oxygenation, and the repeated bout effect. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117:1005&#x2013;1015. doi: 10.1007/s00421-017-3589-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-017-3589-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28324168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bordessa JM, Hearn MC, Reinfeldt AE, Smith TA, Baweja HS, Levy SS, et al. Comparison of blood flow restriction devices and their effect on quadriceps muscle activation. Phys Ther Sport. 2021;49:90&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1016/j.ptsp.2021.02.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2021.02.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33647529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook SB, Murphy BG, Labarbera KE. Neuromuscular function after a bout of low-load blood flow-restricted exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45:67&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31826c6fa8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31826c6fa8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22895371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manini TM, Clark BC. Blood flow restricted exercise and skeletal muscle health. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2009;37:78&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1097/JES.0b013e31819c2e5c.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JES.0b013e31819c2e5c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19305199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Kim D, Fahs CA, Thiebaud RS, Abe T, Larson RD, et al. Effects of exercise with and without different degrees of blood flow restriction on torque and muscle activation. Muscle Nerve. 2015;51:713&#x2013;721. doi: 10.1002/mus.24448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.24448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25187395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott B, Slattery K, Sculley D, Dascombe B. Hypoxia and resistance exercise: a comparison of localized and systemic methods. Sports Med. 2014;44:1037&#x2013;1054. doi: 10.1007/s40279-014-0177-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0177-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24715613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutherford OM, Jones DA. The role of learning and coordination in strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1986;55:100&#x2013;105. doi: 10.1007/BF00422902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00422902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3698983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng Y, Zhang L, Wu X. Effects of blood flow restriction training on blood perfusion and work ability of muscles in Elite Para-alpine Skiers. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2022;54:489&#x2013;496. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000002805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8830888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34669671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott BR, Loenneke JP, Slattery KM, Dascombe BJ. Blood flow restricted exercise for athletes: a review of available evidence. J Sci Med Sport. 2016;19:360&#x2013;367. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2015.04.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2015.04.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26118847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>