<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34027917</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>High Responders to Hypertrophic Strength Training Also Tend to Lose More Muscle Mass and Strength During Detraining Than Low Responders.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1500</StartPage><EndPage>1511</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1500-1511</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004044</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>R&#xe4;ntil&#xe4;, A, Ahtiainen, JP, Avela, J, Restuccia, J, Kidgell, DJ, and H&#xe4;kkinen, K. High responders to hypertrophic strength training also tend to lose more muscle mass and strength during detraining than low responders. J Strength Cond Res 35(6): 1500-1511, 2021-This study investigated differences in individual responses to muscle hypertrophy during strength training and detraining. Ten weeks of resistance training was followed by 6 weeks of detraining in men (n = 24). Bilateral leg press (LP) one-repetition maximum (1RM) and maximal electromyography (EMGs) of vastus lateralis (VL) and vastus medialis, maximal voluntary activation (VA), transcranial magnetic stimulation for corticospinal excitability (CE), cross-sectional area of VL (VLCSA), selected serum hormone concentrations were measured before and repeatedly during training and detraining. In the total group, VLCSA increased by 10.7% (p = 0.025) and LP 1RM by 16.3% (p &lt; 0.0001) after training. The subjects were split into 3 groups according to increases in VLCSA: high responders (HR) &gt; 15% (n = 10), medium responders (MR) 15-4.5% (n = 7), and low responders (LR) &lt; 4.5% (n = 7). Vastus lateralis CSA in HR and MR increased statistically significantly from pre to posttraining but not in LR. Only HR increased LP 1RM statistically significantly from pre to post. Maximal EMG activity increased 21.3 &#xb1; 22.9% from pre- to posttraining for the total group (p = 0.009) and for MR (p &lt; 0.001). No significant changes occurred in VA and CE or serum hormone concentrations. During detraining, HR showed a decrease of -10.5% in VLCSA, whereas MR and LR did not. None of the subgroups decreased maximal strength during the first 3 weeks of detraining, whereas HR showed a slight (by 2.5%) rebound in strength. The present results suggest that strength gains and muscle activation adaptations may take place faster in HR and decrease also faster compared with other subgroups during detraining.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>R&#xe4;ntil&#xe4;</LastName><ForeName>Aapo</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuromuscular Research Center, Faculty of Sport and Health Sciences, University of Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Jyv&#xe4;skyl&#xe4;, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahtiainen</LastName><ForeName>Juha P</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Avela</LastName><ForeName>Janne</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Restuccia</LastName><ForeName>Joel</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kidgell</LastName><ForeName>Dawson</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>H&#xe4;kkinen</LastName><ForeName>Keijo</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014891" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Lifting</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34027917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202106000-00004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Pakarinen A, Alen M, Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K. Muscle hypertrophy, hormonal adaptations and strength development during strength training in strength-trained and untrained men. Eur J Appl Physiol 89: 555&#x2013;563, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Hoffren M, Hulmi J, et al. Panoramic ultrasonography is a valid method to measure changes in muscle cross-sectional area. Eur J Appl Physiol 108: 273&#x2013;279, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Walker S, Peltonen H, et al. Heterogeneity in resistance training-induced muscle strength and mass responses in men and women of different ages. Age (Dordr) 38: 10, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appleby B, Newton R, Prue C. Changes in strength over a 2-year period in professional rugby union players. J Strength Cond Res 26: 2358&#x2013;2546, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker D, Wilson G, Carolyn R. Periodization: The effect on strength of manipulating volume and intensity. J Strength Cond Res 8: 235&#x2013;242, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei S, Sadres E, Church D, et al. Comparison of the recovery response from high-intensity and high-volume resistance exercise in trained men. Eur J Appl Physiol 117: 1287&#x2013;1298, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellemare F, Bigland-Ritchie B. Assessment of human diaphragm strength and activation using phrenic nerve stimulation. Respir Physiol 58: 263&#x2013;277, 1984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickel C, Cross J, Bamman M. Exercise dosing to retain resistance training adaptations in young and older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 43: 1177&#x2013;1187, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard C, Rankinen T. Individual differences in response to regular physical activity. Med Sci Sports Exerc 33(6 Suppl):S446&#x2013;S451&#x2013;453, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caresio C, Molinari F, Emanuel G, Minetto M. Muscle echo intensity: Reliability and conditioning factors. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 35: 393&#x2013;403, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchward-Venne T, Tieland M, Verdijk L, et al. There are no nonresponders to resistance-type exercise training in older men and women. J Am Med Dir Assoc 16: 400&#x2013;411, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Barcelos C, Nobrega S, et al. Individual muscle hypertrophy and strength responses to high vs. low resistance training frequencies. J Strength Cond Res 33: 897&#x2013;901, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deschenes M, Kraemer WJ. Performance and physiologic adaptations to resistance training. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 81: 3&#x2013;16, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erskine R, Jones D, Williams A, Stewart C, Degens H. Inter-individual variability in the adaptation of human muscle specific tension to progressive resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol 110: 1117&#x2013;1125, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erskine R, Fletcher G, Folland J. The contribution of muscle hypertrophy to strength changes following resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol 114: 1239&#x2013;1249, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo VC, de Salles BF, Trajano GS. Volume for muscle hypertrophy and health outcomes: The most effective variable in resistance training. Sports Med 48: 499&#x2013;505, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo VC, Mccarthy J. Regulation of ribosome biogenesis in skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Physiology 34: 30&#x2013;42, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammarstr&#xf6;m D, &#xd8;fsteng S, Koll L, et al. Benefits of higher resistance-training volume are related to ribosome biogenesis. J Physiol 598: 543&#x2013;565, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris-Love M, Seamon B, Teixeira C, Ismail C. Ultrasound estimates of muscle quality in older adults: Reliability and comparison of photoshop and ImageJ for the grayscale analysis of muscle echogenicity. PeerJ 4: e1721, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermens HJ, Fredriks B, Disselhorst-Klug C, Rau G. Development of recommendations for SEMG sensors and sensor placement. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 10: 361&#x2013;374, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortobagyi T, Houmard J, Stevenson J, et al. The effects of detraining on power athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc 25: 929&#x2013;935, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubal MJ, Gordish-Dressman H, Thompson PD, et al. Variability in muscle size and strength gain after unilateral resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc 37: 964&#x2013;972, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang P, Andre T, McKinley-Barnard S, et al. Resistance training-induced elevations in muscular strength in trained men are maintained after 2 weeks of detraining and not differentially affected by whey protein supplementation. J Strength Cond Res 31: 869&#x2013;881, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Komi P. Electromyographic changes during strength training and detraining. Med Sci Sports Exerc 15: 455&#x2013;460, 1983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Alen M, Komi PV. Changes in isometric force- and relaxation-time, electromyographic and muscle fibre characteristics of human skeletal muscle during strength training and detraining. Acta Physiol Scand 125: 573&#x2013;585, 1985a.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Alen M, Kallinen M, Newton RU, Kraemer WJ. Neuromuscular adaptation during prolonged strength training, detraining and re-strength-training in middle-aged and elderly people. Eur J Appl Physiol 83: 51&#x2013;62, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Pakarinen A, Alen M, Kauhanen H, Komi PV. Relationships between training volume, physical performance capacity, and serum hormone concentrations during prolonged training in elite weight lifters. Int J Sports Med 1: 61&#x2013;65, 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Pakarinen A, Al&#xe9;n M, Komi PV. Serum hormones during prolonged training of neuromuscular performance. Eur J Appl Physiol 53: 287&#x2013;293, 1985b.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;kkinen K, Pakarinen A, Alen M, Kauhanen H, Komi PV. Daily hormonal and neuromuscular responses to intensive strength training in 1 week. Int J Sports Med 9: 422&#x2013;428, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Illera-Dom&#xed;nguez V, Nuell S, Carmona G, et al. Early functional and morphological muscle adaptations during short-term inertial-squat training. Front Physiol 9: 1265, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izquierdo M, Ibanez J, Gonzales-Badillo J, et al. Detraining and tapering effects on hormonal responses and strength performance. J Strength Cond Res 21: 768&#x2013;775, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobley C, Haun C, Roberson P, et al. Biomarkers associated with low, moderate, and high vastus lateralis muscle hypertrophy following 12 weeks of resistance training. PLoS One 13: e0195203, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montero D, Lunby C. Refuting the myth of non-response to exercise training: "non-responders" do respond to higher dose of training. J Physiol 595: 3377&#x2013;3387, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, DeVries H. Neural factors versus hypertrophy in the time course of muscle strength gain. Am J Physiol 58: 115&#x2013;130, 1979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujika I, Padilla S. Muscular characteristics of detraining in humans. Med Sci Sports Exerc 33: 1297&#x2013;1303, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narici MV, Roi GS, Landoni L, Minetti AE, Ceretelli P. Changes in force, cross-sectional area and neural activation during strength training and detraining of the human quadriceps. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol 59: 310&#x2013;319, 1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norrbrand L, Fluckey JD, Pozzo M, Tesch PA. Resistance training using eccentric overload induces early adaptations in skeletal muscle size. Eur J Appl Physiol 102: 271&#x2013;281, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickering C, Kiely J. Do Non-responders to exercise exist - and if so, what should we do about them?. Sports Med 49: 1&#x2013;7, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheldon WH, Dupertuis C, McDermott E. Individual differences within the somatotype. In: Sheldon WH, ed. Atlas of Men: A Guide for Somatotyping the Adult Male at All Ages. New York, NY: Harper &amp; Row, 1954. pp. 1&#x2013;357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Crgic J, Krieger J. How many times per week should a muscle Be trained to maximize muscle hypertrophy? A systematic review and meta-analysis of studies examining the effects of resistance training frequency. J Sports Sci 37: 1286&#x2013;1295, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thalacker-Mercer A, Stec M, Cui X, et al. Cluster analysis reveals differential transcript profiles associated with resistance training-induced human skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Physiol Genomics 45: 499&#x2013;507, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaroni R, Brigatto F, Schoenfeld B, et al. High resistance-training frequency enhances muscle thickness in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 33: S140&#x2013;S151, 2019.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>