<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">32762021</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0838</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scandinavian journal of medicine &amp; science in sports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Scand J Med Sci Sports</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Longitudinal hypertrophic and transcriptional responses to high-load eccentric-concentric vs concentric training in males.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2101</StartPage><EndPage>2115</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2101-2115</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/sms.13791</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>High-load eccentric training reputedly produces greater muscle hypertrophy than concentric training, possibly due to greater loading and/or inflammation. We quantified the temporal impact of combined maximal concentric-eccentric training vs maximal concentric training on muscle cross-sectional area (CSA), volume, and targeted mRNA expression (93 transcripts). Eight recreationally active males (24&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;5&#xa0;years, BMI 23.5&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;2.5&#xa0;kg/m<sup>2</sup> ) performed 3&#xa0;x&#xa0;30 maximal eccentric isokinetic knee extensions and 2&#xa0;x&#xa0;30 maximal concentric knee extensions in dominant limb (ECC&#xa0;+&#xa0;CON) and 5&#xa0;x&#xa0;30 maximal concentric contractions (CON) in the non-dominant limb for 12&#xa0;weeks (all 90&#xb0;/s, 3x/wk). Quadriceps muscle CSA and volume were measured at baseline, 28&#xa0;days (d), and 84&#xa0;d in both limbs (3T MRI). Resting vastus lateralis biopsies were obtained from both limbs at baseline, 24&#xa0;hours (h), 7, 28, and 84&#xa0;d for mRNA abundance measurements (RT-PCR microfluidic cards). Work output was greater throughout training in ECC&#xa0;+&#xa0;CON vs CON (20.8&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;9.7%, P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;.001). Muscle CSA increased from baseline in both limbs at 28&#xa0;d (CON 4.3&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;2.6%, ECC&#xa0;+&#xa0;CON 4.0&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;1.9%, both P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;.001) and 84d (CON 3.9&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;2.3%, ECC&#xa0;+&#xa0;CON 4.0&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;3.1%, both P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;.001), and muscle volume and isometric strength at 84&#xa0;d (CON 44.8&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;40.0%, P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;.001; ECC&#xa0;+&#xa0;CON 36.9&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;40.0%, P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;.01), but no between-limb differences existed in any parameter. Ingenuity Pathway Analysis identified several cellular functions associated with regulation of muscle mass and metabolism as altered by both modalities at 24&#xa0;h and 7&#xa0;d, but particularly with ECC&#xa0;+&#xa0;CON. However, mRNA responses waned thereafter, regardless of modality. Initial muscle mRNA responses to training did not reflect chronic training-induced hypertrophy. Moreover, ECC&#xa0;+&#xa0;CON did not produce greater hypertrophy than CON, despite greater loading throughout and a differential mRNA response during the initial training week.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 The Authors. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science In Sports published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mallinson</LastName><ForeName>Joanne E</ForeName><Initials>JE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1275-2448</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, University of Nottingham, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taylor</LastName><ForeName>Tariq</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, University of Nottingham, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Sport, Exercise and Osteoarthritis Research Versus Arthritis, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Constantin-Teodosiu</LastName><ForeName>Dumitru</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, University of Nottingham, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MRC Versus Arthritis Centre for Musculoskeletal Ageing Research, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Billeter-Clark</LastName><ForeName>Rudolf</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, University of Nottingham, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Constantin</LastName><ForeName>Despina</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, University of Nottingham, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MRC Versus Arthritis Centre for Musculoskeletal Ageing Research, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Franchi</LastName><ForeName>Martino V</ForeName><Initials>MV</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3165-4536</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MRC Versus Arthritis Centre for Musculoskeletal Ageing Research, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, University of Nottingham, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Narici</LastName><ForeName>Marco V</ForeName><Initials>MV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MRC Versus Arthritis Centre for Musculoskeletal Ageing Research, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, University of Nottingham, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Auer</LastName><ForeName>Dorothee</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, University of Nottingham, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NIHR Nottingham Biomedical Research Centre, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Greenhaff</LastName><ForeName>Paul L</ForeName><Initials>PL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, University of Nottingham, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Sport, Exercise and Osteoarthritis Research Versus Arthritis, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MRC Versus Arthritis Centre for Musculoskeletal Ageing Research, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NIHR Nottingham Biomedical Research Centre, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MR/K00414X/1</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>21595</GrantID><Acronym>VAC_</Acronym><Agency>Versus Arthritis</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>BB/I020713/1</GrantID><Acronym>BB_</Acronym><Agency>Biotechnology and Biological Sciences Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>MR/P021220/1</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Denmark</Country><MedlineTA>Scand J Med Sci Sports</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9111504</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0905-7188</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007537" MajorTopicYN="N">Isometric Contraction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007866" MajorTopicYN="N">Leg</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="Y">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014158" MajorTopicYN="Y">Transcription, Genetic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">concentric training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eccentric training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle transcriptional response</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32762021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.13791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Higbie EJ, Cureton KJ, Warren GL 3rd, Prior BM. Effects of concentric and eccentric training on muscle strength, cross-sectional area, and neural activation. J Appl Physiol. 1996;81(5):2173-2181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vikne H, Refsnes PE, Ekmark M, Medbo JI, Gundersen V, Gundersen K. Muscular performance after concentric and eccentric exercise in trained men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38(10):1770-1781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roig M, O'Brien K, Kirk G, et al. The effects of eccentric versus concentric resistance training on muscle strength and mass in healthy adults: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2009;43(8):556-568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi MV, Atherton PJ, Reeves ND, et al. Architectural, functional and molecular responses to concentric and eccentric loading in human skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol (Oxf). 2014;210(3):642-654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulsen G, Mikkelsen UR, Raastad T, Peake JM. Leucocytes, cytokines and satellite cells: what role do they play in muscle damage and regeneration following eccentric exercise? Exerc Immunol Rev. 2012;18:42-97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHugh MP. Recent advances in the understanding of the repeated bout effect: the protective effect against muscle damage from a single bout of eccentric exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2003;13(2):88-97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hather BM, Tesch PA, Buchanan P, Dudley GA. Influence of eccentric actions on skeletal muscle adaptations to resistance training. Acta Physiol Scand. 1991;143(2):177-185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudley GA, Tesch PA, Miller BJ, Buchanan P. Importance of eccentric actions in performance adaptations to resistance training. Aviat Space Environ Med. 1991;62(6):543-550.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Phillips SM, Babraj JA, Smith K, Rennie MJ. Myofibrillar and collagen protein synthesis in human skeletal muscle in young men after maximal shortening and lengthening contractions. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2005;288(6):E1153-E1159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YW, Hubal MJ, Hoffman EP, Thompson PD, Clarkson PM. Molecular responses of human muscle to eccentric exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2003;95(6):2485-2494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubal MJ, Chen TC, Thompson PD, Clarkson PM. Inflammatory gene changes associated with the repeated-bout effect. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2008;294(5):R1628-R1637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikkelsen UR, Langberg H, Helmark IC, et al. Local NSAID infusion inhibits satellite cell proliferation in human skeletal muscle after eccentric exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2009;107(5):1600-1611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armand AS, Launay T, Gaspera BD, Charbonnier F, Gallien CL, Chanoine C. Effects of eccentric treadmill running on mouse soleus: degeneration/regeneration studied with Myf-5 and MyoD probes. Acta Physiol Scand. 2003;179(1):75-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serrano AL, Baeza-Raja B, Perdiguero E, Jardi M, Munoz-Canoves P. Interleukin-6 is an essential regulator of satellite cell-mediated skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Cell Metab. 2008;7(1):33-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay BR, De Lisio M, Johnston AP, et al. Association of interleukin-6 signalling with the muscle stem cell response following muscle-lengthening contractions in humans. PLoS One. 2009;4(6):e6027.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krentz JR, Quest B, Farthing JP, Quest DW, Chilibeck PD. The effects of ibuprofen on muscle hypertrophy, strength, and soreness during resistance training. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2008;33(3):470-475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trappe TA, Carroll CC, Dickinson JM, et al. Influence of acetaminophen and ibuprofen on skeletal muscle adaptations to resistance exercise in older adults. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2011;300(3):R655-R662.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazevich AJ, Cannavan D, Coleman DR, Horne S. Influence of concentric and eccentric resistance training on architectural adaptation in human quadriceps muscles. J Appl Physiol. 2007;103(5):1565-1575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones SW, Hill RJ, Krasney PA, O'Conner B, Peirce N, Greenhaff PL. Disuse atrophy and exercise rehabilitation in humans profoundly affects the expression of genes associated with the regulation of skeletal muscle mass. FASEB J. 2004;18(9):1025-1027.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch PA, Dudley GA, Duvoisin MR, Hather BM, Harris RT. Force and EMG signal patterns during repeated bouts of concentric or eccentric muscle actions. Acta Physiol Scand. 1990;138(3):263-271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Young M, Phillips SM. Similar increases in muscle size and strength in young men after training with maximal shortening or lengthening contractions when matched for total work. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(4):1587-1592.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DW, Burd NA, Tang JE, et al. Elevations in ostensibly anabolic hormones with resistance exercise enhance neither training-induced muscle hypertrophy nor strength of the elbow flexors. J Appl Physiol. 2010;108(1):60-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kostek MC, Chen YW, Cuthbertson DJ, et al. Gene expression responses over 24 h to lengthening and shortening contractions in human muscle: major changes in CSRP3, MUSTN1, SIX1, and FBXO32. Physiol Genomics. 2007;31(1):42-52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Selby A, Rankin D, et al. Age-related differences in the dose-response relationship of muscle protein synthesis to resistance exercise in young and old men. J Physiol. 2009;587(1):211-217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergstrom J. Percutaneous needle biopsy of skeletal muscle in physiological and clinical research. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 1975;35(7):609-616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murton AJ, Billeter R, Stephens FB, et al. Transient transcriptional events in human skeletal muscle at the outset of concentric resistance exercise training. J Appl Physiol. 2014;116(1):113-125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Constantin D, Constantin-Teodosiu D, Layfield R, Tsintzas K, Bennett AJ, Greenhaff PL. PPARdelta agonism induces a change in fuel metabolism and activation of an atrophy programme, but does not impair mitochondrial function in rat skeletal muscle. J Physiol. 2007;583(Pt 1):381-390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crossland H, Constantin-Teodosiu D, Gardiner SM, Constantin D, Greenhaff PL. A potential role for Akt/FOXO signalling in both protein loss and the impairment of muscle carbohydrate oxidation during sepsis in rodent skeletal muscle. J Physiol. 2008;586(22):5589-5600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallinson JE, Constantin-Teodosiu D, Sidaway J, Westwood FR, Greenhaff PL. Blunted Akt/FOXO signalling and activation of genes controlling atrophy and fuel use in statin myopathy. J Physiol. 2009;587(1):219-230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortobagyi T, Barrier J, Beard D, et al. Greater initial adaptations to submaximal muscle lengthening than maximal shortening. J Appl Physiol. 1996;81(4):1677-1682.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchi MV, Ruoss S, Valdivieso P, et al. Regional regulation of focal adhesion kinase after concentric and eccentric loading is related to remodelling of human skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol. 2018;223(3):e13056.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadore EL, Gonzalez-Izal M, Pallares JG, et al. Muscle conduction velocity, strength, neural activity, and morphological changes after eccentric and concentric training. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2014;24(5):e343-e352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deane CS, Ames RM, Phillips BE, et al. The acute transcriptional response to resistance exercise: impact of age and contraction mode. Aging. 2019;11(7):2111-2126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaap LA, Pluijm SM, Deeg DJ, et al. Higher inflammatory marker levels in older persons: associations with 5-year change in muscle mass and muscle strength. J Gerontol Ser A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2009;64(11):1183-1189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeFreitas JM, Beck TW, Stock MS, Dillon MA, Kasishke PR 2nd. An examination of the time course of training-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111(11):2785-2790.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brook MS, Wilkinson DJ, Mitchell WK, et al. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy adaptations predominate in the early stages of resistance exercise training, matching deuterium oxide-derived measures of muscle protein synthesis and mechanistic target of rapamycin complex 1 signaling. FASEB J. 2015;29(11):4485-4496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Parise G, Roy BD, Tipton KD, Wolfe RR, Tamopolsky MA. Resistance-training-induced adaptations in skeletal muscle protein turnover in the fed state. Can J Physiol Pharmacol. 2002;80(11):1045-1053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herzog W. The relation between the resultant moments at a joint and the moment measured by an isokinetic dynamometer. J Biomech. 1988;21(1):5-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoppeler H. Eccentric exercise: physiology and application in sport and rehabilitation. In: Science RRiSaE. Oxon, UK: Routledge Taylor and Francis Group; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egan B, Zierath JR. Exercise metabolism and the molecular regulation of skeletal muscle adaptation. Cell Metab. 2013;17(2):162-184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortobagyi T, Lambert NJ, Hill JP. Greater cross education following training with muscle lengthening than shortening. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1997;29(1):107-112.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>