<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32500573</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-0029</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>83</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Microscopy research and technique</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Microsc Res Tech</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Repercussions on sarcomeres of the myotendinous junction and the myofibrillar type adaptations in response to different trainings on vertical ladder.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1190</StartPage><EndPage>1197</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1190-1197</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jemt.23510</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The myofibrillary types establish to the skeletal muscle functional and adaptive properties that influence the sarcomeric arrangement during muscle contraction and may have repercussions on an important related force transmission region of the locomotor apparatus, the myotendinous junction (MTJ). This study aimed to describe changes in myofibrillary type and sarcomeric lengths in the belly muscle and MTJ of the soleus and plantaris muscles associated with training protocols in vertical ladder. Thirty adults male Wistar rats were divided into three groups (n =&#x2009;10): Control (CTR), No-load Training (NLT), and Load Training (LT). Morphoquantitative analysis of different fibers types and sarcomere lengths were performed in distinct regions of plantaris and soleus muscles. In the plantaris muscle with both trainings, there was an increase in the cross-sectional area (CSA) in Type I and II fibers (p &lt;&#x2009;.0001) while sarcomeric lengths revealed greater lengths in the proximal and distal sarcomeres of NLT, although in the LT we found greater lengths in the belly and MTJ sarcomeres. The soleus muscle showed an increase in CSA muscle fiber only in the NLT (p &lt;&#x2009;.0001) and revealed alterations in belly and MTJ sarcomere lengths with training. We concluded that plantaris muscle has an adaptive effect directly associated with training load, with hypertrophy in both trainings and sarcomere length inverse from belly and MTJ, in LT associated with increased force generation and transmission at the MTJ, although soleus muscle has a lower adaptive response to training stimuli with variation in the belly and distal sarcomere of the MTJ.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rocha</LastName><ForeName>Lara Caetano</ForeName><Initials>LC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2346-4807</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Morphology and Physical Activity (LAMAF), Institute of Biosciences, S&#xe3;o Paulo State University (UNESP), Rio Claro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pimentel Neto</LastName><ForeName>Jurandyr</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Morphology and Physical Activity (LAMAF), Institute of Biosciences, S&#xe3;o Paulo State University (UNESP), Rio Claro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Sant'Ana</LastName><ForeName>Jossei Soares</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Morphology and Physical Activity (LAMAF), Institute of Biosciences, S&#xe3;o Paulo State University (UNESP), Rio Claro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jacob</LastName><ForeName>Carolina Dos Santos</ForeName><Initials>CDS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Morphology and Physical Activity (LAMAF), Institute of Biosciences, S&#xe3;o Paulo State University (UNESP), Rio Claro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barbosa</LastName><ForeName>Gabriela Klein</ForeName><Initials>GK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Morphology and Physical Activity (LAMAF), Institute of Biosciences, S&#xe3;o Paulo State University (UNESP), Rio Claro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krause Neto</LastName><ForeName>Walter</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Laboratory of Morphoquantitative Studies and Immunohistochemistry, S&#xe3;o Judas Tadeu University, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Watanabe</LastName><ForeName>Ii-Sei</ForeName><Initials>IS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anatomy, Institute of Biomedical Sciences-III, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo (USP), S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ciena</LastName><ForeName>Adriano Polican</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2912-3376</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Morphology and Physical Activity (LAMAF), Institute of Biosciences, S&#xe3;o Paulo State University (UNESP), Rio Claro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>7/12525-1, 18/09199-8, 17/21977-3</GrantID><Agency>S&#xe3;o Paulo Research Foundation (FAPESP)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Microsc Res Tech</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9203012</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1059-910X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018485" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Fibers, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017208" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats, Wistar</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012518" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sarcomeres</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013710" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tendons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">distal sarcomere</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fiber type</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myotendinous interface</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32500573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jemt.23510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Adams, G. R., &amp; Bamman, M. M. (2012). Characterization and regulation of mechanical loading-induced compensatory muscle hypertrophy. Comprehensive Physiology, 2, 2829-2870.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodine, S. C., Stitt, T. N., Gonzalez, M., Kline, W. O., Stover, G. L., Bauerlein, R., &#x2026; Glass, D. J. (2001). Akt/mTOR pathway is a crucial regulator of skeletal muscle hypertrophy and can prevent muscle atrophy. Nature Cell Biology, 3, 1014-1019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooke, M. H., &amp; Kaiser, K. K. (1974). The use and abuse of muscle histochemistry. Histochemistry, 228, 121-144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos, G. E. R., Luecke, T. J., Wendeln, H. K., Toma, K., Hagerman, F. C., Murray, T. F., &#x2026; Staron, R. S. (2002). Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: Specificity of repetition maximum training zones. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 88, 50-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassilhas, R., Reis, I., Ven&#xe2;ncio, D., Fernandes, J., Tufik, S., &amp; Mello, M. (2013). Animal model for progressive resistance exercise: A detailed description of model and its implications for basic research in exercise. Motriz, 19, 178-184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciena, A. P., De Almeida, S. R. Y., Bolina, C. S., Bolina-Matos, R. S., Rici, R. E. G., Silva, M. C. P., &#x2026; Watanabe, I. S. (2012). Ultrastructural features of the myotendinous junction of the sternomastoid muscle in Wistar rats: From newborn to aging. Microscopy Research and Technique, 75, 1292-1296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciena, A. P., Luques, I. U., Dias, F. J., Almeida, S. R. Y., Iyomasa, M. M., &amp; Watanabe, I. (2010). Ultrastructure of the myotendinous junction of the medial pterygoid muscle of adult and aged Wistar rats. Micron, 41, 1011-1014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornachione, A., Ca&#xe7;&#xe3;o-Benedini, L. O., Shimano, M. M., Volpon, J. B., Martinez, E. Z., &amp; Mattiello-Sverzut, A. C. (2008). Morphological comparison of different protocols of skeletal muscle remobilization in rats after hindlimb suspension. Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports, 18, 453-461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curzi, D., Salucci, S., Marini, M., Esposito, F., Agnello, L., Veicsteinas, A., &#x2026; Falcieri, E. (2012). How physical exercise changes rat myotendinous junctions: An ultrastructural study. European Journal of Histochemistry, 56, 117-122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curzi, D., Sartini, S., Guescini, M., Lattanzi, D., Di Palma, M., Ambrogini, P., &#x2026; Falcieri, E. (2016). Effect of different exercise intensities on the myotendinous junction plasticity. PLoS One, 11, 1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dayanidhi, S., &amp; Lieber, R. L. (2018). Muscle biology of contractures in children with cerebral palsy. In Cerebral palsy: A multidisciplinary approach 3rd ed., (pp. 143-153). Cham, Switzerland: Springer International Publishing.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ertbjerg, P., &amp; Puolanne, E. (2017). Muscle structure, sarcomere length and influences on meat quality: A review. Meat Science, 132, 139-152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawley, J. A., Hargreaves, M., Joyner, M. J., &amp; Zierath, J. R. (2014). Integrative biology of exercise. Cell, 159, 738-749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herzog, W. (2019). Passive force enhancement in striated muscle. Journal of Applied Physiology, 126, 1782-1789.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishihara, A., Roy, R. R., Ohira, Y., Ibata, Y., Edgerton, V. R., Roy, R. R., &#x2026; Edgerton, V. R. (2019). Special communication hypertrophy of rat plantaris muscle fibers after voluntary running with increasing loads. American Physiology Society, 84, 2183-2189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob, C. S., Rocha, L. C., Neto, J. P., Watanabe, I., &amp; Ciena, A. P. (2019). Effects of physical training on sarcomere lengths and muscle-tendon interface of the cervical region in an experimental model of menopause. European Journal of Histochemistry, 63, 131-135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinney, M. C., Dayanidhi, S., Dykstra, P. B., McCarthy, J. J., Peterson, C. A., &amp; Lieber, R. L. (2017). Reduced skeletal muscle satellite cell number alters muscle morphology after chronic stretch but allows limited serial sarcomere addition. Muscle and Nerve, 55, 384-392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kojima, H., Sakuma, E., Mabuchi, Y., Mizutani, J., Horiuchi, O., Wada, I., &#x2026; Otsuka, T. (2008). Ultrastructural changes at the myotendinous junction induced by exercise. Journal of Orthopaedic Science, 13, 233-239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krause Neto, W., Silva, W. A., Ciena, A. P., Anaruma, C. A., &amp; Gama, E. F. (2016). Vertical climbing for rodent resistance training: A Discussion about training parameters. International Journal of Sports Science, 6, 36-49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krause Neto, W., Silva, W. A., Ciena, A. P., Bocalini, D., Nucci, R. A. B., Anaruma, C. A., &amp; Gama, E. F. (2018). Total training load may explain similar strength gains and muscle hypertrophy seen in aged rats submitted to resistance training and anabolic steroids. The Aging Male, 21, 65-76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krause Neto, W., Silva, W. A., Ciena, A. P., Nucci, R. A. B., Anaruma, C. A., &amp; Gama, E. F. (2017). Effects of strength training and anabolic steroid in the peripheral nerve and skeletal muscle morphology of aged rats. Frontiers in Aging Neuroscience, 9, 1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeBlanc, P. J., Howarth, K. R., Gibala, M. J., &amp; Heigenhauser, G. J. F. (2004). Effects of 7 wk of endurance training on human skeletal muscle metabolism during submaximal exercise. Journal of Applied Physiology, 97, 2148-2153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacIntosh, B. R. (2017). Recent developments in understanding the length dependence of contractile response of skeletal muscle. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 117, 1059-1071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobley, C. B., Mumford, P. W., Kephart, W. C., Haun, C. T., Holland, A. M., Beck, D. T., &#x2026; Roberts, M. D. (2017). Aging in rats differentially affects markers of transcriptional and translational capacity in soleus and plantaris muscle. Frontiers in Physiology, 8, 1-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moo, E. K., Fortuna, R., Sibole, S. C., Abusara, Z., &amp; Herzog, W. (2016). In vivo sarcomere lengths and sarcomere elongations are not uniform across an intact muscle. Frontiers in Physiology, 7, 1-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moo, E. K., &amp; Herzog, W. (2018). Single sarcomere contraction dynamics in a whole muscle. Scientific Reports, 8, 1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen, L. A., Nicoll, J. X., &amp; Fry, A. C. (2019). The skeletal muscle fiber: A mechanically sensitive cell. European Journal of Applied Physiology, 119, 333-349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philp, A., Hamilton, D. L., &amp; Baar, K. (2011). Signals mediating skeletal muscle remodeling by resistance exercise: PI3-kinase independent activation of mTORC1. Journal of Applied Physiology, 110, 561-568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qaisar, R., Bhaskaran, S., &amp; Van Remmen, H. (2016). Muscle fiber type diversification during exercise and regeneration. Free Radical Biology &amp; Medicine, 98, 56-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rassier, D. E. (2017). Sarcomere mechanics in striated muscles: From molecules to sarcomeres to cells. American Journal of Physiology-Cell Physiology, 313, C134-C145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott, W., Stevens, J., &amp; Binder-Macleod, S. A. (2001). Human skeletal muscle fiber type classifications. Physical Therapy, 81, 1810-1816.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sierra, L. R., F&#xe1;varo, G., Cerri, B. R., Rocha, L. C., Almeida, S. R. Y., Watanabe, I., &amp; Ciena, A. P. (2018). Myotendinous junction plasticity in aged ovariectomized rats submitted to aquatic training. Microscopy Research and Technique, 81, 816-822.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiering, B. A., Kraemer, W. J., Anderson, J. M., Armstrong, L. E., Nindl, B. C., Volek, J. S., &amp; Maresh, C. M. (2008). Manipulation of resistance exercise Programme variables determines the responses of cellular and molecular Signalling pathways. Sports Medicine, 38, 527-540.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tidball, J. G. (1991). Force transmission across muscle cell membranes. Journal of Biomechanics, 24, 43-52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams, P. E., &amp; Goldspink, G. (1971). Longitudinal growth of striated muscle Fibres. Journal of Cell Science, 9, 751-767.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>