<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39501490</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>57</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Training Effects of Traditional versus Cluster Set Configuration with and without Blood Flow Restriction.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>668</StartPage><EndPage>679</EndPage><MedlinePgn>668-679</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003600</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study compared the effects of four different resistance training (RT) programs that differed in the set configuration (cluster vs traditional) and the blood flow condition (free-flow [FF] vs blood flow restriction [BFR]) on strength, neuromuscular and hypertrophic adaptations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Forty-two resistance-trained males were randomly assigned into four protocols that differed in the set configuration (TRA: without rest between repetitions versus CLU: 30 s rest every two repetitions) and in the blood flow condition (FF vs BFR [50% of arterial occlusion pressure]). Subjects followed an 8-week RT program, twice per week, with similar intensity (55%-65% 1RM), sets (3), repetitions per set (10-6), and resting time (2 min) in the full-squat (SQ) exercise. Before and after the RT program, they were evaluated for: 1) muscle size of the vastus lateralis ; 2) vertical jump; 3) maximal isometric contraction; 4) progressive loading test; and 5) fatigue test.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">BFR-TRA and FF-CLU induced greater increases in 1RM, and velocity against submaximal loads than FF-TRA and BFR-CLU (BFR-time and CLU-time interactions, P = 0.02). The TRA protocols showed greater increases in maximal isometric force than CLU (CLU-time interaction, P = 0.03). BFR did not enhance jump performance unlike the FF protocols ( P &lt; 0.01). The TRA protocols induced greater hypertrophy in the distal region of the vastus lateralis than CLU protocols (CLU-time interaction, P = 0.04), with BFR-TRA producing the greatest gains in all vastus lateralis sections.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The different combinations of set configurations and blood flow conditions resulted in highly specific adaptations that illustrate the potential of adaptation for each protocol. The divergent underlying mechanisms of CLU and BFR methodologies may offset each other when combined.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cornejo-Daza</LastName><ForeName>Pedro Jes&#xfa;s</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2737-5270</Identifier></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>S&#xe1;nchez-Valdepe&#xf1;as</LastName><ForeName>Juan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rodiles-Guerrero</LastName><ForeName>Luis</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boullosa</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Le&#xf3;n-Prados</LastName><ForeName>Juan A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Sport Sciences. Department of Sports and Computers Sciences. Universidad Pablo de Olavide, Seville, SPAIN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wernbom</LastName><ForeName>Mathias</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Rehabilitation, Institute of Neuroscience and Physiology, Sahlgrenska Academy, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, SWEDEN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pareja-Blanco</LastName><ForeName>Fernando</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012039" MajorTopicYN="N">Regional Blood Flow</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000098" MajorTopicYN="N">blood supply</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007537" MajorTopicYN="N">Isometric Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018763" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000098" MajorTopicYN="N">blood supply</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39501490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202504000-00002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sieljacks P, Knudsen L, Wernbom M, Vissing K. Body position influences arterial occlusion pressure: implications for the standardization of pressure during blood flow restricted exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2018;118(2):303&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen JL, Frandsen U, Prokhorova T, et al. Delayed effect of blood flow-restricted resistance training on rapid force capacity. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2017;49(6):1157&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Apro W, Paulsen G, Nilsen TS, Blomstrand E, Raastad T. Acute low-load resistance exercise with and without blood flow restriction increased protein signalling and number of satellite cells in human skeletal muscle. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2013;113(12):2953&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes L, Paton B, Haddad F, Rosenblatt B, Gissane C, Patterson SD. Comparison of the acute perceptual and blood pressure response to heavy load and light load blood flow restriction resistance exercise in anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction patients and non-injured populations. Phys Ther Sport . 2018;33:54&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takada S, Okita K, Suga T, et al. Low-intensity exercise can increase muscle mass and strength proportionally to enhanced metabolic stress under ischemic conditions. J Appl Physiol ( 1985 ) . 2012;113(2):199&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Counts BR, Dankel SJ, Barnett BE, et al. Influence of relative blood flow restriction pressure on muscle activation and muscle adaptation. Muscle Nerve . 2016;53(3):438&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandrao ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Laurentino G, et al. Effects of exercise intensity and occlusion pressure after 12 weeks of resistance training with blood-flow restriction. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2015;115(12):2471&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornsen T, Wernbom M, Kirketeig A, et al. Type 1 muscle fiber hypertrophy after blood flow-restricted training in powerlifters. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2019;51(2):288&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Sato Y, Ishii N. Effects of resistance exercise combined with vascular occlusion on muscle function in athletes. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2002;86(4):308&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lixandrao ME, Ugrinowitsch C, Berton R, et al. Magnitude of muscle strength and mass adaptations between high-load resistance training versus low-load resistance training associated with blood-flow restriction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med . 2018;48(2):361&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Tsuruta T, Ishii N. Cooperative effects of exercise and occlusive stimuli on muscular function in low-intensity resistance exercise with moderate vascular occlusion. Jpn J Physiol . 2004;54(6):585&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vechin FC, Libardi CA, Conceicao MS, et al. Comparisons between low-intensity resistance training with blood flow restriction and high-intensity resistance training on quadriceps muscle mass and strength in elderly. J Strength Cond Res . 2015;29(4):1071&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott BR, Loenneke JP, Slattery KM, Dascombe BJ. Blood flow restricted exercise for athletes: a review of available evidence. J Sci Med Sport . 2016;19(5):360&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Fahs CA, Rossow LM, Abe T, Bemben MG. The anabolic benefits of venous blood flow restriction training may be induced by muscle cell swelling. Med Hypotheses . 2012;78(1):151&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Aagaard P. Muscle fibre activation and fatigue with low-load blood flow restricted resistance exercise&#x2013;an integrative physiology review. Acta Physiol (Oxf) . 2020;228(1):e13302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haussinger D. The role of cellular hydration in the regulation of cell function. Biochem J . 1996;313((Pt 3)(Pt 3)):697&#x2013;710.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haff GG, Whitley A, McCoy LB, et al. Effects of different set configurations on barbell velocity and displacement during a clean pull. J Strength Cond Res . 2003;17(1):95&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jukic I, Van Hooren B, Ramos AG, Helms ER, McGuigan MR, Tufano JJ. The effects of set structure manipulation on chronic adaptations to resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med . 2021;51(5):1061&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mora-Custodio R, Rodriguez-Rosell D, Yanez-Garcia JM, Sanchez-Moreno M, Pareja-Blanco F, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ. Effect of different inter-repetition rest intervals across four load intensities on velocity loss and blood lactate concentration during full squat exercise. J Sports Sci . 2018;36(24):2856&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortega-Becerra M, Sanchez-Moreno M, Pareja-Blanco F. Effects of cluster set configuration on mechanical performance and neuromuscular activity. J Strength Cond Res . 2021;35(2):310&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermens HJ, Bruggen TA, Baten CT, Rutten WL, Boom HB. The median frequency of the surface EMG power spectrum in relation to motor unit firing and action potential properties. J Electromyogr Kinesiol . 1992;2(1):15&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigland-Ritchie BR, Dawson NJ, Johansson RS, Lippold OC. Reflex origin for the slowing of motoneurone firing rates in fatigue of human voluntary contractions. J Physiol . 1986;379:451&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brody LR, Pollock MT, Roy SH, De Luca CJ, Celli B. pH-induced effects on median frequency and conduction velocity of the myoelectric signal. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 1991;71(5):1878&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies TB, Tran DL, Hogan CM, Haff GG, Latella C. Chronic effects of altering resistance training set configurations using cluster sets: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med . 2021;51(4):707&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardee JP, Lawrence MM, Zwetsloot KA, Triplett NT, Utter AC, McBride JM. Effect of cluster set configurations on power clean technique. J Sports Sci . 2013;31(5):488&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornejo-Daza PJ, Villalba-Fernandez A, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ, Pareja-Blanco F. Time course of recovery from different velocity loss thresholds and set configurations during full-squat training. J Strength Cond Res . 2024;38(2):221&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pareja-Blanco F, Alcazar J, Sanchez-Valdepenas J, et al. Velocity loss as a critical variable determining the adaptations to strength training. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2020;52(8):1752&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay AKA, Stellingwerff T, Smith ES, et al. Defining training and performance caliber: a participant classification framework. Int J Sports Physiol Perform . 2022;17(2):317&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narici MV, Landoni L, Minetti AE. Assessment of human knee extensor muscles stress from in vivo physiological cross-sectional area and strength measurements. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol . 1992;65(5):438&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogrel JY, Barnouin Y, Azzabou N, et al. NMR imaging estimates of muscle volume and intramuscular fat infiltration in the thigh: variations with muscle, gender, and age. Age (Dordr) . 2015;37(3):9798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornejo-Daza PJ, Sanchez-Valdepenas J, Rodiles-Guerrero L, et al. Vastus lateralis muscle size is differently associated with the different regions of the squat force-velocity and load-velocity relationships, rate of force development, and physical performance young men. J Strength Cond Res . 2024;38(3):450&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claudino JG, Cronin J, Mezencio B, et al. The countermovement jump to monitor neuromuscular status: a meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport . 2017;20(4):397&#x2013;402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermens HJ, Freriks B, Disselhorst-Klug C, Rau G. Development of recommendations for SEMG sensors and sensor placement procedures. J Electromyogr Kinesiol . 2000;10(5):361&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Medina L, Perez CE, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ. Importance of the propulsive phase in strength assessment. Int J Sports Med . 2010;31(2):123&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L. Movement velocity as a measure of loading intensity in resistance training. Int J Sports Med . 2010;31(5):347&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, Pallar&#xe9;s JG, P&#xe9;rez CE, Mor&#xe1;n-Navarro R, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ. Estimation of relative load from bar velocity in the full back squat exercise. Sports Med Int Open . 2017;1(2):E80&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courel-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez J, Mart&#xed;nez-Cava A, Mor&#xe1;n-Navarro R, et al. Reproducibility and repeatability of five different technologies for bar velocity measurement in resistance training. Ann Biomed Eng . 2019;47(7):1523&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson SD, Hughes L, Warmington S, et al. Blood flow restriction exercise: considerations of methodology, application, and safety. Front Physiol . 2019;10:533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges LV, Olkin I. Statistical methods for meta-analysis: San Diego . CA: Academic Press; 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorostiaga EM, Navarro-Amezqueta I, Calbet JAL, et al. Energy metabolism during repeated sets of leg press exercise leading to failure or not. PLoS One . 2012;7(7):e40621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Husmann F, Mittlmeier T, Bruhn S, Zschorlich V, Behrens M. Impact of blood flow restriction exercise on muscle fatigue development and recovery. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2018;50(3):436&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karabulut M, Cramer JT, Abe T, Sato Y, Bemben MG. Neuromuscular fatigue following low-intensity dynamic exercise with externally applied vascular restriction. J Electromyogr Kinesiol . 2010;20(3):440&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Paulsen G, Nilsen TS, Hisdal J, Raastad T. Contractile function and sarcolemmal permeability after acute low-load resistance exercise with blood flow restriction. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2012;112(6):2051&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morales-Artacho AJ, Padial P, Garcia-Ramos A, Perez-Castilla A, Feriche B. Influence of a cluster set configuration on the adaptations to short-term power training. J Strength Cond Res . 2018;32(4):930&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo K, Komuro T, Ishiguro N, et al. Effects of low-load resistance training with vascular occlusion on the mechanical properties of muscle and tendon. J Appl Biomech . 2006;22(2):112&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Burgomaster KA, Schofield LM, Gibala MJ, Sale DG, Phillips SM. Neuromuscular adaptations in human muscle following low intensity resistance training with vascular occlusion. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2004;92(4&#x2013;5):399&#x2013;406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madarame H, Ochi E, Tomioka Y, Nakazato K, Ishii N. Blood flow-restricted training does not improve jump performance in untrained young men. Acta Physiol Hung . 2011;98(4):465&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Augustsson J, Thomee R. The influence of frequency, intensity, volume and mode of strength training on whole muscle cross-sectional area in humans. Sports Med . 2007;37(3):225&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>