<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40845268</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Similar Neuromuscular and Morphological Adaptations Following Short-Term Blood Flow Restriction and Traditional Resistance Training in Young Men.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005231</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pennartz</LastName><ForeName>Kase J</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, Health Promotions and Recreation, College of Education, University of North Texas, Denton, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Calvin D</ForeName><Initials>CD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science, Falk College of Sport and Human Dynamics, Syracuse University, Syracuse, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Washington</LastName><ForeName>Sierra</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Human Performance, College of Health Sciences, Tarleton State University, Stephenville, Texas; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gebert</LastName><ForeName>Renee</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Human Performance, College of Health Sciences, Tarleton State University, Stephenville, Texas; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wolfe</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Human Performance, College of Health Sciences, Tarleton State University, Stephenville, Texas; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keller</LastName><ForeName>Joshua L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, Health Promotions and Recreation, College of Education, University of North Texas, Denton, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luera</LastName><ForeName>Micheal J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Human Performance, College of Health Sciences, Tarleton State University, Stephenville, Texas; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, College of Science and Mathematics, Tarleton State University, Stephenville, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electrical efficiency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electromyography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">low load</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscular strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skeletal muscle</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40845268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-990000000-00793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Beausejour JP, Knowles KS, Wilson AT, et al. Innovations in the assessment of skeletal muscle health: A glimpse into the future. Int J Sports Med 45: 659&#x2013;671, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bland DC, Prosser LA, Bellini LA, Alter KE, Damiano DL. Tibialis anterior architecture, strength, and gait in individuals with cerebral palsy. Muscle Nerve 44: 509&#x2013;517, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown LE, Whitehurst M, Gilbert R, Buchalter DN. The effect of velocity and gender on load range during knee extension and flexion exercise on an isokinetic device. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther 21: 107&#x2013;112, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burkhardt M, Burkholder E, Goetschius J. Effects of blood flow restriction on muscle activation during dynamic balance exercises in individuals with chronic ankle instability. J Sport Rehabil 30: 870&#x2013;875, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centner C, Lauber B. A systematic review and meta-analysis on neural adaptations following blood flow restriction training: What we know and what we don't know. Front Physiol 11: 887, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y-C, Wu C-C, Lin Y-T, Chen Y, Hwang I-S. Adaptive modification in agonist common drive after combined blood flow restriction and neuromuscular electrical stimulation. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng 33: 372&#x2013;379, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombo V, Valen&#x10d;i&#x10d; T, Steiner K, et al. Comparison of blood flow restriction interventions to standard rehabilitation after an anterior cruciate ligament injury: A systematic review. Am J Sports Med 52: 3641&#x2013;3650, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colomer-Poveda D, Romero-Arenas S, Vera-Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez A, Vi&#xf1;uela-Garc&#xed;a M, M&#xe1;rquez G. Effects of 4 weeks of low-load unilateral resistance training, with and without blood flow restriction, on strength, thickness, V wave, and H reflex of the soleus muscle in men. Eur J Appl Physiol 117: 1339&#x2013;1347, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeVries H. &#x201c;Efficiency of electrical activity&#x201d; as a physiological measure of the functional state of muscle tissue. Am J Phys Med 47: 10&#x2013;22, 1968.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchateau J, Stragier S, Baudry S, Carpentier A. Strength training: In search of optimal strategies to maximize neuromuscular performance. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 49: 2&#x2013;14, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka RM. Mechanisms of muscle fatigue: Central factors and task dependency. J Electromyogr Kinesiol 5: 141&#x2013;149, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina D, Merletti R, Enoka RM. The extraction of neural strategies from the surface EMG: 2004&#x2013;2024. J Appl Physiol 138: 121&#x2013;135, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farup J, De Paoli F, Bjerg K, Riis S, Ringgard S, Vissing K. Blood flow restricted and traditional resistance training performed to fatigue produce equal muscle hypertrophy. Scand J Med Sci Sports 25: 754&#x2013;763, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flewwelling LD, Hannaian SJ, Cao V, et al. What are the potential mechanisms of fatigue-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy with low-load resistance exercise training? Am J Physiol Cell Physiol 328: C1001&#x2013;C1014, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavanda S, Isenmann E, Schl&#xf6;der Y, et al. Low-intensity blood flow restriction calf muscle training leads to similar functional and structural adaptations than conventional low-load strength training: A randomized controlled trial. PLoS One 15: e0235377, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray S, Cuomo A, Proppe C, Traylor MK, Hill EC, Keller JL. Effects of sex and cuff pressure on physiological responses during blood flow restriction resistance exercise in young adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 55: 920&#x2013;931, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill EC, Housh TJ, Keller JL, Smith CM, Schmidt RJ, Johnson GO. Early phase adaptations in muscle strength and hypertrophy as a result of low-intensity blood flow restriction resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol 118: 1831&#x2013;1843, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill EC, Housh TJ, Keller JL, et al. Low-load blood flow restriction elicits greater concentric strength than non-blood flow restriction resistance training but similar isometric strength and muscle size. Eur J Appl Physiol 120: 425&#x2013;441, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill EC, Rivera PM, Proppe CE, Gonzalez Rojas DH, Wizenberg AM, Keller JL. Greater neuromuscular fatigue following low-load blood flow restriction than non-blood flow restriction resistance exercise among recreationally active men. J Neurophysiol 128: 73&#x2013;85, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill EC, Rivera PM, Proppe CE, Gonzalez Rojas DH, Lawson JE. Acute effects of low load blood flow restricted and non restricted exercise on muscle excitation, neuromuscular efficiency, and average torque. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact 23: 165&#x2013;174, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horlings CG, Van Engelen BG, Allum JH, Bloem BR. A weak balance: The contribution of muscle weakness to postural instability and falls. Nat Clin Pract Neurol 4: 504&#x2013;515, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jessee MB, Mattocks KT, Buckner SL, et al. Mechanisms of blood flow restriction: The new testament. Tech Orthop 33: 72&#x2013;79, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xf8;nsson AB, Krogh S, Laursen HS, Aagaard P, Kasch H, Nielsen JF. Safety and efficacy of blood flow restriction exercise in individuals with neurological disorders: A systematic review. Scand J Med Sci Sports 34: e14561, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemoun G, Thoumie P, Boisson D, Guieu JD. Ankle dorsiflexion delay can predict falls in the elderly. J Rehabil Med 34: 278&#x2013;283, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lexell J, Jarvis JC, Currie J, Downham DY, Salmons S. Fibre type composition of rabbit tibialis anterior and extensor digitorum longus muscles. J Anat 185: 95&#x2013;101, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Dankel SJ, Bell ZW, et al. Is muscle growth a mechanism for increasing strength? Med Hypotheses 125: 51&#x2013;56, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Fahs CA, Wilson JM, Bemben MG. Blood flow restriction: The metabolite/volume threshold theory. Med Hypotheses 77: 748&#x2013;752, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Wilson JM, Mar&#xed;n PJ, Zourdos MC, Bemben MG. Low intensity blood flow restriction training: A meta-analysis. Eur J Appl Physiol 112: 1849&#x2013;1859, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maharaj JN, Cresswell AG, Lichtwark GA. Tibialis anterior tendinous tissue plays a key role in energy absorption during human walking. J Exp Biol 222: jeb191247, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattock J, Steele JR, Mickle KJ. Lower leg muscle structure and function are altered in long&#x2010;distance runners with medial tibial stress syndrome: A case control study. J Foot Ankle Res 14: 47, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattocks KT, Jessee MB, Mouser JG, et al. The application of blood flow restriction: Lessons from the laboratory. Curr Sports Med Rep 17: 129&#x2013;134, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller JD, Lippman JD, Trevino MA, Herda TJ. Neural drive is greater for a high-intensity contraction than for moderate-intensity contractions performed to fatigue. J Strength Cond Res 34: 3013&#x2013;3021, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montgomery TR, Olmos A, Sears KN, et al. Influence of blood flow restriction on neuromuscular function and fatigue during forearm flexion in men. J Strength Cond Res 38: e349&#x2013;e358, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T, deVries HA. Neural factors versus hypertrophy in the time course of muscle strength gain. Am J Phys Med 58: 115&#x2013;130, 1979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosavian A, Gaeini A, Hemmatinafar M, Kordi M, Nori R. Effect of low-intensity eccentric resistance training with blood flow restriction on the activation and proliferation indicators of satellite cells. Hormozgan Med J 22: 95&#x2013;102, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xe6;ss-Schmidt ET, Morthorst M, Pedersen AR, Nielsen JF, Stubbs PW. Corticospinal excitability changes following blood flow restriction training of the tibialis anterior: A preliminary study. Heliyon 3: e00217, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen JL, Aagaard P, Bech RD, et al. Proliferation of myogenic stem cells in human skeletal muscle in response to low&#x2010;load resistance training with blood flow restriction. J Physiol 590: 4351&#x2013;4361, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reggiani C, Schiaffino S. Muscle hypertrophy and muscle strength: Dependent or independent variables? A provocative review. Eur J Transl Myol 30: 9311, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinking MF. The effect of concentric and eccentric training on the strengthening of tibialis anterior. IES 1: 193&#x2013;201, 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rojas DHG, Wizenberg AM, Rivera PM, et al. Acute effects of sprint interval training and blood flow restriction on neuromuscular and muscle function. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact 24: 38&#x2013;46, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sacco ICN, Gomes AA, Otuzi ME, Pripas D, Onodera AN. A method for better positioning bipolar electrodes for lower limb EMG recordings during dynamic contractions. J Neurosci Methods 180: 133&#x2013;137, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakuraba K, Ishikawa T. Effect of isokinetic resistance training under a condition of restricted blood flow with pressure. J Orthop Sci 14: 631&#x2013;639, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The mechanisms of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res 24: 2857&#x2013;2872, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Pi&#xf1;ero A, Burke R, Coleman M, Rolnick N. Fiber-type-specific hypertrophy with the use of low-load blood flow restriction resistance training: A systematic review. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 8: 51, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Vigotsky AD, Grgic J, et al. Do the anatomical and physiological properties of a muscle determine its adaptive response to different loading protocols? Physiol Rep 8: e14427, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shields, JoCarol E. and Hernandez-Sarabia, Jesus A. and Lanza, Marcel B. and Barrera-Curiel, Alejandra and Luera, Micheal J. and DeFreitas, Jason, A Comparison of Popular Filters for Surface Electromyography. Available at SSRN: https://ssrn.com/abstract=4719542 or http://dx.doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4719542</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/ssrn.4719542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Sato Y, Ishii N. Effects of resistance exercise combined with vascular occlusion on muscle function in athletes. Eur J Appl Physiol 86: 308&#x2013;314, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taleshi M, Bubeck F, Brunner P, Gizzi L, Vujaklija I. Observing changes in motoneuron characteristics following distorted sensorimotor input via blood flow restriction. J Appl Physiol 138: 559&#x2013;570, 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor JL, Todd G, Gandevia SC. Evidence for a supraspinal contribution to human muscle fatigue. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol 33: 400&#x2013;405, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuominen J, Lepp&#xe4;nen M, Jarske H, Pasanen K, Vasankari T, Parkkari J. Test&#x2212;Retest reliability of isokinetic ankle, knee and hip strength in physically active adults using biodex system 4 pro. Methods Protocols 6: 26, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong V, Spitz RW, Song JS, et al. Blood flow restriction augments the cross-education effect of isometric handgrip training. Eur J Appl Physiol 124: 1575&#x2013;1585, 2024.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>