<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">31318712</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>52</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neuromuscular Function and Blood Flow Occlusion with Dynamic Arm Flexor Contractions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>205</StartPage><EndPage>213</EndPage><MedlinePgn>205-213</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002091</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Blood flow-restricted or occlusion exercise enhances muscle hypertrophy and strength during resistance training. The acute effects on voluntary and electrically evoked muscle contractile characteristics with impaired blood flow at low- and high-contraction forces have not been explored.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">On separate days, nine males completed two different protocols of concentric elbow flexor contractions. A repetitive low-force (~25% of isometric maximum voluntary contraction [MVC]) with blood flow occlusion (BFO) (300 mm Hg) protocol was compared with a high-force (~80% MVC) free blood flow protocol (HF), until range of motion (0&#xb0;-90&#xb0;) was impaired. Torque, velocity, and power were compared with baseline and between protocols. Maximum voluntary contraction and voluntary activation were assessed during and after each protocol. Muscle twitch, low (20 Hz) and high (50 Hz) tetanus, and compound muscle action potential (Mmax) area were measured at 0, 2, 5, 10, and 20 min of recovery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Repetitions to failure (FP) were lower for HF (~16) versus BFO (~21), and MVC at FP was reduced more during BFO (~77%) compared with HF (~23%), with no difference in voluntary activation (~10% loss) between protocols. At FP, velocities for BFO and HF were similarly reduced by approximately 63% and 56%, respectively; however, peak power decreased more during BFO (~90%) compared with HF (~67%). Total work for BFO was approximately 40% lower than for HF. Peak power for HF was recovered by 2 min, whereas BFO required 20 min. Low-frequency fatigue (20 Hz/50 Hz) was greater after BFO (~70% decrease vs ~29% decrease after HF), whereas Mmax area was unaffected.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Concentric elbow flexions at low-force with BFO cause greater impairments in strength and power than HF and, therefore, may be a replacement for high-force exercise used in chronic training.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Copithorne</LastName><ForeName>David B</ForeName><Initials>DB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Canadian Centre for Activity and Aging, School of Kinesiology, Faculty of Health Sciences, The University of Western Ontario, London, ON, CANADA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rice</LastName><ForeName>Charles L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001132" MajorTopicYN="N">Arm</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004558" MajorTopicYN="N">Electric Stimulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007537" MajorTopicYN="N">Isometric Contraction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="N">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000098" MajorTopicYN="Y">blood supply</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012039" MajorTopicYN="N">Regional Blood Flow</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31318712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202001000-00023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Alvar BA, Evetoch TK. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. American College of Sports Medicine. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manimmanakorn A, Manimmanakorn N, Taylor R, et al. Effects of resistance training combined with vascular occlusion or hypoxia on neuromuscular function in athletes. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013a;113(7):1767&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manimmanakorn A, Hamlin MJ, Ross JJ, Taylor R, Manimmanakorn N. Effects of low-load resistance training combined with blood flow restriction or hypoxia on muscle function and performance in netball athletes. J Sci Med Sport. 2013b;16(4):337&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Burgomaster KA, Schofield LM, Gibala MJ, Sale DG, Phillips SM. Neuromuscular adaptations in human muscle following low intensity resistance training with vascular occlusion. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2004;92(4&#x2013;5):399&#x2013;406.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Medina L, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ. Velocity loss as an indicator of neuromuscular fatigue during resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(9):1725&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ. Potential mechanisms for a role of metabolic stress in hypertrophic adaptations to resistance training. Sports Med. 2013;43(3):179&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greising SM, Gransee HM, Mantilla CB, Sieck GC. Systems biology of skeletal muscle: fiber type as an organizing principle. Wiley Interdiscip Rev Syst Biol Med. 2012;4(5):457&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrissey MC, Harman EA, Frykman PN, Han KH. Early phase differential effects of slow and fast barbell squat training. Am J Sports Med. 1998;26(2):221&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaChance PF, Hortobagyi T. Influence of cadence on muscular performance during push-up and pull-up exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 1994;8(2):76&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alway SE, Sale DG, MacDougall JD. Twitch contractile adaptations are not dependent on the intensity of isometric exercise in the human triceps surae. Eur J Appl Physiol. 1990;60(5):346&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards RH, Hill DK, Jones DA, Merton PA. Fatigue of long duration in human skeletal muscle after exercise. J Physiol. 1977;272(3):769&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones DA. High-and low-frequency fatigue revisited. Acta Physiol Scand. 1996;156(3):265&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones DA. Change in excitation threshold as a cause of muscular fatigue [proceedings]. J Physiol. 1979;295:90P&#x2013;1P.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones DA, Bigland-Ritchie B. Electrical and contractile changes in muscle fatigue. Int Ser Sport Sci. 1986;16:377&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Copithorne DB, Rice CL. The effect of blood flow occlusion during acute low-intensity isometric elbow flexion exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2019;119(3):587&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandevia SC. Spinal and supraspinal factors in human muscle fatigue. Physiol Rev. 2001;81(4):1725&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karabulut M, Cramer JT, Abe T, Sato Y, Bemben MG. Neuromuscular fatigue following low-intensity dynamic exercise with externally applied vascular restriction. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2010;20(3):440&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda T, Brechue WF, Fujita T, Shirakawa J, Sato Y, Abe T. Muscle activation during low-intensity muscle contractions with restricted blood flow. J Sports Sci. 2009;27(5):479&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takarada Y, Takazawa H, Sato Y, Takebayashi S, Tanaka Y, Ishii N. Effects of resistance exercise combined with moderate vascular occlusion on muscular function in humans. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88(6):2097&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karabulut M, Abe T, Sato Y, Bemben M. 2007. Overview of neuromuscular adaptations of skeletal muscle to KAATSU Training. Int J Kaatsu Train Res. 2007;3(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigland-Ritchie B, Furbush F, Woods JJ. Fatigue of intermittent submaximal voluntary contractions: central and peripheral factors. J Appl Physiol. 1986a;61(2):421&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linari M, Bottinelli R, Pellegrino MA, Reconditi M, Reggiani C, Lombardi V. The mechanism of the force response to stretch in human skinned muscle fibres with different myosin isoforms. J Physiol. 2004;554(2):335&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiaffino S, Reggiani C. Fiber types in mammalian skeletal muscles. Physiol Rev. 2011;91(4):1447&#x2013;531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhaff PL, S&#xf6;derlund K, Ren JM, Hultman E. Energy metabolism in single human muscle fibres during intermittent contraction with occluded circulation. J Physiol. 1993;460(1):443&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krustrup P, S&#xf6;derlund K, Relu MU, Ferguson RA, Bangsbo J. Heterogeneous recruitment of quadriceps muscle portions and fibre types during moderate intensity knee-extensor exercise: effect of thigh occlusion. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2009;19(4):576&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigland-Ritchie BR, Dawson NJ, Johansson RS, Lippold OC. Reflex origin for the slowing of motoneurone firing rates in fatigue of human voluntary contractions. J Physiol. 1986b;379(1):451&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;n-Hern&#xe1;ndez J, Ruiz-Aguado J, Herrero AJ, et al. Adaptation of perceptual responses to low-load blood flow restriction training. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(3):765&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kernell D, Monster AW. Motoneurone properties and motor fatigue. Exp Brain Res. 1982;46(2):197&#x2013;204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macefield G, Hagbarth KE, Gorman R, Gandevia SC, Burke D. Decline in spindle support to alpha-motoneurones during sustained voluntary contractions. J Physiol. 1991;440(1):497&#x2013;512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zytnicki D, Lafleur J, Horcholle-Bossavit G, Lamy F, Jami L. Reduction of Ib autogenetic inhibition in motoneurons during contractions of an ankle extensor muscle in the cat. J Neurophysiol. 1990;64(5):1380&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farina D, Merletti R, Enoka RM. The extraction of neural strategies from the surface EMG: an update. J Appl Physiol. 2014;117(11):1215&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones DA, Bigland-Ritchie B, Edwards RH. Excitation frequency and muscle fatigue: mechanical responses during voluntary and stimulated contractions. Exp Neurol. 1979a;64(2):401&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigland-Ritchie B, Jones DA, Woods JJ. Excitation frequency and muscle fatigue: electrical responses during human voluntary and stimulated contractions. Exp Neurol. 1979b;64(2):414&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones DA. Muscle fatigue due to changes beyond the neuromuscular junction. Ciba Found Symp. 1981;82:178&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng AJ, Rice CL. Fatigue and recovery of power and isometric torque following isotonic knee extensions. J Appl Physiol. 2005;99(4):1446&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>