<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39589909</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>39</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cardiorespiratory Responses to Flywheel-Based Inertial Training Squats With Varying Moments of Inertia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>300</StartPage><EndPage>306</EndPage><MedlinePgn>300-306</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005018</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Mitchinson, CJ, Best, S, Caruso, J, and Bollinger, LM. Cardiorespiratory responses to flywheel-based inertial training squats with varying moments of inertia. J Strength Cond Res 39(3): 300-306, 2025-Flywheel-based inertial training (FIT) has gained popularity as a means to enhance muscle hypertrophy. Other applications, such as aerobic exercise training, remain unexplored. The aim of this study was to determine the cardiorespiratory responses to acute FIT with varying moments of inertia (MOIs). Overall, 20 (10 M, 10 F) healthy, physically active subjects underwent maximal graded exercise testing and completed 3 bouts of FIT exercise (1 familiarization session and 2 identical data collection sessions). Subjects completed quarter squats (60&#xb0; peak knee flexion) at a pace of 50 squats&#xb7;minute -1 until volitional fatigue. Flywheel-based inertial training MOI was increased by 0.005 kg&#xb7;m 2 every 3 minutes until a final workload of 0.020 kg&#xb7;m 2 . Heart rate and gas exchange data were collected continuously and averaged over the final 60 s of each stage. Data were analyzed by a linear mixed model. During the final testing session, there was a main effect of MOI to increase heart rate (HR), V&#x307; o2 , and RER. Men displayed greater oxygen consumption, but a&#xa0;similar %V&#x307; o2 peak compared with women. We noted a significant inertia &#xd7; sex interaction where RER tended to be lesser in women at higher MOI. In the final stage of exercise (MOI: 0.020 kg&#xb7;m 2 ), HR and V&#x307; o2 were approximately 75-80 and 55% of peak, respectively, and RER was approximately 0.95-1.00. FIT quarter squats elicit moderate HR and V&#x307; o2 responses, but near-maximal RER suggests a novel metabolic training stimulus. This exercise may supersede the&#xa0;lactate threshold and may not be sustainable for prolonged times. The physiological and performance effects of training in this manner are unclear.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mitchinson</LastName><ForeName>Clara J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Health Promotion, University of Kentucky, Lexington, Kentucky; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Best</LastName><ForeName>Stuart</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Health Promotion, University of Kentucky, Lexington, Kentucky; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caruso</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Sport Sciences, University of Louisville, Louisville, Kentucky.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bollinger</LastName><ForeName>Lance M</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4408-4838</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Health Promotion, University of Kentucky, Lexington, Kentucky; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006339" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Rate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010101" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen Consumption</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000295" MajorTopicYN="N">instrumentation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011659" MajorTopicYN="N">Pulmonary Gas Exchange</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005080" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Test</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39589909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000005018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202503000-00004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Askling C, Karlsson J, Thorstensson A. Hamstring injury occurrence in elite soccer players after preseason strength training with eccentric overload. Scand J Med Sci Sports 13: 244&#x2013;250, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beato M, Maroto-Izquierdo S, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Dav&#xf3; JL, Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J. Flywheel training periodization in team sports. Front Physiol 12: 732802, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beato M, Bigby AEJ, De Keijzer KL, Nakamura FY, Coratella G, McErlain-Naylor SA. Post-activation potentiation effect of eccentric overload and traditional weightlifting exercise on jumping and sprinting performance in male athletes. PLoS One 14: e0222466, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg HE, Tesch A. A gravity-independent ergometer to be used for resistance training in space. Aviat Space Environ Med 65: 752&#x2013;756, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bollinger LM, Brantley JT, Tarlton JK, Baker PA, Seay RF, Abel MG. Construct validity, test-retest reliability, and repeatability of performance variables using a flywheel resistance training device. J Strength Cond Res 34: 3149&#x2013;3156, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bollinger LM, Brantley JT, Carpenter RS, Haydon MA, Best S, Abel MG. Quadriceps electromyography during flywheel-based inertial training (FIT) and dynamic constant external resistance (DCER) squats at similar tempo. Sports Biomech 12: 1&#x2013;12, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bollinger LM, Brantley JT, Carpenter RS, Haydon MA, Best S, Abel MG. Quadriceps electromyography during flywheel-based inertial training (FIT) and dynamic constant external resistance (DCER) squats at similar tempo. Sports Biomech 12: 1&#x2013;12, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cotter JA, Yu A, Haddad F, et al. Concurrent exercise on a gravity-independent device during simulated microgravity. Med Sci Sports Exerc 47: 990&#x2013;1000, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darendeli A, Ertan H, Enoka RM. Comparison of EMG activity in leg muscles between overground and treadmill running. Med Sci Sports Exerc 55: 517&#x2013;524, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Souza Silveira R, Carlsohn A, Langen G, Mayer F, Scharhag-Rosenberger F. Reliability and day-to-day variability of peak fat oxidation during treadmill ergometry. J Int Soc Sports Nutr 13: 4, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garatachea N, Jim&#xe9;nez A, Bresciani G, Mari&#xf1;o NA, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Gallego J, de Paz JA. The effects of movement velocity during squatting on energy expenditure and substrate utilization in whole-body vibration. J Strength Cond Res 21: 594&#x2013;598, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goedecke JH, Claassen A, Noakes TD, Lambert EV. Fasting respiratory exchange ratio is consistent at rest and during steady-state exercise of different intensities. S Afr J Sports Med 8: 8&#x2013;11, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liguori G; American College of Sports Medicine. Health-Related Physical Fitness Testing and Interpretation. ACSM&#x2019;s Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription. Philadelphia, PA: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, 2022. pp. 79&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maroto-Izquierdo S, Garc&#xed;a-L&#xf3;pez D, de Paz JA. Functional and muscle-size effects of flywheel resistance training with eccentric-overload in professional handball players. J Hum Kinet 60: 133&#x2013;143, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maroto-Izquierdo S, Garc&#xed;a-L&#xf3;pez D, Fernandez-Gonzalo R, Moreira OC, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Gallego J, de Paz JA. Skeletal muscle functional and structural adaptations after eccentric overload flywheel resistance training: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport 20: 943&#x2013;951, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mat&#xe9;-Mu&#xf1;oz JL, Dom&#xed;nguez R, Barba M, et al. Cardiorespiratory and metabolic responses to loaded half squat exercise executed at an intensity corresponding to the lactate threshold. J Sports Sci Med 14: 648&#x2013;656, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuine TA, Greene JJ, Best T, Leverson G. Balance as a predictor of ankle injuries in high school basketball players. Clin J Sport Med 10: 239&#x2013;244, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monajati A, Larumbe-Zabala E, Goss-Sampson M, Naclerio F. Injury prevention programs based on flywheel vs. Body weight resistance in recreational athletes. J Strength Cond Res 35: S188&#x2013;S196, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norrbrand L. Acute and early chronic responses to resistance exercise using flywheel or weights. Karolinska Institutet Swed 17: 22&#x2013;38, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norrbrand L, Pozzo M, Tesch PA. Flywheel resistance training calls for greater eccentric muscle activation than weight training. Eur J Appl Physiol 110: 997&#x2013;1005, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owerkowicz T, Cotter JA, Haddad F, et al. Exercise responses to gravity-independent flywheel aerobic and resistance training. Aerosp Med Hum Perform 87: 93&#x2013;101, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Marcolin G, Zonin F, Neri M, Sivieri A, Pacelli QF. Exercising fasting or fed to enhance fat loss? Influence of food intake on respiratory ratio and excess postexercise oxygen consumption after a bout of endurance training. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metabol 21: 48&#x2013;54, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Castillo D, Beato M. The flywheel paradigm in team sports: A soccer approach. Strength Condit J 43: 12&#x2013;22, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabido R, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Dav&#xf3; JL, Pereyra-Gerber GT. Influence of different inertial loads on basic training variables during the flywheel squat exercise. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 13: 482&#x2013;489, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesch PA, Pozzo M, Ainegren M, Swar&#xe9;n M, Linnehan RM. Cardiovascular responses to rowing on a novel ergometer designed for both resistance and aerobic training in space. Aviat Space Environ Med 84: 516&#x2013;521, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomlin DL, Wenger HA. The relationship between aerobic fitness and recovery from high intensity intermittent exercise. Sports Med 31: 1&#x2013;11, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tous-Fajardo J, Gonzalo-Skok O, Arjol-Serrano JL, Tesch P. Enhancing change-of-direction speed in soccer players by functional inertial eccentric overload and vibration training. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 11: 66&#x2013;73, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vicens-Bordas J, Esteve E, Fort-Vanmeerhaeghe A, Bandholm T, Thorborg K. Is inertial flywheel resistance training superior to gravity-dependent resistance training in improving muscle strength? A systematic review with meta-analyses. J Sci Med Sport 21: 75&#x2013;83, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voloshina AS, Ferris DP. Biomechanics and energetics of running on uneven terrain. J Exp Biol 218: 711&#x2013;719, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wretenberg P, Feng Y, Lindberg F, Arboreilus UP. Joint moments of force and quadriceps muscle activity during squatting exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports 3: 244&#x2013;250, 1993.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>