<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">28042532</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2228-5806</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2017</Year><Season>Winter</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cell journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cell J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Satellite Cells Contribution to Exercise Mediated Muscle Hypertrophy and Repair.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>473</StartPage><EndPage>484</EndPage><MedlinePgn>473-484</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Satellite cells (SCs) are the most abundant skeletal muscle stem cells. They are widely recognized for their contributions to maintenance of muscle mass, regeneration and hypertrophy during the human life span. These cells are good candidates for cell therapy due to their self-renewal capabilities and presence in an undifferentiated form. Presently, a significant gap exists between our knowledge of SCs behavior and their application as a means for human skeletal muscle tissue repair and regeneration. Both physiological and pathological stimuli potentially affect SCs activation, proliferation, and terminal differentiation the former category being the focus of this article. Activation of SCs occurs following exercise, post-training micro-injuries, and electrical stimulation. Exercise, as a potent and natural stimulus, is at the center of numerous studies on SC activation and relevant fields. According to research, different exercise modalities end with various effects. This review article attempts to picture the state of the art of the SCs life span and their engagement in muscle regeneration and hypertrophy in exercise.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bazgir</LastName><ForeName>Behzad</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Physiology Research Center, Baqiyatallah University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran; Department of Embryology, Reproductive Biomedicine Research Center, Royan Institute for Reproductive Biomedicine, ACECR, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fathi</LastName><ForeName>Rouhollah</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Embryology, Reproductive Biomedicine Research Center, Royan Institute for Reproductive Biomedicine, ACECR, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rezazadeh Valojerdi</LastName><ForeName>Mojtaba</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Embryology, Reproductive Biomedicine Research Center, Royan Institute for Reproductive Biomedicine, ACECR, Tehran, Iran; Department of Anatomy, Faculty of Medical Sciences, Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mozdziak</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiology Graduate Program, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asgari</LastName><ForeName>Alireza</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Physiology Research Center, Baqiyatallah University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran; Aerospace and Subaquatic Medicine Faculty, Aerospace Medicine Research Center, AJA Medical Sciences University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2016</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Iran</Country><MedlineTA>Cell J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101566618</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2228-5806</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Plasticity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Skeletal Muscle Satellite Cells</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2016</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2016</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2017</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28042532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5086326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22074/cellj.2016.4714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mauro A. Satellite cell of skeletal muscle fibers. J Biophys Biochem Cytol. 1961;9(2):493&#x2013;495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2225012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13768451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan JE, Zammit PS. Direct effects of the pathogenic mutation on satellite cell function in muscular dystrophy. Exp Cell Res. 2010;316(18):3100&#x2013;3108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20546725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultz E, Gibson MC, Champion T. Satellite cells are mitotically quiescent in mature mouse muscle: an EM and radioautographic study. J Exp Zool. 1978;206(3):451&#x2013;456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">712350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boldrin L, Muntoni F, Morgan JE. Are human and mouse satellite cells really the same? J Histochem Cytochem. 2010;58(11):941&#x2013;955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2958137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20644208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ono Y, Boldrin L, Knopp P, Morgan JE, Zammit PS. Muscle satellite cells are a functionally heterogeneous population in both somite-derived and branchiomeric muscles. Dev Biol. 2009;337(1):29&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2806517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19835858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultz E, Chamberlain C, McCormick KM, Mozdziak PE. Satellite cells express distinct patterns of myogenic proteins in immature skeletal muscle. Dev Dyn. 2006;235(12):3230&#x2013;3209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17029285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhawan J, Rando TA. Stem cells in postnatal myogenesis: molecular mechanisms of satellite cell quiescence, activation and replenishment. Trends Cell Biol. 2005;15(12):666&#x2013;673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16243526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabourin LA, Rudnicki MA. The molecular regulation of myogenesis. Clin Genet. 2000;57(1):16&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10733231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zammit PS, Heslop L, Hudon V, Rosenblatt JD, Tajbakhsh S, Buckingham ME, et al. Kinetics of myoblast proliferation show that resident satellite cells are competent to fully regenerate skeletal muscle fibers. Exp Cell Res. 2002;281(1):39&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12441128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornelison DDW, Wold BJ. Single-cell analysis of regulatory gene expression in quiescent and activated mouse skeletal muscle satellite cells. Dev Biol. 1997;191(2):270&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9398440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Relaix F, Montarras D, Zaffran S, Gayraud-Morel B, Rocancourt D, Tajbakhsh S, et al. Pax3 and Pax7 have distinct and overlapping functions in adult muscle progenitor cells. J Cell Biol. 2006;172(1):91&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2063537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16380438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin NRW, Lewis MP. Satellite cell activation and number following acute and chronic exercise: a mini review. Cell Mol Exerc Physiol. 2012;1(1):e3&#x2013;e3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wozniak AC, Kong J, Bock E, Pilipowicz O, Anderson JE. Signaling satellite cell activation in skeletal muscle: markers, models, stretch, and potential alternate pathways. Muscle Nerve. 2005;31(3):283&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15627266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wozniak AC, Pilipowicz O, Yablonka-Reuveni Z, Greenway S, Craven S, Scott E, et al. C-Met expression and mechanical activation of satellite cells on cultured muscle fibers. J Histochem Cytochem. 2003;51(11):1437&#x2013;1445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3957553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14566016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darr KC, Schultz E. Exercise-induced satellite cell activation in growing and mature skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol. 1987;63(5):1816&#x2013;1821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3693217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuhaus P, Oustanina S, Loch T, Kr&#xfc;ger M, Bober E, Dono R, et al. Reduced mobility of fibroblast growth factor (FGF)-deficient myoblasts might contribute to dystrophic changes in the musculature of FGF2/FGF6/mdx triplemutant mice. Mol Biol Cell. 2003;23(17):6037&#x2013;6048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC180975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12917328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bankol LC, Feasson L, Ponsot E, Kadi F. Fibre type specific satellite cell content in two models of muscle diseases. Histopathology. 2013;63(6):826&#x2013;832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24111647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiore F, S&#xe9;bille A, Birnbaum D. Skeletal muscle regeneration is not impaired in mutant mice. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2000;272(1):138&#x2013;143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10872817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerletti M, Jang YC, Finley LW, Haigis MC, Wagers AJ. Short-term calorie restriction enhances skeletal muscle stem cell function. Cell Stem Cell. 2012;10(5):515&#x2013;519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3561899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22560075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floss T, Arnold HH, Braun T. A role for FGF-6 in skeletal muscle regeneration. Genes Dev. 1997;11(16):2040&#x2013;2051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC316448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9284044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parise G, McKinnell IW, Rudnicki MA. Muscle satellite cell and atypical myogenic progenitor response following exercise. Muscle Nerve. 2008;37(5):611&#x2013;619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18351585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultz E. A quantitative study of satellite cells in regenerated soleus and extensor digitorum longus muscles. Anat Rec. 1984;208(4):501&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6731859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatsumi R, Hattori A, Ikeuchi Y, Anderson JE, Allen RE. Release of hepatocyte growth factor from mechanically stretched skeletal muscle satellite cells and role of pH and nitric oxide. Mol Biol Cell. 2002;13(8):2909&#x2013;2918.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC117951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12181355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdijk LB, Koopman R, Schaart G, Meijer K, Savelberg HHCM, van Loon LJC. Satellite cell content is specifically reduced in type II skeletal muscle fibers in the elderly. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2007;292(1):E151&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16926381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdijk LB, Dirks ML, Snijders T, Prompers JJ, Beelen M, Jonkers RAM, et al. Reduced satellite cell numbers with spinal cord injury and aging in humans. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44(12):2322&#x2013;2330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22776875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefer G, Van de Mark DP, Richardson JB, YablonkaReuveni Z. Satellite-cell pool size does matter: defining the myogenic potency of aging skeletal muscle. Dev Biol. 2006;294(1):50&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2710453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16554047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi X, Garry DJ. Muscle stem cells in development, regeneration, and disease. Genes Dev. 2006;20(13):1692&#x2013;1708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16818602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mozdziak PE, Schultz E, Cassens RG. The effect of in vivo and in vitro irradiation (25 Gy) on the subsequent in vitro growth of satellite cells. Cell Tissue Res. 1996;283(2):203&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8593649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brack AS, Rando TA. Intrinsic changes and extrinsic influences of myogenic stem cell function during aging. Stem Cell Rev. 2007;3(3):226&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17917136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brack AS, Conboy MJ, Roy S, Lee M, Kuo CJ, Keller C, et al. Increased Wnt signaling during aging alters muscle stem cell fate and increases fibrosis. Science. 2007;317(5839):807&#x2013;810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17690295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conboy MJ, Karasov AO, Rando TA. High incidence of non-random template strand segregation and asymmetric fate determination in dividing stem cells and their progeny. PLoS Biol. 2007;5(5):e102&#x2013;e102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1852584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17439301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopinath SD, Rando TA. Stem cell review series: aging of the skeletal muscle stem cell niche. Aging Cell. 2008;7(4):590&#x2013;598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18462272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ten Broek RW, Grefte S, Von den Hoff JW. Regulatory factors and cell populations involved in skeletal muscle regeneration. J Cell Physiol. 2010;224(1):7&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20232319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatsumi R, Anderson JE, Nevoret CJ, Halevy O, Allen RE. HGF/SF is present in normal adult skeletal muscle and is capable of activating satellite cells. Dev Biol. 1998;194(1):114&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9473336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson J, Pilipowicz O. Activation of muscle satellite cells in single-fiber cultures. Nitric Oxide. 2002;7(1):36&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12175818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM. A brief review of critical processes in exercise-induced muscular hypertrophy. Sports Med. 2014;44(Suppl 1):S71&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24791918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrella JK, Kim JS, Mayhew DL, Cross JM, Bamman MM. Potent myofiber hypertrophy during resistance training in humans is associated with satellite cell-mediated myonuclear addition: a cluster analysis. J Appl Physiol. 2008;104(6):1736&#x2013;1742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18436694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mozdziak PE, Schultz E, Cassens RG. Satellite cell mitotic activity in posthatch turkey skeletal muscle growth. Poult Sci. 1994;73(4):547&#x2013;555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8202434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mozdziak PE, Schultz E, Cassens RG. Myonuclear accretion is a major determinant of avian skeletal muscle growth. Am J Physiol. 1997;272(2):C565&#x2013;571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9124300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mozdziak PE, Pulvermacher PM, Schultz E. Unloading of juvenile muscle results in a reduced muscle size 9 wk after reloading. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88(1):158&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10642376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira CE, Duarte JA. Myonuclear domain in skeletal muscle fibers.A critical review. Arch Exerc Health Dis. 2011;2(2):92&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrella JK, Kim JS, Cross JM, Kosek DJ, Bamman MM. Efficacy of myonuclear addition may explain differential myofiber growth among resistance-trained young and older men and women. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2006;291(5):E937&#x2013;946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16772322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadi F, Thornell LE. Concomitant increases in myonuclear and satellite cell content in female trapezius muscle following strength training. Histochem Cell Biol. 2000;113(2):99&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10766262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosek DJ, Kim JS, Petrella JK, Cross JM, Bamman MM. Efficacy of 3 days/wk resistance training on myofiber hypertrophy and myogenic mechanisms in young vs.older adults. J Appl Physiol. 2006;101(2):531&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16614355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amthor H, Otto A, Vulin A, Rochat A, Dumonceaux J, Garcia L, et al. Muscle hypertrophy driven by myostatin blockade does not require stem/precursor-cell activity. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2009;106(18):7479&#x2013;7484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2671322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19383783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins CA, Gnocchi VF, White RB, Boldrin L, Perez-Ruiz A, Relaix F, et al. Integrated functions of Pax3 and Pax7 in the regulation of proliferation, cell size and myogenic differentiation. PLoS One. 2009;4(2):e4475&#x2013;e4475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2637421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19221588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Mario JX, Stockdale FE. Differences in the developmental fate of cultured and noncultured myoblasts when transplanted into embryonic limbs. Exp Cell Res. 1995;216(2):431&#x2013;442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7843288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malerba A, Vitiello L, Segat D, Dazzo E, Frigo M, Scambi I, et al. Selection of multipotent cells and enhanced muscle reconstruction by myogenic macrophage-secreted factors. Exp Cell Res. 2009;315(6):915&#x2013;927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19371636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chazaud B, Sonnet C, Lafuste P, Bassez G, Rimaniol AC, Poron F, et al. Satellite cells attract monocytes and use macrophages as a support to escape apoptosis and enhance muscle growth. J Cell Biol. 2003;163(5):1133&#x2013;1143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2173611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14662751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhoads RP, Johnson RM, Rathbone CR, Liu X, TemmGrove C, Sheehan SM, et al. Satellite cell-mediated angiogenesis in vitro coincides with a functional hypoxiainducible factor pathway. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2009;296(6):C1321&#x2013;1328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2692418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19386789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatsumi R, Wuollet AL, Tabata K, Nishimura S, Tabata S, Mizunoya W, et al. A role for calcium-calmodulin in regulating nitric oxide production during skeletal muscle satellite cell activation. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2009;296(4):C922&#x2013;929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19158401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abou-Khalil R, Le Grand F, Pallafacchina G, Valable S, Authier FJ, Rudnicki MA, et al. Autocrine and paracrine angiopoietin 1/Tie-2 signaling promotes muscle satellite cell self-renewal. Cell Stem Cell. 2009;5(3):298&#x2013;309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4592285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19733541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mourkioti F, Rosenthal N. IGF-1, inflammation and stem cells: interactions during muscle regeneration. Trends Immunol. 2005;26(10):535&#x2013;542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16109502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurek JB, Bower JJ, Romanella M, Koentgen F, Murphy M, Austin L. The role of leukemia inhibitory factor in skeletal muscle regeneration. Muscle Nerve. 1997;20(7):815&#x2013;822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9179153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller KJ, Thaloor D, Matteson S, Pavlath GK. Hepatocyte growth factor affects satellite cell activation and differentiation in regenerating skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2000;278(1):C174&#x2013;181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10644525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brimah K, Ehrhardt J, Mouly V, Butler-Browne GS, Partridge TA, Morgan JE. Human muscle precursor cell regeneration in the mouse host is enhanced by growth factors. Hum Gene Ther. 2004;15(11):1109&#x2013;1124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15610611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson B. Principles of regenerative biology. 1st ed. Elsevier, Amsterdam, Netherlands: Academic Press; 2011. 121</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parise G. Satellite cells: promoting adaptation over a lifetime. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 2014;210(3):462&#x2013;464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24373175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangan G, Bombardier E, Mitchell AS, Quadrilatero J, Tiidus PM. Oestrogen-dependent satellite cell activation and proliferation following a running exercise occurs via the PI3K signalling pathway and not IGF-1. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 2014;212(1):75&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24862866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van de Vyver M, Myburgh KH. Cytokine and satellite cell responses to muscle damage: interpretation and possible confounding factors in human studies. J Muscle Res Cell Motil. 2012;33(3-4):177&#x2013;185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3413811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22673937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith HK, Maxwell L, Rodgers CD, McKee NH, Plyley MJ. Exercise-enhanced satellite cell proliferation and new myonuclear accretion in rat skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol. 2001;90(4):1407&#x2013;1414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11247941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurosaka M, Naito H, Ogura Y, Machida S, Katamoto S. Satellite cell pool enhancement in rat plantaris muscle by endurance training depends on intensity rather than duration. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 2012;205(1):159&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22040028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augusto V, Padovani CR, Campos GER. Skeletal muscle fiber types in C57BL6J mice. Braz J Morphol Sci. 2004;21(2):89&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eksteen GJ. Satellite cell proliferation in response to a chronic laboratory-controlled uphill vs.downhill interval training intervention.Presented for the M.Sc., Stellenbosch.University of Stellenbosch. University of Stellenbosch; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry CS, Noehren B, Mula J, Ubele MF, Westgate PM, Kern PA, et al. Fibre type specific satellite cell response to aerobic training in sedentary adults. J Physiol. 2014;592(12):2625&#x2013;2635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4080942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24687582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joanisse S, McKay BR, Nederveen JP, Scribbans TD, Gurd BJ, Gillen JB, et al. Satellite cell activity, without expansion, after nonhypertrophic stimuli. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2015;309(9):R1101&#x2013;1111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4666950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26333785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snijders T, Verdijk LB, Hansen D, Dendale P, van Loon LJ. Continuous endurance-type exercise training does not modulate satellite cell content in obese type 2 diabetes patients. Muscle Nerve. 2011;43(3):393&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21321955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crameri RM, Langberg H, Magnusson P, Jensen CH, Schrder HD, Olesen JL, et al. Changes in satellite cells in human skeletal muscle after a single bout of high intensity exercise. J physiol. 2004;558(1):333&#x2013;340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1664917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15121802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibala MJ, MacDougall JD, Tarnopolsky MA, Stauber WT, Elorriaga A. Changes in human skeletal muscle ultrastructure and force production after acute resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1995;78(2):702&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7759443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cermak NM, Snijders T, McKay BR, Parise G, Verdijk LB, Tarnopolsky MA, et al. Eccentric exercise increases satellite cell content in type II muscle fibers. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45(2):230&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22968308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikkelsen UR, Langberg H, Helmark IC, Skovgaard D, Andersen LL, Kjaer M, et al. Local NSAID infusion inhibits satellite cell proliferation in human skeletal muscle after eccentric exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2009;107(5):1600&#x2013;1611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3774508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19713429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Reilly C, McKay B, Phillips S, Tarnopolsky M, Parise G. Hepatocyte growth factor (HGF) and the satellite cell response following muscle lengthening contractions in humans. Muscle Nerve. 2008;38(5):1434&#x2013;1442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18816607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyldahl RD, Olson T, Welling T, Groscost L, Parcell AC. Satellite cell activity is differentially affected by contraction mode in human muscle following a work-matched bout of exercise. Front Physiol. 2014;5:485&#x2013;485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4263080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25566087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crameri RM, Aagaard P, Qvortrup K, Langberg H, Olesen J, Kjaer M. Myofibre damage in human skeletal muscle: effects of electrical stimulation versus voluntary contraction. J Physiol. 2007;583(1):365&#x2013;380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2277245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17584833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, West DW, Staples AW, Atherton PJ, Baker JM, Moore DR, et al. Low-load high volume resistance exercise stimulates muscle protein synthesis more than highload low volume resistance exercise in young men. PLoS One. 2010;5(8):e12033&#x2013;e12033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2918506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20711498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nederveen JP, Joanisse S, S&#xe9;guin CM, Bell KE, Baker SK, Phillips SM, et al. The effect of exercise mode on the acute response of satellite cells in old men. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 2015;215(4):177&#x2013;190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26367861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker DK, Fry CS, Drummond MJ, Dickinson JM, Timmerman KL, Gundermann DM, et al. PAX7+ satellite cells in young and older adults following resistance exercise. Muscle Nerve. 2012;46(1):51&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3374905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22644638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer HC, Blanco CE, Sattler FR, Schroeder ET, Wiswell RA. Satellite cell number in young and older men 24 hours after eccentric exercise. Muscle Nerve. 2006;33(2):242&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16315322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackey AL, Holm L, Reitelseder S, Pedersen TG, Doessing S, Kadi F, et al. Myogenic response of human skeletal muscle to 12 weeks of resistance training at light loading intensity. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2011;21(6):773&#x2013;782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21143306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snijders T, Verdijk LB, Smeets JS, McKay BR, Senden JM, Hartgens F, et al. The skeletal muscle satellite cell response to a single bout of resistance-type exercise is delayed with aging in men. Age (Dordr) 2014;36(4):9699&#x2013;9699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4150882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25108351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farup J, Rahbek SK, Riis S, Vendelbo MH, de Paoli F, Vissing K. Influence of exercise contraction mode and protein supplementation on human skeletal muscle satellite cell content and muscle fiber growth. J Appl Physiol. 2014;117(8):898&#x2013;909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4280155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25103976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shelmadine B, Cooke M, Buford T, Hudson G, Redd L, Leutholtz B, et al. Effects of 28 days of resistance exercise and consuming a commercially available pre-workout supplement, NO-Shotgun, on body composition, muscle strength and mass, markers of satellite cell activation, and clinical safety markers in males. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2009;6:16&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2731073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19656392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen JL, Aagaard P, Bech RD, Nygaard T, Hvid LG, Wernbom M, et al. Proliferation of myogenic stem cells in human skeletal muscle in response to low load resistance training with blood flow restriction. J physiol. 2012;590(17):4351&#x2013;4361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3473290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22802591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Apro W, Paulsen G, Nilsen TS, Blomstrand E, Raastad T. Acute low-load resistance exercise with and without blood flow restriction increased protein signalling and number of satellite cells in human skeletal muscle. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113(12):2953&#x2013;2965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24078212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulsen G, Egner IM, Drange M, Langberg H, Benestad HB, Fjeld JG, et al. A COX inhibitor reduces muscle soreness, but does not influence recovery and adaptation after eccentric exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20(1):e195&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19522751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay BR, Toth KG, Tarnopolsky MA, Parise G. Satellite cell number and cell cycle kinetics in response to acute myotrauma in humans: immunohistochemistry versus flow cytometry. J physiol. 2010;588(17):3307&#x2013;3320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2976024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20624792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackey AL, Kjaer M, Charifi N, Henriksson J, Bojsen Moller J, Holm L, et al. Assessment of satellite cell number and activity status in human skeletal muscle biopsies. Muscle Nerve. 2009;40(3):455&#x2013;465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19705426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts MD, Dalbo VJ, Kerksick CM. Postexercise myogenic gene expression: are human findings lost during translation? Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2011;39(4):206&#x2013;2011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21799423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadi F, Schjerling P, Andersen LL, Charifi N, Madsen JrL, Christensen LR, et al. The effects of heavy resistance training and detraining on satellite cells in human skeletal muscles. J physiol. 2004;558(3):1005&#x2013;1012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1665027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15218062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth SM, Martel GF, Ivey FM, Lemmer JT, Tracy BL, Metter EJ, et al. Skeletal muscle satellite cell characteristics in young and older men and women after heavy resistance strength training. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2001;56(6):B240&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11382785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charifi N, Kadi F, Fasson L, Denis C. Effects of endurance training on satellite cell frequency in skeletal muscle of old men. Muscle Nerve. 2003;28(1):87&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12811778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdijk LB, Snijders T, Drost M, Delhaas T, Kadi F, van Loon LJC. Satellite cells in human skeletal muscle; from birth to old age. Age (Dordr) 2014;36(2):545&#x2013;547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4039250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24122288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdijk LB, Jonkers RA, Gleeson BG, Beelen M, Meijer K, Savelberg HH, et al. Protein supplementation before and after exercise does not further augment skeletal muscle hypertrophy after resistance training in elderly men. Am J Clin Nutr. 2009;89(2):608&#x2013;616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19106243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulmi JJ, Kovanen V, Lisko I, Sel&#xe4;nne H, Mero AA. The effects of whey protein on myostatin and cell cycle-related gene expression responses to a single heavy resistance exercise bout in trained older men. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;102(2):205&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17924133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellamy LM. Temporal pattern of type II fibre-specific satellite cell expansion to exercise correlates with human muscle hypertrophy: potential role for myostatin.Presented for the Ph.D. Hamilton, Ontario, Canada: McMaster University; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen S, Aagaard P, Kadi F, Tufekovic G, Verney J, Olesen JL, et al. Creatine supplementation augments the increase in satellite cell and myonuclei number in human skeletal muscle induced by strength training. J physiol. 2006;573(2):525&#x2013;534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1779717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16581862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdijk LB, Gleeson BG, Jonkers RAM, Meijer K, Savelberg HHCM, Dendale P, et al. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy following resistance training is accompanied by a fiber type specific increase in satellite cell content in elderly men. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2009;64(3):332&#x2013;339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2655000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19196907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verney J, Kadi F, Charifi N, Fasson L, Saafi MA, Castells J, et al. Effects of combined lower body endurance and upper body resistance training on the satellite cell pool in elderly subjects. Muscle Nerve. 2008;38(3):1147&#x2013;1154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18671293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruusgaard JC, Johansen IB, Egner IM, Rana ZA, Gundersen K. Myonuclei acquired by overload exercise precede hypertrophy and are not lost on detraining. Proc Natl Acad Sci. 2010;107(34):15111&#x2013;15116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2930527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20713720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoppeler H, Howald H, Conley K, Lindstedt SL, Claassen H, Vock P, et al. Endurance training in humans: aerobic capacity and structure of skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol. 1985;59(2):320&#x2013;327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4030584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingjer F. Effects of endurance training on muscle fibre ATP-ase activity, capillary supply and mitochondrial content in man. J physiol. 1979;294(1):419&#x2013;432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1280565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">159945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith HK, Merry TL. Voluntary resistance wheel exercise during post natal growth in rats enhances skeletal muscle satellite cell and myonuclear content at adulthood. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 2012;204(3):393&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21854550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kadi F, Eriksson A, Holmner S, Thornell LE. Effects of anabolic steroids on the muscle cells of strength-trained athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31(11):1528&#x2013;1534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10589853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefer G, Rauner G, Yablonka-Reuveni Z, Benayahu D. Reduced satellite cell numbers and myogenic capacity in aging can be alleviated by endurance exercise. PLoS One. 2010;5(10):e13307&#x2013;e13307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2953499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20967266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazgir B, Salesi M, Koushki M, Amirghofran Z. Effects of eccentric and concentric emphasized resistance exercise on IL-15 serum levels and its relation to inflammatory markers in athletes and non-athletes. Asian J Sports Med. 2015;6(3):e27980&#x2013;e27980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4594145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26448857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinemeier K, Mackey A, Doessing S, Hansen M, Bayer M, Nielsen R, et al. GH/IGF-I axis and matrix adaptation of the musculotendinous tissue to exercise in humans. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2012;22(4):e1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22429205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blaauw B, Reggiani C. The role of satellite cells in muscle hypertrophy. J Muscle Res Cell Motil. 2014;35(1):3&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24505026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay BR, O'Reilly CE, Phillips SM, Tarnopolsky MA, Parise G. Co-expression of IGF-1 family members with myogenic regulatory factors following acute damaging muscle-lengthening contractions in humans. J physiol. 2008;586(22):5549&#x2013;560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2655389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18818249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christov C, Chretien F, Abou-Khalil R, Bassez G, Vallet G, Authier FJ, et al. Muscle satellite cells and endothelial cells: close neighbors and privileged partners. Mol Biol Cell. 2007;18(4):1397&#x2013;1409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1838982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17287398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayan K, Thompson JL, Norenberg KM, Fitts R, Riley DA. Fiber-type susceptibility to eccentric contractioninduced damage of hindlimb-unloaded rat AL muscles. J App Physiol. 2001;90(3):770&#x2013;776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11181582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langley B, Thomas M, Bishop A, Sharma M, Gilmour S, Kambadur R. Myostatin inhibits myoblast differentiation by down-regulating MyoD expression. J Biol Chem. 2002;277(51):49831&#x2013;4940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12244043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas M, Langley B, Berry C, Sharma M, Kirk S, Bass J, et al. Myostatin, a negative regulator of muscle growth, functions by inhibiting myoblast proliferation. J Biol Chem. 2000;275(51):40235&#x2013;40243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10976104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raue U, Slivka D, Jemiolo B, Hollon C, Trappe S. Myogenic gene expression at rest and after a bout of resistance exercise in young (18-30 yr) and old (80-89 yr) women. J Appl Physiol. 2006;101(1):53&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16601301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacKenzie MG, Hamilton DL, Pepin M, Patton A, Baar K. Inhibition of myostatin signaling through Notch activation following acute resistance exercise. PLoS One. 2013;8(7):e68743&#x2013;e68743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3699505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23844238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazgir B, Asgari A. The interactive role of exercise and satellite cells in skeletal muscle regeneration and hypertrophy. The scientific and medical journal of Ebnesina. 2015;16(4):47&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baharvand H, Piryaei A, Rohani R, Taei A, Heidari MH, Hosseini A. Ultrastructural comparison of developing mouse embryonic stem celland in vivo-derived cardiomyocytes. Mol Cell Biol. 2006;30(10):800&#x2013;807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16877013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatami L, Valojerdi MR, Mowla SJ. Effects of oxytocin on cardiomyocyte differentiation from mouse embryonic stem cells. Int J Cardiol. 2007;117(1):80&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17034884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taha MF VM. Effect of bone morphogenetic protein-4 on cardiac differentiation from mouse embryonic stem cells in serum-free and low-serum media. Int J Cardiol. 2008;27(1):78&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17714812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharifiaghdas F, Taheri M, Moghadasali R. Isolation of human adult stem cells from muscle biopsy for future treatment of urinary incontinence. Urol J. 2011;8(1):54&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21404204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salesi M, Sheikhani Shahin H, Gramizadeh B, Tanideh N. The effects of 8 week exercise and estrogen supllementation in overctomized rats. Sport Biosciences (Harakat) 2010;(7):137&#x2013;152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khadivi Borujeny AR, Marandi M, Haghjooy Javanmard Sh, Rajabi H, Khadivi Burojeny Z, Khorshidi Behzadi M. Effect of eight weeks of resistance training on some signaling factors affecting on the satellite cells in wistar rats. Journal of Isfahan Medical School. 2012;30(207):1500&#x2013;1511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamalpoor Z, Asgari AR, Nourani MR. Skeletal muscle tissue engineering: present and future. J Mil Med. 2012;14(2):1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugh JK, Faulkner SH, Jackson AP, King JA, Nimmo MA. Acute molecular responses to concurrent resistance and high intensity interval exercise in untrained skeletal muscle. Physiol Rep. 2015;3(4):e12364&#x2013;e12364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4425969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25902785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snijders T, Verdijk LB, Beelen M, McKay BR, Parise G, Kadi F, et al. A single bout of exercise activates skeletal muscle satellite cells during subsequent overnight recovery. Exp Physiol. 2012;97(6):762&#x2013;773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22327327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babcock L, Escano M, D'Lugos A, Todd K, Murach K, Luden N. Concurrent aerobic exercise interferes with the satellite cell response to acute resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2012;302(12):R1458&#x2013;1465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22492813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe9;guin C. A comparison of differing modalities of exercise on the acute satellite cell responses in older adults.Presented for the Ph.D. Hamilton, Ontario, Canada: McMaster University; 2015.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>