<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35044672</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>52</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Periodization on Strength and Muscle Hypertrophy in Volume-Equated Resistance Training Programs: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1647</StartPage><EndPage>1666</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1647-1666</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-021-01636-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">In resistance training, periodization is often used in an attempt to promote development of strength and muscle hypertrophy. However, it remains unclear how resistance training variables are most effectively periodized to maximize gains in strength and muscle hypertrophy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">The aims of this study were to examine the current body of literature to determine whether there is an effect of periodization of training volume and intensity on maximal strength and muscle hypertrophy, and, if so, to determine how these variables are more effectively periodized to promote increases in strength and muscle hypertrophy, when volume is equated between conditions from pre to post intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Systematic searches were conducted in PubMed, Scopus and SPORTDiscus databases. Data from the individual studies were extracted and coded. Meta-analyses using the inverse-variance random effects model were performed to compare 1-repetition maximum (1RM) and muscle hypertrophy outcomes in (a) non-periodized (NP) versus periodized training and (b) in linear periodization (LP) versus undulating periodization (UP). Subgroup analyses examining whether results were affected by training status were performed. Meta-analyses of other periodization model comparisons were not performed, due to a low number of studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Thirty-five studies met the inclusion criteria. Results of the meta-analyses comparing NP and periodized training demonstrated an overall effect on 1RM strength favoring periodized training (ES 0.31, 95% confidence interval (CI) [0.04, 0.57]; Z&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.28, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.02). In contrast, muscle hypertrophy did not differ between NP and periodized training (ES 0.13, 95% CI [-0.10, 0.36]; Z&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.10, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.27). Results of the meta-analyses comparing LP and UP indicated an overall effect on 1RM favoring UP (ES 0.31, 95% CI [0.02, 0.61]; Z&#x2009;=&#x2009;2.06, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.04). Subgroup analyses indicated an effect on 1RM favoring UP in trained participants (ES 0.61, 95% CI [0.00, 1.22]; Z&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.97 (P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.05)), whereas changes in 1RM did not differ between LP and UP in untrained participants (ES 0.06, 95% CI [-0.20, 0.31]; Z&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.43 (P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.67)). The meta-analyses showed that muscle hypertrophy did not differ between LP and UP (ES 0.05, 95% CI [-0.20, 0.29]; Z&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.36 (P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.72)).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The results suggest that when volume is equated between conditions, periodized resistance training has a greater effect on 1RM strength compared to NP resistance training. Also, UP resulted in greater increases in 1RM compared to LP. However, subgroup analyses revealed that this was only the case for trained and not previously untrained individuals, indicating that trained individuals benefit from daily or weekly undulations in volume and intensity, when the aim is maximal strength. Periodization of volume and intensity does not seem to affect muscle hypertrophy in volume-equated pre-post designs. Based on this, we propose that the effects of periodization on maximal strength may instead be related to the neurophysiological adaptations accompanying resistance training.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moesgaard</LastName><ForeName>Lukas</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, Exercise and Sports, University of Copenhagen, Noerre Alle 51, 2200, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beck</LastName><ForeName>Mikkel Malling</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, Exercise and Sports, University of Copenhagen, Noerre Alle 51, 2200, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Christiansen</LastName><ForeName>Lasse</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Danish Research Centre for Magnetic Resonance, Centre for Functional and Diagnostic Imaging and Research, Copenhagen University Hospital, Amager and Hvidovre, Hvidovre, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aagaard</LastName><ForeName>Per</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Science and Clinical Biomechanics, Research Unit for Muscle Physiology and Biomechanics, University of Southern Denmark, Odense M, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lundbye-Jensen</LastName><ForeName>Jesper</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3144-861X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, Exercise and Sports, University of Copenhagen, Noerre Alle 51, 2200, Copenhagen, Denmark. jlundbye@nexs.ku.dk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35044672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-021-01636-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-021-01636-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Westcott WL. Resistance training is medicine: effects of strength training on health. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2012;11(4):209&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22777332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JSR.0b013e31825dabb8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winett RA, Carpinelli RN. Potential health-related benefits of resistance training. Prev Med. 2001;33(5):503&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11676593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/pmed.2001.0909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Granacher U, Fernandez-Del-Olmo M, Howatson G, Manca A, Deriu F, et al. Functional relevance of resistance training-induced neuroplasticity in health and disease. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2020;122:79&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33383071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2020.12.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Alvar BA, Burkett LN, Ball SD. A meta-analysis to determine the dose response for strength development. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(3):456&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12618576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000053727.63505.D4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Rhea MR, Alvar BA. Maximizing strength development in athletes: a meta-analysis to determine the dose-response relationship. J Strength Cond Res. 2004;18(2):377&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15142003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird SP, Tarpenning KM, Marino FE. Designing resistance training programmes to enhance muscular fitness: a review of the acute programme variables. Sports Med. 2005;35(10):841&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16180944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200535100-00002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(3):687&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181915670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston GW, Kilgore L, Wyatt FB, Baker JS. The effect of weekly set volume on strength gain: a meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2017;47(12):2585&#x2013;601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28755103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5684266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0762-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs. high-load resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res. 2017;31(12):3508&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28834797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci. 2017;35(11):1073&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27433992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2016.1210197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunanan AJ, DeWeese BH, Wagle JP, Carroll KM, Sausaman R, Hornsby WG 3rd, et al. The general adaptation syndrome: a foundation for the concept of periodization. Sports Med. 2018;48(4):787&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29307100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0855-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams TD, Tolusso DV, Fedewa MV, Esco MR. Comparison of periodized and non-periodized resistance training on maximal strength: a meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2017;47(10):2083&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28497285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0734-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer JB, Stone MH, O&#x2019;Bryant HS, Conley MS, Johnson RL, Nieman DC, et al. Effects of single vs. multiple sets of weight training: impact of volume, intensity, and variation. J Strength Cond Res. 1997;11(3):143&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG, The PG. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. PLoS Med. 2009;6(7):e1000097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19621072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2707599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maher CG, Sherrington C, Herbert RD, Moseley AM, Elkins M. Reliability of the PEDro scale for rating quality of randomized controlled trials. Phys Ther. 2003;83(8):713&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12882612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/83.8.713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris SB. Estimating effect sizes from pretest-posttest-control group designs. Organ Res Methods. 2008;11(2):364&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1094428106291059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JPT, Rothstein HR. Effect sizes based on means. Introduction to meta-analysis. London: Wiley; 2009. p. 21&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/9780470743386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JPT, Rothstein HR. Multiple outcomes or time-points within a study. Introduction to meta-analysis. London: Wiley; 2009. p. 225&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eifler C. Short-term effects of different loading schemes in fitness-related resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(7):1880&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26670986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leppink J, O&#x2019;Sullivan P, Winston K. Effect size&#x2014;large, medium, and small. Perspect Med Educ. 2016;5(6):347&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27752936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5122517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40037-016-0308-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. 2003;327(7414):557&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.327.7414.557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, Potteiger JA, Pierce KC, Proulx CM, O&#x2019;Bryant HS, Johnson RL, et al. Comparison of the effects of three different weight-training programs on the one repetition maximum squat. J Strength Cond Res. 2000;14(3):332&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadizad S, Ghorbani S, Ghasemikaram M, Bahmanzadeh M. Effects of short-term nonperiodized, linear periodized and daily undulating periodized resistance training on plasma adiponectin, leptin and insulin resistance. Clin Biochem. 2014;47(6):417&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24380765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinbiochem.2013.12.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker D, Wilson G, Carlyon R. Periodization: the effect on strength of manipulating volume and intensity. J Strength Cond Res. 1994;8(4):235&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei S, Hoffman JR, Merni F, Stout JR. A comparison of traditional and block periodized strength training programs in trained athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2014;28(4):990&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24476775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei S, Stout JR, Fukuda DH, Hoffman JR, Merni F. Block vs. weekly undulating periodized resistance training programs in women. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(10):2679&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25807030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartolomei S, Hoffman JR, Stout JR, Zini M, Stefanelli C, Merni F. Comparison of block versus weekly undulating periodization models on endocrine and strength changes in male athletes. Kinesiology. 2016;48(1):71&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26582/k.48.1.9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buford TW, Rossi SJ, Smith DB, Warren AJ. A comparison of periodization models during nine weeks with equated volume and intensity for strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2007;21(4):1245&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18076234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conlon JA, Newton RU, Tufano JJ, Banyard HG, Hopper AJ, Ridge AJ, et al. Periodization strategies in older adults: impact on physical function and health. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48(12):2426&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27434088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeBeliso M, Harris C, Spitzer-Gibson T, Adams KJ. A comparison of periodised and fixed repetition training protocol on strength in older adults. J Sci Med Sport. 2005;8(2):190&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16075779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1440-2440(05)80010-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Lima C, Boullosa DA, Frollini AB, Donatto FF, Leite RD, Gonelli PRG, et al. Linear and daily undulating resistance training periodizations have differential beneficial effects in young sedentary women. Int J Sports Med. 2012;33(9):723&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22562746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0032-1306324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Souza EO, Tricoli V, Rauch A, Alvarez MR, Laurentino G, Aihara AY et al. Different patterns in muscular strength and hypertrophy adaptations in untrained individuals undergoing non-periodized and periodized strength regimens. J Strength Cond Res. 2018;32(5):1238&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29683914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foschini D, Arajo RC, Bacurau RFP, De Piano A, De Almeida SS, Carnier J, et al. Treatment of obese adolescents: the influence of periodization models and ACE genotype. Obesity. 2010;18(4):766&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19680237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/oby.2009.247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchini E, Branco BM, Agostinho MF, Calmet M, Candau R. Influence of linear and undulating strength periodization on physical fitness, physiological, and performance responses to simulated judo matches. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(2):358&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24662235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavanda S, Geisler S, Quittmann OJ, Schiffer T. The effect of block versus daily undulating periodization on strength and performance in adolescent football players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14(6):814&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30569761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2018-0609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harries SK, Lubans DR, Callister R. Comparison of resistance training progression models on maximal strength in sub-elite adolescent rugby union players. J Sci Med Sport. 2016;19(2):163&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25709054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2015.01.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrick AB, Stone WJ. The effects of periodization versus progressive resistance exercise on upper and lower body strength in women. J Strength Cond Res. 1996;10(2):72&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue DS, De Mello MT, Foschini D, Lira FS, De Piano GA, Da Silveira Campos RM, et al. Linear and undulating periodized strength plus aerobic training promote similar benefits and lead to improvement of insulin resistance on obese adolescents. J Diabetes Complications. 2015;29(2):258&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25441178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jdiacomp.2014.11.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kok LY, Hamer PW, Bishop DJ. Enhancing muscular qualities in untrained women: linear versus undulating periodization. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(9):1797&#x2013;807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19657289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181a154f3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, H&#xe4;kkinen K, Triplett-McBride NT, Fry AC, Koziris LP, Ratamess NA, et al. Physiological changes with periodized resistance training in women tennis players. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(1):157&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12544650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200301000-00024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miranda F, Sim&#xe3;o R, Rhea M, Bunker D, Prestes J, Leite RD, et al. Effects of linear vs. daily undulatory periodized resistance training onmaximal and submaximal strength gains. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25(7):1824&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21499134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e7ff75</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteiro AG, Aoki MS, Evangelista AL, Alveno DA, Monteiro GA, Pi&#xe7;arro IDC, et al. Nonlinear periodization maximizes strength gains in split resistance training routines. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(4):1321&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19528843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181a00f96</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moraes E, Fleck SJ, Dias MR, Sim&#xe3;o R. Effects on strength, power, and flexibility in adolescents of nonperiodized vs. daily nonlinear periodized weight training. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(12):3310&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23442273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31828de8c3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Dodd DJ, Alvar BA, Rhea MR, Favre M. Undulation training for development of hierarchical fitness and improved firefighter job performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(5):1683&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18714214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31818215f4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prestes J, Frollini AB, de Lima C, Donatto FF, Foschini D, de C&#xe1;ssia MR, et al. Comparison between linear and daily undulating periodized resistance training to increase strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(9):2437&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19910831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181c03548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prestes J, da Cunha ND, Tibana RA, Teixeira TG, Vieira DCL, Tajra V, et al. Understanding the individual responsiveness to resistance training periodization. Age. 2015. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11357-015-9793-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11357-015-9793-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25971877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4430497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Ball SD, Phillips WT, Burkett LN. A comparison of linear and daily undulating periodized programs with equated volume and intensity for strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2002;16(2):250&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11991778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Phillips WT, Burkett LN, Stone WJ, Ball SD, Alvar BA, et al. A comparison of linear and daily undulating periodized programs with equated volume and intensity for local muscular endurance. J Strength Cond Res. 2003;17(1):82&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12580661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiotz MK, Potteiger JA, Huntsinger PG, Denmark DC. The short-term effects of periodized and constant-intensity training on body composition, strength, and performance. J Strength Cond Res. 1998;12(3):173&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim&#xe3;o R, Spineti J, De Salles BF, Matta T, Fernandes L, Fleck SJ, et al. Comparison between nonlinear and linear periodized resistance training: hypertrophic and strength effects. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26(5):1389&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22516910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e318231a659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soares VL, Soares WF, Zanetti HR, Neves FF, Silva-Vergara ML, Mendes EL. Daily undulating periodization is more effective than nonperiodized training on maximal strength, aerobic capacity, and TCD4+ cell count in people living with HIV. J Strength Cond Res. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000003675 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32604148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souza EO, Ugrinowitsch C, Tricoli V, Roschel H, Lowery RP, Aihara AY, et al. Early adaptations to six weeks of non-periodized and periodized strength training regimens in recreational males. J Sports Sci Med. 2014;13(3):604&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25177188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4126298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spineti J, Figueiredo T, de Salles BF, Assis M, Fernandes L, Novaes J, et al. Comparison between different periodization models on muscular strength and thickness in a muscle group increasing sequence. Rev Bras Med Esporte. 2013;19(4):280&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1517-86922013000400011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Streb AR, Passos da Silva R, Leonel LDS, Possamai LT, Gerage da Silva AM, Turnes T, et al. Effects of nonperiodized and linear periodized combined training on health-related physical fitness in adults with obesity: a randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1519/JSC.0000000000003859 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33044366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanni AC, Meyer F, Da Veiga ADR, Zanardo VPS. Comparison of the effects of two resistance training regimens on muscular and bone responses in premenopausal women. Osteoporos Int. 2010;21(9):1537&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20057999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00198-009-1139-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harries SK, Lubans DR, Callister R. Systematic review and meta-analysis of linear and undulating periodized resistance training programs on muscular strength. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(4):1113&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25268290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldas LC, Guimar&#xe3;es-Ferreira L, Duncan MJ, Leopoldo AS, Leopoldo APL, Wellington L. Traditional vs. undulating periodization in the context of muscular strength and hypertrophy: a meta-analysis. Int J Sports Sci. 2016;6(6):219&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Lazinica B, Mikulic P, Schoenfeld BJ. Should resistance training programs aimed at muscular hypertrophy be periodized? A systematic review of periodized versus non-periodized approaches. Sci Sports. 2018;33(3):e97&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scispo.2017.09.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Mikulic P, Podnar H, Pedisic Z. Effects of linear and daily undulating periodized resistance training programs on measures of muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PeerJ. 2017;5:e3695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28848690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5571788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.3695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Williams AG. The adaptations to strength training: morphological and neurological contributions to increased strength. Sports Med. 2007;37(2):145&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17241104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200737020-00004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P. Training-induced changes in neural function. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2003;31(2):61&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12715968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00003677-200304000-00002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosek DJ, Kim JS, Petrella JK, Cross JM, Bamman MM. Efficacy of 3 days/wk resistance training on myofiber hypertrophy and myogenic mechanisms in young vs. older adults. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2006;101(2):531&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01474.2005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welle S, Totterman S, Thornton C. Effect of age on muscle hypertrophy induced by resistance training. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 1996;51(6):M270&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8914498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/51A.6.M270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Simonsen EB, Andersen JL, Magnusson P, Dyhre-Poulsen P. Neural adaptation to resistance training: changes in evoked V-wave and H-reflex responses. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2002;92(6):2309&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01185.2001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard P, Bojsen-M&#xf8;ller J, Lundbye-Jensen J. Assessment of neuroplasticity with strength training. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2020;48(4):151&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32658038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JES.0000000000000229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutherford OM, Jones DA. The role of learning and coordination in strength training. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1986;55(1):100&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3698983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00422902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM. Short-term training: when do repeated bouts of resistance exercise become training? Can J Appl Physiol. 2000;25(3):185&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10932036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/h00-014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bemben M, Sato Y, Abe T. The use of anthropometry for assessing muscle size. Int J Kaatsu Training Res. 2005;1:33&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3806/ijktr.1.33</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez G, Moreno LA, Blay MG, Blay VA, Fleta J, Sarria A, et al. Body fat measurement in adolescents: comparison of skinfold thickness equations with dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2005;59(10):1158&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16047030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ejcn.1602226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pons C, Borotikar B, Garetier M, Burdin V, Ben Salem D, Lempereur M, et al. Quantifying skeletal muscle volume and shape in humans using MRI: a systematic review of validity and reliability. PLoS ONE. 2018;13(11): e0207847. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0207847 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0207847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30496308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6264864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone MH, Stone M, Sands WA. Principles and practice of resistance training. Champaign: Human Kinetics; 2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5040/9781492596875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prestes J, De Lima C, Frollini AB, Donatto FF, Conte M. Comparison of linear and reverse linear periodization effects on maximal strength and body composition. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(1):266&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19057409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181874bf3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klemp A, Dolan C, Quiles JM, Blanco R, Zoeller RF, Graves BS, et al. Volume-equated high- and low-repetition daily undulating programming strategies produce similar hypertrophy and strength adaptations. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2016;41(7):699&#x2013;705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27218448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2015-0707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zourdos MC, Jo E, Khamoui AV, Lee SR, Park BS, Ormsbee MJ, et al. Modified daily undulating periodization model produces greater performance than a traditional configuration in powerlifters. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30(3):784&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26332783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000001165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher JP, Steele J, Smith D, Gentil P. Periodization for optimizing strength and hypertrophy; the forgotten variables. J Trainology. 2018;7(1):10&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17338/trainology.7.1_10</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahtiainen JP, Walker S, Peltonen H, Holviala J, Sillanp&#xe4;&#xe4; E, Karavirta L, et al. Heterogeneity in resistance training-induced muscle strength and mass responses in men and women of different ages. Age (Dordr). 2016;38(1):10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11357-015-9870-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>