<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">34138817</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>53</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sex Differences in Cardiac Adaptation to Distinct Modalities of Exercise: A Cardiac Magnetic Resonance Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2543</StartPage><EndPage>2552</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2543-2552</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002729</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">No previous study has described sex differences in chronic cardiac adaptation in response to distinct modalities of exercise training in humans.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Cardiac magnetic resonance imaging (1.5 T) was used to assess left ventricular (LV) outcomes in 78 untrained subjects (46F, 26 M; 26.1 &#xb1; 5.4 yr). Subjects underwent 3 months of closely supervised and monitored resistance (RES) and endurance (END) training, separated by a 3-month washout period.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">LV mass (LVM) increased in response to END in both sexes (females &#x25b3;3.98 &#xb1; 7.98 g, P = 0.002; males &#x25b3;5.99 &#xb1; 10.67 g, P = 0.005), whereas LV end-diastolic volume (EDV) increased in males (&#x25b3;7.48 &#xb1; 11.91 mL, P = 0.002) but not females (&#x25b3;1.54 &#xb1; 10.49 mL, P = 0.373). In response to RES, LVM and EDV did not increase in either sex. The proportion of subjects exhibiting a positive response to training (i.e., a change &gt;0) for LVM and EDV did not differ between sexes for either training modality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Eccentric hypertrophy in response to END training was more apparent in males than females, whereas there were no notable cardiac changes between sexes for RES training. The proportion of low versus high responders to training was not sex specific for LVM or EDV in response to either commonly prescribed exercise training modality.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marsh</LastName><ForeName>Channa E</ForeName><Initials>CE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Sciences (Exercise and Sport Science), The University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thomas</LastName><ForeName>Hannah J</ForeName><Initials>HJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Sciences (Exercise and Sport Science), The University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Naylor</LastName><ForeName>Louise H</ForeName><Initials>LH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Sciences (Exercise and Sport Science), The University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dembo</LastName><ForeName>Lawrence G</ForeName><Initials>LG</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Green</LastName><ForeName>Daniel J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Sciences (Exercise and Sport Science), The University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, AUSTRALIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000076663" MajorTopicYN="N">Endurance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006352" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Ventricles</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017379" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy, Left Ventricular</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="Y">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012737" MajorTopicYN="N">Sex Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34138817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202112000-00010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Diaz-Canestro C, Pentz B, Sehgal A, et al. Sex differences in cardiorespiratory fitness are explained by blood volume and oxygen carrying capacity. Cardiovasc Res . 2021;cvab028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green DJ, Hopkins ND, Jones H, Thijssen DHJ, Eijsvogels TMH, Yeap BB. Sex differences in vascular endothelial function and health in humans: impacts of exercise. Exp Physiol . 2016;101(2):230&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naylor LH, George K, O&#x2019;Driscoll G, Green DJ. The athlete&#x2019;s heart: a contemporary appraisal of the &#x2018;Morganroth hypothesis&#x2019;. Sports Med . 2008;38(1):69&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angell P, Chester N, Green D, Somauroo J, Whyte G, George K. Anabolic steroids and cardiovascular risk. Sports Med . 2012;42(2):119&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konhilas JP, Maass AH, Luckey SW, Stauffer BL, Olson EN, Leinwand LA. Sex modifies exercise and cardiac adaptation in mice. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol . 2004;287(6):H2768&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foryst-Ludwig A, Kreissl MC, Sprang C, et al. Sex differences in physiological cardiac hypertrophy are associated with exercise-mediated changes in energy substrate availability. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol . 2011;301(1):H115&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aufradet E, Bessaad A, Alsaid H, et al. In vivo cardiac anatomical and functional effects of wheel running in mice by magnetic resonance imaging. Exp Biol Med . 2012;237(3):263&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz-Canestro C, Montero D. The impact of sex on left ventricular cardiac adaptations to endurance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med . 2020;50(8):1501&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spina RJ, Ogawa T, Kohrt WM, Martin WH 3rd, Holloszy JO, Ehsani AA. Differences in cardiovascular adaptations to endurance exercise training between older men and women. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 1993;75(2):849&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howden EJ, Perhonen M, Peshock RM, et al. Females have a blunted cardiovascular response to one year of intensive supervised endurance training. J Appl Physiol . 2015;119(1):37&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellenger NG, Davies LC, Francis JM, Coats AJ, Pennell DJ. Reduction in sample size for studies of remodeling in heart failure by the use of cardiovascular magnetic resonance. J Cardiovasc Magn Reson . 2000;2(4):271&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spence AL, Naylor LH, Carter HH, et al. Does echocardiography accurately reflect CMR-determined changes in left ventricular parameters following exercise training? A prospective longitudinal study. J Appl Physiol . 2013;114(8):1052&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strohm O, Schulz-Menger J, Pilz B, Osterziel KJ, Dietz R, Friedrich MG. Measurement of left ventricular dimensions and function in patients with dilated cardiomyopathy. J Magn Reson Imaging . 2001;13(3):367&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morganroth J, Maron B, Henry W, Epstein S. Comparative left ventricular dimensions in trained athletes. Ann Intern Med . 1975;82:521&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spence AL, Naylor LH, Carter HH, et al. A prospective randomised longitudinal MRI study of left ventricular adaptation to endurance and resistance exercise training in humans. J Physiol . 2011;589(22):5443&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsh CE, Thomas HJ, Naylor LH, Scurrah KJ, Green DJ. Fitness and strength responses to distinct exercise modes in twins: Studies of Twin Responses to Understand Exercise as a Therapy (STRUETH) study. J Physiol . 2020;598(18):3845&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard C, Blair SN, Church TS, et al. Adverse metabolic response to regular exercise: is it a rare or common occurrence? PLoS One . 2012;7(5):e37887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsh CE, Thomas HJ, Naylor LH, Scurrah KJ, Green DJ. Exploring human trainability: design and rationale of Studies of Twin Responses to Understand Exercise as a Therapy (STRUETH) study. Contemp Clin Trials Commun . 2020;19:100584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swoboda PP, Garg P, Levelt E, et al. Regression of left ventricular mass in athletes undergoing complete detraining is mediated by decrease in intracellular but not extracellular compartments. Circ Cardiovasc Imaging . 2019;12(9):e009417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spence AL, Carter HH, Murray CP, et al. Magnetic resonance imaging-derived right ventricular adaptations to endurance versus resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2013;45(3):534&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas HJ, Marsh CE, Maslen BA, Scurrah KJ, Naylor LH, Green DJ. Studies of Twin Responses to Understand Exercise Therapy (STRUETH): body composition. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2021;53(1):58&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrick-Ranson G, Sloane NM, Howden EJ, et al. The effect of lifelong endurance exercise on cardiovascular structure and exercise function in women. J Physiol . 2020;598(13):2589&#x2013;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagberg JM, Goldberg AP, Lakatta L, et al. Expanded blood volumes contribute to the increased cardiovascular performance of endurance-trained older men. J Appl Physiol . 1998;85(2):484&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Best S, Okada Y, Galbreath MM, et al. The effect of gender and age on hemodynamics, blood volume and cardiac size in healthy humans. FASEB J . 2012;26:lb635.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celentano A, Palmieri V, Arezzi E, et al. Gender differences in left ventricular chamber and midwall systolic function in normotensive and hypertensive adults. J Hypertens . 2003;21(7):1415&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang RM, Bierig M, Devereux RB, et al. Recommendations for chamber quantification. Eur J Echocardiogr . 2006;7(2):79&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandstede J, Lipke C, Beer M, et al. Age- and gender-specific differences in left and right ventricular cardiac function and mass determined by cine magnetic resonance imaging. Eur Radiol . 2000;10(3):438&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>