<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">31868813</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>High Resistance-Training Volume Enhances Muscle Thickness in Resistance-Trained Men.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>22</StartPage><EndPage>30</EndPage><MedlinePgn>22-30</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003413</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Brigatto, FA, Lima, LEdM, Germano, MD, Aoki, MS, Braz, TV, and Lopes, CR. High resistance-training volume enhances muscle thickness in resistance-trained men. J Strength Cond Res 36(1): 22-30, 2022-This study investigated the effects of different volumes of resistance training (RT) (8 weeks of 16, 24, and 32 weekly sets per muscle group) on muscular strength and hypertrophy. Subjects were pair-matched according to baseline strength and then randomly assigned to 1 of 3 experimental groups: 16 weekly sets per muscle group (G16, n = 9), 24 weekly sets per muscle group (G24, n = 9), or 32 weekly sets per muscle group (G32, n = 9). All other RT variables (e.g., exercise performed, exercise order, weekly frequency, range of repetitions, rest interval between sets and exercises, etc.) were maintained constant. The total load lifted was calculated for every RT session to compare the accumulated external training load among experimental groups across the intervention period. Testing was conducted before intervention (pre) and after 8-week (post-8) periods for maximal voluntary muscle strength (1 repetition maximum [1RM] test for bench press and parallel back squat exercises) and muscle thickness (MT) of the biceps brachii, triceps brachii, and vastus lateralis. The major findings were as follows: (a) all RT volumes increased bench press and parallel back squat 1RM and (b) all RT volumes increased the biceps brachii, triceps brachii, and vastus lateralis MT. The magnitude of increase in 1RM and MT of the lower body when training with 32 weekly sets per muscle group was higher than for 16 weekly sets per muscle group. The magnitude of the increase in MTTB was higher when training with 32 weekly sets than for 16 weekly sets.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2019 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brigatto</LastName><ForeName>Felipe A</ForeName><Initials>FA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Methodist University of Piracicaba, Human Performance Research Laboratory, Piracicaba, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhanguera University Center, Leme, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lima</LastName><ForeName>Leonardo Emmanuel de Medeiros</ForeName><Initials>LEM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Methodist University of Piracicaba, Human Performance Research Laboratory, Piracicaba, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Germano</LastName><ForeName>Mois&#xe9;s D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Methodist University of Piracicaba, Human Performance Research Laboratory, Piracicaba, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aoki</LastName><ForeName>Marcelo S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Arts, Sciences and Humanities, University of S&#xe3;o Paulo, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Braz</LastName><ForeName>Tiago V</ForeName><Initials>TV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Methodist University of Piracicaba, Human Performance Research Laboratory, Piracicaba, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lopes</LastName><ForeName>Charles R</ForeName><Initials>CR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Methodist University of Piracicaba, Human Performance Research Laboratory, Piracicaba, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Adventist Faculty of Hortol&#xe2;ndia, Hortol&#xe2;ndia, S&#xe3;o Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000222" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptation, Physiological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D052097" MajorTopicYN="N">Quadriceps Muscle</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31868813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202201000-00004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abe T, DeHoyos DV, Pollock ML, Garzarella L. Time course for strength and muscle thickness changes following upper and lower body resistance training in men and women. Eur J Appl Physiol 81: 174&#x2013;180, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baz-Valle E, Fontes-Villalba M, Santos-Concejero M. Total number of sets as a training volume quantification method for muscle hypertrophy: A systematic review. J Strength Cond Res 35: 870&#x2013;878, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brigatto FA, Braz TV, Zanini TCDC, et al. Effect of resistance training frequency on neuromuscular performance and muscle morphology after eight weeks in trained men. J Strength Cond Res 33: 2104&#x2013;2116, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claudino JG, Cronin JB, Amadio AC, Serr&#xe3;o JC. How can the training load be adjusted individually in athletes with an applied statistical approach? J Athl Enhanc 5: 1&#x2013;4, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva JJ, Schoenfeld BJ, Marchetti PN, et al. Muscle activation differs between partial and full back squat exercise with external load equated. J Strength Cond Res 31: 1688&#x2013;1693, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankel SJ, Mouser JG, Mattocks KT, et al. The widespread misuse of effect sizes. J Sci Med Sport 20: 446&#x2013;450, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eng J. Sample size estimation: How many individuals should be studied? Radiology 227: 309&#x2013;313, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueiredo VC, De Salles BF, Trajano GS. Volume for muscle hypertrophy and health outcomes: The most effective variable in resistance training. Sports Med 48: 499&#x2013;505, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Johnson NA, Chow CM. Training practices and ergogenic aids used by male bodybuilders. J Strength Cond Res 27: 1609&#x2013;1617, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heaselgrave SR, Blacker J, Smeuninx B, McKendry J, Breen L. Dose-response relationship of weekly resistance-training volume and frequency on muscular adaptations in trained men. Int J Sports Physiol Perform 14: 360&#x2013;368, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helms ER, Cronin J, Storey A, Zourdos MC. Application of the repetitions in reserve-based rating of perceived exertion scale for resistance training. Strength Cond J 38: 42&#x2013;49, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins WG, Marshall SW, Batterham AM, Hanin J. Progressive statistics for studies in sports medicine and exercise science. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 3&#x2013;13, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klemp A, Dolan C, Quiles JM, et al. Volume-equated high- and low-repetition daily undulating programming strategies produces similar hypertrophy and strength adaptations. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 41: 699&#x2013;705, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Hakkinen K, Triplett-McBride NT, et al. Physiological changes with periodized resistance training in women tennis players. Med Sci Sports Exerc 35: 157&#x2013;168, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW. Single versus multiple sets of resistance exercise: A meta-regression. J Strength Cond Res 23: 1890&#x2013;1901, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW. Single vs. multiple sets of resistance exercise for muscle hypertrophy: A meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 24: 1150&#x2013;1159, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall PW, McEwen M, Robbins DW. Strength and neuromuscular adaptation following one, four, and eight sets of high intensity resistance exercise in trained males. Eur J Appl Physiol 111: 3007&#x2013;3016, 2011 . 24: 1150-1159, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuigan M. Principles of test selection and administration. In: Baechle TR, Earle RW, eds. Essentials of Strength Training and Conditioning. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2008. pp. 249&#x2013;258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara R, Thiebaud RS, Loenneke JP, Loftin M, Abe T. Time course for arm and chest muscle thickness changes following bench press training. Interv Med Appl Sci 4: 217&#x2013;220, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostrowski K, Wilson GJ, Weatherby R, Murphy PW, Little AD. The effect of weight training volume on hormonal output and muscular size and function. J Strength Cond Res 11: 149&#x2013;154, 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padulo J, Laffaye G, Chaouachi A, Chamari K. Bench press exercise: The key points. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 55: 604&#x2013;608, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson MD, Rhea MR, Alvar BA. Applications of the dose-response for muscular strength development: A review of meta-analytic efficacy and reliability for designing training prescription. J Strength Cond Res 19: 950&#x2013;958, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radaelli R, Fleck SJ, Leite T, et al. Dose-response of 1, 3, and 5 sets of resistance exercise on strength, local muscular endurance, and hypertrophy. J Strength Cond Res 29: 1349&#x2013;1358, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston GW, Kilgore L, Wyatt FB, Baker JS. The effect of weekly set volume on strength gain: A meta-analysis. Sports Med 47: 2585&#x2013;2601, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratamess NA, Alvar BA, Evetoch TK, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position strand. Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc 41: 687&#x2013;708, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Alvar BA, Ball SD, Burkett LN. Three sets of weight training superior to 1 set with equal intensity for eliciting strength. J Strength Cond Res 16: 525&#x2013;529, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR, Alvar BA, Burkett LN, Ball SD. A meta-analysis to determine the dose response for strength development. Med Sci Sports Exerc 35: 456&#x2013;464, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;nnestad BR, Egeland W, Kvamme NH, et al. Dissimilar effects of one- and three-set strength training on strength and muscle mass gains in upper and lower body in untrained subjects. J Strength Cond Res 21: 157&#x2013;163, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Dose-response relationship between weekly resistance training volume and increases in muscle mass: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci 35: 1073&#x2013;1082, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Contreras B, Krieger J, et al. Resistance training volume enhances muscle hypertrophy but not strength in trained men. Med Sci Sports Exerc 51: 94&#x2013;103, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott BR, Duthie GM, Thornton HR, Dascombe BJ. Training monitoring for resistance exercise: Theory and applications. Sports Med 46: 687&#x2013;698, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira CVLE, Pereira EFM, Evangelista AL, et al. Is the weekly sets volume training performed by trained subjects in accordance with training recommendations guidelines for muscle hypertrophy? Motriz 24: 1&#x2013;6, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas JR, Nelson JK, Silverman SJ. Differences among groups. In: Research Methods in Physical Activity. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics, 2015. pp. 167&#x2013;200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Augustsson J, Thome&#xe9; R. The influence of frequency, intensity, volume and mode of strength training on whole muscle cross-sectional area in humans. Sports Med 37: 225&#x2013;264, 2007.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>