<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">25780086</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2015</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2051-817X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2015</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physiological reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Physiol Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Moderate alcohol consumption does not impair overload-induced muscle hypertrophy and protein synthesis.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e12333</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.14814/phy2.12333</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Chronic alcohol consumption leads to muscle weakness and atrophy in part by suppressing protein synthesis and mTORC1-mediated signaling. However, it is unknown whether moderate alcohol consumption also prevents overload-induced muscle growth and related anabolic signaling. Hypertrophy of the plantaris muscle was induced by removal of a section of the gastrocnemius and soleus muscles from one leg of C57BL/6 adult male mice while the contralateral leg remained intact as the sham control. A nutritionally complete alcohol-containing liquid diet (EtOH) or isocaloric, alcohol-free liquid diet (Con) was provided for 14&#xa0;days post-surgery. EtOH intake was increased progressively (day 1-5) before being maintained at ~20&#xa0;g/day/kg BW. The plantaris muscle from the sham and OL leg was removed after 14&#xa0;days at which time there was no difference in body weight between Con and EtOH-fed mice. OL increased muscle weight (90%) and protein synthesis (125%) in both Con and EtOH mice. The overload-induced increase in mTOR (Ser2448), 4E-BP1 (Thr37/46), S6K1 (Thr389), rpS6 (Ser240/244), and eEF2 (Thr56) were comparable in muscle from Con and EtOH mice. Modulation of signaling upstream of mTORC1 including REDD1 protein expression, Akt (Thr308), PRAS40 (Thr246), and ERK (Thr202/Tyr204) also did not differ between Con and EtOH mice. Markers of autophagy (ULK1, p62, and LC3) suggested inhibition of autophagy with overload and activation with alcohol feeding. These data show that moderate alcohol consumption does not impair muscle growth, and therefore imply that resistance exercise may be an effective therapeutic modality for alcoholic-related muscle disease.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2015 The Authors. Physiological Reports published by Wiley Periodicals, Inc. on behalf of the American Physiological Society and The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Steiner</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cellular and Molecular Physiology, Penn State College of Medicine, Hershey, Pennsylvania jls1075@psu.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gordon</LastName><ForeName>Bradley S</ForeName><Initials>BS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cellular and Molecular Physiology, Penn State College of Medicine, Hershey, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lang</LastName><ForeName>Charles H</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cellular and Molecular Physiology, Penn State College of Medicine, Hershey, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>F32 AA023422</GrantID><Acronym>AA</Acronym><Agency>NIAAA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R37 AA011290</GrantID><Acronym>AA</Acronym><Agency>NIAAA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Physiol Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101607800</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2051-817X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethanol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mTORC1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">overload</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein synthesis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2015</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25780086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4393167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.12333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">3/3/e12333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Anjum R. Blenis J. The RSK family of kinases: emerging roles in cellular signalling. Nat. Rev. Mol. Cell Biol. 2008;9:747&#x2013;758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18813292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baehr LM, Tunzi M. Bodine SC. Muscle hypertrophy is associated with increases in proteasome activity that is independent of MuRF1 and MAFbx expression. Front. Physiol. 2014;5:69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3930915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24600408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodine SC. Baar K. Analysis of skeletal muscle hypertrophy in models of increased loading. Methods Mol. Biol. 2012;798:213&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22130839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodine SC, Stitt TN, Gonzalez M, Kline WO, Stover GL, Bauerlein R, et al. Akt/mTOR pathway is a crucial regulator of skeletal muscle hypertrophy and can prevent muscle atrophy in&#xa0;vivo. Nat. Cell Biol. 2001;3:1014&#x2013;1019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11715023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browne GJ. Proud CG. Regulation of peptide-chain elongation in mammalian cells. Eur. J. Biochem. 2002;269:5360&#x2013;5368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12423334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estruch R, Nicol&#xe1;s JM, Villegas E, Junqu&#xe9; A. Urbano-M&#xe1;rquez A. Relationship between ethanol-related diseases and nutritional status in chronically alcoholic men. Alcohol Alcohol. 1993;28:543&#x2013;550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8274178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filiano AN, Millender-Swain T, Johnson R, Young ME, Gamble KL. Bailey SM. Chronic ethanol consumption disrupts the core molecular clock and diurnal rhythms of metabolic genes in the liver without affecting the suprachiasmatic nucleus. PLoS ONE. 2013;8:e71684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3741117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23951220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freund G. Alcohol consumption and its circadian distribution in mice. J. Nutr. 1970;100:30&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5460896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry CS, Drummond MJ, Glynn EL, Dickinson JM, Gundermann DM, Timmerman KL, et al. Skeletal muscle autophagy and protein breakdown following resistance exercise are similar in younger and older adults. J. Gerontol. A Biol. Sci. Med. Sci. 2013;68:599&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3623482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23089333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman CA. Hornberger TA. Measuring protein synthesis with SUnSET: a valid alternative to traditional techniques? Exerc. Sport Sci. Rev. 2013;41:107&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3951011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23089927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman CA, Mabrey DM, Frey JW, Miu MH, Schmidt EK, Pierre P, et al. Novel insights into the regulation of skeletal muscle protein synthesis as revealed by a new nonradioactive in&#xa0;vivo technique. FASEB J. 2011;25:1028&#x2013;1039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3042844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21148113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong-Brown LQ, Brown CR, Huber DS. Lang CH. Alcohol regulates eukaryotic elongation factor 2 phosphorylation via an AMP-activated protein kinase-dependent mechanism in C2C12 skeletal myocytes. J. Biol. Chem. 2007;282:3702&#x2013;3712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17164244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jelic P, Shih MF. Taberner PV. Diurnal variation in plasma ethanol levels of TO and CBA mice on chronic ethanol drinking or ethanol liquid diet schedules. Psychopharmacology. 1998;138:143&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9718283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanny D, Liu Y, Brewer RD, Lu H (CDC), C. F. D. C. A. P. Binge drinking - United States, 2011. MMWR Surveill. Summ. 2013;62(Suppl 3):77&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24264494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelleher AR, Kimball SR, Dennis MD, Schilder RJ. Jefferson LS. The mTORC1 signaling repressors REDD1/2 are rapidly induced and activation of p70S6K1 by leucine is defective in skeletal muscle of an immobilized rat hindlimb. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2013;304:E229&#x2013;E236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3543567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23193052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Kundu M, Viollet B. Guan KL. AMPK and mTOR regulate autophagy through direct phosphorylation of Ulk1. Nat. Cell Biol. 2011;13:132&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3987946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21258367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korzick DH, Sharda DR, Pruznak AM. Lang CH. Aging accentuates alcohol-induced decrease in protein synthesis in gastrocnemius. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 2013;304:R887&#x2013;R898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3652166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23535459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Frost RA. Lang CH. Alcohol impairs insulin and IGF-I stimulation of S6K1 but not 4E-BP1 in skeletal muscle. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2002;283:E917&#x2013;E928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12376318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang CH, Kimball SR, Frost RA. Vary TC. Alcohol myopathy: impairment of protein synthesis and translation initiation. Int. J. Biochem. Cell Biol. 2001;33:457&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11331201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang CH, Frost RA, Deshpande N, Kumar V, Vary TC, Jefferson LS, et al. Alcohol impairs leucine-mediated phosphorylation of 4E-BP1, S6K1, eIF4G, and mTOR in skeletal muscle. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2003;285:E1205&#x2013;E1215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12944322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang CH, Pruznak AM, Deshpande N, Palopoli MM, Frost RA. Vary TC. Alcohol intoxication impairs phosphorylation of S6K1 and S6 in skeletal muscle independently of ethanol metabolism. Alcohol. Clin. Exp. Res. 2004;28:1758&#x2013;1767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15547464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang CH, Frost RA. Vary TC. Skeletal muscle protein synthesis and degradation exhibit sexual dimorphism after chronic alcohol consumption but not acute intoxication. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2007;292:E1497&#x2013;E1506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17264221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang CH, Pruznak AM, Nystrom GJ. Vary TC. Alcohol-induced decrease in muscle protein synthesis associated with increased binding of mTOR and raptor: comparable effects in young and mature rats. Nutr. Metab. (Lond.) 2009;6:4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2651172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19154606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mammucari C, Milan G, Romanello V, Masiero E, Rudolf R, del Piccolo P, et al. FoxO3 controls autophagy in skeletal muscle in&#xa0;vivo. Cell Metab. 2007;6:458&#x2013;471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18054315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin FC. Peters TJ. Assessment in&#xa0;vitro and in&#xa0;vivo of muscle degradation in chronic skeletal muscle myopathy of alcoholism. Clin. Sci. (Lond.) 1985;68:693&#x2013;700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2485272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin F, Ward K, Slavin G, Levi J. Peters TJ. Alcoholic skeletal myopathy, a clinical and pathological study. Q. J. Med. 1985;55:233&#x2013;251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2991970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masiero E, Agatea L, Mammucari C, Blaauw B, Loro E, Komatsu M, et al. Autophagy is required to maintain muscle mass. Cell Metab. 2009;10:507&#x2013;515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19945408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGee SL, Mustard KJ, Hardie DG. Baar K. Normal hypertrophy accompanied by phosphoryation and activation of AMP-activated protein kinase alpha1 following overload in LKB1 knockout mice. J. Physiol. 2008;586:1731&#x2013;1741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2327866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18202101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazaki M, McCarthy JJ, Fedele MJ. Esser KA. Early activation of mTORC1 signalling in response to mechanical overload is independent of phosphoinositide 3-kinase/Akt signalling. J. Physiol. 2011;589:1831&#x2013;1846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3099033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21300751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pankiv S, Clausen TH, Lamark T, Brech A, Bruun JA, Outzen H, et al. p62/SQSTM1 binds directly to Atg8/LC3 to facilitate degradation of ubiquitinated protein aggregates by autophagy. J. Biol. Chem. 2007;282:24131&#x2013;24145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17580304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Schindler J, Summermatter S, Santos G, Zorzato F. Handschin C. The transcriptional coactivator PGC-1&#x3b1; is dispensable for chronic overload-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy and metabolic remodeling. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA. 2013;110:20314&#x2013;20319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3864298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24277823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roux PP, Shahbazian D, Vu H, Holz MK, Cohen MS, Taunton J, et al. RAS/ERK signaling promotes site-specific ribosomal protein S6 phosphorylation via RSK and stimulates cap-dependent translation. J. Biol. Chem. 2007;282:14056&#x2013;14064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3618456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17360704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sneddon AA, Koll M, Wallace MC, Jones J, Miell JP, Garlick PJ, et al. Acute alcohol administration inhibits the refeeding response after starvation in rat skeletal muscle. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 2003;284:E874&#x2013;E882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12388171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spangenburg EE, le Roith D, Ward CW. Bodine SC. A functional insulin-like growth factor receptor is not necessary for load-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy. J. Physiol. 2008;586:283&#x2013;291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2375552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17974583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steiner JL. Lang CH. Alcohol impairs skeletal muscle protein synthesis and mTOR signaling in a time-dependent manner following electrically stimulated muscle contraction. J. Appl. Physiol. (1985) 2014;117:1170&#x2013;1179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4233249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25257868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steiner J. Lang C. Alcohol intoxication following muscle contraction in mice decreases muscle protein synthesis but not mTOR signal transduction. Alcohol. Clin. Exp. Res. 2015;39:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4308817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25623400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thapaliya S, Runkana A, McMullen MR, Nagy LE, McDonald C, Prasad SV, et al. Alcohol-induced autophagy contributes to loss in skeletal muscle mass. Autophagy. 2014;10:677&#x2013;690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4091154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24492484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vargas R. Lang CH. Alcohol accelerates loss of muscle and impairs recovery of muscle mass resulting from disuse atrophy. Alcohol. Clin. Exp. Res. 2008;32:128&#x2013;137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18028527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X. Proud CG. The mTOR pathway in the control of protein synthesis. Physiology (Bethesda) 2006;21:362&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16990457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Li W, Williams M, Terada N, Alessi DR. Proud CG. Regulation of elongation factor 2 kinase by p90(RSK1) and p70 S6 kinase. EMBO J. 2001;20:4370&#x2013;4379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC125559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11500364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Zhang Q, Wen Q, Zheng Y, Lazarovici P, Philip L, et al. Proline-rich Akt substrate of 40&#xa0;kDa (PRAS40): a novel downstream target of PI3k/Akt signaling pathway. Cell. Signal. 2012;24:17&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21906675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widegren U, Ryder JW. Zierath JR. Mitogen-activated protein kinase signal transduction in skeletal muscle: effects of exercise and muscle contraction. Acta Physiol. Scand. 2001;172:227&#x2013;238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11472310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J, Brault JJ, Schild A, Cao P, Sandri M, Schiaffino S, et al. FoxO3 coordinately activates protein degradation by the autophagic/lysosomal and proteasomal pathways in atrophying muscle cells. Cell Metab. 2007;6:472&#x2013;483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18054316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng X, Liang Y, He Q, Yao R, Bao W, Bao L, et al. Current models of mammalian target of rapamycin complex 1 (mTORC1) activation by growth factors and amino acids. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2014;15:20753&#x2013;20769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4264194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25402640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>