<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">18188414</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0912-0009</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2007</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of clinical biochemistry and nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Biochem Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Abdominal Irradiation Ameliorates Obesity in ob/ob Mice.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>123</StartPage><EndPage>130</EndPage><MedlinePgn>123-30</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3164/jcbn.40.123</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Leptin-deficient ob/ob mice are a murine model for obesity, insulin resistance, and diabetes. Here we report that non-lethal abdominal irradiation (a single fraction of 850 cGy) to ob/ob mice retarded rapid gain of body weight, leading to amelioration of obesity without marked changes in food intake. This effect was observed only in ob/ob mice and not in lean controls. Reduction of body weight was accompanied by decreased adipose tissue weight without any marked change in the size of adipocytes, indicating prevention of hyperplasia rather than hypertrophy. Gene expression of the radiation-inducible cdk-inhibitor, p21, and the adipocytokines, tumor necrosis factor alpha and interleukin-1beta, were induced as expected; but genes involved in adipogenesis such as peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor gamma and adipsin were not affected in the irradiated adipose tissue. Inversely, hepatic lipid content was elevated with concomitant increases in the expression of lipogenic enzymes such as fatty acid synthase (FAS), and sterol regulatory element-binding protein 1c. Despite the decreased adiposity, there was no improvement in hyperglycemia and hyperinsulinemia after the irradiation. In conclusion, abdominal irradiation to ob/ob mice affected the progression of obesity and altered the energy metabolism between organs through a novel mechanism, implicating a new approach or factor for understanding and treatment of obesity.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okada</LastName><ForeName>Sumiyo</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine (Endocrinology and Metabolism), Graduate School of Comprehensive Human Sciences, University of Tsukuba, Tsukuba 305-8575, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kobayashi</LastName><ForeName>Kazuto</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ishikawa</LastName><ForeName>Mayumi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Inoue</LastName><ForeName>Noriyuki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamada</LastName><ForeName>Nobuhiro</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shimano</LastName><ForeName>Hitoshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Biochem Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8700907</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0912-0009</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">irradiation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">leptin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ob/ob mice</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">radiation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2006</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2006</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2008</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2008</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2008</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2007</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18188414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2127230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3164/jcbn.40.123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ingalls A.M., Dickie M.M., Snell G.D. Obese, a new mutation in the mouse. J. Hered. 1950;41:317&#x2013;318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14824537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Proenca R., Maffei M., Barone M., Leopold L., Friedman J.M. Positional cloning of the mouse obese gene and its human homologue. Nature. 1994;372:425&#x2013;432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7984236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiota G., Tsuchiya H. Pathophysiology of NASH: insulin resistance, free fatty acids and oxidative stress. J. Clin. Biochem. Nutr. 2006;38:127&#x2013;132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hotamisligil G.S., Shargill N.S., Spiegelman B.M. Adipose expression of tumor necrosis factor-alpha: direct role in obesity-linked insulin resistance. Science. 1993;259:87&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7678183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiegelman B.M., Flier J.S. Adipogenesis and obesity: rounding out the big picture. Cell. 1996;87:377&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8898192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H., Barnes G.T., Yang Q., Tan G., Yang D., Chou C.J., Sole J., Nichols A., Ross J.S., Tartaglia L.A., Chen H. Chronic inflammation in fat plays a crucial role in the development of obesity-related insulin resistance. J. Clin. Invest. 2003;112:1821&#x2013;1830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC296998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14679177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wellen K.E., Hotamisligil G.S. Obesity-induced inflammatory changes in adipose tissue. J. Clin. Invest. 2003;112:1785&#x2013;1788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC297006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14679172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakagawa Y., Shimano H., Yoshikawa T., Ide T., Tamura M., Furusawa M., Yamamoto T., Inoue N., Matsuzaka T., Takahashi A., Hasty A.H., Suzuki H., Sone H., Toyoshima H., Yahagi N., Yamada N. TFE3 transcriptionally activates hepatic IRS-2, participates in insulin signaling and ameliorates diabetes. Nat. Med. 2006;12:107&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16327801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagy T.R., Clair A.L. Precision and accuracy of dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry for determining in vivo body composition of mice. Obes. Res. 2000;8:392&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10968731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue N., Shimano H., Nakakuki M., Matsuzaka T., Nakagawa Y., Yamamoto T., Sato R., Takahashi A., Sone H., Yahagi N., Suzuki H., Toyoshima H., Yamada N. Lipid synthetic transcription factor SREBP-1a activates p21WAF1/CIP1, a universal cyclin-dependent kinase inhibitor. Mol. Cell Biol. 2005;25:8938&#x2013;8947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1265776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16199872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuzaka T., Shimano H., Yahagi N., Amemiya-Kudo M., Okazaki H., Tamura Y., Iizuka Y., Ohashi K., Tomita S., Sekiya M., Hasty A., Nakagawa Y., Sone H., Toyoshima H., Ishibashi S., Osuga J., Yamada N. Insulin-independent induction of sterol regulatory element-binding protein-1c expression in the livers of streptozotocin-treated mice. Diabetes. 2004;53:560&#x2013;569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14988238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisberg S.P., McCann D., Desai M., Rosenbaum M., Leibel R.L., Ferrante A.W.Jr. Obesity is associated with macrophage accumulation in adipose tissue. J. Clin. Invest. 2003;112:1796&#x2013;1808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC296995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14679176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimano H., Yahagi N., Amemiya-Kudo M., Hasty A.H., Osuga J., Tamura Y., Shionoiri F., Iizuka Y., Ohashi K., Harada K., Gotoda T., Ishibashi S., Yamada N. Sterol regulatory element-binding protein-1 as a key transcription factor for nutritional induction of lipogenic enzyme genes. J. Biol. Chem. 1999;274:35832&#x2013;35839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10585467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimano H. Sterol regulatory element-binding protein family as global regulators of lipid synthetic genes in energy metabolism. Vitam. Horm. 2002;65:167&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12481547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>el-Deiry W.S., Tokino T., Velculescu V.E., Levy D.B., Parsons R., Trent J.M., Lin D., Mercer W.E., Kinzler K.W., Vogelstein B. WAF1, a potential mediator of p53 tumor suppression. Cell. 1993;75:817&#x2013;825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8242752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harper J.W., Adami G.R., Wei N., Keyomarsi K., Elledge S.J. The p21 Cdk-interacting protein Cip1 is a potent inhibitor of G1 cyclin-dependent kinases. Cell. 1993;75:805&#x2013;816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8242751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yahagi N., Shimano H., Matsuzaka T., Najima Y., Sekiya M., Nakagawa Y., Ide T., Tomita S., Okazaki H., Tamura Y., Iizuka Y., Ohashi K., Gotoda T., Nagai R., Kimura S., Ishibashi S., Osuga J., Yamada N. p53 Activation in adipocytes of obese mice. J. Biol. Chem. 2003;278:25395&#x2013;25400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12734185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yahagi N., Shimano H., Matsuzaka T., Sekiya M., Najima Y., Okazaki S., Okazaki H., Tamura Y., Iizuka Y., Inoue N., Nakagawa Y., Takeuchi Y., Ohashi K., Harada K., Gotoda T., Nagai R., Kadowaki T., Ishibashi S., Osuga J., Yamada N. p53 involvement in the pathogenesis of fatty liver disease. J. Biol. Chem. 2004;279:20571&#x2013;20575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14985341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon J., Bradwin G., Cocchia M.A., Coffey D., Condon T., Garrity W., Grieco W. Effects of adrenalectomy on body weight and hyperglycemia in five months old Ob/Ob mice. Horm. Metab. Res. 1977;9:152&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">863380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittmers L.E.Jr., Haller E.W. Effect of adrenalectomy on the metabolism of glucose in obese (C57 Bl/6J ob/ob) mice. Metabolism. 1983;32:1093&#x2013;1100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6645960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohshima K., Shargill N.S., Chan T.M., Bray G.A. Adrenalectomy reverses insulin resistance in muscle from obese (ob/ob) mice. Am. J. Physiol. 1984;246:E193&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6421176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saito M., Bray G.A. Adrenalectomy and food restriction in the genetically obese (ob/ob) mouse. Am. J. Physiol. 1984;246:R20&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6421174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldkircher K.M., Mistry A.M., Romsos D.R. Adrenalectomy reverses pre-existing obesity in adult genetically obese (ob/ob) mice. Int. J. Obes. Relat. Metab. Disord. 1996;20:232&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8653144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakae J., Kitamura T., Kitamura Y., Biggs W.H., 3rd, Arden. K.C., Accili D. The forkhead transcription factor Foxo1 regulates adipocyte differentiation. Dev. Cell. 2003;4:119&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12530968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S., Lin H.Z., Hwang J., Chacko V.P., Diehl A.M. Hepatic hyperplasia in noncirrhotic fatty livers: is obesity-related hepatic steatosis a premalignant condition? Cancer Res. 2001;61:5016&#x2013;5023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11431335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson C.I., Kreider J.W., Margules D.L. Food intake during tumor growth: anorexia in genetically obese ob/ob mice and hyperphagia in lean mice. Physiol. Behav. 1984;32:935&#x2013;939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6593752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>