<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38687626</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evidence for Simultaneous Muscle Atrophy and Hypertrophy in Response to Resistance Training in Humans.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1634</StartPage><EndPage>1643</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1634-1643</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003475</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Human skeletal muscle has the profound ability to hypertrophy in response to resistance training (RT). However, this has a high energy and protein cost and is presumably mainly restricted to recruited muscles. It remains largely unknown what happens with nonrecruited muscles during RT. This study investigated the volume changes of 17 recruited and 13 nonrecruited muscles during a 10-wk single-joint RT program targeting upper arm and upper leg musculature.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Muscle volume changes were measured by manual or automatic 3D segmentation in 21 RT novices. Subjects ate ad libitum during the study and energy and protein intake were assessed by self-reported diaries.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Posttraining, all recruited muscles increased in volume (range: +2.2% to +17.7%, P &lt; 0.05), whereas the nonrecruited adductor magnus (mean: -1.5% &#xb1; 3.1%, P = 0.038) and soleus (-2.4% &#xb1; 2.3%, P = 0.0004) decreased in volume. Net muscle growth ( r = 0.453, P = 0.045) and changes in adductor magnus volume ( r = 0.450, P = 0.047) were positively associated with protein intake. Changes in total nonrecruited muscle volume ( r = 0.469, P = 0.037), adductor magnus ( r = 0.640, P = 0.002), adductor longus ( r = 0.465, P = 0.039), and soleus muscle volume ( r = 0.481, P = 0.032) were positively related to energy intake. When subjects were divided into a HIGH or LOW energy intake group, overall nonrecruited muscle volume (-1.7% &#xb1; 2.0%), adductor longus (-5.6% &#xb1; 3.7%), adductor magnus (-2.8% &#xb1; 2.4%), and soleus volume (-3.7% &#xb1; 1.8%) decreased significantly ( P &lt; 0.05) in the LOW but not the HIGH group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">To our knowledge, this is the first study documenting that some nonrecruited muscles significantly atrophy during a period of RT. Our data therefore suggest muscle mass reallocation, that is, that hypertrophy in recruited muscles takes place at the expense of atrophy in nonrecruited muscles, especially when energy and protein availability are limited.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>VAN Vossel</LastName><ForeName>Kim</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement and Sports Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, BELGIUM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hardeel</LastName><ForeName>Julie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement and Sports Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, BELGIUM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>VAN DER Stede</LastName><ForeName>Thibaux</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cools</LastName><ForeName>Tom</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Integrative Metabolomics, Department of Translational Physiology, Infectiology and Public Health, Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, Ghent University, BELGIUM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vandecauter</LastName><ForeName>Jonas</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement and Sports Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, BELGIUM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vanhaecke</LastName><ForeName>Lynn</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boone</LastName><ForeName>Jan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement and Sports Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, BELGIUM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blemker</LastName><ForeName>Silvia Salinas</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lievens</LastName><ForeName>Eline</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement and Sports Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, BELGIUM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Derave</LastName><ForeName>Wim</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Movement and Sports Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, BELGIUM.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004044">Dietary Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009133" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscular Atrophy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004044" MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002149" MajorTopicYN="N">Energy Intake</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001132" MajorTopicYN="N">Arm</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007866" MajorTopicYN="N">Leg</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38687626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202409000-00009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zihlman AL, Bolter DR. Body composition in pan paniscus compared with Homo sapiens has implications for changes during human evolution. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A . 2015;112(24):7466&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Neill MC, Umberger BR, Holowka NB, Larson SG, Reiser PJ. Chimpanzee super strength and human skeletal muscle evolution. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A . 2017;114(28):7343&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slater GJ, Dieter BP, Marsh DJ, Helms ER, Shaw G, Iraki J. Is an energy surplus required to maximize skeletal muscle hypertrophy associated with resistance training. Front Nutr . 2019;6:131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Tipton KD, Aarsland A, Wolf SE, Wolfe RR. Mixed muscle protein synthesis and breakdown after resistance exercise in humans. Am J Physiol . 1997;273(1 Pt 1):E99&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozenek R, Ward P, Long S, Garhammer J. Effects of high-calorie supplements on body composition and muscular strength following resistance training. J Sports Med Phys Fitness . 2002;42(3):340&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro AS, Nunes JP, Schoenfeld BJ, Aguiar AF, Cyrino ES. Effects of different dietary energy intake following resistance training on muscle mass and body fat in bodybuilders: a pilot study. J Hum Kinet . 2019;70:125&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemmer JT, Ivey FM, Ryan AS, et al. Effect of strength training on resting metabolic rate and physical activity: age and gender comparisons. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2001;33(4):532&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aristizabal JC, Freidenreich DJ, Volk BM, et al. Effect of resistance training on resting metabolic rate and its estimation by a dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry metabolic map. Eur J Clin Nutr . 2015;69(7):831&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacKenzie-Shalders K, Kelly JT, So D, Coffey VG, Byrne NM. The effect of exercise interventions on resting metabolic rate: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sports Sci . 2020;38(14):1635&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolfe DF, Brown GC. Cellular energy utilization and molecular origin of standard metabolic rate in mammals. Physiol Rev . 1997;77(3):731&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Hulst G, Deldicque L. Human skeletal muscle wasting in hypoxia: a matter of hypoxic dose? J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2017;122(2):406&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speth JD, Spielmann KA. Energy source, protein metabolism, and hunter-gatherer subsistence strategies. J Anthropol Archeol . 1983;2(1):1&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Areta JL, Burke LM, Camera DM, et al. Reduced resting skeletal muscle protein synthesis is rescued by resistance exercise and protein ingestion following short-term energy deficit. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab . 2014;306(8):E989&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hector AJ, McGlory C, Damas F, Mazara N, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Pronounced energy restriction with elevated protein intake results in no change in proteolysis and reductions in skeletal muscle protein synthesis that are mitigated by resistance exercise. FASEB J . 2018;32(1):265&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DWD, Kujbida GW, Moore DR, et al. Resistance exercise&#x2013;induced increases in putative anabolic hormones do not enhance muscle protein synthesis or intracellular signalling in young men. J Physiol . 2009;587(21):5239&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Sato K, Gallaugher MPB, et al. Muscle androgen receptor content but not systemic hormones is associated with resistance training-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy in healthy, young men. Front Physiol . 2018;9:1373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni R, Meyer CH, Blemker SS, Hart JM, Feng X. Automatic segmentation of all lower limb muscles from high-resolution magnetic resonance imaging using a cascaded three-dimensional deep convolutional neural network. J Med Imaging (Bellingham) . 2019;6(4):044009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handsfield GG, Meyer CH, Hart JM, Abel MF, Blemker SS. Relationships of 35 lower limb muscles to height and body mass quantified using MRI. J Biomech . 2014;47(3):631&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Vossel K, Hardeel J, Van de Casteele F, et al. Can muscle typology explain the inter-individual variability in resistance training adaptations? J Physiol . 2023;601(12):2307&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kissow J, Jacobsen KJ, Gunnarsson TP, Jessen S, Hostrup M. Effects of follicular and luteal phase-based menstrual cycle resistance training on muscle strength and mass. Sports Med . 2022;52(12):2813&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durnin JVGA, Rahaman MM. The assessment of the amount of fat in the human body from measurements of skinfold thickness. Br J Nutr . 1967;21(3):681&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yushkevich PA, Piven J, Hazlett HC, et al. User-guided 3D active contour segmentation of anatomical structures: significantly improved efficiency and reliability. Neuroimage . 2006;31(3):1116&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Mee&#xfb;s D&#x2019;Argenteuil C, Boshuizen B, Oosterlinck M, et al. Flexibility of equine bioenergetics and muscle plasticity in response to different types of training: an integrative approach, questioning existing paradigms. PLoS One . 2021;16(4):e0249922.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hides J, Stanton W. Muscle imbalance among elite Australian rules football players: a longitudinal study of changes in trunk muscle size. J Athl Train . 2012;47(3):314&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rader EP, Naimo MA, Ensey J, Baker BA. Agonist muscle adaptation accompanied by antagonist muscle atrophy in the hindlimb of mice following stretch-shortening contraction training. BMC Musculoskelet Disord . 2017;18(1):60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinheimer EM, Sands LP, Campbellnure WW. A systematic review of the separate and combined effects of energy restriction and exercise on fat-free mass in middle-aged and older adults: implications for sarcopenic obesity. Nutr Rev . 2010;68(7):375&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbone JW, McClung JP, Pasiakos SM. Recent advances in the characterization of skeletal muscle and whole-body protein responses to dietary protein and exercise during negative energy balance. Adv Nutr . 2019;10(1):70&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM. Protein requirements and supplementation in strength sports. Nutrition . 2004;20(7&#x2013;8):689&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasiakos SM, Vislocky LM, Carbone JW, et al. Acute energy deprivation affects skeletal muscle protein synthesis and associated intracellular signaling proteins in physically active adults. J Nutr . 2010;140(4):745&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbone JW, Pasiakos SM, Vislocky LM, Anderson JM, Rodriguez NR. Effects of short-term energy deficit on muscle protein breakdown and intramuscular proteolysis in normal-weight young adults. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab . 2014;39(8):960&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick CM, Wilborn CD, Roberts MD, et al. ISSN exercise &amp; sports nutrition review update: research &amp; recommendations. J Int Soc Sports Nutr . 2018;15(1):38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW, Sitren HS, Daniels MJ, Langkamp-Henken B. Effects of variation in protein and carbohydrate intake on body mass and composition during energy restriction: a meta-regression. Am J Clin Nutr . 2006;83(2):260&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasiakos SM, Cao JJ, Margolis LM, et al. Effects of high-protein diets on fat-free mass and muscle protein synthesis following weight loss: a randomized controlled trial. FASEB J . 2013;27(9):3837&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rand WM, Pellett PL, Young VR. Meta-analysis of nitrogen balance studies for estimating protein requirements in healthy adults. Am J Clin Nutr . 2003;77(1):109&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Murphy KT, McKellar SR, et al. A systematic review, meta-analysis and meta-regression of the effect of protein supplementation on resistance training-induced gains in muscle mass and strength in healthy adults. Br J Sports Med . 2018;52(6):376&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes EA, Colenso-Semple L, McKellar SR, et al. Systematic review and meta-analysis of protein intake to support muscle mass and function in healthy adults. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle . 2022;13(2):795&#x2013;810.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mettler S, Mitchell N, Tipton KD. Increased protein intake reduces lean body mass loss during weight loss in athletes. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 2010;42(2):326&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mourier A, Bigard AX, de Kerviler E, Roger B, Legrand H, Guezennec CY. Combined effects of caloric restriction and branched-chain amino acid supplementation on body composition and exercise performance in elite wrestlers. Int J Sports Med . 1997;18(1):47&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson AG, Alexander L, Witard OC, Coughlin TE, Tipton KD, Walshe IH. A hypoenergetic diet with decreased protein intake does not reduce lean body mass in trained females. Eur J Appl Physiol . 2021;121(3):771&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walberg JL, Leidy MK, Sturgill DJ, Hinkle DE, Ritchey SJ, Sebolt DR. Macronutrient content of a hypoenergy diet affects nitrogen retention and muscle function in weight lifters. Int J Sports Med . 1988;9(4):261&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe4;estu J, Eliakim A, J&#xfc;rim&#xe4;e J, Valter I, J&#xfc;rimae T. Anabolic and catabolic hormones and energy balance of the male bodybuilders during the preparation for the competition. J Strength Cond Res . 2010;24(4):1074&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mero AA, Huovinen H, Matintupa O, et al. Moderate energy restriction with high protein diet results in healthier outcome in women. J Int Soc Sports Nutr . 2010;7(1):4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garthe I, Raastad T, Refsnes PE, Koivisto A, Sundgot-borgen J. Effect of two different weight-loss rates on body composition and strength and power-related performance in elite athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 2011;21(2):97&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Josse AR, Atkinson SA, Tarnopolsky MA, Phillips SM. Increased consumption of dairy foods and protein during diet- and exercise-induced weight loss promotes fat mass loss and lean mass gain in overweight and obese premenopausal women. J Nutr . 2011;141(9):1626&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longland TM, Oikawa SY, Mitchell CJ, DeVries MC, Phillips SM. Higher compared with lower dietary protein during an energy deficit combined with intense exercise promotes greater lean mass gain and fat mass loss: a randomized trial. Am J Clin Nutr . 2016;103(3):738&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hector AJ, Phillips SM. Protein recommendations for weight loss in elite athletes: a focus on body composition and performance. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 2018;28(2):170&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biolo G, Zhang XJ, Wolfe RR. Role of membrane transport in interorgan amino acid flow between muscle and small intestine. Metabolism . 1995;44(6):719&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond MJ, Fry CS, Glynn EL, et al. Skeletal muscle amino acid transporter expression is increased in young and older adults following resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2011;111(1):135&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steenberg DE, Hingst JR, Birk JB, et al. A single bout of one-legged exercise to local exhaustion decreases insulin action in nonexercised muscle leading to decreased whole-body insulin action. Diabetes . 2020;69(4):578&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Hulst G, Masschelein E, De Bock K. Resistance exercise enhances long-term mTORC1 sensitivity to leucine. Mol Metab . 2022;66:101615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sj&#xf8;gaard G. Capillary supply and cross-sectional area of slow and fast twitch muscle fibres in man. Histochemistry . 1982;76(4):547&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickiewicz TL, Roy RR, Powell PL, Edgerton VR. Muscle architecture of the human lower limb. Clin Orthop Relat Res . 1983;179:275&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friederich JA, Brand RA. Muscle fiber architecture in the human lower limb. J Biomech . 1990;23(1):91&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voronov AV. Anatomical cross-sectional areas and volumes of the lower extremity muscles. Fiziol Cheloveka . 2003;29(2):81&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takizawa M, Suzuki D, Ito H, Fujimiya M, Uchiyama E. Why adductor magnus muscle is large: the function based on muscle morphology in cadavers. Scand J Med Sci Sports . 2014;24(1):197&#x2013;203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miokovic T, Armbrecht G, Felsenberg D, Belav&#xfd; DL. Heterogeneous atrophy occurs within individual lower limb muscles during 60 days of bed rest. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2012;113(10):1545&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kehler DS, Theou O, Rockwood K. Bed rest and accelerated aging in relation to the musculoskeletal and cardiovascular systems and frailty biomarkers: a review. Exp Gerontol . 2019;124:110643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y, Arfat Y, Wang H, Goswami N. Muscle atrophy induced by mechanical unloading: mechanisms and potential countermeasures. Front Physiol . 2018;9:235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson MA, Polgar J, Weightman D, Appleton D. Data on the distribution of fibre types in thirty-six human muscles. An autopsy study. J Neurol Sci . 1973;18(1):111&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrett WE Jr, Califf JC, Bassett FH 3rd. Histochemical correlates of hamstring injuries. Am J Sports Med . 1984;12(2):98&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magkos F, Yannakoulia M. Methodology of dietary assessment in athletes: concepts and pitfalls. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care . 2003;6(5):539&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livingstone MB, Black AE. Markers of the validity of reported energy intake. J Nutr . 2003;133 Suppl 3:895S&#x2013;920S.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll TJ, Herbert RD, Munn J, Lee M, Gandevia SC. Contralateral effects of unilateral strength training: evidence and possible mechanisms. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2006;101(5):1514&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munn J, Herbert RD, Gandevia SC. Contralateral effects of unilateral resistance training: a meta-analysis. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2004;96(5):1861&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norman K, Pichard C, Lochs H, Pirlich M. Prognostic impact of disease-related malnutrition. Clin Nutr . 2008;27(1):5&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal E, Miller M, Yaxley A, Isenring E. Malnutrition in the elderly: a narrative review. Maturitas . 2013;76(4):296&#x2013;302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mareschal J, Achamrah N, Norman K, Genton L. Clinical value of muscle mass assessment in clinical conditions associated with malnutrition. J Clin Med . 2019;8(7):1040.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>