<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">26889130</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2016</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1661-7649</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2015</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current urology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Urol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Polyuria on Bladder Function in Diabetics versus Non-Diabetics: An Article Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>119</StartPage><EndPage>125</EndPage><MedlinePgn>119-25</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1159/000365702</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To review studies that investigated the role of polyuria on bladder function.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We performed a search of the English literature through PubMed. We only included animal studies that assessed parameters of bladder function and had compared diabetic and non-diabetic polyuric animals.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Fluid intake and urine output were increased in diabetic and polyuric animals; failure to appropriately gain weight was seen in diabetics only. All but 1 study reported increase in bladder weight in both groups. In cystometrograms, control mice showed reductions in basal bladder pressure over time, whereas diabetic and diuretic groups stabilized or increased. Both groups showed larger bladder capacity. Overall, many characteristic changes in cystometrographic studies in diabetic animals could be attributed to polyuria. In histological studies, bladder hypertrophy, increase in smooth muscle and urothelium, and increase in protein and DNA content per bladder were observed in diuretic and diabetic rats. Actual collagen cross-sectional area did not change during the progression of diabetes or diuresis but decreased over time in both groups as a percentage of total tissue area. Both groups expressed less type I collagen mRNA and TGF-beta-1 mRNA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Although lower urinary tract changes in anatomy and function in diabetic patients might arise from a number of causes, polyuria seems to play an important causative role.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fathollahi</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Urology Institute, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, OH., USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daneshgari</LastName><ForeName>Firouz</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Urology Institute, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, OH., USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hanna-Mitchell</LastName><ForeName>Ann T</ForeName><Initials>AT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Urology Institute, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, OH., USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2015</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Urol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101471188</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1661-7649</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bladder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Polyuria</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2015</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2015</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2016</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2016</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26889130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4748805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000365702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">cur-0008-0119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mokdad AH, Ford ES, Bowman BA, Nelson DE, Engelgau MM, Vinicor F, Marks JS. The continuing increase of diabetes in the US. Diabetes Care. 2001;24:412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11213906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention National diabetes fact sheet National estimates and general information on diabetes and prediabetes in the United States, 2011. Atlanta, GA, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown JS, Wessells H, Chancellor MB, Howards SS, Stamm WE, Stapleton AE, Steers WD, Van Den Eeden SK, McVary KT. Urologic complications of diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2005;28:177&#x2013;185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15616253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baneerjee MK, Das AK, Basha A, Ganesan TS, Chandrasekhar S. Reversibility of diabetic bladder dysfunction with early and good control. J Assoc Physicians India. 1985;33:337&#x2013;338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4044498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daneshgari F, Liu G, Birder L, Hanna-Mitchell AT, Chacko S. Diabetic bladder dysfunction: current translational knowledge. J Urol. 2009;182(6 suppl):S18&#x2013;S26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4684267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19846137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moller CF. Diabetic cystopathy. I: A clinical study of the frequency of bladder dysfunction in diabetics. Dan Med Bull. 1976;23:267&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1009795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moller CF. Diabetic cystopathy. II: Relationship to some late-diabetic manifestations. Dan Med Bull. 1976;23:279&#x2013;287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1009796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moller CF. Diabetic cystopathy. III: Urinary bladder dysfunction in relation to bacteriuria. Dan Med Bull. 1976;23:287&#x2013;291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1009797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frimodt-Moller C. Diabetic cystopathy. A review of the urodynamic and clinical features of neurogenic bladder dysfunction in diabetes mellitus. Dan Med Bull. 1978;25:49&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">344005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan SA, Blaivas JG. Diabetic cystopathy. J Diabet Complications. 1988;2:133&#x2013;139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2975663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G, Daneshgari F. Diabetic bladder dysfunction. Chin Med J (Engl) 2014;127:1357&#x2013;1364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4426965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24709194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tammela TLJ, Leggett RE, Levin RM, Longhurst PA. Temporal changes in micturition and bladder contractility after sucrose dieresis and streptozotocin-induced diabetes mellitus in rats. J Urol. 1995;153:2014&#x2013;2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7752386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kudlacz EM, Chun AL, Skau KA, Gerald MC, Wallace LJ. Diabetes and diuretic-Induced alterations in function of rat urinary bladder. Diabetes. 1988;37:949&#x2013;955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3384189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levin RM, Wein AJ, Eika B, Tammela TL, Longhurst PA. Effects of diuresis on micturition. Neurourol Urodyn. 1995;14:169&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7780442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G, Daneshgari F. Temporal diabetes- and diuresis-induced remodeling of the urinary bladder in the rat. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2006;291:R837&#x2013;R843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16513765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eika B, Levin RM, Longhurst PA. Comparison of urinary bladder function in rats with hereditary diabetes insipidus, streptozotocin-induced diabetes mellitus, and nondiabetic osmotic diuresis. J Urol. 1994;151:496&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8283565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao N, Wang Z, Huang Y, Daneshgari F, Liu G. Roles of polyuria and hyperglycemia in bladder dysfunction in diabetes. J Urol. 2013;189:1130&#x2013;1136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4104602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22999997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malmgren A, Andersson PO, Uvelius B. Bladder function in rats with short- and long-term diabetes; effects of age and muscarinic blockade. J Urol. 1989;142:1608&#x2013;1614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2585645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daneshgari F, Huang X, Liu G, Bena J, Saffore L, Powell CT. Temporal differences in bladder dysfunction caused by diabetes, diuresis, and treated diabetes in mice. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2006;290:R1728&#x2013;R1735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16439670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray MA, Wang CC, Sacks MS, Yoshimura N, Chancellor MB, Nagatomi J. Time-dependent alterations of select genes in streptozotocin-induced diabetic rat bladder. Urology. 2008;71:1214&#x2013;1219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18279932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukomoto Y, Yoshida M, Weiss RM, Latifpour J. Reversibility of diabetes- and diuresis-induced alterations in rat bladder dome muscarinic receptors. Diabetes. 1994;43:819&#x2013;826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8194669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CC, Nagatomi J, Toosi KK, Yoshimura N, Hsieh JH, Chancellor MB, Sacks MS. Diabetes-induced alternations in the biomechanical properties of the urinary bladder wall in rats. Urology. 2009;73:911&#x2013;915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2728502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19168204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter FG. Impairment and restoration of rat urinary bladder responsiveness following distension. Am J Physiol. 1983;244:R106&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6849410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malmgren A, Uvelius B, Andersson KE, Andersson PO. Urinary bladder function in rats with hereditary diabetes insipidus; a cystometrical and in vitro evaluation. J Urol. 1992;148:930&#x2013;934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1512862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santicioli P, Gamse R, Maggi CA, Meli A. Cystometric changes in the early phase of streptozotocin-induced diabetes in rats: evidence for sensory changes not correlated to diabetic neuropathy. Naunyn Schmiedebergs Arch Pharmacol. 1987;335:580&#x2013;587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3614389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan SA, Te AE, Blaivas JG. Urodynamic findings in patients with diabetic cystopathy. J Urol. 1995;153:342&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7815578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starer P, Libow L. Cystometric evaluation of bladder dysfunction in elderly diabetic patients. Arch Intern Med. 1990;150:810&#x2013;813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2327841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>