<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">12734561</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1480-9222</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>5</Volume><PubDate><Year>2003</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biological procedures online</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Proced Online</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Experimental Assessment of the Role of Acetaldehyde in Alcoholic Cardiomyopathy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>12</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-12</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Alcoholism is one of the major causes of non-ischemic heart damage. The myopathic state of the heart due to alcohol consumption, namely alcoholic cardiomyopathy, is manifested by cardiac hypertrophy, compromised ventricular contractility and cardiac output. Several mechanisms have been postulated for alcoholic cardiomyopathy including oxidative damage, accumulation of triglycerides, altered fatty acid extraction, decreased myofilament Ca(2+ )sensitivity, and impaired protein synthesis. Despite intensive efforts to unveil the mechanism and ultimate toxin responsible for alcohol-induced cardiac toxicity, neither has been clarified thus far. Primary candidates for the specific toxins are ethanol, its first and major metabolic product - acetaldehyde (ACA) and fatty acid ethyl esters. Evidence from our lab suggests that ACA directly impairs cardiac function and promotes lipid peroxidation resulting in oxidative damage. The ACA-induced cardiac contractile depression may be reconciled with inhibitors of Cytochrome P-450 oxidase, xanthine oxidase and lipid peroxidation Unfortunately, the common methods to investigate the toxicity of ACA have been hampered by the fact that direct intake of ACA is toxic and unsuitable for chronic study, which is unable to provide direct evidence of direct cardiac toxicity for ACA. In order to overcome this obstacle associated with the chemical properties of ACA, our laboratory has used the chronic ethanol feeding model in transgenic mice with cardiac over-expression of alcohol dehydrogenase (ADH) and an in vitro ventricular myocyte culture model. The combination of both in vivo and in vitro approaches allows us to evaluate the role of ACA in ethanol-induced cardiac toxicity and certain cellular signaling pathways leading to alcoholic cardiomyopathy.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aberle II</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas S.</ForeName><Initials>NS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, Physiology and Therapeutics, University of North Dakota School of Medicine and Health Sciences. Grand Forks, ND 58203. USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2003</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Proced Online</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100963717</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1480-9222</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2002</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2002</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2002</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2003</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2003</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2003</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2003</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12734561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC150386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1251/bpo41</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Sola J, Estruch R, Grau JM, Pare JC, Rubin E, Urbano-Marquez A. The relation of alcoholic myopathy to cardiomyopathy. Ann Intl Med. 1994;120:529&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8116990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel VB, Why HJ, Richardson PJ, Preedy VR. The effects of alcohol on the heart. Adverse Drug React Toxicol Rev. 1997;16:15&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9192055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson PJ, Patel VB, Preedy VR. Alcohol and the myocardium. Novartis Found Symp. 1998;216:35&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9949786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preedy VR, Patel VB, Reilly ME, Richardson PJ, Falkous G, Mantle D. Oxidants, antioxidants and alcohol: implications for skeletal and cardiac muscle. Front Biosci. 1999;4:e58&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10430553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laposata EA, Lange LG. Presence of nonoxidative ethanol metabolism in human organs commonly damaged by ethanol abuse. Science. 1986;231:497&#x2013;499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3941913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espinet C, Argiles JM. Ethanol and acetaldehyde levels in rat blood and tissues after an acute ethanol administration. IRCS Med Sci. 1984;12:830&#x2013;831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren J, Davidoff AJ, Brown RA. Acetaldehyde depresses shortening and intracellular Ca2+ transients in adult rat ventricular myocytes. Cell Mol Biol. 1997;43:825&#x2013;834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9359629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown RA, Jefferson L, Sudan N, Lloyd LC, Ren J. Acetaldehyde depresses myocardial contraction and cardiac myocyte shortening in spontaneously hypertensive rats: Role of intracellular Ca2+. Cell Mol Biol. 1999;45:453&#x2013;465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10432192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren J, Wold LE, Epstein PN. Diabetes enhances acetaldehyde-induced depression of cardiac myocyte contraction. Biochem Biophys Res Comm. 2000;269:697&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10720479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren J, Brown RA. Influence of chronic alcohol ingestion on acetaldehyde-induced depression of cardiac contractile function. Alcohol Alcoholism. 2000;35:554&#x2013;560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11093961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leiber C, Barona E, Leo M, Garro A. Effect of chronic alcohol consumption on the metabolism of ethanol. Prog Clin Biochem Res. 1987;241:161&#x2013;172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3615512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida A. Molecular genetics of human aldehyde dehydrogenase. Pharmacogenetics. 1992;2:139&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1306115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preedy VR, Richardson PJ. Ethanol induced cardiovascular disease. Br Med Bull. 1994;50:152&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8149190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown RA, Crawford M, Natavio M, Petrovski P, Ren J. Dietary magnesium supplementation attenuates ethanol-induced myocardial dysfunction. Alcohol Clin Exp Res. 1998;22:2062&#x2013;2072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9884152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Carli LM, Leiber CS. Fatty liver in the rat after prolonged intake of ethanol with a nutritionally adequate new liquid diet. J Nutrit. 1967;91:331&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6021815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keane B, Leonard BE. Rodent models of alcoholism: a review. Alcohol and Alcohol. 1989;24:299&#x2013;309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2675861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edenberg HJ, Zhang K, Fong K, Bosron WF, Li TK. Cloning and sequencing of cDNA encoding the complete mouse liver alcohol dehydrogenase. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1985;82:2262&#x2013;2266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC397537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3157987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taketo M, Schroeder AC, Mobraaten LE et al. FVB/N: an inbred mouse strain preferable for transgenic analyses. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1991;88:2065&#x2013;2069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC51169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1848692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overbeek PA, Aguilar-Cordova E, Hanten G. Coinjection strategy for visual identification of transgenic mice. Transgenic Res. 1991;1:31&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1844573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Q, Carlson EC, Borgerding AJ, Epstein PN. A transgenic model of acetaldehyde overproduction accelerates alcohol cardiomyopathy. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 1999;291:766&#x2013;772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10525098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan J, McFadden GE, Borgerding AJ, Norby FL, Ren BH, Ye G, Epstein PN, Ren J. Overexpression of alcohol dehydrogenase exacerbates ethanol-induced contractile defect in cardiac myocytes. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2002;282:H1216&#x2013;H1222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11893554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellingsen O, Davidoff AJ, Prasad SK, Berger HJ, Springhorn JP, Marsh JD, Kelly RA, Smith TW. Adult rat ventricular myocytes cultured in defined medium: phenotype and electromechanical function. Am J Physiol. 1993;265:H747&#x2013;H754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8368376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aberle NS II, Ren J. Acetaldehyde depresses cardiac contraction in ventricular myocytes: Role of cytochrome p-450 oxidase, xanthine oxidase and lipid peroxidation. Alcohol Clin Exp Res In press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12711919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren J, Wold L. Measurement of cardiac mechanical function in isolated ventricular myocytes from rats and mice by computerized video-based imaging. Biol Proced Online. 2001;3:43&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC145545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12734580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao A, Su Z, Nonaka A, Zubair I, Lu L, Philipson KD, Bridge JHB, Barry WH. Effects of overexpression of the Na+-Ca2+ exchanger on [Ca2+]i transients in murine ventricular myocytes. Circ Res. 1998;82:657&#x2013;665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9546374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCall E, Ginsburg KS, Bassani RA, Shannon TR, Qi M, Samarel AM, Bers DM. Ca flux, contractility and excitation-contraction coupling in hypertrophic rat ventricular myocytes. Am J Physiol. 1998;274:H1348&#x2013;H1360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9575940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bers DM. Calcium fluxes involved in control of cardiac myocyte contraction. Circ Res. 1996;87:275&#x2013;281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10948060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ide T, Tsutsui H, Hayashidani S. Mitochondrial DNA damage and dysfunction associated with oxidative stress in failing hearts following myocardial infarction. Circ Res. 2001;88:529&#x2013;535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11249877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picklo MJ, Amarnath V, McIntyre JO, Graham DG, Montine TJ. 4-Hydroxy-2(E)-nonenal inhibits CNS mitochondrial respiration at multiple sites. J Neurochem. 1999;72:1617&#x2013;1624. doi: 10.1046/j.1471-4159.1999.721617.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1471-4159.1999.721617.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10098869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picklo MJ Sr., Montine TJ. Acrolein inhits respiration in isolated brain mitochondria. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2001;1535:145&#x2013;152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11342003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffith OW. Glutathione and glutathione disulfide In: Bergmeyer HU Bergmeyer J (eds) Methods of enzymatic analysis Vol 8, Verlag Chemie Deerfield Beach, FL. 1986; pp. 521-529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye G, Metreveli NS, Ren J, Epstein PN. Overexpression of metallothionein reverses diabetes induced functional deficits in diabetic cardiomyocytes by inhibiting ROS production. Diabetes In press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esterbauer H, Schaur RJ, Zollner H. Chemistry and biochemistry of 4-hydroxynonenal malonaldehyde and related aldehydes. Free Radic Biol Med. 1991;11:81&#x2013;128. doi: 10.1016/0891-5849(91)90192-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0891-5849(91)90192-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1937131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren J, Roughead ZK, Norby FL, Rakoczy S, Wold LE, Mabey RL, Brown-Borg HM. Increases in insulin-like growth factor-1 level and peroxidative damage after gestational ethanol exposure in rats. Pharmacol Res In press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12644392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohhira M, Ohtake T, Matsumoto A, Saito H, Ikuta K, Fujimoto Y, Ono M, Toyokuni S, Kohgo Y. Immunohistochemical detection of 4-hydroxy-2-nonenal-modified-protein adducts in human alcoholic liver diseases. Alcohol Clin Exp Res. 1998;22:145S&#x2013;149S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9622393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montine KS, Reich E, Neely MD, Sidell KR, Olson SJ, Markesbery WR, Montine TJ. Distribution of reducible 4-hydroxynonenal adduct immunoreactivity in Alzheimer disease is associated with APOE genotype. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 1998;57:415&#x2013;425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9596412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantle D, Preedy VR. Free radicals as mediators of alcohol toxicity. Adverse Drug React Toxicol Rev. 1999;18:235&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10687026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka E, Terada M, Misawa S. Cytochrome P450 2E1: its clinical and toxicological role. J Clin Pharm Ther. 2000;25:165&#x2013;175. doi: 10.1046/j.1365-2710.2000.00282.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-2710.2000.00282.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10886461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieber CS. Alcoholic liver injury: pathogenesis and therapy in 2001. Pathol Biol (Paris) 2001;49:738&#x2013;752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11762137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cederbaum AI, Wu D, Mari M, Bai J. CYP2E1-dependent toxicity and oxidative stress in HepG2 cells. Free Radic Biol Med. 2001;31:1539&#x2013;1543. doi: 10.1016/S0891-5849(01)00743-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0891-5849(01)00743-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11744327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thum T, Borlak J. Cytochrome P450 mono-oxygenase gene expression and protein activity in cultures of adult cardiomyocytes of the rat. Br J Pharmacol. 2000;130:1745&#x2013;1752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1572248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10952662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novak RF, Woodcroft KJ. The alcohol-inducible form of cytochrome P450 (CYP 2E1): role in toxicology and regulation of expression. Arch Pharm Res. 2000;23:267&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10976571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoek JB, Cahill A, Pastorino JG. Alcohol and mitochondria: A dysfunctional relationship. Gastroenterology. 2002;122:2049&#x2013;2063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1868435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12055609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkola T, Iles MR, Kohlenberg-Mueller K, Eriksson CJ. Ethanol acetaldehyde, acetate and lactate levels after alcohol intake in white men and women: effect of 4-methylpyrazole. Alcohol Clin Exp Res. 2002;26:239&#x2013;245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11964564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petry NM. A behavioral economic analysis of polydrug abuse in alcoholics: asymmetrical substitution of alcohol and cocaine. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2001;62:31&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11173165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta MC, Jain AC, Billie M. Combined effects of alcohol and nicotine on cardiovascular performance in a canine model. J Cardiovasc Pharmacol. 1998;31:930&#x2013;936. doi: 10.1097/00005344-199806000-00018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005344-199806000-00018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9641479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>