<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">26388782</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2015</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-042X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>6</Volume><PubDate><Year>2015</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nutritional interventions to augment resistance training-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>245</StartPage><MedlinePgn>245</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">245</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fphys.2015.00245</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Skeletal muscle mass is regulated by a balance between muscle protein synthesis (MPS) and muscle protein breakdown (MPB). In healthy humans, MPS is more sensitive (varying 4-5 times more than MPB) to changes in protein feeding and loading rendering it the primary locus determining gains in muscle mass. Performing resistance exercise (RE) followed by the consumption of protein results in an augmentation of MPS and, over time, can lead to muscle hypertrophy. The magnitude of the RE-induced increase in MPS is dictated by a variety of factors including: the dose of protein, source of protein, and possibly the distribution and timing of post-exercise protein ingestion. In addition, RE variables such as frequency of sessions, time under tension, volume, and training status play roles in regulating MPS. This review provides a brief overview of our current understanding of how RE and protein ingestion can influence gains in skeletal muscle mass in young, healthy individuals. It is the goal of this review to provide nutritional recommendations for optimal skeletal muscle adaptation. Specifically, we will focus on how the manipulation of protein intake during the recovery period following RE augments the adaptive response.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morton</LastName><ForeName>Robert W</ForeName><Initials>RW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Metabolism Research Group, Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McGlory</LastName><ForeName>Chris</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Metabolism Research Group, Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phillips</LastName><ForeName>Stuart M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise Metabolism Research Group, Department of Kinesiology, McMaster University Hamilton, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2015</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101549006</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-042X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anabolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">leucine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle protein synthesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein balance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">whey</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2015</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2015</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2015</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26388782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4558471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2015.00245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Acheson K. J., Blondel-Lubrano A., Oguey-Araymon S., Beaumont M., Emady-Azar S., Ammon-Zufferey C., et al. (2011). Protein choices targeting thermogenesis and metabolism. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 93, 525&#x2013;534. 10.3945/ajcn.110.005850</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.110.005850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21228266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams G. R., Bamman M. M. (2010). Characterization and regulation of mechanical loading-induced compensatory muscle muscle hypertrophy. Compr. Physiol. 2, 2829&#x2013;2870. 10.1002/cphy.cp040251</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cphy.cp040251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23720267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amann M., Proctor L. T., Sebranek J. J., Pegelow D. F., Dempsey J. A. (2009). Opioid-mediated muscle afferents inhibit central motor drive and limit peripheral muscle fatigue development in humans. J. Physiol. 587, 271&#x2013;283. 10.1113/jphysiol.2008.163303</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2008.163303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2670040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19015193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine . (2009). Progression models in resistance training for healthy adults. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 41, 687&#x2013;708. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181915670</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181915670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19204579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Areta J. L., Burke L. M., Camera D. M., West D. W. D., Crawshay S., Moore D. R., et al. (2014). Reduced resting skeletal muscle protein synthesis is rescued by resistance exercise and protein ingestion following short-term energy deficit. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 306, E989&#x2013;E997. 10.1152/ajpendo.00590.2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00590.2013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24595305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Areta J. L., Burke L. M., Ross M. L., Camera D. M., West D. W. D., Broad E. M., et al. (2013). Timing and distribution of protein ingestion during prolonged recovery from resistance exercise alters myofibrillar protein synthesis. J. Physiol. 591, 2319&#x2013;2331. 10.1113/jphysiol.2012.244897</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2012.244897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3650697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23459753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atherton P. J., Etheridge T., Watt P. W., Wilkinson D., Selby A., Rankin D., et al. (2010). Muscle full effect after oral protein: time-dependent concordance and discordance between human muscle protein synthesis and mTORC1 signaling. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 92, 1080&#x2013;1088. 10.3945/ajcn.2010.29819</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.2010.29819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20844073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beelen M., Koopman R., Gijsen A. P., Vandereyt H., Kies A. K., Kuipers H., et al. (2008). Protein coingestion stimulates muscle protein synthesis during resistance-type exercise. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 295, E70&#x2013;E77. 10.1152/ajpendo.00774.2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00774.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18430966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennet W. M., Connacher A. A., Scrimgeour C. M., Jung R. T., Rennie M. J. (1990). Euglycemic hyperinsulinemia augments amino acid uptake by human leg tissues during hyperaminoacidemia. Am. J. Physiol. 259, E185&#x2013;E194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2166435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biolo G., Fleming R. Y. D., Wolfe R. R. (1995a). Physiologic hyperinsulinemia stimulates protein synthesis and enhances transport of selected amino acids in human skeletal muscle. J. Clin. Invest. 95, 811&#x2013;819. 10.1172/JCI117731</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI117731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC295560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7860765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biolo G., Maggi S. P., Williams B. D., Tipton K. D., Wolf R. R., Wolfe R. R. (1995b). Increased rates of muscle protein turnover and amino acid transport after resistance exercise in humans. Am. J. Physiol. 268, E514&#x2013;E520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7900797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biolo G., Tipton K. D., Klein S., Wolfe R. R. (1997). An abundant supply of amino acids enhances the metabolic effect of exercise on muscle protein. Am. J. Physiol. 273, E122&#x2013;E129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biolo G., Williams B. D., Fleming R. Y. D., Wolfe R. R. (1999). Insulin action on muscle protein kinetics and amino acid transport during recovery after resistance exercise. Diabetes 48, 949&#x2013;957. 10.2337/diabetes.48.5.949</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diabetes.48.5.949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10331397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blaauw B., Reggiani C. (2014). The role of satellite cells in muscle hypertrophy. J. Muscle Res. Cell Motil. 35, 3&#x2013;10. 10.1007/s10974-014-9376-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10974-014-9376-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24505026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boirie Y., Dangin M., Gachon P., Vasson M. P., Maubois J. L., Beaufr&#xe8;re B., et al. (1997). Slow and fast dietary proteins differently modulate postprandial protein accretion. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 94, 14930&#x2013;14935. 10.1073/pnas.94.26.14930</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.94.26.14930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC25140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9405716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf8;rsheim E., Cree M. G., Tipton K. D., Elliott T. A., Aarsland A., Wolfe R. R. (2004). Effect of carbohydrate intake on net muscle protein synthesis during recovery from resistance exercise. J. Appl. Physiol. 96, 674&#x2013;678. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00333.2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00333.2003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14594866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd N. A., Andrews R. J., West D. W. D., Little J. P., Cochran A. J. R., Hector A. J., et al. (2012). Muscle time under tension during resistance exercise stimulates differential muscle protein sub-fractional synthetic responses in men. J. Physiol. 590, 351&#x2013;362. 10.1113/jphysiol.2011.221200</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2011.221200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3285070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22106173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd N. A., West D. W. D., Moore D. R., Atherton P. J., Staples A. W., Prior T., et al. (2011). Enhanced amino acid sensitivity of myofibrillar protein synthesis persists for up to 24 h after resistance exercise in young men. J. Nutr. 141, 568&#x2013;573. 10.3945/jn.110.135038</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.110.135038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21289204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd N. A., West D. W. D., Staples A. W., Atherton P. J., Baker J. M., Moore D. R., et al. (2010). Low-load high volume resistance exercise stimulates muscle protein synthesis more than high-load low volume resistance exercise in young men. PLoS ONE 5:e12033. 10.1371/journal.pone.0012033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0012033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2918506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20711498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke L. M., Hawley J. A., Ross M. L., Moore D. R., Phillips S. M., Slater G. R., et al. (2012a). Preexercise aminoacidemia and muscle protein synthesis after resistance exercise. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 44, 1968&#x2013;1977. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31825d28fa</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31825d28fa</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22617396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke L. M., Winter J. A., Cameron-Smith D., Enslen M., Farnfield M., Decombaz J. (2012b). Effect of intake of different dietary protein sources on plasma amino acid profiles at rest and after exercise. Int. J. Sport Nutr. Exerc. Metab. 22, 452&#x2013;462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22807528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camera D. M., West D. W. D., Burd N. A., Phillips S. M., Garnham A. P., Hawley J. A., et al. (2012). Low muscle glycogen concentration does not suppress the anabolic response to resistance exercise. J. Appl. Physiol. 113, 206&#x2013;214. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00395.2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00395.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22628371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos G. E. R., Luecke T. J., Wendeln H. K., Toma K., Hagerman F. C., Murray T. F., et al. (2002). Muscular adaptations in response to three different resistance-training regimens: specificity of repetition maximum training zones. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 88, 50&#x2013;60. 10.1007/s00421-002-0681-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-002-0681-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12436270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cermak N. M., Res P. T., Groot L. C., De Saris W. H. M., Van Loon L. J. C. (2012). Protein supplementation augments the adaptive response of skeletal muscle to resistance-type exercise training: a meta-analysis 1 &#x2013; 3. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 96, 1454&#x2013;1464. 10.3945/ajcn.112.037556</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.112.037556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23134885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chesley A., MacDougall J. D., Tarnopolsky M. A., Atkinson S. A., Smith K. (1992). Changes in human muscle protein synthesis after resistance exercise. J. Appl. Physiol. 73, 1383&#x2013;1388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1280254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchward-Venne T. A., Breen L., Di Donato D. M., Hector A. J., Mitchell C. J., Moore D. R., et al. (2014). Leucine supplementation of a low-protein mixed macronutrient beverage enhances myofibrillar protein synthesis in young men: a double-blind, randomized trial1-3. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 99, 276&#x2013;286. 10.3945/ajcn.113.068775</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.113.068775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24284442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuthbertson D., Smith K., Babraj J., Leese G., Waddell T., Atherton P., et al. (2005). Anabolic signaling deficits underlie amino acid resistance of wasting, aging muscle. FASEB J. 19, 422&#x2013;424. 10.1096/fj.04-2640fje</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.04-2640fje</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15596483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F., Phillips S., Vechin F. C., Ugrinowitsch C. (2015). A review of resistance training-induced changes in skeletal muscle protein synthesis and their contribution to hypertrophy. Sports. Med. 45, 801&#x2013;807. 10.1007/s40279-015-0320-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0320-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25739559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deutz N. E., Wolfe R. R. (2013). Is there a maximal anabolic response to protein intake with a meal? Clin. Nutr. 32, 309&#x2013;313. 10.1016/j.clnu.2012.11.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2012.11.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3595342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23260197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorfman L. J., Howard J. E., McGill K. C. (1990). Triphasic behavioral response of motor units to submaximal fatiguing exercise. Muscle Nerve 13, 621&#x2013;628. 10.1002/mus.880130711</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.880130711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2388662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egan B., Zierath J. R. (2013). Exercise metabolism and the molecular regulation of skeletal muscle adaptation. Cell Metab. 17, 162&#x2013;184. 10.1016/j.cmet.2012.12.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmet.2012.12.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23395166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita S., Dreyer H. C., Drummond M. J., Glynn E. L., Volpi E., Rasmussen B. B. (2009). Essential amino acid and carbohydrate ingestion before resistance exercise does not enhance postexercise muscle protein synthesis. J. Appl. Physiol. 106, 1730&#x2013;1739. 10.1152/japplphysiol.90395.2008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.90395.2008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2681328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18535123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glynn E. L., Fry C. S., Drummond M. J., Dreyer H. C., Dhanani S., Volpi E., et al. (2010). Muscle protein breakdown has a minor role in the protein anabolic response to essential amino acid and carbohydrate intake following resistance exercise. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 299, R533&#x2013;R540. 10.1152/ajpregu.00077.2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00077.2010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2928613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20519362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhaff P. L., Karagounis L. G., Peirce N., Simpson E. J., Hazell M., Layfield R., et al. (2008). Disassociation between the effects of amino acids and insulin on signaling, ubiquitin ligases, and protein turnover in human muscle. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 295, E595&#x2013;E604. 10.1152/ajpendo.90411.2008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.90411.2008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2536736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18577697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hector A. J., Marcotte G. R., Churchward-venne T. A., Murphy C. H., Breen L., von Allmen M., et al. (2015). Whey protein supplementation preserves postprandial myofibrillar protein synthesis during short-term energy restriction in overweight and obese adults. J. Nutr. 145, 246&#x2013;252. 10.3945/jn.114.200832</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.114.200832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25644344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillier T. A., Fryburg D. A., Jahn L. A., Barrett E. J. (1998). Extreme hyperinsulinemia unmasks insulin's effect to stimulate protein synthesis in the human forearm. Am. J. Physiol. 274, E1067&#x2013;E1074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9611157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyde R., Taylor P. M., Hundal H. S. (2003). Amino acid transporters: roles in amino acid sensing and signalling in animal cells. Biochem. J. 373, 1&#x2013;18. 10.1042/bj20030405</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/bj20030405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1223487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12879880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Josse A. R., Atkinson S. A., Tarnopolsky M. A., Phillips S. M. (2011). Increased consumption of dairy foods and protein during diet-and exercise-induced weight loss promotes fat mass loss and lean mass gain in overweight and obese premenopausal women. J. Nutr. 141, 1626&#x2013;1634. 10.3945/jn.111.141028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.111.141028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3159052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21775530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim P. L., Staron R. S., Phillips S. M. (2005). Fasted-state skeletal muscle protein synthesis after resistance exercise is altered with training. J. Physiol. 568, 283&#x2013;290. 10.1113/jphysiol.2005.093708</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2005.093708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1474760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16051622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman R., Beelen M., Stellingwerff T., Pennings B., Saris W. H. M., Kies A. K., et al. (2007). Coingestion of carbohydrate with protein does not further augment postexercise muscle protein synthesis. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 293, E833&#x2013;E842. 10.1152/ajpendo.00135.2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00135.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17609259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger J. W. (2010). Single vs. multiple sets of resistance exercise for muscle hypertrophy: a meta-analysis. J. Strength Cond. Res. 24, 1150&#x2013;1159. 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181d4d436</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181d4d436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20300012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layman D. K., Anthony T. G., Rasmussen B. B., Adams S. H., Lynch C. J., Brinkworth G. D., et al. (2015). Defining meal requirements for protein to optimize metabolic roles of amino acids. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 101, 1330&#x2013;1338. 10.3945/ajcn.114.084053</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.114.084053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5278948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25926513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leidy H. J., Clifton P. M., Astrup A., Wycherley T. P., Westerterp-plantenga M. S., Luscombe-marsh N. D., et al. (2015). The role of protein in weight loss and maintenance 1&#x2013;5. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 101, 1320&#x2013;1329. 10.3945/ajcn.114.084038</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.114.084038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25926512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mettler S., Mitchell N., Tipton K. D. (2010). Increased protein intake reduces lean body mass loss during weight loss in athletes. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 42, 326&#x2013;337. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181b2ef8e</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181b2ef8e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19927027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell C. J., Churchward-venne T. A., West D. W. D., Burd A., Breen L., Baker S. K., et al. (2012). Resistance exercise load does not determine training-mediated hypertrophic gains in young men. J. Apply Physiol. 113, 71&#x2013;77. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00307.2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00307.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3404827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22518835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore D. R., Churchward-Venne T. A., Witard O., Breen L., Burd N. A., Tipton K. D., et al. (2015). Protein ingestion to stimulate myofibrillar protein synthesis requires greater relative protein intakes in healthy older versus younger men. J. Gerontol. Ser. A Biol. Sci. Med. Sci. 70, 57&#x2013;62. 10.1093/gerona/glu103</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glu103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25056502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore D. R., Robinson M. J., Fry J. L., Tang J. E., Glover E. I., Wilkinson S. B., et al. (2009). Ingested protein dose response of muscle and albumin protein synthesis after resistance exercise in young men 1&#x2013;3. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 89, 161&#x2013;168. 10.3945/ajcn.2008.26401</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.2008.26401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19056590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritani T., Sherman W. M., Shibata M., Matsumoto T., Shinohara M. (1992). Oxygen availability and motor unit activity in humans. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. Occup. Physiol. 64, 552&#x2013;556. 10.1007/BF00843767</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00843767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1618195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nair K. S., Halliday D., Griggs R. C. (1988). Leucine incorporation into mixed skeletal muscle protein in humans. Am. J. Physiol. 254, E208&#x2013;E213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3279803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pennings B., Boirie Y., Senden J. M. G., Gijsen A. P., Kuipers H., van Loon L. J. C., et al. (2011). Whey protein stimulates postprandial muscle protein accretion more effectively than do casein and casein hydrolysate in older men. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 93, 997&#x2013;1005. 10.3945/ajcn.110.008102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.110.008102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21367943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson M. D., Rhea M. R., Alvar B. A. (2005). Applications of the dose-response for muscular strength development: a review of meta-analytic efficacy and reliability for designing training prescription. J. Strength Cond. Res. 19, 950&#x2013;958. 10.1519/R-16874.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/R-16874.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16287373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips S. M. (2004). Protein requirements and supplementation in strength sports. Nutrition 20, 689&#x2013;695. 10.1016/j.nut.2004.04.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2004.04.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15212752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips S. M. (2012). Dietary protein requirements and adaptive advantages in athletes. Br. J. Nutr. 108, S158&#x2013;S167. 10.1017/s0007114512002516</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/s0007114512002516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23107527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips S. M. (2014a). A brief review of critical processes in exercise-induced muscular hypertrophy. Sport. Med. 44, 71&#x2013;77. 10.1007/s40279-014-0152-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0152-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24791918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips S. M. (2014b). A brief review of higher dietary protein diets in weight loss: a focus on athletes. Sport. Med. 44, 149&#x2013;153. 10.1007/s40279-014-0254-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0254-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4213385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25355188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips S. M., Glover E. I., Rennie M. J. (2009). Alterations of protein turnover underlying disuse atrophy in human skeletal muscle. J. Appl. Physiol. 107, 645&#x2013;654. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00452.2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00452.2009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19608931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips S. M., Tipton K. D., Ferrando A. A., Wolfe R. R. (1999). Resistance training reduces the acute exercise-induced increase in muscle protein turnover. Am. J. Physiol. 276, E118&#x2013;E124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9886957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips S. M., Tipton K. D., Aarsland A., Wolf S. E., Wolfe R. R. (1997). Mixed muscle protein synthesis and breakdown after resistance exercise in humans. Am. J. Physiol. 273, E99&#x2013;E107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips S. M., van Loon L. J. C. (2011). Dietary protein for athletes: from requirements to optimum adaptation. J. Sports Sci. 29, S29&#x2013;S38. 10.1080/02640414.2011.619204</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2011.619204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22150425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips S. M., Winett R. A. (2010). Uncomplicated resistance training and health-related outcomes: evidence for a public health mandate. Curr. Sports Med. Rep. 9, 208&#x2013;213. 10.1249/JSR.0b013e3181e7da73</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JSR.0b013e3181e7da73</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4086449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20622538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price G. M., Halliday D., Pacy P. J., Quevedo M. R., Millward D. J. (1994). Nitrogen homeostasis in man: influence of protein intake on the amplitude of diurnal cycling of body nitrogen. Clin. Sci. (Lond). 86, 91&#x2013;102. 10.1042/cs0860091</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/cs0860091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8306557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proske U., Morgan D. L. (2001). Muscle damage from eccentric exercise: mechanism, mechanical signs, adaptation and clinical applications. J. Physiol. 537, 333&#x2013;345. 10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.00333.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.00333.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11731568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reidy P. T., Walker D. K., Dickinson J. M., Gundermann D. M., Drummond M. J., Timmerman K. L., et al. (2013). Protein blend ingestion following resistance exercise promotes human muscle protein synthesis. J. Nutr. 143, 410&#x2013;416. 10.3945/jn.112.168021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.112.168021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3738242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23343671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reitelseder S., Agergaard J., Doessing S., Helmark I. C., Lund P., Kristensen N. B., et al. (2011). Whey and casein labeled with L - [1- 13 C] leucine and muscle protein synthesis: effect of resistance exercise and protein ingestion. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 300, E231&#x2013;E242. 10.1152/ajpendo.00513.2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00513.2010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21045172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rennie M. J., Wackerhage H., Spangenburg E. E., Booth F. W. (2004). Control of the size of the human muscle mass. Annu. Rev. Physiol. 66, 799&#x2013;828. 10.1146/annurev.physiol.66.052102.134444</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.physiol.66.052102.134444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14977422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Res P. T., Groen B., Pennings B., Beelen M., Wallis G. A., Gijsen A. P., et al. (2012). Protein ingestion before sleep improves postexercise overnight recovery. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 44, 1560&#x2013;1569. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31824cc363</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31824cc363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22330017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy B. D., Tarnopolsky M. A., MacDougall J. D., Fowles J., Yarasheski K. E. (1997). Effect of glucose supplement timing on protein metabolism after resistance training. J. Appl. Physiol. 82, 1882&#x2013;1888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9173954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B. J., Aragon A. A., Krieger J. W. (2013). The effect of protein timing on muscle strength and hypertrophy: a meta-analysis. J. Int. Soc. Sports Nutr. 10:53. 10.1186/1550-2783-10-53</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-10-53</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3879660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24299050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B. J., Ogborn D. I., Krieger J. W. (2015). Effect of repetition duration during resistance training on muscle hypertrophy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sport. Med. 45, 577&#x2013;585. 10.1007/s40279-015-0304-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-015-0304-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25601394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B. J., Wilson J. M., Lowery R. P., Krieger J. W. (2014). Muscular adaptations in low- versus high-load resistance training: a meta-analysis. Eur. J. Sport Sci. 10.1080/17461391.2014.989922. [Epub ahead of print].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2014.989922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25530577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snijders T., Res P. T., Smeets J. S. J., Vliet S., Van Kranenburg J., Van Maase K., et al. (2015). Protein ingestion before sleep increases muscle mass and strength gains during prolonged resistance-type exercise training in healthy young men. J. Nutr. 145, 1178&#x2013;1784. 10.3945/jn.114.208371</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.114.208371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25926415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staples A. W., Burd N. A., West D. W. D., Currie K. D., Atherton P. J., Moore D. R., et al. (2011). Carbohydrate does not augment exercise-induced protein accretion versus protein alone. Med. Sci. Sports Exerc. 43, 1154&#x2013;1161. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31820751cb</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31820751cb</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21131864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens J. A., Taylor A. (1972). Fatigue of maintained voluntary muscle contraction in man. J. Physiol. 220, 1&#x2013;18. 10.1113/jphysiol.1972.sp009691</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.1972.sp009691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1331686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5059236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Symons T. B., Sheffield-Moore M., Wolfe R. R., Paddon-Jones D. (2009). A moderate serving of high-quality protein maximally stimulates skeletal muscle protein synthesis in young and elderly subjects. J. Am. Diet. Assoc. 109, 1582&#x2013;1586. 10.1016/j.jada.2009.06.369</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jada.2009.06.369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3197704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19699838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang J. E., Moore D. R., Kujbida G. W., Tarnopolsky M. A., Phillips S. M. (2009). Ingestion of whey hydrolysate, casein, or soy protein isolate: effects on mixed muscle protein synthesis at rest and following resistance exercise in young men. J. Appl. Physiol. 107, 987&#x2013;992. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00076.2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00076.2009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19589961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang J. E., Perco J. G., Moore D. R., Wilkinson S. B., Phillips S. M. (2008). Resistance training alters the response of fed state mixed muscle protein synthesis in young men. Am. J. Physiol. Regul. Integr. Comp. Physiol. 294, R172&#x2013;R178. 10.1152/ajpregu.00636.2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00636.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18032468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton K. D., Elliott T. A., Cree M. G., Aarsland A. A., Sanford A. P., Wolfe R. R. (2007). Stimulation of net muscle protein synthesis by whey protein ingestion before and after exercise. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 292, E71&#x2013;E76. 10.1152/ajpendo.00166.2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00166.2006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16896166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trommelen J., Groen B., Hamer H., de Groot L. C. P. G. M., van Loon L. J. (2015). Mechanisms in endocrinology: exogenous insulin does not increase muscle protein synthesis rate when administrated systemically: a systematic review. Eur. J. Endocrinol. 173, R25&#x2013;R34. 10.1530/eje-14-0902</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1530/eje-14-0902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25646407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West D. W. D., Burd N. A., Coffey V. G., Baker S. K., Burke L. M., Hawley J. A., et al. (2011). Rapid aminoacidemia enhances myofibrillar protein synthesis and anabolic intramuscular signaling responses after resistance exercise. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 94, 795&#x2013;803. 10.3945/ajcn.111.013722</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.111.013722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21795443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson S. B., Phillips S. M., Atherton P. J., Patel R., Yarasheski K. E., Tarnopolsky M. A., et al. (2008). Differential effects of resistance and endurance exercise in the fed state on signalling molecule phosphorylation and protein synthesis in human muscle. J. Physiol. 586, 3701&#x2013;3717. 10.1113/jphysiol.2008.153916</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2008.153916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2538832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18556367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witard O. C., Jackman S. R., Breen L., Smith K., Selby A., Tipton K. D. (2014a). Myofibrillar muscle protein synthesis rates subsequent to a meal in response to increasing doses of whey protein at rest and after resistance exercise. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 99, 86&#x2013;95. 10.3945/ajcn.112.055517</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.112.055517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24257722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witard O. C., Turner J. E., Jackman S. R., Kies A. K., Jeukendrup A. E., Bosch J. A., et al. (2014b). High dietary protein restores overreaching induced impairments in leukocyte trafficking and reduces the incidence of upper respiratory tract infection in elite cyclists. Brain Behav. Immun. 39, 211&#x2013;219. 10.1016/j.bbi.2013.10.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2013.10.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24120932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe R. R. (2006). The underappreciated role of muscle in health and disease. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 84, 475&#x2013;482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16960159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yarasheski K. E., Zachwieja J. J., Bier D. M. (1993). Acute effects of resistance exercise on muscle protein synthesis rate in young and elderly men and women. Am. J. Physiol. Endocrinol. Metab. 265, E210&#x2013;E214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8368290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>