<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">24248330</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1574-4647</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2014</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Age (Dordrecht, Netherlands)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Age (Dordr)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>AMPK activation--protean potential for boosting healthspan.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>641</StartPage><EndPage>663</EndPage><MedlinePgn>641-63</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11357-013-9595-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>AMP-activated kinase (AMPK) is activated when the cellular (AMP+ADP)/ATP ratio rises; it therefore serves as a detector of cellular "fuel deficiency." AMPK activation is suspected to mediate some of the health-protective effects of long-term calorie restriction. Several drugs and nutraceuticals which slightly and safely impede the efficiency of mitochondrial ATP generation-most notably metformin and berberine-can be employed as clinical AMPK activators and, hence, may have potential as calorie restriction mimetics for extending healthspan. Indeed, current evidence indicates that AMPK activators may reduce risk for atherosclerosis, heart attack, and stroke; help to prevent ventricular hypertrophy and manage congestive failure; ameliorate metabolic syndrome, reduce risk for type 2 diabetes, and aid glycemic control in diabetics; reduce risk for weight gain; decrease risk for a number of common cancers while improving prognosis in cancer therapy; decrease risk for dementia and possibly other neurodegenerative disorders; help to preserve the proper structure of bone and cartilage; and possibly aid in the prevention and control of autoimmunity. While metformin and berberine appear to have the greatest utility as clinical AMPK activators-as reflected by their efficacy in diabetes management-regular ingestion of vinegar, as well as moderate alcohol consumption, may also achieve a modest degree of health-protective AMPK activation. The activation of AMPK achievable with any of these measures may be potentiated by clinical doses of the drug salicylate, which can bind to AMPK and activate it allosterically.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCarty</LastName><ForeName>Mark F</ForeName><Initials>MF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Catalytic Longevity, 7831 Rush Rose Dr., Apt. 316, Carlsbad, CA, 92009, USA, markfmccarty@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2013</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Age (Dordr)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101250497</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0161-9152</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.11.31</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D055372">AMP-Activated Protein Kinases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055372" MajorTopicYN="N">AMP-Activated Protein Kinases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000375" MajorTopicYN="Y">Aging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002149" MajorTopicYN="N">Energy Intake</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004734" MajorTopicYN="N">Energy Metabolism</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004789" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enzyme Activation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008136" MajorTopicYN="N">Longevity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2013</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2013</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2015</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24248330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4039279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11357-013-9595-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abbasi F, Kamath V, Rizvi AA, Carantoni M, Chen YD, Reaven GM. Results of a placebo-controlled study of the metabolic effects of the addition of metformin to sulfonylurea-treated patients. Evidence for a central role of adipose tissue. Diabetes Care. 1997;20(12):1863&#x2013;1869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9405908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbasi F, Carantoni M, Chen YD, Reaven GM. Further evidence for a central role of adipose tissue in the antihyperglycemic effect of metformin. Diabetes Care. 1998;21(8):1301&#x2013;1305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9702437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abidi P, Zhou Y, Jiang JD, Liu J. Extracellular signal-regulated kinase-dependent stabilization of hepatic low-density lipoprotein receptor mRNA by herbal medicine berberine. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2005;25(10):2170&#x2013;2176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16100034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad R, Sylvester J, Ahmad M, Zafarullah M. Involvement of H-Ras and reactive oxygen species in proinflammatory cytokine-induced matrix metalloproteinase-13 expression in human articular chondrocytes. Arch Biochem Biophys. 2011;507(2):350&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21211511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alba G, El Bekay R, varez-Maqueda M, et al. Stimulators of AMP-activated protein kinase inhibit the respiratory burst in human neutrophils. FEBS Lett. 2004;573(1&#x2013;3):219&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15328001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anisimov VN. Metformin for aging and cancer prevention. Aging (Albany NY) 2010;2(11):760&#x2013;774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3006019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21084729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anisimov VN, Berstein LM, Popovich IG, et al. If started early in life, metformin treatment increases life span and postpones tumors in female SHR mice. Aging (Albany NY) 2011;3(2):148&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3082009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21386129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arad M, Moskowitz IP, Patel VV, et al. Transgenic mice overexpressing mutant PRKAG2 define the cause of Wolff&#x2013;Parkinson&#x2013;White syndrome in glycogen storage cardiomyopathy. Circulation. 2003;107(22):2850&#x2013;2856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12782567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armour KE, Armour KJ, Gallagher ME, et al. Defective bone formation and anabolic response to exogenous estrogen in mice with targeted disruption of endothelial nitric oxide synthase. Endocrinology. 2001;142(2):760&#x2013;766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11159848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athar M, Elmets CA, Kopelovich L. Pharmacological activation of p53 in cancer cells. Curr Pharm Des. 2011;17(6):631&#x2013;639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3780581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21391904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attane C, Foussal C, Le GS, et al. Apelin treatment increases complete fatty acid oxidation, mitochondrial oxidative capacity, and biogenesis in muscle of insulin-resistant mice. Diabetes. 2012;61(2):310&#x2013;320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3266414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22210322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austin SA, Santhanam AV, Katusic ZS. Endothelial nitric oxide modulates expression and processing of amyloid precursor protein. Circ Res. 2010;107(12):1498&#x2013;1502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3064266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21127294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai A, Yong M, Ma AG, et al. Novel anti-inflammatory action of 5-aminoimidazole-4-carboxamide ribonucleoside with protective effect in dextran sulfate sodium-induced acute and chronic colitis. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2010;333(3):717&#x2013;725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20237071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai A, Ma AG, Yong M, et al. AMPK agonist downregulates innate and adaptive immune responses in TNBS-induced murine acute and relapsing colitis. Biochem Pharmacol. 2010;80(11):1708&#x2013;1717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20797389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee R, Beal MF, Thomas B. Autophagy in neurodegenerative disorders: pathogenic roles and therapeutic implications. Trends Neurosci. 2010;33(12):541&#x2013;549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2981680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20947179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartke A. Minireview: role of the growth hormone/insulin-like growth factor system in mammalian aging. Endocrinology. 2005;146(9):3718&#x2013;3723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15919742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battu SK, Repka MA, Maddineni S, Chittiboyina AG, Avery MA, Majumdar S. Physicochemical characterization of berberine chloride: a perspective in the development of a solution dosage form for oral delivery. AAPS PharmSciTech. 2010;11(3):1466&#x2013;1475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2974104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20842541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baur JA, Pearson KJ, Price NL, et al. Resveratrol improves health and survival of mice on a high-calorie diet. Nature. 2006;444(7117):337&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4990206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17086191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beauloye C, Bertrand L, Horman S, Hue L. AMPK activation, a preventive therapeutic target in the transition from cardiac injury to heart failure. Cardiovasc Res. 2011;90(2):224&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21285292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benes J, Kazdova L, Drahota Z, et al. Effect of metformin therapy on cardiac function and survival in a volume-overload model of heart failure in rats. Clin Sci (Lond) 2011;121(1):29&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21275906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben-Shlomo S, Zvibel I, Shnell M, et al. Glucagon-like peptide-1 reduces hepatic lipogenesis via activation of AMP-activated protein kinase. J Hepatol. 2011;54(6):1214&#x2013;1223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21145820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergamini E, Cavallini G, Cecchi L, et al. A proposed mechanism of the antiaging action of diet restriction. Aging (Milano) 1998;10(2):174&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9666231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bess E, Fisslthaler B, Fromel T, Fleming I. Nitric oxide-induced activation of the AMP-activated protein kinase alpha2 subunit attenuates IkappaB kinase activity and inflammatory responses in endothelial cells. PLoS ONE. 2011;6(6):e20848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3108981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21673972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blagosklonny MV. Calorie restriction: decelerating mTOR-driven aging from cells to organisms (including humans) Cell Cycle. 2010;9(4):683&#x2013;688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20139716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bo S, Ciccone G, Rosato R, et al. Cancer mortality reduction and metformin. A retrospective cohort study in type 2 diabetic patients. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2012;14(1):23&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21812892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodmer M, Meier C, Krahenbuhl S, Jick SS, Meier CR, Meier CR. Long-term metformin use is associated with decreased risk of breast cancer. Diabetes Care. 2010;33(6):1304&#x2013;1308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2875444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20299480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boocock DJ, Faust GE, Patel KR, et al. Phase I dose escalation pharmacokinetic study in healthy volunteers of resveratrol, a potential cancer chemopreventive agent. Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev. 2007;16(6):1246&#x2013;1252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17548692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowker SL, Yasui Y, Veugelers P, Johnson JA. Glucose-lowering agents and cancer mortality rates in type 2 diabetes: assessing effects of time-varying exposure. Diabetologia. 2010;53(8):1631&#x2013;1637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20407744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown GC. Mechanisms of inflammatory neurodegeneration: iNOS and NADPH oxidase. Biochem Soc Trans. 2007;35(Pt 5):1119&#x2013;1121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17956292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown KA, McInnes KJ, Hunger NI, Oakhill JS, Steinberg GR, Simpson ER. Subcellular localization of cyclic AMP-responsive element binding protein-regulated transcription coactivator 2 provides a link between obesity and breast cancer in postmenopausal women. Cancer Res. 2009;69(13):5392&#x2013;5399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19509226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown KA, Hunger NI, Docanto M, Simpson ER. Metformin inhibits aromatase expression in human breast adipose stromal cells via stimulation of AMP-activated protein kinase. Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2010;123(2):591&#x2013;596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20300828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bulcao C, Ribeiro-Filho FF, Sanudo A, Roberta Ferreira SG. Effects of simvastatin and metformin on inflammation and insulin resistance in individuals with mild metabolic syndrome. Am J Cardiovasc Drugs. 2007;7(3):219&#x2013;224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17610348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canto C, Auwerx J. Calorie Restriction: is AMPK a key sensor and effector? Physiology (Bethesda) 2011;26(4):214&#x2013;224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3627048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21841070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canto C, Gerhart-Hines Z, Feige JN, et al. AMPK regulates energy expenditure by modulating NAD+metabolism and SIRT1 activity. Nature. 2009;458(7241):1056&#x2013;1060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3616311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19262508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canto C, Jiang LQ, Deshmukh AS, et al. Interdependence of AMPK and SIRT1 for metabolic adaptation to fasting and exercise in skeletal muscle. Cell Metab. 2010;11(3):213&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3616265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20197054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carling D, Mayer FV, Sanders MJ, Gamblin SJ. AMP-activated protein kinase: nature's energy sensor. Nat Chem Biol. 2011;7(8):512&#x2013;518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21769098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cartee GD, Wojtaszewski JF. Role of Akt substrate of 160&#xa0;kDa in insulin-stimulated and contraction-stimulated glucose transport. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2007;32(3):557&#x2013;566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17510697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceolotto G, Gallo A, Papparella I, et al. Rosiglitazone reduces glucose-induced oxidative stress mediated by NAD(P)H oxidase via AMPK-dependent mechanism. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2007;27(12):2627&#x2013;2633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17916771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chari NS, Pinaire NL, Thorpe L, Medeiros LJ, Routbort MJ, McDonnell TJ. The p53 tumor suppressor network in cancer and the therapeutic modulation of cell death. Apoptosis. 2009;14(4):336&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19229632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen ZP, Mitchelhill KI, Michell BJ, et al. AMP-activated protein kinase phosphorylation of endothelial NO synthase. FEBS Lett. 1999;443(3):285&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10025949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Peng IC, Sun W, et al. AMP-activated protein kinase functionally phosphorylates endothelial nitric oxide synthase Ser633. Circ Res. 2009;104(4):496&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2761102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19131647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Zhou K, Wang R, et al. Antidiabetic drug metformin (GlucophageR) increases biogenesis of Alzheimer's amyloid peptides via up-regulating BACE1 transcription. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2009;106(10):3907&#x2013;3912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2656178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19237574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ching YP, Davies SP, Hardie DG. Analysis of the specificity of the AMP-activated protein kinase by site-directed mutagenesis of bacterially expressed 3-hydroxy 3-methylglutaryl-CoA reductase, using a single primer variant of the unique-site-elimination method. Eur J Biochem. 1996;237(3):800&#x2013;808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8647128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chong ZZ, Shang YC, Zhang L, Wang S, Maiese K. Mammalian target of rapamycin: hitting the bull's-eye for neurological disorders. Oxidative Med Cell Longev. 2010;3(6):374&#x2013;391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3154047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21307646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cicero AF, Rovati LC, Setnikar I. Eulipidemic effects of berberine administered alone or in combination with other natural cholesterol-lowering agents. A single-blind clinical investigation. Arzneimittelforschung. 2007;57(1):26&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17341006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombo SL, Moncada S. AMPKalpha1 regulates the antioxidant status of vascular endothelial cells. Biochem J. 2009;421(2):163&#x2013;169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19442239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooke JP. The pivotal role of nitric oxide for vascular health. Can J Cardiol. 2004;20(Suppl B):7B&#x2013;15B.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15309199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cool B, Zinker B, Chiou W, et al. Identification and characterization of a small molecule AMPK activator that treats key components of type 2 diabetes and the metabolic syndrome. Cell Metab. 2006;3(6):403&#x2013;416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16753576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortizo AM, Sedlinsky C, McCarthy AD, Blanco A, Schurman L. Osteogenic actions of the anti-diabetic drug metformin on osteoblasts in culture. Eur J Pharmacol. 2006;536(1&#x2013;2):38&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16564524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuervo AM. Calorie restriction and aging: the ultimate &#x201c;cleansing diet&#x201d;. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2008;63(6):547&#x2013;549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18559626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Culjkovic B, Topisirovic I, Borden KL. Controlling gene expression through RNA regulons: the role of the eukaryotic translation initiation factor eIF4E. Cell Cycle. 2007;6(1):65&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17245113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Currie CJ, Poole CD, Gale EA. The influence of glucose-lowering therapies on cancer risk in type 2 diabetes. Diabetologia. 2009;52(9):1766&#x2013;1777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19572116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dagher Z, Ruderman N, Tornheim K, Ido Y. Acute regulation of fatty acid oxidation and amp-activated protein kinase in human umbilical vein endothelial cells. Circ Res. 2001;88(12):1276&#x2013;1282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11420304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dao TM, Waget A, Klopp P, et al. Resveratrol increases glucose induced GLP-1 secretion in mice: a mechanism which contributes to the glycemic control. PLoS ONE. 2011;6(6):e20700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3108962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21673955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Leo V, La Marca A, Orvieto R, Morgante G. Effect of metformin on insulin-like growth factor (IGF) I and IGF-binding protein I in polycystic ovary syndrome. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2000;85(4):1598&#x2013;1600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10770203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De BA, Graff JR. eIF-4E expression and its role in malignancies and metastases. Oncogene. 2004;23(18):3189&#x2013;3199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15094768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Decensi A, Puntoni M, Goodwin P, et al. Metformin and cancer risk in diabetic patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Cancer Prev Res (Phila) 2010;3(11):1451&#x2013;1461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20947488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dellavalle A, Maroli G, Covarello D, et al. Pericytes resident in postnatal skeletal muscle differentiate into muscle fibres and generate satellite cells. Nat Commun. 2011;2:499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21988915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng G, Long Y, Yu YR, Li MR. Adiponectin directly improves endothelial dysfunction in obese rats through the AMPK-eNOS Pathway. Int J Obes (Lond) 2010;34(1):165&#x2013;171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19823181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desilets AR, Dhakal-Karki S, Dunican KC. Role of metformin for weight management in patients without type 2 diabetes. Ann Pharmacother. 2008;42(6):817&#x2013;826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18477733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhahbi JM, Mote PL, Fahy GM, Spindler SR. Identification of potential caloric restriction mimetics by microarray profiling. Physiol Genomics. 2005;23(3):343&#x2013;350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16189280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di MS, Mazroui R, Dallaire P, et al. NF-kappa B-mediated MyoD decay during muscle wasting requires nitric oxide synthase mRNA stabilization, HuR protein, and nitric oxide release. Mol Cell Biol. 2005;25(15):6533&#x2013;6545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1190341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16024790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diogo CV, Machado NG, Barbosa IA, Serafim TL, Burgeiro A, Oliveira PJ. Berberine as a promising safe anti-cancer agent&#x2014;is there a role for mitochondria? Curr Drug Targets. 2011;12(6):850&#x2013;859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21269266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolinsky VW, Morton JS, Oka T, et al. Calorie restriction prevents hypertension and cardiac hypertrophy in the spontaneously hypertensive rat. Hypertension. 2010;56(3):412&#x2013;421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20696994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowling RJ, Goodwin PJ, Stambolic V. Understanding the benefit of metformin use in cancer treatment. BMC Med. 2011;9:33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3224599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21470407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drew BG, Fidge NH, Gallon-Beaumier G, Kemp BE, Kingwell BA. High-density lipoprotein and apolipoprotein AI increase endothelial NO synthase activity by protein association and multisite phosphorylation. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2004;101(18):6999&#x2013;7004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC406455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15107497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egan D, Kim J, Shaw RJ, Guan KL. The autophagy initiating kinase ULK1 is regulated via opposing phosphorylation by AMPK and mTOR. Autophagy. 2011;7(6):643&#x2013;644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3359466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21460621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Assaad W, Buteau J, Peyot ML, et al. Saturated fatty acids synergize with elevated glucose to cause pancreatic beta-cell death. Endocrinology. 2003;144(9):4154&#x2013;4163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12933690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans JM, Donnelly LA, Emslie-Smith AM, Alessi DR, Morris AD. Metformin and reduced risk of cancer in diabetic patients. BMJ. 2005;330(7503):1304&#x2013;1305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC558205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15849206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faghihimani E, Aminorroaya A, Rezvanian H, Adibi P, Ismail-Beigi F, Amini M. Salsalate improves glycemic control in patients with newly diagnosed type 2 diabetes. Acta Diabetol. 2013;50(4):537&#x2013;543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21938543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faubert B, Boily G, Izreig S, et al. AMPK is a negative regulator of the Warburg effect and suppresses tumor growth in vivo. Cell Metab. 2013;17(1):113&#x2013;124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3545102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23274086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fidan E, Onder EH, Yilmaz M, et al. The effects of rosiglitazone and metformin on inflammation and endothelial dysfunction in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Acta Diabetol. 2011;48(4):297&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21424914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foretz M, Ancellin N, Andreelli F, et al. Short-term overexpression of a constitutively active form of AMP-activated protein kinase in the liver leads to mild hypoglycemia and fatty liver. Diabetes. 2005;54(5):1331&#x2013;1339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15855317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeland KR, Wolever TM. Acute effects of intravenous and rectal acetate on glucagon-like peptide-1, peptide YY, ghrelin, adiponectin and tumour necrosis factor-alpha. Br J Nutr. 2010;103(3):460&#x2013;466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19818198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu YN, Xiao H, Ma XW, Jiang SY, Xu M, Zhang YY. Metformin attenuates pressure overload-induced cardiac hypertrophy via AMPK activation. Acta Pharmacol Sin. 2011;32(7):879&#x2013;887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4003117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21552292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu X, Zhao JX, Liang J, Zhu MJ, Viollet B, Du M. AMP-activated protein kinase mediates myogenin expression and myogenesis via histone deacetylase 5. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2013;305(8):C887&#x2013;C895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3798682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23926128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fulco M, Cen Y, Zhao P, et al. Glucose restriction inhibits skeletal myoblast differentiation by activating SIRT1 through AMPK-mediated regulation of Nampt. Dev Cell. 2008;14(5):661&#x2013;673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2431467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18477450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y, Li Y, Xue J, Jia Y, Hu J. Effect of the anti-diabetic drug metformin on bone mass in ovariectomized rats. Eur J Pharmacol. 2010;635(1&#x2013;3):231&#x2013;236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20307532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao N, Zhao TY, Li XJ. The protective effect of berberine on beta-cell lipoapoptosis. J Endocrinol Invest. 2011;34(2):124&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20414047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garton AJ, Yeaman SJ. Identification and role of the basal phosphorylation site on hormone-sensitive lipase. Eur J Biochem. 1990;191(1):245&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2165906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geisler J, Haynes B, Ekse D, Dowsett M, Lonning PE. Total body aromatization in postmenopausal breast cancer patients is strongly correlated to plasma leptin levels. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2007;104(1&#x2013;2):27&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17350249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannarelli R, Aragona M, Coppelli A, Del PS. Reducing insulin resistance with metformin: the evidence today. Diabetes Metab. 2003;29(4 Pt 2):6S28&#x2013;6S35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14502098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gingras AC, Raught B, Gygi SP, et al. Hierarchical phosphorylation of the translation inhibitor 4E-BP1. Genes Dev. 2001;15(21):2852&#x2013;2864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC312813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11691836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldfine AB, Fonseca V, Jablonski KA, Pyle L, Staten MA, Shoelson SE. The effects of salsalate on glycemic control in patients with type 2 diabetes: a randomized trial. Ann Intern Med. 2010;152(6):346&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3138470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20231565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gollob MH, Green MS, Tang AS, et al. Identification of a gene responsible for familial Wolff&#x2013;Parkinson&#x2013;White syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2001;344(24):1823&#x2013;1831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11407343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graff JR, Konicek BW, Carter JH, Marcusson EG. Targeting the eukaryotic translation initiation factor 4E for cancer therapy. Cancer Res. 2008;68(3):631&#x2013;634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18245460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grange L, Nguyen MV, Lardy B, et al. NAD(P)H oxidase activity of Nox4 in chondrocytes is both inducible and involved in collagenase expression. Antioxid Redox Signal. 2006;8(9&#x2013;10):1485&#x2013;1496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16987005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greco SJ, Sarkar S, Johnston JM, Tezapsidis N. Leptin regulates tau phosphorylation and amyloid through AMPK in neuronal cells. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2009;380(1):98&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2657956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19166821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greer EL, Oskoui PR, Banko MR, et al. The energy sensor AMP-activated protein kinase directly regulates the mammalian FOXO3 transcription factor. J Biol Chem. 2007;282(41):30107&#x2013;30119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17711846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu Y, Zhang Y, Shi X, et al. Effect of traditional Chinese medicine berberine on type 2 diabetes based on comprehensive metabonomics. Talanta. 2010;81(3):766&#x2013;772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20298851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan S, Wang B, Li W, Guan J, Fang X. Effects of berberine on expression of LOX-1 and SR-BI in human macrophage-derived foam cells induced by ox-LDL. Am J Chin Med. 2010;38(6):1161&#x2013;1169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21061468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gui SY, Wu L, Peng DY, Liu QY, Yin BP, Shen JZ. Preparation and evaluation of a microemulsion for oral delivery of berberine. Pharmazie. 2008;63(7):516&#x2013;519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18717486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y, Chen Y, Tan ZR, Klaassen CD, Zhou HH. Repeated administration of berberine inhibits cytochromes P450 in humans. Eur J Clin Pharmacol. 2012;68(2):213&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4898966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21870106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habegger KM, Hoffman NJ, Ridenour CM, Brozinick JT, Elmendorf JS. AMPK enhances insulin-stimulated GLUT4 regulation via lowering membrane cholesterol. Endocrinology. 2012;153(5):2130&#x2013;2141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3339638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22434076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hara T, Nakamura K, Matsui M, et al. Suppression of basal autophagy in neural cells causes neurodegenerative disease in mice. Nature. 2006;441(7095):885&#x2013;889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16625204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harborne LR, Sattar N, Norman JE, Fleming R. Metformin and weight loss in obese women with polycystic ovary syndrome: comparison of doses. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2005;90(8):4593&#x2013;4598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15886247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardie DG. AMP-activated/SNF1 protein kinases: conserved guardians of cellular energy. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2007;8(10):774&#x2013;785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17712357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardie DG. Energy sensing by the AMP-activated protein kinase and its effects on muscle metabolism. Proc Nutr Soc. 2011;70(1):92&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21067629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hariharan N, Maejima Y, Nakae J, Paik J, DePinho RA, Sadoshima J. Deacetylation of FoxO by Sirt1 plays an essential role in mediating starvation-induced autophagy in cardiac myocytes. Circ Res. 2010;107(12):1470&#x2013;1482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3011986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20947830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison DE, Strong R, Sharp ZD, et al. Rapamycin fed late in life extends lifespan in genetically heterogeneous mice. Nature. 2009;460(7253):392&#x2013;395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2786175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19587680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hattori Y, Jojima T, Tomizawa A, et al. A glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP-1) analogue, liraglutide, upregulates nitric oxide production and exerts anti-inflammatory action in endothelial cells. Diabetologia. 2010;53(10):2256&#x2013;2263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20593161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawley SA, Ross FA, Chevtzoff C, et al. Use of cells expressing gamma subunit variants to identify diverse mechanisms of AMPK activation. Cell Metab. 2010;11(6):554&#x2013;565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2935965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20519126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawley SA, Fullerton MD, Ross FA, et al. The ancient drug salicylate directly activates AMP-activated protein kinase. Science. 2012;336(6083):918&#x2013;922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3399766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22517326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haxhinasto S, Mathis D, Benoist C. The AKT-mTOR axis regulates de novo differentiation of CD4+Foxp3+ cells. J Exp Med. 2008;205(3):565&#x2013;574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2275380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18283119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He L, Sabet A, Djedjos S, et al. Metformin and insulin suppress hepatic gluconeogenesis through phosphorylation of CREB binding protein. Cell. 2009;137(4):635&#x2013;646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2775562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19450513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hearle N, Schumacher V, Menko FH, et al. Frequency and spectrum of cancers in the Peutz-Jeghers syndrome. Clin Cancer Res. 2006;12(10):3209&#x2013;3215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16707622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellerstein MK. De novo lipogenesis in humans: metabolic and regulatory aspects. Eur J Clin Nutr. 1999;53(Suppl 1):S53&#x2013;S65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10365981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirsch HA, Iliopoulos D, Tsichlis PN, Struhl K. Metformin selectively targets cancer stem cells, and acts together with chemotherapy to block tumor growth and prolong remission. Cancer Res. 2009;69(19):7507&#x2013;7511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2756324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19752085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holland WL, Miller RA, Wang ZV, et al. Receptor-mediated activation of ceramidase activity initiates the pleiotropic actions of adiponectin. Nat Med. 2011;17(1):55&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3134999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21186369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holman RR, Paul SK, Bethel MA, Matthews DR, Neil HA. 10-year follow-up of intensive glucose control in type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med. 2008;359(15):1577&#x2013;1589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18784090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong Y, Hui SC, Chan TY, Hou JY. Effect of berberine on regression of pressure-overload induced cardiac hypertrophy in rats. Am J Chin Med. 2002;30(4):589&#x2013;599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12568286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong Y, Hui SS, Chan BT, Hou J. Effect of berberine on catecholamine levels in rats with experimental cardiac hypertrophy. Life Sci. 2003;72(22):2499&#x2013;2507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12650858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu CC, Wahlqvist ML, Lee MS, Tsai HN. Incidence of dementia is increased in type 2 diabetes and reduced by the use of sulfonylureas and metformin. J Alzheimers Dis. 2011;24(3):485&#x2013;493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21297276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu JP, Nishishita K, Sakai E, et al. Berberine inhibits RANKL-induced osteoclast formation and survival through suppressing the NF-kappaB and Akt pathways. Eur J Pharmacol. 2008;580(1&#x2013;2):70&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18083161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu GX, Chen GR, Xu H, Ge RS, Lin J. Activation of the AMP activated protein kinase by short-chain fatty acids is the main mechanism underlying the beneficial effect of a high fiber diet on the metabolic syndrome. Med Hypotheses. 2010;74(1):123&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19665312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu PF, Chen WP, Tang JL, Bao JP, Wu LD. Protective effects of berberine in an experimental rat osteoarthritis model. Phytother Res. 2011;25(6):878&#x2013;885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21108488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X, Wullschleger S, Shpiro N, et al. Important role of the LKB1&#x2013;AMPK pathway in suppressing tumorigenesis in PTEN-deficient mice. Biochem J. 2008;412(2):211&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18387000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisamen B, Genade S, Lochner A. Signalling pathways activated by glucagon-like peptide-1 (7&#x2013;36) amide in the rat heart and their role in protection against ischaemia. Cardiovasc J Afr. 2008;19(2):77&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3975219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18516352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibanez L, Potau N, Ferrer A, Rodriguez-Hierro F, Marcos MV, De ZF. Anovulation in eumenorrheic, nonobese adolescent girls born small for gestational age: insulin sensitization induces ovulation, increases lean body mass, and reduces abdominal fat excess, dyslipidemia, and subclinical hyperandrogenism. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2002;87(12):5702&#x2013;5705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12466374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iliopoulos D, Hirsch HA, Struhl K. Metformin decreases the dose of chemotherapy for prolonging tumor remission in mouse xenografts involving multiple cancer cell types. Cancer Res. 2011;71(9):3196&#x2013;3201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3085572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21415163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishii N, Matsumura T, Kinoshita H, et al. Activation of AMP-activated protein kinase suppresses oxidized low-density lipoprotein-induced macrophage proliferation. J Biol Chem. 2009;284(50):34561&#x2013;34569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2787318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19843515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwabu M, Yamauchi T, Okada-Iwabu M, et al. Adiponectin and AdipoR1 regulate PGC-1alpha and mitochondria by Ca(2+) and AMPK/SIRT1. Nature. 2010;464(7293):1313&#x2013;1319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20357764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jager S, Handschin C, St-Pierre J, Spiegelman BM. AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) action in skeletal muscle via direct phosphorylation of PGC-1alpha. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2007;104(29):12017&#x2013;12022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1924552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17609368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakubowicz DJ, Seppala M, Jakubowicz S, et al. Insulin reduction with metformin increases luteal phase serum glycodelin and insulin-like growth factor-binding protein 1 concentrations and enhances uterine vascularity and blood flow in the polycystic ovary syndrome. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2001;86(3):1126&#x2013;1133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11238496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jalving M, Gietema JA, Lefrandt JD, et al. Metformin: taking away the candy for cancer? Eur J Cancer. 2010;46(13):2369&#x2013;2380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20656475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang WG, Kim EJ, Bae IH, et al. Metformin induces osteoblast differentiation via orphan nuclear receptor SHP-mediated transactivation of Runx2. Bone. 2011;48(4):885&#x2013;893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21147283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimenez-Sanchez M, Thompson F, Zavodsky E, Rubinsztein DC. Autophagy and polyglutamine diseases. Prog Neurobiol. 2012;97(2):67&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3712188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21930185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiralerspong S, Palla SL, Giordano SH, et al. Metformin and pathologic complete responses to neoadjuvant chemotherapy in diabetic patients with breast cancer. J Clin Oncol. 2009;27(20):3297&#x2013;3302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2736070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19487376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson JB, Laub DR, John S. The effect on health of alternate day calorie restriction: eating less and more than needed on alternate days prolongs life. Med Hypotheses. 2006;67(2):209&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16529878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson JB, Summer W, Cutler RG, et al. Alternate day calorie restriction improves clinical findings and reduces markers of oxidative stress and inflammation in overweight adults with moderate asthma. Free Radic Biol Med. 2007;42(5):665&#x2013;674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1859864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17291990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston CS, White AM, Kent SM. Preliminary evidence that regular vinegar ingestion favorably influences hemoglobin A1c values in individuals with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2009;84(2):e15&#x2013;e17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19269707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston CS, Steplewska I, Long CA, Harris LN, Ryals RH. Examination of the antiglycemic properties of vinegar in healthy adults. Ann Nutr Metab. 2010;56(1):74&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20068289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones RG, Plas DR, Kubek S, et al. AMP-activated protein kinase induces a p53-dependent metabolic checkpoint. Mol Cell. 2005;18(3):283&#x2013;293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15866171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Julius U. Influence of plasma free fatty acids on lipoprotein synthesis and diabetic dyslipidemia. Exp Clin Endocrinol Diabetes. 2003;111(5):246&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12951628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanazawa I, Yamaguchi T, Yano S, Yamauchi M, Sugimoto T. Metformin enhances the differentiation and mineralization of osteoblastic MC3T3-E1 cells via AMP kinase activation as well as eNOS and BMP-2 expression. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2008;375(3):414&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18721796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang KY, Kim YK, Yi H, et al. Metformin downregulates Th17 cells differentiation and attenuates murine autoimmune arthritis. Int Immunopharmacol. 2013;16(1):85&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23557965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YD, Park KG, Lee YS, et al. Metformin inhibits hepatic gluconeogenesis through AMP-activated protein kinase-dependent regulation of the orphan nuclear receptor SHP. Diabetes. 2008;57(2):306&#x2013;314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17909097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura T, Tomura H, Sato K, et al. Mechanism and role of high density lipoprotein-induced activation of AMP-activated protein kinase in endothelial cells. J Biol Chem. 2010;285(7):4387&#x2013;4397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2836043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20018878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirpichnikov D, McFarlane SI, Sowers JR. Metformin: an update. Ann Intern Med. 2002;137(1):25&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12093242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kisfalvi K, Rey O, Young SH, Sinnett-Smith J, Rozengurt E. Insulin potentiates Ca2+ signaling and phosphatidylinositol 4,5-bisphosphate hydrolysis induced by Gq protein-coupled receptor agonists through an mTOR-dependent pathway. Endocrinology. 2007;148(7):3246&#x2013;3257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17379645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kisfalvi K, Eibl G, Sinnett-Smith J, Rozengurt E. Metformin disrupts crosstalk between G protein-coupled receptor and insulin receptor signaling systems and inhibits pancreatic cancer growth. Cancer Res. 2009;69(16):6539&#x2013;6545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2753241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19679549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowler WC, Barrett-Connor E, Fowler SE, et al. Reduction in the incidence of type 2 diabetes with lifestyle intervention or metformin. N Engl J Med. 2002;346(6):393&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1370926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11832527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondo T, Kishi M, Fushimi T, Ugajin S, Kaga T. Vinegar intake reduces body weight, body fat mass, and serum triglyceride levels in obese Japanese subjects. Biosci Biotechnol Biochem. 2009;73(8):1837&#x2013;1843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19661687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondo T, Kishi M, Fushimi T, Kaga T. Acetic acid upregulates the expression of genes for fatty acid oxidation enzymes in liver to suppress body fat accumulation. J Agric Food Chem. 2009;57(13):5982&#x2013;5986.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19469536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong W, Wei J, Abidi P, et al. Berberine is a novel cholesterol-lowering drug working through a unique mechanism distinct from statins. Nat Med. 2004;10(12):1344&#x2013;1351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15531889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong WJ, Wei J, Zuo ZY, et al. Combination of simvastatin with berberine improves the lipid-lowering efficacy. Metabolism. 2008;57(8):1029&#x2013;1037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18640378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo SH, Flechner L, Qi L, et al. The CREB coactivator TORC2 is a key regulator of fasting glucose metabolism. Nature. 2005;437(7062):1109&#x2013;1111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16148943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kukidome D, Nishikawa T, Sonoda K, et al. Activation of AMP-activated protein kinase reduces hyperglycemia-induced mitochondrial reactive oxygen species production and promotes mitochondrial biogenesis in human umbilical vein endothelial cells. Diabetes. 2006;55(1):120&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16380484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landman GW, Kleefstra N, van Hateren KJ, Groenier KH, Gans RO, Bilo HJ. Metformin associated with lower cancer mortality in type 2 diabetes: ZODIAC-16. Diabetes Care. 2010;33(2):322&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2809274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19918015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee WJ, Song KH, Koh EH, et al. Alpha-lipoic acid increases insulin sensitivity by activating AMPK in skeletal muscle. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2005;332(3):885&#x2013;891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15913551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YS, Kim WS, Kim KH, et al. Berberine, a natural plant product, activates AMP-activated protein kinase with beneficial metabolic effects in diabetic and insulin-resistant states. Diabetes. 2006;55(8):2256&#x2013;2264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16873688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee TS, Pan CC, Peng CC, et al. Anti-atherogenic effect of berberine on LXRalpha-ABCA1-dependent cholesterol efflux in macrophages. J Cell Biochem. 2010;111(1):104&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20506155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JM, Seo WY, Song KH, et al. AMPK-dependent repression of hepatic gluconeogenesis via disruption of CREB.CRTC2 complex by orphan nuclear receptor small heterodimer partner. J Biol Chem. 2010;285(42):32182&#x2013;32191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2952219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20688914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YS, Kim YS, Lee SY, et al. AMP kinase acts as a negative regulator of RANKL in the differentiation of osteoclasts. Bone. 2010;47(5):926&#x2013;937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20696287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee IA, Hyun YJ, Kim DH. Berberine ameliorates TNBS-induced colitis by inhibiting lipid peroxidation, enterobacterial growth and NF-kappaB activation. Eur J Pharmacol. 2010;648(1&#x2013;3):162&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20828550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee CG, Boyko EJ, Barrett-Connor E, et al. Insulin sensitizers may attenuate lean mass loss in older men with diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2011;34(11):2381&#x2013;2386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3198278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21926282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JH, Kim TI, Jeon SM, Hong SP, Cheon JH, Kim WH. The effects of metformin on the survival of colorectal cancer patients with diabetes mellitus. Int J Cancer. 2012;131(3):751&#x2013;759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21913184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonhardt M, Langhans W. Fatty acid oxidation and control of food intake. Physiol Behav. 2004;83(4):645&#x2013;651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15621070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesniewski LA, Durrant JR, Connell ML, Folian BJ, Donato AJ, Seals DR. Salicylate treatment improves age-associated vascular endothelial dysfunction: potential role of nuclear factor kappaB and forkhead Box O phosphorylation. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2011;66(4):409&#x2013;418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3055281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21303813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Miyahara T, Tezuka Y, et al. The effect of kampo formulae on bone resorption in vitro and in vivo. II. Detailed study of berberine. Biol Pharm Bull. 1999;22(4):391&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10328560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F, Wang HD, Lu DX, et al. Neutral sulfate berberine modulates cytokine secretion and increases survival in endotoxemic mice. Acta Pharmacol Sin. 2006;27(9):1199&#x2013;1205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16923341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li HL, Yin R, Chen D, et al. Long-term activation of adenosine monophosphate-activated protein kinase attenuates pressure-overload-induced cardiac hypertrophy. J Cell Biochem. 2007;100(5):1086&#x2013;1099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17266062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li K, Yao W, Zheng X, Liao K. Berberine promotes the development of atherosclerosis and foam cell formation by inducing scavenger receptor A expression in macrophage. Cell Res. 2009;19(8):1006&#x2013;1017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19546885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D, Wang D, Wang Y, Ling W, Feng X, Xia M. Adenosine monophosphate-activated protein kinase induces cholesterol efflux from macrophage-derived foam cells and alleviates atherosclerosis in apolipoprotein E-deficient mice. J Biol Chem. 2010;285(43):33499&#x2013;33509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2963409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20713354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Benashski SE, Venna VR, McCullough LD. Effects of metformin in experimental stroke. Stroke. 2010;41(11):2645&#x2013;2652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2994809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Xu S, Mihaylova MM, et al. AMPK phosphorylates and inhibits SREBP activity to attenuate hepatic steatosis and atherosclerosis in diet-induced insulin-resistant mice. Cell Metab. 2011;13(4):376&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3086578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21459323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Chen H, Guan Y, et al. Acetic acid activates the AMP-activated protein kinase signaling pathway to regulate lipid metabolism in bovine hepatocytes. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(7):e67880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3701595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23861826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libby G, Donnelly LA, Donnan PT, Alessi DR, Morris AD, Evans JM. New users of metformin are at low risk of incident cancer: a cohort study among people with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2009;32(9):1620&#x2013;1625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2732153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19564453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linker K, Pautz A, Fechir M, Hubrich T, Greeve J, Kleinert H. Involvement of KSRP in the post-transcriptional regulation of human iNOS expression-complex interplay of KSRP with TTP and HuR. Nucleic Acids Res. 2005;33(15):4813&#x2013;4827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1192834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16126846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu LZ, Cheung SC, Lan LL, et al. Berberine modulates insulin signaling transduction in insulin-resistant cells. Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2010;317(1&#x2013;2):148&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20036710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo YY, Conquer JA, Grinstein S, Cruz TF. Interleukin-1 beta induction of c-fos and collagenase expression in articular chondrocytes: involvement of reactive oxygen species. J Cell Biochem. 1998;69(1):19&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9513043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu J, McKinsey TA, Zhang CL, Olson EN. Regulation of skeletal myogenesis by association of the MEF2 transcription factor with class II histone deacetylases. Mol Cell. 2000;6(2):233&#x2013;244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10983972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu DY, Tang CH, Chen YH, Wei IH. Berberine suppresses neuroinflammatory responses through AMP-activated protein kinase activation in BV-2 microglia. J Cell Biochem. 2010;110(3):697&#x2013;705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20512929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luque-Ramirez M, Escobar-Morreale HF. Treatment of polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS) with metformin ameliorates insulin resistance in parallel with the decrease of serum interleukin-6 concentrations. Horm Metab Res. 2010;42(11):815&#x2013;820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20730705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma X, Jiang Y, Wu A, et al. Berberine attenuates experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis in C57 BL/6 mice. PLoS ONE. 2010;5(10):e13489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2957444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20976070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mai QG, Zhang ZM, Xu S, et al. Metformin stimulates osteoprotegerin and reduces RANKL expression in osteoblasts and ovariectomized rats. J Cell Biochem. 2011;112(10):2902&#x2013;2909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21618594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mamane Y, Petroulakis E, Rong L, Yoshida K, Ler LW, Sonenberg N. eIF4E&#x2014;from translation to transformation. Oncogene. 2004;23(18):3172&#x2013;3179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15094766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marambaud P, Zhao H, Davies P. Resveratrol promotes clearance of Alzheimer's disease amyloid-beta peptides. J Biol Chem. 2005;280(45):37377&#x2013;37382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16162502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masoudi FA, Inzucchi SE, Wang Y, Havranek EP, Foody JM, Krumholz HM. Thiazolidinediones, metformin, and outcomes in older patients with diabetes and heart failure: an observational study. Circulation. 2005;111(5):583&#x2013;590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15699279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massion PB, Balligand JL. Relevance of nitric oxide for myocardial remodeling. Curr Heart Fail Rep. 2007;4(1):18&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17386181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarty MF. Hepatothermic therapy of obesity: rationale and an inventory of resources. Med Hypotheses. 2001;57(3):324&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11516225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarty MF. Does regular ethanol consumption promote insulin sensitivity and leanness by stimulating AMP-activated protein kinase? Med Hypotheses. 2001;57(3):405&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11516237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarty MF. Chronic activation of AMP-activated kinase as a strategy for slowing aging. Med Hypotheses. 2004;63(2):334&#x2013;339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15236799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarty MF. High mitochondrial redox potential may promote induction and activation of UCP2 in hepatocytes during hepatothermic therapy. Med Hypotheses. 2005;64(6):1216&#x2013;1219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15823721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarty MF. Salsalate may have broad utility in the prevention and treatment of vascular disorders and the metabolic syndrome. Med Hypotheses. 2010;75(3):276&#x2013;281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20080359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarty MF. mTORC1 activity as a determinant of cancer risk&#x2014;rationalizing the cancer-preventive effects of adiponectin, metformin, rapamycin, and low-protein vegan diets. Med Hypotheses. 2011;77(4):642&#x2013;648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21862237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarty MF (2013) Could carbohydrate-concentrated diets mimic calorie restriction in slowing the aging process? Available at: http://catalyticlongevity.org/prepub_archive/Slabber-essay.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarty MF, Block KI. Preadministration of high-dose salicylates, suppressors of NF-kappaB activation, may increase the chemosensitivity of many cancers: an example of proapoptotic signal modulation therapy. Integr Cancer Ther. 2006;5(3):252&#x2013;268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16880431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarty MF, Barroso-Aranda J, Contreras F. AMP-activated kinase may suppress NADPH oxidase activation in vascular tissues. Med Hypotheses. 2009;72(4):468&#x2013;470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19181455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McFate T, Mohyeldin A, Lu H, et al. Pyruvate dehydrogenase complex activity controls metabolic and malignant phenotype in cancer cells. J Biol Chem. 2008;283(33):22700&#x2013;22708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2504897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18541534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGarry JD, Leatherman GF, Foster DW. Carnitine palmitoyltransferase I. The site of inhibition of hepatic fatty acid oxidation by malonyl-CoA. J Biol Chem. 1978;253(12):4128&#x2013;4136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">659409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGee SL, van Denderen BJ, Howlett KF, et al. AMP-activated protein kinase regulates GLUT4 transcription by phosphorylating histone deacetylase 5. Diabetes. 2008;57(4):860&#x2013;867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18184930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehenni H, Gehrig C, Nezu J, et al. Loss of LKB1 kinase activity in Peutz&#x2013;Jeghers syndrome, and evidence for allelic and locus heterogeneity. Am J Hum Genet. 1998;63(6):1641&#x2013;1650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1377635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9837816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meneghini LF, Orozco-Beltran D, Khunti K, et al. Weight beneficial treatments for type 2 diabetes. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2011;96(11):3337&#x2013;3353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21900381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michalek RD, Gerriets VA, Jacobs SR, et al. Cutting edge: distinct glycolytic and lipid oxidative metabolic programs are essential for effector and regulatory CD4+ T cell subsets. J Immunol. 2011;186(6):3299&#x2013;3303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3198034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21317389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Micic D, Cvijovic G, Trajkovic V, Duntas LH, Polovina S. Metformin: its emerging role in oncology. Hormones (Athens) 2011;10(1):5&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21349801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihaylova MM, Vasquez DS, Ravnskjaer K, et al. Class IIa histone deacetylases are hormone-activated regulators of FOXO and mammalian glucose homeostasis. Cell. 2011;145(4):607&#x2013;621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3117637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21565617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min SW, Cho SH, Zhou Y, et al. Acetylation of tau inhibits its degradation and contributes to tauopathy. Neuron. 2010;67(6):953&#x2013;966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3035103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20869593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monsuez JJ, Gesquiere-Dando A, Rivera S. Cardiovascular prevention of cognitive decline. Cardiol Res Pract. 2011;2011:250970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3035018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21318115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulherin AJ, Oh AH, Kim H, Grieco A, Lauffer LM, Brubaker PL. Mechanisms underlying metformin-induced secretion of glucagon-like peptide-1 from the intestinal L cell. Endocrinology. 2011;152(11):4610&#x2013;4619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21971158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muoio DM, Seefeld K, Witters LA, Coleman RA. AMP-activated kinase reciprocally regulates triacylglycerol synthesis and fatty acid oxidation in liver and muscle: evidence that sn-glycerol-3-phosphate acyltransferase is a novel target. Biochem J. 1999;338(Pt 3):783&#x2013;791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1220117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10051453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musi N, Goodyear LJ. AMP-activated protein kinase and muscle glucose uptake. Acta Physiol Scand. 2003;178(4):337&#x2013;345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12864738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musi N, Hirshman MF, Nygren J, et al. Metformin increases AMP-activated protein kinase activity in skeletal muscle of subjects with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes. 2002;51(7):2074&#x2013;2081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12086935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nath N, Giri S, Prasad R, Salem ML, Singh AK, Singh I. 5-aminoimidazole-4-carboxamide ribonucleoside: a novel immunomodulator with therapeutic efficacy in experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis. J Immunol. 2005;175(1):566&#x2013;574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15972693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nath N, Khan M, Paintlia MK, Singh I, Hoda MN, Giri S. Metformin attenuated the autoimmune disease of the central nervous system in animal models of multiple sclerosis. J Immunol. 2009;182(12):8005&#x2013;8014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2965405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19494326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nath N, Khan M, Rattan R, et al. Loss of AMPK exacerbates experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis disease severity. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2009;386(1):16&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2976596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19486896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieuwenhuis-Ruifrok AE, Kuchenbecker WK, Hoek A, Middleton P, Norman RJ. Insulin sensitizing drugs for weight loss in women of reproductive age who are overweight or obese: systematic review and meta-analysis. Hum Reprod Update. 2009;15(1):57&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18927072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira SM, Ehtisham J, Redwood CS, Ostman-Smith I, Blair EM, Watkins H. Mutation analysis of AMP-activated protein kinase subunits in inherited cardiomyopathies: implications for kinase function and disease pathogenesis. J Mol Cell Cardiol. 2003;35(10):1251&#x2013;1255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14519435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olmos Y, Valle I, Borniquel S, et al. Mutual dependence of Foxo3a and PGC-1alpha in the induction of oxidative stress genes. J Biol Chem. 2009;284(21):14476&#x2013;14484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2682896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19324885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostman E, Granfeldt Y, Persson L, Bjorck I. Vinegar supplementation lowers glucose and insulin responses and increases satiety after a bread meal in healthy subjects. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2005;59(9):983&#x2013;988.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16015276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park H, Kaushik VK, Constant S, et al. Coordinate regulation of malonyl-CoA decarboxylase, sn-glycerol-3-phosphate acyltransferase, and acetyl-CoA carboxylase by AMP-activated protein kinase in rat tissues in response to exercise. J Biol Chem. 2002;277(36):32571&#x2013;32577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12065578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson KJ, Baur JA, Lewis KN, et al. Resveratrol delays age-related deterioration and mimics transcriptional aspects of dietary restriction without extending life span. Cell Metab. 2008;8(2):157&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2538685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18599363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelletier JP, DiBattista JA, Roughley P, McCollum R, Martel-Pelletier J. Cytokines and inflammation in cartilage degradation. Rheum Dis Clin North Am. 1993;19(3):545&#x2013;568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8210574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelletier JP, Jovanovic D, Fernandes JC, et al. Reduced progression of experimental osteoarthritis in vivo by selective inhibition of inducible nitric oxide synthase. Arthritis Rheum. 1998;41(7):1275&#x2013;1286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9663486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelletier JP, Lascau-Coman V, Jovanovic D, et al. Selective inhibition of inducible nitric oxide synthase in experimental osteoarthritis is associated with reduction in tissue levels of catabolic factors. J Rheumatol. 1999;26(9):2002&#x2013;2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10493683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng L, Li ZR, Green RS, Holzman IR, Lin J. Butyrate enhances the intestinal barrier by facilitating tight junction assembly via activation of AMP-activated protein kinase in Caco-2 cell monolayers. J Nutr. 2009;139(9):1619&#x2013;1625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2728689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19625695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips LK, Prins JB. The link between abdominal obesity and the metabolic syndrome. Curr Hypertens Rep. 2008;10(2):156&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18474184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SA, Ciaraldi TP, Kong AP, et al. Modulation of circulating and adipose tissue adiponectin levels by antidiabetic therapy. Diabetes. 2003;52(3):667&#x2013;674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12606507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce GL, Lesniewski LA, Lawson BR, Beske SD, Seals DR. Nuclear factor-{kappa}B activation contributes to vascular endothelial dysfunction via oxidative stress in overweight/obese middle-aged and older humans. Circulation. 2009;119(9):1284&#x2013;1292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2810548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19237660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piwkowska A, Rogacka D, Jankowski M, Dominiczak MH, Stepinski JK, Angielski S. Metformin induces suppression of NAD(P)H oxidase activity in podocytes. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2010;393(2):268&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20123087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poulsen MM, Vestergaard PF, Clasen BF, et al. High-dose resveratrol supplementation in obese men: an investigator-initiated, randomized, placebo-controlled clinical trial of substrate metabolism, insulin sensitivity, and body composition. Diabetes. 2013;62(4):1186&#x2013;1195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3609591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23193181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Praharaj SK, Jana AK, Goyal N, Sinha VK. Metformin for olanzapine-induced weight gain: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2011;71(3):377&#x2013;382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3045546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21284696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puyal J, Ginet V, Grishchuk Y, Truttmann AC, Clarke PG. Neuronal autophagy as a mediator of life and death: contrasting roles in chronic neurodegenerative and acute neural disorders. Neuroscientist. 2011;18(3):224&#x2013;236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21525331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin X, Guo BT, Wan B, et al. Regulation of Th1 and Th17 cell differentiation and amelioration of experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis by natural product compound berberine. J Immunol. 2010;185(3):1855&#x2013;1863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20622114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasouli N, Molavi B, Elbein SC, Kern PA. Ectopic fat accumulation and metabolic syndrome. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2007;9(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17199713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rejnmark L. Bone effects of glitazones and other anti-diabetic drugs. Curr Drug Saf. 2008;3(3):194&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18691001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Moctezuma JR, Robles-Lopez G, Lopez-Carmona JM, Gutierrez-Rosas MJ. Effects of metformin on the body composition in subjects with risk factors for type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2005;7(2):189&#x2013;192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15715892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothwell PM, Fowkes FG, Belch JF, Ogawa H, Warlow CP, Meade TW. Effect of daily aspirin on long-term risk of death due to cancer: analysis of individual patient data from randomised trials. Lancet. 2010;377(9759):31&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21144578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roussel R, Travert F, Pasquet B, et al. Metformin use and mortality among patients with diabetes and atherothrombosis. Arch Intern Med. 2010;170(21):1892&#x2013;1899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21098347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozengurt E, Sinnett-Smith J, Kisfalvi K. Crosstalk between insulin/insulin-like growth factor-1 receptors and G protein-coupled receptor signaling systems: a novel target for the antidiabetic drug metformin in pancreatic cancer. Clin Cancer Res. 2010;16(9):2505&#x2013;2511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2862089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20388847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakakibara S, Yamauchi T, Oshima Y, Tsukamoto Y, Kadowaki T. Acetic acid activates hepatic AMPK and reduces hyperglycemia in diabetic KK-A(y) mice. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2006;344(2):597&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16630552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakakibara S, Murakami R, Takahashi M, et al. Vinegar intake enhances flow-mediated vasodilatation via upregulation of endothelial nitric oxide synthase activity. Biosci Biotechnol Biochem. 2010;74(5):1055&#x2013;1061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20460711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salminen A, Hyttinen JM, Kaarniranta K. AMP-activated protein kinase inhibits NF-kappaB signaling and inflammation: impact on healthspan and lifespan. J Mol Med (Berl) 2011;89(7):667&#x2013;676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3111671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21431325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salminen A, Kaarniranta K, Haapasalo A, Soininen H, Hiltunen M. AMP-activated protein kinase: a potential player in Alzheimer's disease. J Neurochem. 2011;118(4):460&#x2013;474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21623793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salpeter SR, Greyber E, Pasternak GA, Salpeter EE. Risk of fatal and nonfatal lactic acidosis with metformin use in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2010;4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7138050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20393934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuels A, Perry MJ, Gibson RL, Colley S, Tobias JH. Role of endothelial nitric oxide synthase in estrogen-induced osteogenesis. Bone. 2001;29(1):24&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11472887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez AM, Candau RB, Csibi A, Pagano AF, Raibon A, Bernardi H. The role of AMP-activated protein kinase in the coordination of skeletal muscle turnover and energy homeostasis. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2012;303(5):C475&#x2013;C485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22700795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanli T, Rashid A, Liu C, et al. Ionizing radiation activates AMP-activated kinase (AMPK): a target for radiosensitization of human cancer cells. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2010;78(1):221&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20615625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpello JH. Improving survival with metformin: the evidence base today. Diabetes Metab. 2003;29(4 Pt 2):6S36&#x2013;6S43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14502099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scharrer E. Control of food intake by fatty acid oxidation and ketogenesis. Nutrition. 1999;15(9):704&#x2013;714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10467616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scheen AJ. Clinical pharmacokinetics of metformin. Clin Pharmacokinet. 1996;30(5):359&#x2013;371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8743335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schramm TK, Gislason GH, Vaag A, et al. Mortality and cardiovascular risk associated with different insulin secretagogues compared with metformin in type 2 diabetes, with or without a previous myocardial infarction: a nationwide study. Eur Heart J. 2011;32(15):1900&#x2013;1908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21471135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selman C, Tullet JM, Wieser D, et al. Ribosomal protein S6 kinase 1 signaling regulates mammalian life span. Science. 2009;326(5949):140&#x2013;144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4954603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19797661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semenza GL. HIF-1 mediates the Warburg effect in clear cell renal carcinoma. J Bioenerg Biomembr. 2007;39(3):231&#x2013;234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17551816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sengupta S, Jang BC, Wu MT, Paik JH, Furneaux H, Hla T. The RNA-binding protein HuR regulates the expression of cyclooxygenase-2. J Biol Chem. 2003;278(27):25227&#x2013;25233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12704185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma PK, Bhansali A, Sialy R, Malhotra S, Pandhi P. Effects of pioglitazone and metformin on plasma adiponectin in newly detected type 2 diabetes mellitus. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 2006;65(6):722&#x2013;728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17121522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw RJ. LKB1 and AMP-activated protein kinase control of mTOR signalling and growth. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 2009;196(1):65&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2760308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19245654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson ER, Misso M, Hewitt KN, et al. Estrogen&#x2014;the good, the bad, and the unexpected. Endocr Rev. 2005;26(3):322&#x2013;330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15817672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith MR, Jaramillo M, Liu YL, et al. Translation initiation factors induce DNA synthesis and transform NIH 3&#xa0;T3 cells. New Biol. 1990;2(7):648&#x2013;654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2083255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AR, Visioli F, Frei B, Hagen TM. Lipoic acid significantly restores, in rats, the age-related decline in vasomotion. Br J Pharmacol. 2008;153(8):1615&#x2013;1622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2438266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18297110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith DL, Jr, Elam CF, Jr, Mattison JA, et al. Metformin supplementation and life span in Fischer-344 rats. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2010;65(5):468&#x2013;474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2854888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20304770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song G, Ouyang G, Bao S. The activation of Akt/PKB signaling pathway and cell survival. J Cell Mol Med. 2005;9(1):59&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6741304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15784165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St-Onge MP, Jones PJ. Physiological effects of medium-chain triglycerides: potential agents in the prevention of obesity. J Nutr. 2002;132(3):329&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11880549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumarac-Dumanovic M, Jeremic D, Pantovic A, et al. Therapeutic improvement of glucoregulation in newly diagnosed type 2 diabetes patients is associated with a reduction of IL-17 levels. Immunobiology. 2013;218(8):1113&#x2013;1118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23623393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y, Xun K, Wang Y, Chen X. A systematic review of the anticancer properties of berberine, a natural product from Chinese herbs. Anticancer Drugs. 2009;20(9):757&#x2013;769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19704371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan BX, Yao WX, Ge J, et al. Prognostic influence of metformin as first-line chemotherapy for advanced nonsmall cell lung cancer in patients with type 2 diabetes. Cancer. 2011;117(22):5103&#x2013;5111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21523768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang J, Feng Y, Tsao S, Wang N, Curtain R, Wang Y. Berberine and Coptidis rhizoma as novel antineoplastic agents: a review of traditional use and biomedical investigations. J Ethnopharmacol. 2009;126(1):5&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19686830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y, Chen Y, Jiang H, Nie D. The role of short-chain fatty acids in orchestrating two types of programmed cell death in colon cancer. Autophagy. 2011;7(2):235&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21160278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarkun I, Dikmen E, Cetinarslan B, Canturk Z. Impact of treatment with metformin on adipokines in patients with polycystic ovary syndrome. Eur Cytokine Netw. 2010;21(4):272&#x2013;277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21126943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terkeltaub R, Yang B, Lotz M, Liu-Bryan R. Chondrocyte AMP-activated protein kinase activity suppresses matrix degradation responses to proinflammatory cytokines interleukin-1beta and tumor necrosis factor alpha. Arthritis Rheum. 2011;63(7):1928&#x2013;1937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3128233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21400477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas GV, Tran C, Mellinghoff IK, et al. Hypoxia-inducible factor determines sensitivity to inhibitors of mTOR in kidney cancer. Nat Med. 2006;12(1):122&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16341243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornton C, Bright NJ, Sastre M, Muckett PJ, Carling D. AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) is a tau kinase, activated in response to amyloid beta-peptide exposure. Biochem J. 2011;434(3):503&#x2013;512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21204788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmers S, Konings E, Bilet L, et al. Calorie restriction-like effects of 30&#xa0;days of resveratrol supplementation on energy metabolism and metabolic profile in obese humans. Cell Metab. 2011;14:612&#x2013;622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3880862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22055504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turban S, Stretton C, Drouin O, et al. Defining the contribution of AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK) and protein kinase C (PKC) in regulation of glucose uptake by metformin in skeletal muscle cells. J Biol Chem. 2012;287(24):20088&#x2013;20099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3370192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22511782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner N, Li JY, Gosby A, et al. Berberine and its more biologically available derivative, dihydroberberine, inhibit mitochondrial respiratory complex I: a mechanism for the action of berberine to activate AMP-activated protein kinase and improve insulin action. Diabetes. 2008;57(5):1414&#x2013;1418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18285556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzoulaki I, Molokhia M, Curcin V, et al. Risk of cardiovascular disease and all cause mortality among patients with type 2 diabetes prescribed oral antidiabetes drugs: retrospective cohort study using UK general practice research database. BMJ. 2009;339:b4731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2788912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19959591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>UK Prospective Diabetes Study (UKPDS) Group Effect of intensive blood-glucose control with metformin on complications in overweight patients with type 2 diabetes (UKPDS 34) Lancet. 1998;352(9131):854&#x2013;865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9742977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Um JH, Park SJ, Kang H, et al. AMP-activated protein kinase-deficient mice are resistant to the metabolic effects of resveratrol. Diabetes. 2010;59(3):554&#x2013;563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2828647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19934007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unger RH, Clark GO, Scherer PE, Orci L. Lipid homeostasis, lipotoxicity and the metabolic syndrome. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2010;1801(3):209&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19948243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varady KA, Hellerstein MK. Alternate-day fasting and chronic disease prevention: a review of human and animal trials. Am J Clin Nutr. 2007;86(1):7&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17616757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vazquez-Martin A, Oliveras-Ferraros C, Cufi S, Del BS, Martin-Castillo B, Menendez JA. Metformin regulates breast cancer stem cell ontogeny by transcriptional regulation of the epithelial&#x2013;mesenchymal transition (EMT) status. Cell Cycle. 2010;9(18):3807&#x2013;3814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20890129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vazquez-Martin A, Oliveras-Ferraros C, Del BS, Martin-Castillo B, Menendez JA. The anti-diabetic drug metformin suppresses self-renewal and proliferation of trastuzumab-resistant tumor-initiating breast cancer stem cells. Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2011;126(2):355&#x2013;364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20458531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vestergaard P, Rejnmark L, Mosekilde L. Relative fracture risk in patients with diabetes mellitus, and the impact of insulin and oral antidiabetic medication on relative fracture risk. Diabetologia. 2005;48(7):1292&#x2013;1299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15909154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viana R, Aguado C, Esteban I, et al. Role of AMP-activated protein kinase in autophagy and proteasome function. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2008;369(3):964&#x2013;968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18328803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villanueva-Penacarrillo ML, Martin-Duce A, Ramos-Alvarez I, et al. Characteristic of GLP-1 effects on glucose metabolism in human skeletal muscle from obese patients. Regul Pept. 2011;168(1&#x2013;3):39&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21419173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vingtdeux V, Giliberto L, Zhao H, et al. AMP-activated protein kinase signaling activation by resveratrol modulates amyloid-beta peptide metabolism. J Biol Chem. 2010;285(12):9100&#x2013;9113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2838330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20080969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vingtdeux V, Chandakkar P, Zhao H, d&#x2019;Abramo C, Davies P, Marambaud P. Novel synthetic small-molecule activators of AMPK as enhancers of autophagy and amyloid-beta peptide degradation. FASEB J. 2011;25(1):219&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3005419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20852062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walle T, Hsieh F, DeLegge MH, Oatis JE, Jr, Walle UK. High absorption but very low bioavailability of oral resveratrol in humans. Drug Metab Dispos. 2004;32(12):1377&#x2013;1382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15333514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Fan J, Yang X, et al. AMP-activated kinase regulates cytoplasmic HuR. Mol Cell Biol. 2002;22(10):3425&#x2013;3436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC133799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11971974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Yang X, Kawai T, et al. AMP-activated protein kinase-regulated phosphorylation and acetylation of importin alpha1: involvement in the nuclear import of RNA-binding protein HuR. J Biol Chem. 2004;279(46):48376&#x2013;48388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15342649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Xu J, Song P, Viollet B, Zou MH. In vivo activation of AMP-activated protein kinase attenuates diabetes-enhanced degradation of GTP cyclohydrolase I. Diabetes. 2009;58(8):1893&#x2013;1901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2712774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19528375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Zhang M, Liang B, et al. AMPKalpha2 deletion causes aberrant expression and activation of NAD(P)H oxidase and consequent endothelial dysfunction in vivo: role of 26S proteasomes. Circ Res. 2010;106(6):1117&#x2013;1128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2920052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20167927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watt MJ, Holmes AG, Pinnamaneni SK, et al. Regulation of HSL serine phosphorylation in skeletal muscle and adipose tissue. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2006;290(3):E500&#x2013;E508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16188906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei W, Zhao H, Wang A, et al. A clinical study on the short-term effect of berberine in comparison to metformin on the metabolic characteristics of women with polycystic ovary syndrome. Eur J Endocrinol. 2012;166(1):99&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22019891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijkander J, Landstrom TR, Manganiello V, Belfrage P, Degerman E. Insulin-induced phosphorylation and activation of phosphodiesterase 3B in rat adipocytes: possible role for protein kinase B but not mitogen-activated protein kinase or p70 S6 kinase. Endocrinology. 1998;139(1):219&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9421418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Won JS, Im YB, Kim J, Singh AK, Singh I. Involvement of AMP-activated-protein-kinase (AMPK) in neuronal amyloidogenesis. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2010;399(4):487&#x2013;491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2977999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20659426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright JL, Stanford JL. Metformin use and prostate cancer in Caucasian men: results from a population-based case&#x2013;control study. Cancer Causes Control. 2009;20(9):1617&#x2013;1622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2767519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19653109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Song P, Xu J, Zhang M, Zou MH. Activation of protein phosphatase 2A by palmitate inhibits AMP-activated protein kinase. J Biol Chem. 2007;282(13):9777&#x2013;9788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17255104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia X, Yan J, Shen Y, et al. Berberine improves glucose metabolism in diabetic rats by inhibition of hepatic gluconeogenesis. PLoS ONE. 2011;6(2):e16556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3033390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21304897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao B, Sanders MJ, Underwood E, et al. Structure of mammalian AMPK and its regulation by ADP. Nature. 2011;472(7342):230&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3078618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21399626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Z, Zhang J, Wu J, Viollet B, Zou MH. Upregulation of mitochondrial uncoupling protein-2 by the AMP-activated protein kinase in endothelial cells attenuates oxidative stress in diabetes. Diabetes. 2008;57(12):3222&#x2013;3230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2584127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18835932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xilouri M, Stefanis L. Autophagy in the central nervous system: implications for neurodegenerative disorders. CNS Neurol Disord Drug Targets. 2010;9(6):701&#x2013;719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20942791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yap F, Craddock L, Yang J. Mechanism of AMPK suppression of LXR-dependent Srebp-1c transcription. Int J Biol Sci. 2011;7(5):645&#x2013;650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3107472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21647332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeung F, Hoberg JE, Ramsey CS, et al. Modulation of NF-kappaB-dependent transcription and cell survival by the SIRT1 deacetylase. EMBO J. 2004;23(12):2369&#x2013;2380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC423286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15152190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin MJ, Yamamoto Y, Gaynor RB. The anti-inflammatory agents aspirin and salicylate inhibit the activity of I(kappa)B kinase-beta. Nature. 1998;396(6706):77&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9817203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshino J, Conte C, Fontana L, et al. Resveratrol supplementation does not improve metabolic function in nonobese women with normal glucose tolerance. Cell Metab. 2012;16(5):658&#x2013;664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3496026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23102619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young A, Wu W, Sun W, et al. Flow activation of AMP-activated protein kinase in vascular endothelium leads to Kruppel-like factor 2 expression. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2009;29(11):1902&#x2013;1908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2766008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19696400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y, Liu L, Wang X, et al. Modulation of glucagon-like peptide-1 release by berberine: in vivo and in vitro studies. Biochem Pharmacol. 2010;79(7):1000&#x2013;1006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19945441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng X, Zeng X. Relationship between the clinical effects of berberine on severe congestive heart failure and its concentration in plasma studied by HPLC. Biomed Chromatogr. 1999;13(7):442&#x2013;444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10534753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng XH, Zeng XJ, Li YY. Efficacy and safety of berberine for congestive heart failure secondary to ischemic or idiopathic dilated cardiomyopathy. Am J Cardiol. 2003;92(2):173&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12860219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Lee TS, Kolb EM, et al. AMP-activated protein kinase is involved in endothelial NO synthase activation in response to shear stress. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2006;26(6):1281&#x2013;1287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16601232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Li X, Zou D, et al. Treatment of type 2 diabetes and dyslipidemia with the natural plant alkaloid berberine. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2008;93(7):2559&#x2013;2565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18397984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang P, Hu X, Xu X, et al. AMP activated protein kinase-alpha2 deficiency exacerbates pressure-overload-induced left ventricular hypertrophy and dysfunction in mice. Hypertension. 2008;52(5):918&#x2013;924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2760829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18838626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang CX, Pan SN, Meng RS, et al. Metformin attenuates ventricular hypertrophy by activating the AMP-activated protein kinase-endothelial nitric oxide synthase pathway in rats. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol. 2011;38(1):55&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21083698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang ZJ, Zheng ZJ, Kan H, et al. Reduced risk of colorectal cancer with metformin therapy in patients with type 2 diabetes: a meta-analysis. Diabetes Care. 2011;34(10):2323&#x2013;2328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3177711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21949223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou H, Mineshita S. The effect of berberine chloride on experimental colitis in rats in vivo and in vitro. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2000;294(3):822&#x2013;829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10945829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou G, Myers R, Li Y, et al. Role of AMP-activated protein kinase in mechanism of metformin action. J Clin Invest. 2001;108(8):1167&#x2013;1174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC209533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11602624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou J, Zhou S, Tang J, et al. Protective effect of berberine on beta cells in streptozotocin- and high-carbohydrate/high-fat diet-induced diabetic rats. Eur J Pharmacol. 2009;606(1&#x2013;3):262&#x2013;268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19374872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>