<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">30651825</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1792-0981</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Experimental and therapeutic medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Exp Ther Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Carvedilol alleviates diabetic cardiomyopathy in diabetic rats.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>479</StartPage><EndPage>487</EndPage><MedlinePgn>479-487</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3892/etm.2018.6954</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Diabetic cardiomyopathy (DCM) is characterized by structural and functional changes in the myocardium. Several studies have revealed that myocardial apoptosis and fibrosis occur during DCM. Studies have also indicated that oxidative stress may be a major factor associated with the development of DCM. Protein kinase C (PKC)&#x3b2;<sub>2</sub> has been demonstrated to be activated in diabetic rats, and overexpression of PKC&#x3b2;<sub>2</sub> in the myocardium may result in cardiac hypertrophy and fibrosis. The P66<sup>shc</sup> adaptor protein, which is mediated by PKC&#x3b2;, serves an important role in apoptosis during oxidative stress. The aim of the present study was to investigate whether the PKC&#x3b2;<sub>2</sub>/P66<sup>shc</sup> oxidative stress pathway is associated with DCM, and to investigate the role and mechanisms of carvedilol in preserving cardiac function. Experimental diabetic rat models were induced by streptozotocin treatment accompanied by high energy intake. Carvedilol was orally administrated at a dose of 1 or 10 mg/kg/day. Cardiac function was evaluated by serum N-terminal pro-B-type natriuretic peptide level and cardiac ultrasound. Myocardial inflammation, oxidative stress, apoptosis and fibrosis were assessed by histopathological and echocardiographic analyses and tests for oxidative markers. Associated proteins and factors were examined by immunohistochemical and western blot analyses. Rats in the diabetes mellitus group exhibited significantly decreased systolic cardiac function along with elevated expression levels of phosphorylated (p)-PKC&#x3b2;<sub>2</sub>, phos-P66<sup>shc</sup>, caspase-3, malondialdehyde, collagen type I, tumor necrosis factor-&#x3b1; and interleukin-1&#x3b2;, which were accompanied by disorder in metabolic processes. Treatment with carvedilol reversed these changes. Thus, the present results suggest that the PKC&#x3b2;<sub>2</sub>/P66<sup>shc</sup> signaling pathway may be associated with diabetic cardiomyopathy; furthermore, carvedilol, as a novel &#x3b2;-receptor blocker, may protect the myocardium from injury by suppressing the myocardial inflammatory response, fibrosis, P66<sup>shc</sup>-mediated oxidative stress and subsequent apoptosis in myocardial tissue. Consequently, carvedilol may have potential as a therapy for the treatment of DCM.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Wencheng</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fourth Department of Cardiology, Tangshan Gongren Hospital, Tangshan, Hebei 063000, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Ding</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiac Electrophysiology, Peking University People's Hospital, Peking University, Beijing 100044, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Xiang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>First Department of Cardiology, Tangshan Gongren Hospital, Tangshan, Hebei 063000, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Wenqian</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Tangshan Gongren Hospital, Tangshan, Hebei 063000, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Robinson</LastName><ForeName>Barry O</ForeName><Initials>BO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Non-Invasive Cardiovascular Services, Brookwood Health Hospital, Birmingham, AL 35211, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Greece</Country><MedlineTA>Exp Ther Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101531947</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1792-0981</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">P66shc</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">apoptosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">carvedilol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diabetic cardiomyopathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fibrosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxidative stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein kinase C&#x3b2;2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">signaling pathway</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2018</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30651825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6307467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/etm.2018.6954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ETM-0-0-6954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shaw JE, Sicree RA, Zimmet PZ. Global estimates of the prevalence of diabetes for 2010 and 2030. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2010;87:4&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1016/j.diabres.2009.10.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diabres.2009.10.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19896746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell DS. Heart failure: The frequent, forgotten, and often fatal complication of diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2003;26:2433&#x2013;2441. doi: 10.2337/diacare.26.8.2433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diacare.26.8.2433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12882875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang ZY, Prins JB, Marwick TH. Diabetic cardiomyopathy: Evidence, mechanisms, and therapeutic implications. Endocr Rev. 2004;25:543&#x2013;567. doi: 10.1210/er.2003-0012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/er.2003-0012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15294881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westermann D, Walther T, Savvatis K, Escher F, Sobirey M, Riad A, Bader M, Schultheiss HP, Tsch&#xf6;pe C. Gene deletion of the kinin receptor B1 attenuates cardiac inflammation and fibrosis during the development of experimental diabetic cardiomyopathy. Diabetes. 2009;58:1373&#x2013;1381. doi: 10.2337/db08-0329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/db08-0329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2682670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19276445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falc&#xe3;o-Pires I, Leite-Moreira AF. Diabetic cardiomyopathy: Understanding the molecular and cellular basis to progress in diagnosis and treatment. Heart Fail Rev. 2012;17:325&#x2013;344. doi: 10.1007/s10741-011-9257-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10741-011-9257-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21626163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aksakal E, Akaras N, Kurt M, Tanboga IH, Halici Z, Odabasoglu F, Bakirci EM, Unal B. The role of oxidative stress in diabetic cardiomyopathy: An experimental study. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2011;15:1241&#x2013;1246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22195355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halliwell B. Biochemistry of oxidative stress. Biochem Soc Trans. 2007;35:1147&#x2013;1150. doi: 10.1042/BST0351147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/BST0351147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17956298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mat&#xe9;s JM, S&#xe1;nchez-Jim&#xe9;nez F. Antioxidant enzymes and their implications in pathophysiologic processes. Front Biosci. 1999;4:D339&#x2013;D345. doi: 10.2741/Mates.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2741/Mates</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10077544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellor H, Parker P. The extended protein kinase C superfamily. Biochem J. 1998;332:281&#x2013;292. doi: 10.1042/bj3320281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/bj3320281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1219479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9601053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurusamy N, Watanabe K, Ma M, Zhang S, Muslin AJ, Kodama M, Aizawa Y. Inactivation of 14-3-3 protein exacerbates cardiac hypertrophy and fibrosis through enhanced expression of protein kinase C beta 2 in experimental diabetes. Biol Pharm Bull. 2005;28:957&#x2013;962. doi: 10.1248/bpb.28.957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1248/bpb.28.957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15930726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Way KJ, Isshiki K, Suzuma K, Yokota T, Zvagelsky D, Schoen FJ, Sandusky GE, Pechous PA, Vlahos CJ, Wakasaki H, King GL. Expression of connective tissue growth factor is increased in injured myocardium associated with protein kinase C beta2 activation and diabetes. Diabetes. 2002;51:2709&#x2013;2718. doi: 10.2337/diabetes.51.9.2709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diabetes.51.9.2709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12196463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Migliaccio E, Giorgio M, Mele S, Pelicci G, Reboldi P, Pandolfi PP, Lanfrancone L, Pelicci PG. The p66shc adaptor protein controls oxidative stress response and life span in mammals. Nature. 1999;402:309&#x2013;313. doi: 10.1038/46311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/46311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10580504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nemoto S, Finkel T. Redox regulation of forkhead proteins through a p66shc-dependent signaling pathway. Science. 2002;295:2450&#x2013;2452. doi: 10.1126/science.1069004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1069004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11884717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinton P, Rimessi A, Marchi S, Orsini F, Migliaccio E, Giorgio M, Contursi C, Minucci S, Mantovani F, Wieckowski MR, et al. Protein kinase C beta and prolyl isomerase 1 regulate mitochondrial effects of the life-span determinant p66Shc. Science. 2007;315:659&#x2013;663. doi: 10.1126/science.1135380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1135380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17272725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paneni F, Mocharla P, Akhmedov A, Costantino S, Osto E, Volpe M, L&#xfc;scher TF, Cosentino F. Gene silencing of the mitochondrial adaptor p66shc suppresses vascular hyperglycemic memory in diabetes. Circ Res. 2012;111:278&#x2013;289. doi: 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.112.266593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.112.266593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22693349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arab HH, El-Sawalhi MM. Carvedilol alleviates adjuvant-induced arthritis and subcutaneous air pouch edema: Modulation of oxidative stress and inflammatory mediators. Toxicol Appl Pharmacol. 2013;268:241&#x2013;248. doi: 10.1016/j.taap.2013.01.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.taap.2013.01.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23360886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasar A, Erdemir F, Parlaktas BS, Atilgan D, Koseoglu RD, Saylan O, Firat F. The effect of carvedilol on serum and tissue oxidative stress parameters in partial ureteral obstruction induced rat model. Kaohsiung J Med Sci. 2013;29:19&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1016/j.kjms.2012.08.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.kjms.2012.08.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11916189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23257252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feuerstein GZ, Poste G, Ruffolo RR., Jr Carvedilol update III: Rationale for and use in congestive heart failure. Drugs Today. 1995;31:307&#x2013;326. doi: 10.1358/dot.1995.31.5.325339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1358/dot.1995.31.5.325339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Research Council (US) Committee for the Update of the Guide for the Care and Use of Laboratory Animals, corp-author. Guide for the care and use of laboratory animals. Publication no. 85-23(rev) (Eighth) 1996;327:963&#x2013;965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maeda H, Nagai H, Takemura G, Shintani-Ishida K, Komatsu M, Ogura S, Aki T, Shirai M, Kuwahira I, Yoshida K. Intermittent-hypoxia induced autophagy attenuates contractile dysfunction and myocardial injury in rat heart. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2013;1832:1159&#x2013;1166. doi: 10.1016/j.bbadis.2013.02.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbadis.2013.02.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23499993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frustaci A, Kajstura J, Chimenti C, Jakoniuk I, Leri A, Maseri A, Nadal-Ginard B, Anversa P. Myocardial cell death in human diabetes. Circ Res. 2000;87:1123&#x2013;1132. doi: 10.1161/01.RES.87.12.1123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.RES.87.12.1123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11110769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Li B, Wang W, Zhang C, Zhang M, Zhang Y, Xia Y, Dong Z, Guo Y, An F. Effects of HMG-CoA reductase inhibitor on experimental autoimmune myocarditis. Cardiovasc Drugs Ther. 2012;26:121&#x2013;130. doi: 10.1007/s10557-012-6372-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10557-012-6372-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22382902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei S, Li H, Xu J, Liu Y, Gao X, Wang J, Ng KF, Lau WB, Ma XL, Rodrigues B, et al. Hyperglycemia-induced protein kinase C &#x3b2;2 activation induces diastolic cardiac dysfunction in diabetic rats by impairing caveolin-3 expression and Akt/eNOS signaling. Diabetes. 2013;62:2318&#x2013;2328. doi: 10.2337/db12-1391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/db12-1391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3712061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23474486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang H, Shan J, Pan XH, Wang HP, Qian LB. Carvedilol protected diabetic rat hearts via reducing oxidative stress. J Zhejiang Univ Sci B. 2006;7:725&#x2013;731. doi: 10.1631/jzus.2006.B0725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1631/jzus.2006.B0725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1559793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16909474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsen SL, Gilbert EM, Renlund DG, Taylor DO, Yanowitz FD, Bristow MR. Carvedilol improves left ventricular function and symptoms in chronic heart failure: A double-blind randomized study. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1995;25:1225&#x2013;1231. doi: 10.1016/0735-1097(95)00012-S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0735-1097(95)00012-S</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7722114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer M, Bristow MR, Cohn JN, Colucci WS, Fowler MB, Gilbert EM, Shusterman NH. The effect of carvedilol on morbidity and mortality in patients with chronic heart failure. N Engl J Med. 1996;334:1349&#x2013;1355. doi: 10.1056/NEJM199605233342101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM199605233342101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8614419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarquini R, Lazzeri C, Pala L, Rotella CM, Gensini GF. The diabetic cardiomyopathy. Acta Diabetol. 2011;48:173&#x2013;181. doi: 10.1007/s00592-010-0180-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00592-010-0180-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20198391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou H, Li YJ, Wang M, Zhang LH, Guo BY, Zhao ZS, Meng FL, Deng YG, Wang RY. Involvement of RhoA/ROCK in myocardial fibrosis in a rat model of type 2 diabetes. Acta Pharmacol Sin. 2011;32:999&#x2013;1008. doi: 10.1038/aps.2011.54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/aps.2011.54</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4002528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21743486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morsy MA, Ibrahim SA, Amin EF, Kamel MY, Abdelwahab SA, Hassan MK. Carvedilol ameliorates early diabetic nephropathy in streptozotocin-induced diabetic rats. Biomed Res Int. 2014;2014:105214. doi: 10.1155/2014/105214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2014/105214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4065664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24991534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajesh M, Mukhopadhyay P, B&#xe1;tkai S, Patel V, Saito K, Matsumoto S, Kashiwaya Y, Horv&#xe1;th B, Mukhopadhyay B, Becker L, et al. Cannabidiol attenuates cardiac dysfunction, oxidative stress, fibrosis, and inflammatory and cell death signaling pathways in diabetic cardiomyopathy. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2010;56:2115&#x2013;2125. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2010.07.033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2010.07.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3026637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21144973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Wang G, Zhai X, Hu Y, Gao D, Ma L, Yao J, Tian X. Selective inhibition of protein kinase C &#x3b2;2 attenuates the adaptor P66Shc-mediated intestinal ischemia-reperfusion injury. Cell Death Dis. 2014;5:e1164. doi: 10.1038/cddis.2014.131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/cddis.2014.131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5424109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24722289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke M, Dodson PM. PKC inhibition and diabetic microvascular complications. Best Pract Res Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2007;21:573&#x2013;586. doi: 10.1016/j.beem.2007.09.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.beem.2007.09.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18054736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson PC. Beta-protein kinase C and hypertrophic signaling in human heart failure. Circulation. 1999;99:334&#x2013;337. doi: 10.1161/01.CIR.99.3.334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.99.3.334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9918516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connelly KA, Kelly DJ, Zhang Y, Prior DL, Advani A, Cox AJ, Thai K, Krum H, Gilbert RE. Inhibition of protein kinase C-beta by ruboxistaurin preserves cardiac function and reduces extracellular matrix production in diabetic cardiomyopathy. Circ Heart Fail. 2009;2:129&#x2013;137. doi: 10.1161/CIRCHEARTFAILURE.108.765750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCHEARTFAILURE.108.765750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19808328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devereux RB, Roman MJ, Paranicas M, O'Grady MJ, Lee ET, Welty TK, Fabsitz RR, Robbins D, Rhoades ER, Howard BV. Impact of diabetes on cardiac structure and function the strong heart study. Circulation. 2000;101:2271&#x2013;2276. doi: 10.1161/01.CIR.101.19.2271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.101.19.2271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10811594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>