<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34006994</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1476-5640</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>76</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of clinical nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Clin Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease in obese children and adolescents: a role for nutrition?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>28</StartPage><EndPage>39</EndPage><MedlinePgn>28-39</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41430-021-00928-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) has become the most common cause of chronic liver disease in children, paralleling the increasing prevalence of obesity worldwide. The pathogenesis of paediatric NAFLD is not fully understood, but it is known that obesity, nutrition, lifestyle variables, genetic and epigenetic factors may be causally involved in the development of this common metabolic liver disease. In particular, obesity and nutrition are among the strongest risk factors for paediatric NAFLD, which may exert their adverse hepatic effects already before birth. Excess energy intake induces hypertrophy and hyperplasia of adipose tissue with subsequent development of systemic insulin resistance, which is another important risk factor for NAFLD. Diet composition and in particular simple carbohydrate intake (especially high fructose intake) may promote the development of NAFLD, whereas non-digestible carbohydrates (dietary fiber), by affecting gut microbiota, may favour the integrity of gut wall and reduce inflammation, opposing this process. Saturated fat intake may also promote NAFLD development, whereas unsaturated fat intake has some beneficial effects. Protein intake does not seem to affect the development of NAFLD, but further investigation is needed. In conclusion, lifestyle modifications to induce weight loss, through diet and physical activity, remain the mainstay of treatment for paediatric NAFLD. The use of dietary supplements, such as omega-3 fatty acids and probiotics, needs further study before recommendation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Limited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bonsembiante</LastName><ForeName>Luisa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9585-4452</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Pediatric Diabetes and Metabolic Disorders Unit, Department of Surgical Sciences, Dentistry, Paediatrics and Gynaecology, University and Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Integrata of Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Targher</LastName><ForeName>Giovanni</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4325-3900</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Endocrinology, Diabetes and Metabolism, Department of Medicine, University and Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Integrata of Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maffeis</LastName><ForeName>Claudio</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3563-4404</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Pediatric Diabetes and Metabolic Disorders Unit, Department of Surgical Sciences, Dentistry, Paediatrics and Gynaecology, University and Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Integrata of Verona, Verona, Italy. claudio.maffeis@univr.it.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Clin Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8804070</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0954-3007</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004032" MajorTopicYN="N">Diet</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008099" MajorTopicYN="N">Liver</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D065626" MajorTopicYN="Y">Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009752" MajorTopicYN="N">Nutritional Status</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063766" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pediatric Obesity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015431" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Loss</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34006994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41430-021-00928-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41430-021-00928-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Swinburn BA, Kraak VI, Allender S, Atkins VJ, Baker PI, Bogard JR, et al. The global syndemic of obesity, undernutrition, and climate change: the lancet commission report. Lancet. 2019;393:791&#x2013;846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30700377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)32822-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valerio G, Maffeis C, Saggese G, Ambruzzi MA, Balsamo A, Bellone S, et al. Diagnosis, treatment and prevention of pediatric obesity: consensus position statement of the Italian Society for Pediatric Endocrinology and Diabetology and the Italian Society of Pediatrics. Ital J Pediatr. 2018;44:1&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13052-018-0525-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentham J, Di Cesare M, Bilano V, Bixby H, Zhou B, Stevens GA, et al. Worldwide trends in body-mass index, underweight, overweight, and obesity from 1975 to 2016: a pooled analysis of 2416 population-based measurement studies in 128&#xb7;9 million children, adolescents, and adults. Lancet 2017;390:2627&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(17)32129-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmonds M, Llewellyn A, Owen CG, Woolacott N. Predicting adult obesity from childhood obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Obes Rev. 2016;17:95&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26696565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.12334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twig G, Yaniv G, Levine H, Leiba A, Goldberger N, Derazne E, et al. Body-mass index in 2.3 million adolescents and cardiovascular death in adulthood. N. Engl J Med. 2016;374:2430&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27074389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1503840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemente MG, Mandato C, Poeta M, Vajro P. Pediatric non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: recent solutions, unresolved issues, and future research directions. World J Gastroenterol. 2016;22:8078&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27688650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5037077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v22.i36.8078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Bonito P, Miraglia del Giudice E, Chiesa C, Licenziati MR, Manco M, Franco F, et al. Preclinical signs of liver and cardiac damage in youth with metabolically healthy obese phenotype. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2018;28:1230&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30355472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.numecd.2018.08.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobili V, Alisi A, Valenti L, Miele L, Feldstein AE, Alkhouri N. NAFLD in children: new genes, new diagnostic modalities and new drugs. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2019;16:517&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31278377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41575-019-0169-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldstein AE, Charatcharoenwitthaya P, Treeprasertsuk S, Benson JT, Enders FB, Angulo P. The natural history of nonalcoholic fatty liver disease in children: a follow-up study for up to 20-years. Gut 2009;58:1538&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19625277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gut.2008.171280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uppal V, Mansoor S, Furuya KN. Pediatric non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. Curr Gastroenterol Rep. 2016;18:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11894-016-0498-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Younossi Z, Tacke F, Arrese M, Chander Sharma B, Mostafa I, Bugianesi E, et al. Global perspectives on nonalcoholic fatty liver disease and nonalcoholic steatohepatitis. Hepatology. 2019;69:2672&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30179269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.30251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwimmer JB, Behling C, Newbury R, Deutsch R, Nievergelt C, Schork NJ, et al. Histopathology of pediatric nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Hepatology. 2005;42:641&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16116629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.20842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudolph B, Bjorklund N, Ovchinsky N, Kogan-Liberman D, Perez A, Liszewski M, et al. Methods to Improve the Noninvasive Diagnosis and Assessment of Disease Severity in Children with Suspected Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease (NAFLD): Study Design. Contemp Clin Trials. 2018;75:51&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30401631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6249118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cct.2018.10.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan M, Zong W, Biank VF, Hageman JR. Nonalcoholic fatty liver disease in pediatrics. Pediatr Ann. 2016;45:e54&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26878184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3928/00904481-20160113-01</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vos MB, Abrams SH, Barlow SE, Caprio S, Daniels SR, Kohli R, et al. NASPGHAN Clinical Practice Guideline for the Diagnosis and Treatment of Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease in Children: Recommendations from the Expert Committee on NAFLD (ECON) and the North American Society of Pediatric Gastroenterology, Hepatology and Nu. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2017;64:319&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28107283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5413933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MPG.0000000000001482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavine JE, Schwimmer JB, Molleston JP, O. SA, Murray KF, Abrams SH, et al. Treatment of Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease in Children: TONIC Trial Design. Contemp Clin Trials. 2010;31:62&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19761871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cct.2009.09.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colantonio DA, Kyriakopoulou L, Chan MK, Daly CH, Brinc D, Venner AA, et al. Closing the gaps in pediatric laboratory reference intervals: A caliper database of 40 biochemical markers in a healthy and multiethnic population of children. Clin Chem. 2012;58:854&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22371482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1373/clinchem.2011.177741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papatheodoridi M, Cholongitas E. Diagnosis of Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease (NAFLD): Current Concepts. Curr Pharm Des. 2019;24:4574&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1381612825666190117102111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panera N, Barbaro B, Della Corte C, Mosca A, Nobili V, Alisi A. A review of the pathogenic and therapeutic role of nutrition in pediatric nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Nutr Res. 2018;58:1&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30340810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nutres.2018.05.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zusi C, Mantovani A, Olivieri F, Morandi A, Corradi M. Miraglia Del Giudice E, et al. Contribution of a genetic risk score to clinical prediction of hepatic steatosis in obese children and adolescents. Dig Liver Dis. 2019;51:1586&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modi N, Murgasova D, Ruager-Martin R, Thomas EL, Hyde MJ, Gale C, et al. The influence of maternal body mass index on infant adiposity and hepatic lipid content. Pediatr Res. 2011;70:287&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21629154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1203/PDR.0b013e318225f9b1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dayanand NP, Schwimmer JB. The progression and natural history of pediatric nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Clin Liver Dis. 2016;20:325&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cld.2015.10.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haczeyni F, Bell-Anderson KS, Farrell GC. Causes and mechanisms of adipocyte enlargement and adipose expansion. Obes Rev. 2018;19:406&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29243339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.12646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canfora EE, Meex RCR, Venema K, Blaak EE. Gut microbial metabolites in obesity, NAFLD and T2DM. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2019;15:261&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30670819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41574-019-0156-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutkowski JM, Stern JH, Scherer PE. The cell biology of fat expansion. J Cell Biol. 2015;208:501&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25733711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4347644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1083/jcb.201409063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sbarbati A, Osculati F, Silvagni D, Benati D, Gali&#xe8; M, Camoglio FS, et al. Obesity and inflammation: evidence for an elementary lesion. Pediatrics. 2006;117:220&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16396883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2004-2854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JI, Huh JY, Sohn JH, Choe SS, Lee YS, Lim CY, et al. Lipid-overloaded enlarged adipocytes provoke insulin resistance independent of inflammation. Mol Cell Biol. 2015;35:1686&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25733684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4405637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/MCB.01321-14</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landgraf K, Rockstroh D, Wagner IV, Weise S, Tauscher R, Schwartze JT, et al. Evidence of early alterations in adipose tissue biology and function and its association with obesity-related inflammation and insulin resistance in children. Diabetes. 2015;64:1249&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25392242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/db14-0744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skurk T, Alberti-huber C, Herder C, Hauner H. Relationship between adipocyte size and adipokine expression and secretion. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2007;92:1023&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17164304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2006-1055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bugianesi E, Moscatiello S, Ciaravella MF, Marchesini G. Insulin resistance in non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. Curr Pharm Des. 2010;16:1941&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20370677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/138161210791208875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morandi A, Sessa ADI, Zusi C, Umano GR, Mazloum DEL, Fornari E, et al. Nonalcoholic fatty liver disease and estimated insulin resistance in obese youth: a mendelian randomization analysis. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2020;105:4046&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/clinem/dgaa583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastaldelli A. Insulin resistance and reduced metabolic flexibility: cause or consequence of NAFLD? Clin Sci. 2017;131:2701&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/CS20170987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne CD, Targher G. NAFLD: a multisystem disease. J Hepatol. 2015;62:S47&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25920090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2014.12.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korenblat KM, Fabbrini E, Mohammed BS, Klein S. Liver, muscle and adipose tissue insulin action is directly related to intrahepatic triglyceride content in obese subjects. Gastroenterology. 2008;134:1369&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18355813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2008.01.075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watt MJ, Miotto PM, De Nardo W, Montgomery MK. The liver as an endocrine organ&#x2014;linking NAFLD and insulin resistance. Endocr Rev. 2019;40:1367&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31098621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/er.2019-00034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefan N, H&#xe4;ring HU. The metabolically benign and malignant fatty liver. Diabetes. 2011;60:2011&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21788578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3142070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/db11-0231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kantartzis K, Peter A, Machicao F, Machann J, Wagner S, K&#xf6;nigsrainer I, et al. Dissociation between fatty liver and insulin resistance in humans carrying a variant of the patatin-like phospholipase 3 gene. Diabetes. 2009;58:2616&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19651814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2768178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/db09-0279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mameli C, Mazzantini S, Zuccotti GV. Nutrition in the first 1000 days: the origin of childhood obesity. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2016;13:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph13090838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maffeis C, Morandi A. Effect of maternal obesity on foetal growth and metabolic health of the offspring. Obes Facts. 2017;10:112&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28384625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5644955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000456668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zelber-Sagi S, Nitzan-Kaluski D, Goldsmith R, Webb M, Blendis L, Halpern Z, et al. Long term nutritional intake and the risk for non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD): A population based study. J Hepatol. 2007;47:711&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17850914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2007.06.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson AL. Developmental origins of obesity: early feeding environments, infant growth, and the intestinal microbiome. Am J Hum Biol. 2012;24:350&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22378322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajhb.22254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seki E, Brenner DA, Karin M. A liver full of JNK: signaling in regulation of cell function and disease pathogenesis, and clinical approaches. Gastroenterology. 2012;143:307&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22705006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2012.06.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobili V, Schwimmer JB, Vajro P. Breastfeeding and NAFLD from the maternal side of the mother-infant dyad. J Hepatol. 2019;70:13&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30414736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2018.10.030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobili V, Bedogni G, Alisi A, Pietrobattista A, Alterio A, Tiribelli C, et al. A protective effect of breastfeeding on the progression of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. Arch Dis Child. 2009;94:801&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19556219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/adc.2009.159566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakravarthy MV, Waddell T, Banerjee R, Guess N. Nutrition and nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: current perspectives. Gastroenterol Clin North Am. 2020;49:63&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32033765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gtc.2019.09.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nier A, Brandt A, Conzelmann IB, &#xd6;zel Y, Bergheim I. Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease in overweight children: role of fructose intake and dietary pattern. Nutrients. 2018;10:1&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10091329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mager DR, I&#xf1;iguez IR, Gilmour S, Yap J. The effect of a low fructose and low glycemic index/load (FRAGILE) dietary intervention on indices of liver function, cardiometabolic risk factors, and body composition in children and adolescents with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD). J Parenter Enter Nutr. 2015;39:73&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0148607113501201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarz J, Noworolski SM, Erkin-cakmak A, Korn NJ, Wen MJ, Tai VW, et al. Effects of dietary fructose restriction on liver fat, de novo lipogenesis, and insulin kinetics in children with obesity. Gastroenterology. 2018;153:743&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2017.05.043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludwig DS. Examining the health effects of fructose. JAMA. 2013;310:33&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23732692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2013.6562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roncal-Jimenez CA, Lanaspa MA, Rivard CJ, Nakagawa T, Sanchez-Lozada LG, Jalal D, et al. Sucrose induces fatty liver and pancreatic inflammation in male breeder rats independent of excess energy intake. Metabolism. 2011;60:1259&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21489572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3137694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.metabol.2011.01.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao L, Zhang F, Ding X, Wu G, Lam YY, Wang X, et al. Gut bacteria selectively promoted by dietary fibers alleviate type 2 diabetes. Science. 2018;359:1151&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29590046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aao5774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchesi JR, Adams DH, Fava F, Hermes GDA, Hirsch GM, Hold G, et al. The gut microbiota and host health: a new clinical frontier. Gut. 2016;65:330&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26338727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gutjnl-2015-309990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charbonneau MR, Donnell DO, Blanton LV, Totten SM, Davis JCC, Barratt MJ, et al. Growth in Models of Infant Undernutrition. Cell. 2016;164:859&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26898329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4793393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2016.01.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson AL, Monteagudo-Mera A, Cadenas MB, Lampl ML, Azcarate-Peril MA. Milk- and solid-feeding practices and daycare attendance are associated with differences in bacterial diversity, predominant communities, and metabolic and immune function of the infant gut microbiome. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2015;5:1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcimb.2015.00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Filippo C, Cavalieri D, Di Paola M, Ramazzotti M, Poullet JB, Massart S, et al. Impact of diet in shaping gut microbiota revealed by a comparative study in children from Europe and rural Africa. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2010;107:14691&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20679230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2930426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1005963107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miele L, Valenza V, La Torre G, Montalto M, Cammarota G, Ricci R, et al. Increased intestinal permeability and tight junction alterations in nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Hepatology. 2009;49:1877&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19291785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.22848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parry SA, Hodson L. Influence of dietary macronutrients on liver fat accumulation and metabolism. J Investig Med. 2017;65:1102&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28947639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5749316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jim-2017-000524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morandi A, Fornari E, Opri F, Corradi M, Tommasi M, Bonadonna R, et al. High-fat meal, systemic inflammation and glucose homeostasis in obese children and adolescents. Int J Obes. 2017;41:986&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ijo.2017.48</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ris&#xe9;rus U. Fatty acids and insulin sensitivity. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2008;11:100&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18301083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCO.0b013e3282f52708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaitosaari T, R&#xf6;nnemaa T, Viikari J, Raitakari O, Arffman M, Marniemi J, et al. Low-saturated fat dietary counseling starting in infancy improves insulin sensitivity in 9-year-old healthy children: The Special Turku Coronary Risk Factor Intervention Project for Children (STRIP) study. Diabetes Care. 2006;29:781&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16567815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diacare.29.04.06.dc05-1523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyraz M, Pirgon O, Dundar B, Cekmez F, Hatipoglu N. Long-term treatment with n-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids as a monotherapy in children with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. J Clin Res Pediatr Endocrinol. 2015;7:121&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26316434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4563183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4274/jcrpe.1749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobili V, Alisi A, Musso G, Scorletti E, Calder PC, Byrne CD. Omega-3 fatty acids: mechanisms of benefit and therapeutic effects in pediatric and adult NAFLD. Crit Rev Clin Lab Sci. 2015;53:106&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26463349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/10408363.2015.1092106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montagner A, Polizzi A, Fouch&#xe9; E, Ducheix S, Lippi Y, Lasserre F, et al. Liver PPAR&#x3b1; is crucial for whole-body fatty acid homeostasis and is protective against NAFLD. Gut. 2016;65:1202&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26838599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gutjnl-2015-310798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francque S, Verrijken A, Caron S, Prawitt J, Paumelle R, Derudas B, et al. PPAR&#x3b1; gene expression correlates with severity and histological treatment response in patients with non-alcoholic steatohepatitis. J Hepatol. 2015;63:164&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25703085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2015.02.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbel EE, Lavine JE, Downes M, Van Natta M, Yu R, Schwimmer JB, et al. Hepatic nuclear receptor expression associates with features of histology in pediatric nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Hepatol Commun. 2018;2:1213&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30288476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6167075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep4.1232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markova M, Pivovarova O, Hornemann S, Sucher S, Frahnow T, Wegner K, et al. Isocaloric diets high in animal or plant protein reduce liver fat and inflammation in individuals with type 2 diabetes. Gastroenterology. 2016;152:571&#x2013;85.e8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27765690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2016.10.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bortolotti M, Kreis R, Debard C, Cariou B, Faeh D, Chetiveaux M, et al. High protein intake reduces intrahepatocellular lipid deposition in humans. Am J Clin Nutr. 2009;90:1002&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19710199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.2008.27296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wehmeyer MH, Zyriax BC, Jagemann B, Roth E, Windler E. JS Zur W, et al. Nonalcoholic fatty liver disease is associated with excessive calorie intake rather than a distinctive dietary pattern. Medicine. 2016;95:e3887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao N, Baker SS, Chapa-Rodriguez A, Liu W, Nugent CA, Tsompana M, et al. Suppressed hepatic bile acid signalling despite elevated production of primary and secondary bile acids in NAFLD. Gut 2017;0:1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arab JP, Karpen SJ, Dawson PA, Arrese M, Trauner M. Bile acids and nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: molecular insights and therapeutic perspectives. Hepatology. 2017;65:350&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27358174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.28709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGlone ER, Bloom SR. Bile acids and the metabolic syndrome. Ann Clin Biochem. 2019;56:1&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0004563218817798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez-Morat&#xf3; J, Matthan NR. Nutrition and gastrointestinal microbiota, microbial-derived secondary bile acids, and cardiovascular disease. Curr Atheroscler Rep. 2020;22:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11883-020-00863-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trefflich I, Marschall HU, Di Giuseppe R, St&#xe5;hlman M, Michalsen A, Lampen A, et al. Associations between dietary patterns and bile acids&#x2014;results from a cross-sectional study in vegans and omnivores. Nutrients. 2020;12:1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T, Chiang JYL. Bile acid signaling in metabolic disease and drug therapy. Pharm Rev. 2014;66:948&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25073467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4180336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1124/pr.113.008201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ridlon JM, Joong Kang D, Hylemon PB, Bajaj JS. Bile acids and the gut microbiome. Curr Opin Gastroenterol. 2014;30:332&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24625896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4215539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MOG.0000000000000057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Africa JA, Newton KP, Schwimmer JB. Lifestyle interventions including nutrition, exercise, and supplements for nonalcoholic fatty liver disease in children. Dig Dis Sci. 2016;61:1375&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27041377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4848041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10620-016-4126-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xf8;nb&#xe6;k H, Lange A, Birkeb&#xe6;k NH, Holland-Fischer P, Solvig J, H&#xf8;rlyck A, et al. Effect of a 10-week weight loss camp on fatty liver disease and insulin sensitivity in obese danish children. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2012;54:223&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21760546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MPG.0b013e31822cdedf</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campos RMS, De Piano A, Da Silva PL, Carnier J, Sanches PL, Corgosinho FC, et al. The role of pro/anti-inflammatory adipokines on bone metabolism in NAFLD obese adolescents: Effects of long-term interdisciplinary therapy. Endocrine. 2012;42:146&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22315014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12020-012-9613-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekkarie A, Welsh JA, Vos MB. Carbohydrates and diet patterns in nonalcoholic fatty liver disease in children and adolescents. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2018;21:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCO.0000000000000476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Della Corte C, Mosca A, Vania A, Alterio A, Iasevoli S, Nobili V. Good adherence to the Mediterranean diet reduces the risk for NASH and diabetes in pediatric patients with obesity: The results of an Italian Study. Nutrition. 2017;39&#x2013;40:8&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28606575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2017.02.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramon-Krauel M, Salsberg SL, Ebbeling CB, Voss SD, Mulkern RV, Apura MM, et al. A low-glycemic-load versus low-fat diet in the treatment of fatty liver in obese children. Child Obes. 2013;9:252&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23705885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3675832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/chi.2013.0022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin R, Welsh JA, Le NA, Holzberg J, Sharma P, Martin DR, et al. Dietary fructose reduction improves markers of cardiovascular disease risk in Hispanic-American adolescents with NAFLD. Nutrients. 2014;6:3187&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25111123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4145302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu6083187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobili V, Bedogni G, Alisi A, Pietrobattista A, Ris&#xe9; P, Galli C, et al. Docosahexaenoic acid supplementation decreases liver fat content in children with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: Double-blind randomised controlled clinical trial. Arch Dis Child. 2011;96:350&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21233083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/adc.2010.192401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janczyk W, Lebensztejn D, Wierzbicka-Ruci&#x144;ska A, Mazur A, Neuhoff-Murawska J, Matusik P, et al. Omega-3 fatty acids therapy in children with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: a randomized controlled trial. J Pediatr. 2015;166:1358&#x2013;1363.e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25771388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpeds.2015.01.056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houringan SK, Abrams S, Yates K, Pfeifer K, Torbenson M, Murray K, et al. The relationship between vitamin D status and non-alcoholic fatty liver disease in children. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2015;60:396&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MPG.0000000000000598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitson MT, Pham A, Gordon A, Kemp W, Roberts SK. High-dose vitamin D supplementation and liver histology in NASH. Gut. 2016;65:717&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26294696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gutjnl-2015-310417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corte CD, Carpino G, De Vito R, et al. Docosahexanoic acid plus vitamin D treatment improves features of NAFLD in children with serum vitamin D deficiency: results from a single centre trial. PLoS One. 2016;11:1&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janczyk W, Socha P, Lebensztejn D, Wierzbicka A, Mazur A, Neuhoff-Murawska J, et al. Omega-3 fatty acids for treatment of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: design and rationale of randomized controlled trial. BMC Pediatr. 2013;13:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2431-13-85</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma YY, Li L, Yu CH, Shen Z, Chen LH, Li YM. Effects of probiotics on nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: a meta-analysis. World J Gastroenterol. 2013;19:6911&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24187469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3812493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v19.i40.6911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vajro P, Mandato C, Licenziati MR, Franzese A, Vitale DF, Lenta S, et al. Effects of lactobacillus rhamnosus strain gg in pediatric obesity-related liver disease. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2011;52:740&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21505361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MPG.0b013e31821f9b85</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Famouri F, Shariat Z, Hashemipour M, Keikha M, Kelishadi R. Effects of probiotics on nonalcoholic fatty liver disease in obese children and adolescents. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2017;64:413&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28230607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MPG.0000000000001422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanyal AJ, Chalasani N, Kowdley KV, McCullough A, Diehl AM, Bass NM, et al. Pioglitazone, vitamin E, or placebo for nonalcoholic steatohepatitis. N. Engl J Med. 2010;362:1675&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20427778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2928471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa0907929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavine JE, Schwimmer JB, Van Natta ML, Molleston JP, Murray KF, Rosenthal P, et al. Effect of vitamin e or metformin for treatment of nonalcoholic fatty liver disease in children and adolescents the tonic randomized controlled trial. JAMA. 2011;305:1659&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21521847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3110082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2011.520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster C, Moore JB, Singletary CR, Skelton JA. Physical activity and family-based obesity treatment: a review of expert recommendations on physical activity in youth. Clin Obes. 2018;8:68&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29224232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cob.12230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobili V, Marcellini M, Devito R, Ciampalini P, Piemonte F, Comparcola D, et al. NAFLD in children: a prospective clinical-pathological study and effect of lifestyle advice. Hepatology. 2006;44:458&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16871574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.21262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pozzato C, Verduci E, Scaglioni S, Radaelli G, Salvioni M, Rovere A, et al. Liver fat change in obese children after a 1-year nutrition-behavior intervention. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2010;51:331&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20562718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MPG.0b013e3181d70468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacchi E, Negri C, Targher G, Faccioli N, Lanza M, Zoppini G, et al. Both resistance training and aerobic training reduce hepatic fat content in type 2 diabetic subjects with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (the RAED2 randomized trial). Hepatology. 2013;58:1287&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23504926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.26393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashida R, Kawaguchi T, Bekki M, Omoto M, Matsuse H, Nago T, et al. Aerobic vs. resistance exercise in non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: a systematic review. J Hepatol. 2017;66:142&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27639843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2016.08.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-G&#xf3;mez M, Zelber-Sagi S, Trenell M. Treatment of NAFLD with diet, physical activity and exercise. J Hepatol. 2017;67:829&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28545937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2017.05.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thyfault JP. Scott Rector R. Exercise combats hepatic steatosis: Potential mechanisms and clinical implications. Diabetes. 2020;69:517&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32198195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7085252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dbi18-0043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SJ, Bacha F, Hannon T, Kuk JL, Boesch C, Arslanian S. Effects of aerobic versus resistance exercise without caloric restriction on abdominal fat, intrahepatic lipid, and insulin sensitivity in obese adolescent boys a randomized, controlled trial. Diabetes. 2012;61:2787&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22751691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3478522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/db12-0214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Ruiz K, Ram&#xed;rez-V&#xe9;lez R, Correa-Bautista JE, Peterson MD, Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A. The effects of exercise on abdominal fat and liver enzymes in pediatric obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Child Obes. 2017;13:272&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28322576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/chi.2017.0027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kantartzis K, Thamer C, Peter A, Machann J, Schick F, Schraml C, et al. High cardiorespiratory fitness is an independent predictor of the reduction in liver fat during a lifestyle intervention in non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. Gut. 2009;58:1281&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19074179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gut.2008.151977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson NA, Sachinwalla T, Walton DW, Smith K, Armstrong A, Thompson MW, et al. Aerobic exercise training reduces hepatic and visceral lipids in obese individuals without weight loss. Hepatology. 2009;50:1105&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19637289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.23129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meissner M, Lombardo E, Havinga R, Tietge UJF, Kuipers F, Groen AK. Voluntary wheel running increases bile acid as well as cholesterol excretion and decreases atherosclerosis in hypercholesterolemic mice. Atherosclerosis. 2011;218:323&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21802084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2011.06.040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Der Windt DJ, Sud V, Zhang H, Tsung A, Huang H. The effects of physical exercise on fatty liver disease. Gene Expr. 2018;18:89&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29212576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5954622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3727/105221617X15124844266408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. Evidence on physical activity and sedentary behaviour for children and adolescents (5 to under 18 years of age). In: Who Guidelines on Physical Activity. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2020. p. 8&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nobili V, Vajro P, Dezsofi A, Fischler B, Hadzic N, Jahnel J, et al. Indications and limitations of bariatric intervention in severely obese children and adolescents with and without nonalcoholic steatohepatitis: ESPGHAN hepatology committee position statement. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2015;60:550&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25591123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MPG.0000000000000715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bower G, Toma T, Harling L, Jiao LR, Efthimiou E, Darzi A, et al. Bariatric surgery and non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: a systematic review of liver biochemistry and histology. Obes Surg. 2015;25:2280&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25917981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11695-015-1691-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lassailly G, Caiazzo R, Buob D, Pigeyre M, Verkindt H, Labreuche J, et al. Bariatric surgery reduces features of nonalcoholic steatohepatitis in morbidly obese patients. Gastroenterology. 2015;149:379&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25917783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2015.04.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudolph A, Hilbert A. Post-operative behavioural management in bariatric surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Obes Rev. 2013;14:292&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23294936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.12013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>