<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">21694920</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1178-7058</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>2</Volume><PubDate><Year>2009</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of nephrology and renovascular disease</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Nephrol Renovasc Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Manifestation of renal disease in obesity: pathophysiology of obesity-related dysfunction of the kidney.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>39</StartPage><EndPage>49</EndPage><MedlinePgn>39-49</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Albuminuria in individuals whose body mass index exceeds 40 kg/m(2) is associated with the presence of large glomeruli, thickened basement membrane and epithelial cellular (podocyte) distortion. Obstructive sleep apnea magnifies glomerular injury as well, probably through a vasoconstrictive mechanism. Insulin resistance from excess fatty acids is exacerbated by decreased secretion of high molecular weight adiponectin from adipose cells in the obese state. Adiponectin potentiates insulin in its post-receptor signaling resulting in glucose oxidation in mitochondria. Recent studies of podocyte physiology have concentrated on the structural and functional requirements that prevent glomerular albumin leakage. The architecture of the podocyte involves nephrin and podocin, proteins that cooperate to keep slit pores between foot processes competent to retain albumin. Insulin and adiponectin are necessary for high-energy phosphate generation. When fatty acids bind to albumin, the toxicity to proximal renal tubules is magnified. Albumin and fatty acids are elevated in urine of individuals with obesity related nephrotic syndrome. Fatty acid accumulation and resistin inhibit insulin and adiponectin. Study of cytokines produced by adipose tissue (adiponectin and leptin) and macrophages (resistin) has led to a better understanding of the relationship between weight and hypertension. Leptin, is presumably secreted after food intake to inhibit the midbrain/hypothalamic appetite centers. Resistance to leptin results in excess signaling to hypothalamic sympathetics leading to hypertension. Demonstration of the existence of a cerebral receptor mutation provide evidence for a role in hypertension of a central nervous reflex arc in humans. Further understanding of obesity-related renal dysfunction has been accomplished recently using experimental models. Rapid weight loss following bariatric surgery may reverse renal pathology of obesity with restoration of normal blood pressure.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>D'Elia</LastName><ForeName>John A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Joslin Diabetes Center, Renal Unit, Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, Department of Medicine, Mount Auburn Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston and Cambridge, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roshan</LastName><ForeName>Bijan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maski</LastName><ForeName>Manish</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weinrauch</LastName><ForeName>Larry A</ForeName><Initials>LA</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2009</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Nephrol Renovasc Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101550217</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1178-7058</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adiponectin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">albuminuria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glomerulomegaly</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insulin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">leptin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">podocyte hypertrophy</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2009</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2009</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2009</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2009</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21694920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3108758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/ijnrd.s7999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fox C, Larson M, Leip E, Culleton B, Wilson P, Levy D. Predictors of new-onset kidney disease in a community-based population. JAMA. 2004;291:844&#x2013;850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14970063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timpson N, Harbord R, Smith G, Zacho J, Tybjaerg-Hansen A, Nordestgaard B. Does greater adiposity increase blood pressure and hypertension risk? Mendelian randomization using the FTO/MC4R genotype. Hypertension. 2009;54:84&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19470880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rheaume C, Arsenaylt, Belanger S, et al. Low cardiorespiratory fitness levels and elevated blood pressure. What is the contribution of visceral adiposity? Hypertension. 2009;54:91&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19470873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavakol M, Vincenti F, Assadi H, et al. Long-term renal function and cardiovascular disease risk in obese kidney donors. Clinical J of the American Society of Nephrology. 2009;4:1230&#x2013;1238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2709512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19443625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obermayr R, Temml C, Gutjahr G, et al. Body mass index modifies the risk of cardiovascular death in proteinuric chronic kidney disease. Nephrology Dialysis and Transplantation. 2009;24:2421&#x2013;2428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19244226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serra A, Romero R, Lopez D, et al. Renal injury in extremely obese patients with normal renal function. Kidney International. 2008;73:947&#x2013;955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18216780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato S, Nazneen A, Nakashima Y, et al. Pathological influence of obesity on renal structural changes in chronic kidney disease. Clinical Experimental Nephrology. 2009;9:169&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19533267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goumenos D, Kawar B, El Nahas M, et al. Early histological changes in the kidney of people with morbid obesity. Nephrology Dialysis and Transplantation. 2009 Jul 13; [Epub ahead of print].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19596742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young T, Skatrud J, Peppard PE. Risk factors for obstructive sleep apnea in adults. JAMA. 2004;291:2013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15113821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peppard PE, Young T, Palta M, Skatrud J. Prospective study of the association between sleep-disordered breathing and hypertension. NEJM. 2000;342:1378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10805822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhary BA, Sklar AH, Chaudhary TK, Kolbeck RC, Speir WA., Jr Sleep apnea, proteinuria, and nephrotic syndrome. Sleep. 1988;11:69&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3363272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sklar A, Chaudhary B. Reversible proteinuria in obstructive sleep apnea syndrome. Archives of Internal Medicine. 1988;148:87&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3337606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sklar AH, Chaudhary BA, Harp R. Nocturnal urinary protein excretion rates in patients with sleep apnea. Nephron. 1989;51:35&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2915755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsioufis C, Thomopoulos C, Dimitriadis K, et al. Association of obstructive sleep apnea with urinary albumin excretion in essential hypertension: a cross-sectional study. Am J Kidney Dis. 2008;52:285&#x2013;293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18617307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kambham N, Markowitz G, Valeri A, Lin J, D&#x2019;Agati V. Obesity-related glomerulopathy: an emerging epidemic. Kidney International. 2001;59:1498&#x2013;1509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11260414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verani R. Obesity-associated focal segmental glomerulosclerosis: pathologic features of the lesion and relationship with cardiomegaly and hyperlipidemia. Am J Kidney Diseases. 1992;20:629&#x2013;634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1462993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnett F, Deprele C, Sassolas A, et al. Excessive body weight as a new risk factor for clinical and pathological progression in primary IgA nephritis. American J of Kidney Disease. 2001;37:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11273871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouchi N, Kihara S, Arita Y, et al. Adiponectin, an adipocyte-derived plasma protein, inhibits endothelial NF kappa B signaling through a cyclic AMP-dependent pathway. Circulation. 2000;102:1296&#x2013;1301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10982546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stilmant M. Crescenteric glomerulonephritis Chapter 3, page 40 in Pathology of Glomerular Disease. In: Rosen Seymour., editor. Churchill-Livingston; New York: 1983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall J. Mechanisms of abnormal renal sodium handling in obesity. Hypertension. Amer J Hypertension. 1997;10:49S&#x2013;55S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9160781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haynes W, Sivitz W, Morgan D, Walsh S, Mark A. Sympathetic and cardiorenal actions of leptin. Hypertension. 1997;30:619&#x2013;631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9322991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi GP, Belfiore A, Bernini G, et al. Primary Aldosteronism Prevalence in hYpertension Study Investigators Body mass index predicts plasma aldosterone concentrations in overweight-obese primary hypertension patients. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2008;93:2566&#x2013;2571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18445663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentley-Lewis R, Adler GK, Perlstein T, Selly EW, Hopkins PN. Body mass index predicts aldosterone production in normotensive adults on a high salt diet. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2007;92:4472&#x2013;4475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4428584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17726083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chagnac A, Weinstein T, Korzets A, Ramadan E, Hirsch J, Gafter U. Glomerular hemodynamics in severe obesity. Amer J Physiology Renal Physiology. 2000;278:F817&#x2013;F822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10807594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribstein J, du Cailar G, Mimran A. Combined renal effects of overweight and hypertension. Hypertension. 1995;26:610&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7558220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron A. Hemodynamic actions of insulin. The American Journal of Physiology. 1994;267:E187&#x2013;E202. Endocrinology Metabolism 30:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8074198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao J, Richards R, Zhang R, Reisin E. Effects of a modified low calorie diet in metabolic changes and kidney histology in young obese Zucker rats. J Am Soc Nephrology. 2007;18:823A.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morales E, Valero M, Leon M, Hernandez E, Praga M. Beneficial effects of weight loss in overweight patients with chronic proteinuric nephropathies. Am J Kidney Dis. 2003;41:319&#x2013;327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12552492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chagnac A, Weinstein T, Herman N, Hirsch J, Gafter U, Ori Y. The effects of weight loss on renal function in patients with severe obesity. J Am Soc Nephrology. 2003;14:1480&#x2013;1486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12761248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki, Asanum H, Fujita M, et al. Metformin prevents progression of heart failure in dogs. Role of AMP-activated protein kinase. Circulation. 2009;119:2568&#x2013;2577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19414638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coward RJM, Welsh GI, Kopziell A, et al. Nephrin is critical for the action of insulin on human glomerular podocytes. Diabetes. 2007;56:1127&#x2013;1135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17395751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma K, RamachandraRao S, Qiu G, et al. Adiponectin regulates albuminuria and podocyte function in mice. J Clin Invest. 2008;118:1645&#x2013;1656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2323186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18431508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagby S. Obesity-initiated metabolic syndrome and the kidney: A recipe for chronic renal disease? J of the American Society of Nephrology. 2004;15:2775&#x2013;2791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15504931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Wi J, Youn J. Plasma free fatty acids decrease insulin-stimulated skeletal muscle glucose uptake by suppressing glycolysis in conscious rats. Diabetes. 1996;45:446&#x2013;453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8603766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hitomi H, Kiyomoto H, Nishiyama A, et al. Aldosterone suppresses insulin signaling via the downregulation of insulin receptor substrate-1 in vascular smooth muscle cells. Hypertension. 2007;50:750&#x2013;755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17646573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callera G, Touyz R, Tostes R, et al. Aldosterone activates vascular p38MAP kinase and NADP oxidase via c-Src. Hypertension. 2005;45:773&#x2013;779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15699470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coughlan MT, Thorburn DR, Penfold SA, et al. RAGE-induced cytosolic ROS promote mitochondrial superoxide generation in diabetes. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2009 Apr;20(4):742&#x2013;752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2663823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19158353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wendt T, Tanji N, Guo J, et al. Glucose, glycation, and RAGE: Implications for amplification of cellular dysfunction in diabetic nephropathy. J American Society of Nephrology. 2003;14:1383&#x2013;1395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12707408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geltman J, Sun J, Keenan H, et al. Unexpected high prevalence of cardiovascular complications in type 1 diabetes of extreme duration. Diabetes. 2009;58(S1):A199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roest P, Molin D, Schralkwijk C, et al. Specific local cardiovascular changes of N (carboxymethyl) lysine, vascular endothelial growth factor and Smad2 in the developing embryos coincide with maternal diabetes-induced congenital heart defects. Diabetes. 2009;58:1222&#x2013;1228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2671058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19188426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt AM, Yan S, Wautier J, Stern D. Activation of receptor for advanced glycation end products: a mechanism for chronic vascular dysfunction in diabetic vasculopathy and atherosclerosis. Circulation Research. 1999;84:489&#x2013;497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10082470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamijo Y, Hora K, Kono K, et al. PPAR alpha protects proximal tubular cells from acute fatty acid toxicity. J Am Soc Nephrology. 2007;18:3089&#x2013;4011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17978304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruggenti P, Cattaneo D, Loriga G, et al. Ameliorating hypertension and insulin resistance ion subjects at increased cardiovascular risk. Hypertension. 2009;54:567&#x2013;574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19620516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Berggren P, Grill V. A fatty acid-induced decrease in pyruvate hydrogenase activity is an important determination of beta-cell dysfunction in the obese diabetic db/db mouse. Diabetes. 1996;45:580&#x2013;586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8621007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hotta K, Kuwajima M, Ono A, et al. Disordered expression of glyoclytic and gluconeogenic liver enzymes of juvenile visceral steatosis mice with systemic carnitine deficiency. Diabetes Research Clinical Practice. 1996;32:117&#x2013;123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8858199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo L, Sandoval R, Campos S, Molitoris B, Comper W, Brown D. Impaired tubular uptake explains albuminuria in early diabetic nephropathy. J Am Soc of Nephrology. 2009;20:489&#x2013;494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2653682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19118149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu G, Liu A, Liu X. Aldosterone induces collagen synthesis via activation of extracellular signal-regulated kinase 1 and 2 in renal proximal tubules. Nephrology. 2008;13:694&#x2013;701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19154323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumann M, von Eynatten M, Dan L, Kopuznetsova T, Heemann U, Staessen JA. Altered molecular weight forms of adiponectin in hypertension. J Clin Hypertens. 2009;11:11&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8673079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19125853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwashima Y, Horio T, Kumada M, et al. Adiponectin and renal function, and implication as a risk factor of cardiovascular disease. Am J Cardiol. 2006;98:1603&#x2013;1608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17145218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsnefes M, Kartal J, Khoury P, Daniels S. Adiponectin in children with chronic kidney disease: role of adiposity and kidney dysfunction. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2007;2:46&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17699386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellington AA, Malik AR, Klee GG, et al. Association of plasma resistin with glomerular filtration rate and albuminuria in hypertensive adults. Hypertension. 2007;50:708&#x2013;714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17785630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vecchione C, Maffei A, Colella S, et al. Leptin effect on endothelial nitric oxide is mediated through Akt-endothelial nitric oxide synthase phosphorylation pathway. Diabetes. 2002;51:168&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11756337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straznicky N, Lambert G, McGrane M, et al. Weight loss may reverse blunted sympathetic neural responsiveness to glucose ingestion in obese subjects with metabolic syndrome. Diabetes. 2009;58:1126&#x2013;1132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2671050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19188428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomopoulos C, Papadopoulos D, Papazachou O, et al. Free leptin is associated with masked hypertension in nonobese subjects. Hypertension. 2009;53:965&#x2013;972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19398660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenfield JR, Miller JW, Keogh JM, et al. Modulation of blood pressure by central melanocortinergic pathways. NEJM. 2009;360:44&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19092146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva A, do Carmo J, Freeman J, Tallum L, Hall J. A functional melanocortin system may be required for CNS-mediated antidiabetic and cardiovascular actions of leptin. Diabetes. 2009;58:1749&#x2013;1756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2712780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19491210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haynes W, Morgan D, Djalali A, Svitz W, Mark A. Interactions between the melanocortin system and leptin in control of sympathetic nerve traffic. Hypertension. 1999;33:542&#x2013;547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9931162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenstein AS, Khavandi K, Withers SB, et al. Local inflammation and hypoxia abolish the protective anticontractile properties of perivascular fat in obese patients. Circulation. 2009;119:1661&#x2013;1670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19289637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schling P, Mallow H, Trindl A, L&#xf6;ffler G. Evidence for a local renin angiotensin system in primary cultured human adipocytes. J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 1999;23:336&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10340809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodfriend TL, Ball DL, Egan BM, Campbell WB, Nithipatikom K. Epoxy-keto derivative of linoleic acid stimulates aldosterone secretion. Hypertension. 2004;43(Part 2):358&#x2013;363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14718355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehrhart-Bornstein M, Lamounier-Zepter V, Schraven A, et al. Human adipocytes secrete mineralocorticoid-releasing factors. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2003 Nov 25;100(24):14211&#x2013;14216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC283571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14614137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epstein M. Aldosterone blockade: an emerging strategy for abrogating progressive renal disease. Am J Med. 2006;119:912&#x2013;919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17071154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epstein M, Williams GH, Weinberger M, et al. Selective aldosterone blockade with Eplerenone reduces albuminuria in patients with type 2 diabetes. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2006;1:940&#x2013;951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17699311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefterova M, Mullican S, Tomaru T, Qatanani M, Schupp M, Lazar M. Endoplasmic reticulum stress regulated adipocyte resistin expression. Diabetes. 2009;58:1879&#x2013;1886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2712799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19491212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolf G, Chen S, Han D, Ziyadeh F. Leptin and renal disease. American J of Kidney Diseases. 2002;39:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11774095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Susztak K, Raff A, Schiffer M, Bottinger E. Glucose &#x2013; induced reactive oxygen species causes apoptosis of podocytes and podocyte depletion at the onset of diabetic nephropathy. Diabetes. 2006;55:225&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16380497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chuang P, Yu Q, Fang W, Uribarri J, He J. Advanced glycation end products induce podocyte apoptosis by activation of the FOXO 4 transcription factor. Kid Int. 2007;72:965&#x2013;976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3191877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17667983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagtalunan M, Miller P, Jumping-Eagle S, et al. Podocyte loss and progressive glomerular injury in type 2 diabetes. J Clin Invest. 1997;99:m342&#x2013;m348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC507802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9006003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doublier S, Salvidio G, Lupia E, et al. Nephrin expression is reduced in human diabetic nephropathy: evidence for a distinct role for glycated albumin and angiotensin 2. Diabetes. 2003;52:1023&#x2013;1030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12663475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakagawa T, Kosugi T, Haneda M, Rivard C, Long D. Abnormal angiogenesis in diabetic nephropathy. Diabetes. 2009;58:1471&#x2013;1478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2699857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19564458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hummel S, Pfluger M, Kriechauf S, Hummel M, Ziegler A. Predictors of overweight during childhood in offspring of parents with type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2009;32:921&#x2013;925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2671121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19228867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufman F, Hirst K, Linder B, et al. Health Study Writing Group. Risk factors for Type 2 Diabetes in a sixth grade multiracial cohort. Diabetes Care. 2009;32:953&#x2013;955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2671115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19196888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong J, Qiao G, Zhang Z, Liu S, Li Y. Targeted vitamin D receptor expression in juxtaglomerular cells suppresses renin expression independent of parathyroid hormone and calcium. Kidney International. 2008;74:1577&#x2013;1581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19034301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worstman J, Matsuoka L, Chen T, Hollick M. Decreased bioavailability of vitamin D in obesity. Am J Clin Nutrition. 2000;72:690&#x2013;693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10966885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagase M, Fujita T. Mineralocorticoid receptor activation in obesity hypertension. Hypertens Res. 2009;32:649&#x2013;657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19521418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai C, Stolz D, St Bastacky S, et al. The central role of integrin-linked kinase in podocyte biology: bridging the integrin and slit diagram signaling. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2006;17:2164&#x2013;2175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16837631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouchi N, Kihara S, Arita Y, et al. Novel modulator of endothelial adhesion molecules: adipocyte-derived plasma protein adiponectin. Circulation. 1999;100:2473&#x2013;2476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10604883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajiwara S, Makita Y, Gu L, et al. Eicosopentanoic acid ameliorates diabetic nephropathy of type 2 diabetic KKAy/TA mice: involvement of MCP-1 suppression and decreased ERK1/2 and p38 phosphorylation. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2006;21:605&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16282336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah KB, Duda MK, O&#x2019;Shea KM, et al. The cardioprotective effects of fish oil during pressure overload are blocked by high fat intake: role of cardiac phospholipids remodeling. Hypertension. 2009;54:605&#x2013;611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3103889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19597033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller ER, 3rd, Juraschek SP, Appel LJ, et al. The effect of n-3 long-chain polyunsaturated fatty acid supplementation on urine protein excretion and kidney function: meta-analysis of clinical trials. Am J Clin Nutr. 2009;89:1937&#x2013;1945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3148029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19403630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>