<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39676329</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2826</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of neuroendocrinology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Neuroendocrinol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The phytoestrogen genistein improves hippocampal neurogenesis and cognitive impairment and decreases neuroinflammation in an animal model of metabolic syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e13480</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e13480</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jne.13480</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Metabolic syndrome (MS) is the medical term for the combination of at least three of the following factors: obesity, hyperlipidemia, hyperglycemia, insulin resistance, and hypertension. The spontaneously hypertensive rat (SHR) is an accepted animal model for the study of human MS that reveals all the features of the syndrome when fed high-fat, high-carbohydrate diets. The intake of high-fat diets in rats has been shown to produce brain neuropathology. In humans, MS increases the risk of cognitive impairment, dementia, and Alzheimer's disease. Genistein (GEN) is a phytoestrogen found in soy that lacks feminizing and carcinogenic effects and was found to have neuroprotective and anti-inflammatory effects in many pathological conditions. Considering that multiple data support that natural phytoestrogens may be therapeutic options for CNS maladies, we aim to elucidate if these properties also apply to a rat model of MS. Thus, GEN effects on neuroinflammation, neurogenesis, and cognition were evaluated in SHR eating a fat/carbohydrate-enriched diet. To characterize the neuropathology and cognitive dysfunction of MS we fed SHR with a high-fat diet (4520 kcal/kg) along with a 20% sucrose solution to drink. MS rats displayed a significant increase in body weight, BMI and obesity indexes along with an increased in fasting glucose levels, glucose intolerance, high blood pressure, and high blood triglyceride levels. MS rats were injected with GEN during 2&#x2009;weeks a dose of 10&#x2009;mg/kg. We found that MS rats showed a decreased number of DCX+ neural progenitors in the dentate gyrus and treatment with GEN increased this parameter. Expression of GFAP was increased in the DG and CA1 areas of the hippocampus and treatment decreased astrogliosis in all of them. We measured the expression of IBA1+ microglia in the same regions and classified microglia according to their morphology: we found that MS rats presented an increased proportion of the hypertrophied phenotype and GEN produced a shift in microglial phenotypes toward a ramified type. Furthermore, colocalization of IBA1 with the proinflammatory marker TNF&#x3b1; showed increased proportion of proinflammatory microglia in MS and a reduction with GEN treatment. On the other hand, colocalization with the anti-inflammatory marker Arg1 showed that MS has decreased proportion of anti-inflammatory microglia and GEN treatment increased this parameter. Cognitive dysfunction was evaluated in rats with MS using a battery of behavioral tests that assessed hippocampus-dependent spatial and working memory, such as the novel object recognition test (NOR), the novel object location test (NOL), and the free-movement pattern Y-maze (FMP-YMAZE) and the d-YMAZE. In all of them, MS performed poorly and GEN was able to improve cognitive impairments. These results indicate that GEN was able to exert neuroprotective actions increasing neurogenesis and improving cognitive impairments while decreasing astrogliosis, microgliosis, and neuroinflammatory environment in MS rats. Together, these results open an interesting possibility for proposing this phytoestrogen as a neuroprotective therapy for MS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 British Society for Neuroendocrinology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ronchetti</LastName><ForeName>Santiago</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Neuroendocrine Biochemistry, Instituto de Biolog&#xed;a y Medicina Experimental, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Labombarda</LastName><ForeName>Florencia</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7911-1173</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Neuroendocrine Biochemistry, Instituto de Biolog&#xed;a y Medicina Experimental, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Biochemistry, Faculty of Medicine, University of Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Del Core</LastName><ForeName>Julian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Neuroendocrine Biochemistry, Instituto de Biolog&#xed;a y Medicina Experimental, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roig</LastName><ForeName>Paulina</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Neuroendocrine Biochemistry, Instituto de Biolog&#xed;a y Medicina Experimental, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Nicola</LastName><ForeName>Alejandro F</ForeName><Initials>AF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3523-9148</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Neuroendocrine Biochemistry, Instituto de Biolog&#xed;a y Medicina Experimental, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Biochemistry, Faculty of Medicine, University of Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pietranera</LastName><ForeName>Luciana</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2150-6142</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Neuroendocrine Biochemistry, Instituto de Biolog&#xed;a y Medicina Experimental, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Biochemistry, Faculty of Medicine, University of Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>348</GrantID><Agency>Ministerio de Ciencia, Tecnolog&#xed;a e Innovaci&#xf3;n</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>334</GrantID><Agency>Consejo Nacional de Investigaciones Cient&#xed;ficas y T&#xe9;cnicas</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>20020100100089BA</GrantID><Agency>Universidad de Buenos Aires</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Williams, Brown and Cherny Foundations</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Neuroendocrinol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8913461</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0953-8194</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>DH2M523P0H</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019833">Genistein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D048789">Phytoestrogens</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000089662">Doublecortin Protein</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000714848">Dcx protein, rat</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D024821" MajorTopicYN="Y">Metabolic Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055495" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurogenesis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060825" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cognitive Dysfunction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019833" MajorTopicYN="Y">Genistein</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D048789" MajorTopicYN="Y">Phytoestrogens</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006624" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hippocampus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000090862" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neuroinflammatory Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011918" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats, Inbred SHR</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000089662" MajorTopicYN="N">Doublecortin Protein</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059305" MajorTopicYN="N">Diet, High-Fat</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">genistein</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metabolic syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuroinflammation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39676329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jne.13480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>National Cholesterol Education Program Expert Panel on Detection, E. and A. Treatment of High Blood Cholesterol. Third report of the National Cholesterol Education Program (NCEP) expert panel on detection, evaluation, and treatment of high blood cholesterol in adults (Adult Treatment Panel III) final report. Circulation. 2002;106(25):3143&#x2010;3421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miesel A, M&#xfc;ller H, Thermann M, Heidbreder M, Dominiak P, Raasch W. Overfeeding&#x2010;induced obesity in spontaneously hypertensive rats: an animal model of the human metabolic syndrome. Ann Nutr Metab. 2010;56(2):127&#x2010;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindqvist A, Mohapel P, Bouter B, et al. High&#x2010;fat diet impairs hippocampal neurogenesis in male rats. Eur J Neurol. 2006;13(12):1385&#x2010;1388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarchielli E, Comeglio P, Filippi S, et al. Neuroprotective effects of testosterone in the hypothalamus of an animal model of metabolic syndrome. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(4):1589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sierra A, Beccari S, Diaz&#x2010;Aparicio I, Encinas JM, Comeau S, Tremblay M&#xc8;. Surveillance, phagocytosis, and inflammation: how never&#x2010;resting microglia influence adult hippocampal neurogenesis. Neural Plast. 2014;2014:610343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y, Le W. Differential roles of M1 and M2 microglia in neurodegenerative diseases. MolNeurobiol. 2016;53(2):1181&#x2010;1194.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liddelow SA, Guttenplan KA, Clarke LE, et al. Neurotoxic reactive astrocytes are induced by activated microglia. Nature. 2017;541(7638):481&#x2010;487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belarbi K, Jopson T, Tweedie D, et al. TNF&#x2010;alpha protein synthesis inhibitor restores neuronal function and reverses cognitive deficits induced by chronic neuroinflammation. J Neuroinflammation. 2012;9:23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foret JT, Oleson S, Hickson B, Valek S, Tanaka H, Haley AP. Metabolic syndrome and cognitive function in midlife. Arch Clin Neuropsychol. 2020;36:897&#x2010;907.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borshchev YY, Uspensky YP, Galagudza MM. Pathogenetic pathways of cognitive dysfunction and dementia in metabolic syndrome. Life Sci. 2019;237:116932.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen TT, Ta QTH, Nguyen TTD, le TT, Vo VG. Role of insulin resistance in the Alzheimer's disease progression. Neurochem Res. 2020;45(7):1481&#x2010;1491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis AR, Singh S, Youssef FF. Cafeteria&#x2010;diet induced obesity results in impaired cognitive functioning in a rodent model. Heliyon. 2019;5(3):e01412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietranera L, Saravia F, Gonzalez Deniselle MC, Roig P, Lima A, de Nicola AF. Abnormalities of the hippocampus are similar in deoxycorticosterone acetate&#x2010;salt hypertensive rats and spontaneously hypertensive rats. J Neuroendocrinol. 2006;18(6):466&#x2010;474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietranera L, Lima A, Roig P, de Nicola AF. Involvement of brain&#x2010;derived neurotrophic factor and neurogenesis in oestradiol neuroprotection of the hippocampus of hypertensive rats. J Neuroendocrinol. 2010;22(10):1082&#x2010;1092.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller AA, Spencer SJ. Obesity and neuroinflammation: a pathway to cognitive impairment. Brain Behav Immun. 2014;42:10&#x2010;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang D, Yang C, Luo Q, et al. Soy isoflavones improve the oxidative stress induced hypothalamic inflammation and apoptosis in high fat diet&#x2010;induced obese male mice through PGC1&#x2010;alpha pathway. Aging (Albany NY). 2020;12(9):8710&#x2010;8727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki S, Gerhold LM, B&#xf6;ttner M, et al. Estradiol enhances neurogenesis following ischemic stroke through estrogen receptors alpha and beta. J Comp Neurol. 2007;500(6):1064&#x2010;1075.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YZ, Liu YJ, Zhang W, Luo SF, Zhou X, He GQ. Combined treatment with valproic acid and estrogen has neuroprotective effects in ovariectomized mice with Alzheimer's disease. Neural Regen Res. 2021;16(10):2078&#x2010;2085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang WJ, Lee TY, Kim NS, Kwon JS. The role of estrogen receptors and their signaling across psychiatric disorders. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;22(1):373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulkarni J, Butler S, Riecher&#x2010;Rossler A. Estrogens and SERMS as adjunctive treatments for schizophrenia. Front Neuroendocrinol. 2019;53:100743.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cambiasso MJ, D&#xed;az H, C&#xe1;ceres A, Carrer HF. Neuritogenic effect of estradiol on rat ventromedial hypothalamic neurons co&#x2010;cultured with homotopic or heterotopic glia. J Neurosci Res. 1995;42(5):700&#x2010;709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietranera L, Brocca ME, Roig P, Lima A, Garcia&#x2010;Segura LM, de Nicola AF. Estrogens are neuroprotective factors for hypertensive encephalopathy. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2015;146:15&#x2010;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietranera L, Correa J, Brocca ME, et al. Selective Oestrogen receptor agonists rescued hippocampus parameters in male spontaneously hypertensive rats. J Neuroendocrinol. 2016;28(10). https://doi.org/10.1111/jne.12415</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saravia F, Beauquis J, Pietranera L, de Nicola AF. Neuroprotective effects of estradiol in hippocampal neurons and glia of middle age mice. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2007;32(5):480&#x2010;492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadal A, Diaz M, Valverde MA. The estrogen trinity: membrane, cytosolic, and nuclear effects. News Physiol Sci. 2001;16:251&#x2010;255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dey P, Dey P, Barros RP, Warner M, Str&#xf6;m A, Gustafsson J&#xc5;. Insight into the mechanisms of action of estrogen receptor beta in the breast, prostate, colon, and CNS. J Mol Endocrinol. 2013;51(3):T61&#x2010;T74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arevalo MA, Diz&#x2010;Chaves Y, Santos&#x2010;Galindo M, Bellini MJ, Garcia&#x2010;Segura LM. Selective oestrogen receptor modulators decrease the inflammatory response of glial cells. J Neuroendocrinol. 2012;24(1):183&#x2010;190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Szinte JS, Boulware MI, Frick KM. 17beta&#x2010;estradiol and Agonism of G&#x2010;protein&#x2010;coupled estrogen receptor enhance hippocampal memory via different cell&#x2010;signaling mechanisms. J Neurosci. 2016;36(11):3309&#x2010;3321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kastenberger I, Schwarzer C. GPER1 (GPR30) knockout mice display reduced anxiety and altered stress response in a sex and paradigm dependent manner. Horm Behav. 2014;66(4):628&#x2010;636.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blasko E, Haskell CA, Leung S, et al. Beneficial role of the GPR30 agonist G&#x2010;1 in an animal model of multiple sclerosis. J Neuroimmunol. 2009;214(1&#x2013;2):67&#x2010;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yates MA, Li Y, Chlebeck PJ, Offner H. GPR30, but not estrogen receptor&#x2010;alpha, is crucial in the treatment of experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis by oral ethinyl estradiol. BMC Immunol. 2010;11:20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Sweidi S, Sanchez MG, Bourque M, Morissette M, Dluzen D, Di Paolo T. Oestrogen receptors and signalling pathways: implications for neuroprotective effects of sex steroids in Parkinson's disease. J Neuroendocrinol. 2012;24(1):48&#x2010;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correa J, Ronchetti S, Labombarda F, de Nicola AF, Pietranera L. Activation of the G protein&#x2010;coupled estrogen receptor (GPER) increases neurogenesis and ameliorates Neuroinflammation in the hippocampus of male spontaneously hypertensive rats. Cell Mol Neurobiol. 2020;40(5):711&#x2010;723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossouw JE, Anderson GL, Prentice RL, et al. Risks and benefits of estrogen plus progestin in healthy postmenopausal women: principal results from the Women's Health Initiative randomized controlled trial. JAMA. 2002;288(3):321&#x2010;333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuiper GG, Carlsson B, Grandien K, et al. Comparison of the ligand binding specificity and transcript tissue distribution of estrogen receptors alpha and beta. Endocrinology. 1997;138(3):863&#x2010;870.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuiper GG, Lemmen JG, Carlsson BO, et al. Interaction of estrogenic chemicals and phytoestrogens with estrogen receptor beta. Endocrinology. 1998;139(10):4252&#x2010;4263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas P, Dong J. Binding and activation of the seven&#x2010;transmembrane estrogen receptor GPR30 by environmental estrogens: a potential novel mechanism of endocrine disruption. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2006;102(1&#x2013;5):175&#x2010;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang NH, Shin HC, Oh S, Lee KH, Lee YB, Choi KC. Soy milk digestion extract inhibits progression of prostate cancer cell growth via regulation of prostate cancerspecific antigen and cell cycle&#x2010;regulatory genes in human LNCaP cancer cells. Mol Med Rep. 2016;14(2):1809&#x2010;1816.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu HC, Hu QL, Zhang SJ, et al. Neuroprotective effects of genistein on SH&#x2010;SY5Y cells overexpressing A53T mutant alpha&#x2010;synuclein. Neural Regen Res. 2018;13(8):1375&#x2010;1383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valles SL, Dolz&#x2010;Gaiton P, Gambini J, et al. Estradiol or genistein prevent Alzheimer's disease&#x2010;associated inflammation correlating with an increase PPAR gamma expression in cultured astrocytes. Brain Res. 2010;1312:138&#x2010;144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jantaratnotai N, Utaisincharoen P, Sanvarinda P, Thampithak A, Sanvarinda Y. Phytoestrogens mediated anti&#x2010;inflammatory effect through suppression of IRF&#x2010;1 and pSTAT1 expressions in lipopolysaccharide&#x2010;activated microglia. Int Immunopharmacol. 2013;17(2):483&#x2010;488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian Y, Cao L, Guan T, et al. Protection by genistein on cortical neurons against oxidative stress injury via inhibition of NF&#x2010;kappaB, JNK and ERK signaling pathway. Pharm Biol. 2015;53(8):1124&#x2010;1132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDowell ML, das A, Smith JA, Varma AK, Ray SK, Banik NL. Neuroprotective effects of genistein in VSC4.1 motoneurons exposed to activated microglial cytokines. Neurochem Int. 2011;59(2):175&#x2010;184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arbabi E, Hamidi G, Talaei SA, Salami M. Estrogen agonist genistein differentially influences the cognitive and motor disorders in an ovariectomized animal model of parkinsonism. Iran J Basic Med Sci. 2016;19(12):1285&#x2010;1290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z, Fu J, Li S, Li Z. Neuroprotective effects of Genistein in a SOD1&#x2010;G93A transgenic mouse model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neuroimmune Pharmacol. 2019;14(4):688&#x2010;696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kageyama A, Sakakibara H, Zhou W, et al. Genistein regulated serotonergic activity in the hippocampus of ovariectomized rats under forced swimming stress. Biosci Biotechnol Biochem. 2010;74(10):2005&#x2010;2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee B, Choi GM, Shim I, Lee H. Genistein prevents single prolonged stress&#x2010;induced cognitive impairment in a post&#x2010;traumatic stress disorder rat model via activation of the serotonergic system. J Med Food. 2020;23(5):476&#x2010;484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azcoitia I, Moreno A, Carrero P, Palacios S, Garcia&#x2010;Segura LM. Neuroprotective effects of soy phytoestrogens in the rat brain. Gynecol Endocrinol. 2006;22(2):63&#x2010;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petry FDS, Hoppe JB, Klein CP, et al. Genistein attenuates amyloid&#x2010;beta&#x2010;induced cognitive impairment in rats by modulation of hippocampal synaptotoxicity and hyperphosphorylation of tau. J Nutr Biochem. 2021;87:108525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li RZ, Ding XW, Geetha T, al&#x2010;Nakkash L, Broderick TL, Babu JR. Beneficial effect of Genistein on diabetes&#x2010;induced brain damage in the ob/ob mouse model. Drug Des Devel Ther. 2020;14:3325&#x2010;3336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronchetti S, Labombarda F, Roig P, de Nicola AF, Pietranera L. Beneficial effects of the phytoestrogen genistein on hippocampal impairments of spontaneously hypertensive rats (SHR). J Neuroendocrinol. 2023;35(1):e13228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moiola CP, de Luca P, Zalazar F, et al. Prostate tumor growth is impaired by CtBP1 depletion in high&#x2010;fat diet&#x2010;fed mice. Clin Cancer Res. 2014;20(15):4086&#x2010;4095.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reckelhoff JF. Sex differences in regulation of blood pressure. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2018;1065:139&#x2010;151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conti FF, Brito JO, Bernardes N, et al. Positive effect of combined exercise training in a model of metabolic syndrome and menopause: autonomic, inflammatory, and oxidative stress evaluations. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2015;309(12):R1532&#x2010;R1539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novelli EL, Diniz YS, Galhardi CM, et al. Anthropometrical parameters and markers of obesity in rats. Lab Anim. 2007;41(1):111&#x2010;119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian Y, Guan T, Huang M, et al. Neuroprotection by the soy isoflavone, genistein, via inhibition of mitochondria&#x2010;dependent apoptosis pathways and reactive oxygen induced&#x2010;NF&#x2010;kappaB activation in a cerebral ischemia mouse model. Neurochem Int. 2012;60(8):759&#x2010;767.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Wang K, Chen L, Yin B, Song Y. Is phytoestrogen intake associated with decreased risk of prostate cancer? A systematic review of epidemiological studies based on 17,546 cases. Andrology. 2016;4:745&#x2010;756.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paxinos G, Watson C. The Rat Brain in Stereotaxic Coordinates. 3rd ed. Academic Press; 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howart C, Reed M. Unbiased Stereology. Three&#x2010;Dimensional Measurment in Microscopy. Garland Science/BIOS Scientific Publisher; 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz C, Hof PR. Design&#x2010;based stereology in neuroscience. Neuroscience. 2005;130(4):813&#x2010;831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres&#x2010;Platas SG, Comeau S, Rachalski A, et al. Morphometric characterization of microglial phenotypes in human cerebral cortex. J Neuroinflammation. 2014;11:12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gresack JE, Kerr KM, Frick KM. Life&#x2010;long environmental enrichment differentially affects the mnemonic response to estrogen in young, middle&#x2010;aged, and aged female mice. Neurobiol Learn Mem. 2007;88(4):393&#x2010;408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z, Loane DJ, Murray MG II, Stoica BA, Faden AI. Comparing the predictive value of multiple cognitive, affective, and motor tasks after rodent traumatic brain injury. J Neurotrauma. 2012;29(15):2475&#x2010;2489.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murai T, Okuda S, Tanaka T, Ohta H. Characteristics of object location memory in mice: behavioral and pharmacological studies. Physiol Behav. 2007;90(1):116&#x2010;124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ennaceur A. One&#x2010;trial object recognition in rats and mice: methodological and theoretical issues. Behav Brain Res. 2010;215(2):244&#x2010;254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, Zhao Z, Sabirzhanov B, et al. Spinal cord injury causes brain inflammation associated with cognitive and affective changes: role of cell cycle pathways. J Neurosci. 2014;34(33):10989&#x2010;11006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dellu F, Fauchey V, Moal ML, Simon H. Extension of a new two&#x2010;trial memory task in the rat: influence of environmental context on recognition processes. Neurobiol Learn Mem. 1997;67(2):112&#x2010;120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietranera L, Saravia FE, Roig P, Lima A, de Nicola AF. Protective effects of estradiol in the brain of rats with genetic or mineralocorticoid&#x2010;induced hypertension. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2008;33(3):270&#x2010;281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomassoni D, Avola R, di Tullio MA, Sabbatini M, Vitaioli L, Amenta F. Increased expression of glial fibrillary acidic protein in the brain of spontaneously hypertensive rats. Clin Exp Hypertens. 2004;26(4):335&#x2010;350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amar J, Chabo C, Waget A, et al. Intestinal mucosal adherence and translocation of commensal bacteria at the early onset of type 2 diabetes: molecular mechanisms and probiotic treatment. EMBO Mol Med. 2011;3(9):559&#x2010;572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blackburn P, Despr&#xe9;s JP, Lamarche B, et al. Postprandial variations of plasma inflammatory markers in abdominally obese men. Obesity (Silver Spring). 2006;14(10):1747&#x2010;1754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jais A, Bruning JC. Hypothalamic inflammation in obesity and metabolic disease. J Clin Invest. 2017;127(1):24&#x2010;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietranera L, Brocca ME, Cymeryng C, et al. Increased expression of the mineralocorticoid receptor in the brain of spontaneously hypertensive rats (Shr). J Neuroendocrinol. 2012;24:1&#x2010;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietranera L, Saravia F, Roig P, Lima A, de Nicola AF. Mineralocorticoid treatment upregulates the hypothalamic vasopressinergic system of spontaneously hypertensive rats. Neuroendocrinology. 2004;80(2):100&#x2010;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritter S, Dinh TT, Stone S, Ross N. Cerebroventricular dilation in spontaneously hypertensive rats (SHRs) is not attenuated by reduction of blood pressure. Brain Res. 1988;450(1&#x2013;2):354&#x2010;359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saavedra JM. Opportunities and limitations of genetic analysis of hypertensive rat strains. J Hypertens. 2009;27(6):1129&#x2010;1133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnal JF, Lenfant F, Metivier R, et al. Membrane and nuclear estrogen receptor alpha actions: from tissue specificity to medical implications. Physiol Rev. 2017;97(3):1045&#x2010;1087.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>An J, Tzagarakis&#x2010;Foster C, Scharschmidt TC, Lomri N, Leitman DC. Estrogen receptor beta&#x2010;selective transcriptional activity and recruitment of coregulators by phytoestrogens. J Biol Chem. 2001;276(21):17808&#x2010;17814.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguilera G, Rabadan&#x2010;Diehl C. Vasopressinergic regulation of the hypothalamic&#x2013;pituitary&#x2013;adrenal axis: implications for stress adaptation. Regul Pept. 2000;96:23&#x2010;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al&#x2010;Shami AS, Essawy AE, Elkader H. Molecular mechanisms underlying the potential neuroprotective effects of Trifolium pratense and its phytoestrogen&#x2010;isoflavones in neurodegenerative disorders. Phytother Res. 2023;37(6):2693&#x2010;2737.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du ZR, Feng XQ, Li N, et al. G protein&#x2010;coupled estrogen receptor is involved in the anti&#x2010;inflammatory effects of genistein in microglia. Phytomedicine. 2018;43:11&#x2010;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menze ET, Esmat A, Tadros MG, Abdel&#x2010;Naim AB, Khalifa AE. Genistein improves 3&#x2010;NPA&#x2010;induced memory impairment in ovariectomized rats: impact of its antioxidant, anti&#x2010;inflammatory and acetylcholinesterase modulatory properties. PLoS One. 2015;10(2):e0117223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Francesco EM, Angelone T, Pasqua T, Pupo M, Cerra MC, Maggiolini M. GPER mediates cardiotropic effects in spontaneously hypertensive rat hearts. PLoS One. 2013;8(8):e69322.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>