<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32698256</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2733-7545</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physical activity and nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Phys Act Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pre-sleep casein protein ingestion: new paradigm in post-exercise recovery nutrition.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>6</StartPage><EndPage>10</EndPage><MedlinePgn>6-10</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.20463/pan.2020.0009</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Milk is a commonly ingested post-exercise recovery protein source. Casein protein, found in milk, is characterized by its slow digestion and absorption. Recently, several studies have been conducted with a focus on how pre-sleep casein protein intake could affect post-exercise recovery but our knowledge of the subject remains limited. This review aimed at presenting and discussing how pre-sleep casein protein ingestion affects post-exercise recovery and the details of its potential effector mechanisms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We systematically reviewed the topics of 1) casein nutritional characteristics, 2) pre-sleep casein protein effects on post-exercise recovery, and 3) potential effector mechanisms of pre-sleep casein protein on post-exercise recovery, based on the currently available published studies on pre-sleep casein protein ingestion.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Studies have shown that pre-sleep casein protein ingestion (timing: 30 minutes before sleep, amount of casein protein ingested: 40-48 g) could help post-exercise recovery and positively affect acute protein metabolism and exercise performance. In addition, studies have suggested that repeated pre-sleep casein protein ingestion for post-exercise recovery over a long period might also result in chronic effects that optimize intramuscular physiological adaptation (muscle strength and muscle hypertrophy). The potential mechanisms of pre-sleep casein protein ingestion that contribute to these effects include the following: 1) significantly increasing plasma amino acid availability during sleep, thereby increasing protein synthesis, inhibiting protein breakdown, and achieving a positive protein balance; and 2) weakening exercise-induced muscle damage or inflammatory responses, causing reduced muscle soreness. Future studies should focus on completely elucidating these potential mechanisms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In conclusion, post-exercise ingestion of at least 40 g of casein protein, approximately 30 minutes before sleep and after a bout of resistance exercise in the evening, might be an effective nutritional intervention to facilitate muscle recovery.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;2020 The Korean Society for Exercise Nutrition.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Jooyoung</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Phys Act Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101770644</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2733-7545</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">casein protein</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32698256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7451833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20463/pan.2020.0009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JENB_2020_v24n2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.3389/fnut.2019.00147. [Moore DR. Maximizing post-exercise anabolism: the case for relative protein intakes. Front Nutr. 2019;6:147.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2019.00147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.3390/sports7010005. [Apweiler E, Wallace D, Stansfield S, Allerton DM, Brown MA, Stevenson EJ, Clifford T. Pre-bed casein protein supplementation does not enhance acute functional recovery in physically active males and females when exercise is performed in the morning. Sports. 2018;7:5.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports7010005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.3945/jn.114.203208. [Reidy PT, Rasmussen BB. Role of ingested amino acids and protein in the promotion of resistance exercise-induced muscle protein anabolism. J Nutr. 2016;146:155-83.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.114.203208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.3945/jn.108.092924. [Beelen M, Tieland M, Gijsen AP, Vandereyt H, Kies AK, Kuipers H, Saris WHM, Koopman R, van Loon LJC. Coingestion of carbohydrate and protein hydrolysate stimulates muscle protein synthesis during exercise in young men, with no further increase during subsequent overnight recovery. J. Nutr. 2008;138:2198-204.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.108.092924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2018-0385. [Abbott W, Brett A, Cockburn E, Clifford T. Presleep casein protein ingestion: acceleration of functional recovery in professional soccer players. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019;14:385-91.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2018-0385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.3945/jn.114.208371. [Snijders T, Res PT, Smeets JS, van Vliet S, van Kranenburg J, Maase K, Kies AK, Verdijk LB, van Loon LJ. Protein ingestion before sleep increases muscle mass and strength gains during prolonged resistance-type exercise training in healthy young men. J Nutr. 2015;145:1178-84.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.114.208371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>[Antonio J, Ellerbroek A, Peacock C, Silver T. Casein protein supplementation in trained men and women: morning versus evening. Int J Exerc Sci. 2017;10:479-86.]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31824cc363. [Res PT, Groen B, Pennings B, Beelen M, Wallis GA, Gijsen AP, Senden JM, VAN Loon LJ. Protein ingestion before sleep improves postexercise overnight recovery. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44:1560-9.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31824cc363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.3390/nu10091273. [Madzima TA, Melanson JT, Black JR, Nepocatych S. Presleep consumption of casein and whey protein: effects on morning metabolism and resistance exercise performance in active women. Nutrients. 2018;10:1273.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10091273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.3390/nu8060339. [Kanda A, Nakayama K, Sanbongi C, Nagata M, Ikegami S, Itoh H. Effects of whey, caseinate, or milk protein ingestion on muscle protein synthesis after exercise. Nutrients. 2016;8:339.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu8060339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00076.2009. [Tang JE, Moore DR, Kujbida GW, Tarnopolsky MA, Phillips SM. Ingestion of whey hydrolysate, casein, or soy protein isolate: effects on mixed muscle protein synthesis at rest and following resistance exercise in young men. J Appl Physiol. 2009;107:987-92.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00076.2009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.3168/jds.2013-6831. [Holt C, Carver JA, Ecroyd H, Thorn DC. Invited review: Caseins and the casein micelle: their biological functions, structures, and behavior in foods. J Dairy Sci. 2013;96:6127-46.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2013-6831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.1186/1743-7075-10-46. [McGregor RA, Poppitt SD. Milk protein for improved metabolic health: a review of the evidence. Nutr Metab. 2013;10:46.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-10-46</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.1079/BJN2002760. [Hall WL, Millward DJ, Long SJ, Morgan LM. Casein and whey exert different effects on plasma amino acid profiles, gastrointestinal hormone secretion and appetite. Br J Nutr. 2003;89:239-48.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1079/BJN2002760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.00513.2010. [Reitelseder S, Agergaard J, Doessing S, Helmark IC, Lund P, Kristensen NB, Frystyk J, Flyvbjerg A, Schjerling P, van Hall G, Kjaer M, Holm L. Whey and casein labeled with L-[1-13C] leucine and muscle protein synthesis: effect of resistance exercise and protein ingestion. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2011;300:231-42.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00513.2010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.1016/j.metabol.2012.03.001. [Engelen MP, Rutten EP, De Castro CL, Wouters EF, Schols AM, Deutz NE. Casein protein results in higher prandial and exercise induced whole body protein anabolism than whey protein in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Metabolism. 2012;61:1289-300.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.metabol.2012.03.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.1186/s12970-017-0193-8. [Ranchordas MK, Dawson JT, Russell M. Practical nutritional recovery strategies for elite soccer players when limited time separates repeated matches. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2017;14:35.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-017-0193-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.3389/fphys.2018.00403. [Dupuy O, Douzi W, Theurot D, Bosquet L, Dugu&#xe9; B. An evidence-based approach for choosing post-exercise recovery techniques to reduce markers of muscle damage, soreness, fatigue, and inflammation: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Front Physiol. 2018;9:403.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2018.00403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.1093/ajcn/85.4.1031. [Wilkinson SB, Tarnopolsky MA, Macdonald MJ, Macdonald JR, Armstrong D, Phillips SM. Consumption of fluid skim milk promotes greater muscle protein accretion after resistance exercise than does consumption of an isonitrogenous and isoenergetic soy-protein beverage. Am J Clin Nutr. 2007;85:1031-40.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/85.4.1031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.3389/fnut.2019.00055. [Bridge A, Brown J, Snider H, Nasato M, Ward WE, Roy BD, Josse AR. Greek yogurt and 12 weeks of exercise training on strength, muscle thickness and body composition in lean, untrained, university-aged males. Front Nutr. 2019;6:55.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2019.00055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.1186/s12970-018-0228-9. [Joy JM, Vogel RM, Shane Broughton K, Kudla U, Kerr NY, Davison JM, Wildman REC, DiMarco NM. Daytime and nighttime casein supplements similarly increase muscle size and strength in response to resistance training earlier in the day: a preliminary investigation. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2018;15:24.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-018-0228-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.00273.2016. [Trommelen J, Kouw IWK, Holwerda AM, Snijders T, Halson SL, Rollo I, Verdijk LB, van Loon LJC. Presleep dietary protein-derived amino acids are incorporated in myofibrillar protein during postexercise overnight recovery. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2018;314:457-67.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00273.2016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>[Trommelen J, Holwerda AM, Senden JM, Goessens JPB, van Kranenburg J, Gijsen AP, Verdijk LB, van Loon LJC. Casein ingestion does not increase muscle connective tissue protein synthesis rates. Med Sci Sports Exerc. Epub 2020/03/18. PubMed PMID: 32195768.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.3945/jn.117.254532. [Kouw IW, Holwerda AM, Trommelen J, Kramer IF, Bastiaanse J, Halson SL, Wodzig WK, Verdijk LB, van Loon LJ. Protein ingestion before sleep increases overnight muscle protein synthesis rates in healthy older men: a randomized controlled trial. J Nutr. 2017;147:2252-61.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.117.254532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.3945/jn.115.213710. [Churchward-Venne TA, Snijders T, Linkens AM, Hamer HM, van Kranenburg J, van Loon LJ. Ingestion of casein in a milk matrix modulates dietary protein digestion and absorption kinetics but does not modulate postprandial muscle protein synthesis in older men. J Nutr. 2015;145:1438-45.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.115.213710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.3390/nu10020180. [Stokes T, Hector AJ, Morton RW, McGlory C, Phillips SM. Recent perspectives regarding the role of dietary protein for the promotion of muscle hypertrophy with resistance exercise training. Nutrients. 2018;10:180.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10020180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.00466.2001. [B&#xf8;rsheim E, Tipton KD, Wolf SE, Wolfe RR. Essential amino acids and muscle protein recovery from resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2002;283:648-57.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00466.2001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.1249/01.MSS.0000053910.63105.45. [Miller SL, Tipton KD, Chinkes DL, Wolf SE, Wolfe RR. Independent and combined effects of amino acids and glucose after resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35:449-55.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000053910.63105.45</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.1152/japplphysiol.00971.2016. [Peake JM, Neubauer O, Della Gatta PA, Nosaka K. Muscle damage and inflammation during recovery from exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2017;122:559-70.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00971.2016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.12965/jer.140179. [Kim J, Lee J. A review of nutritional intervention on delayed onset muscle soreness. Part I. J Exerc Rehabil. 2014;10:349-56.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12965/jer.140179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>doi: 10.3389/fnut.2019.00017. [Snijders T, Trommelen J, Kouw IWK, Holwerda AM, Verdijk LB, van Loon LJC. The impact of pre-sleep protein ingestion on the skeletal muscle adaptive response to exercise in humans: an update. Front Nutr. 2019;6:17.]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2019.00017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>