<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38117486</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-6860</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>FASEB journal : official publication of the Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>FASEB J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Leptin-dependent differential remodeling of visceral and pericardial adipose tissue following chronic exercise and psychosocial stress.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e23325</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e23325</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1096/fj.202300269RRR</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Obesity is driven by an imbalance between caloric intake and energy expenditure, causing excessive storage of triglycerides in adipose tissue at different sites around the body. Increased visceral adipose tissue (VAT) is associated with diabetes, while pericardial adipose tissue (PAT) is associated with cardiac pathology. Adipose tissue can expand either through cellular hypertrophy or hyperplasia, with the former correlating with decreased metabolic health in obesity. The aim of this study was to determine how VAT and PAT remodel in response to obesity, stress, and exercise. Here we have used the male obese Zucker rats, which carries two recessive fa alleles that result in the development of hyperphagia with reduced energy expenditure, resulting in morbid obesity and leptin resistance. At 9&#x2009;weeks of age, a group of lean (Fa/Fa or Fa/fa) Zucker rats (LZR) and obese (fa/fa) Zucker rats (OZR) were treated with unpredictable chronic mild stress or exercise for 8&#x2009;weeks. To determine the phenotype for PAT and VAT, tissue cellularity and gene expression were analyzed. Finally, leptin signaling was investigated further using cultured 3T3-derived adipocytes. Tissue cellularity was determined following hematoxylin and eosin (H&amp;E) staining, while qPCR was used to examine gene expression. PAT adipocytes were significantly smaller than those from VAT and had a more beige-like appearance in both LZR and OZR. In the OZR group, VAT adipocyte cell size increased significantly compared with LZR, while PAT showed no difference. Exercise and stress resulted in a significant reduction in VAT cellularity in OZR, while PAT showed no change. This suggests that PAT cellularity does not remodel significantly compared with VAT. These data indicate that the extracellular matrix of PAT is able to remodel more readily than in VAT. In the LZR group, exercise increased insulin receptor substrate 1 (IRS1) in PAT but was decreased in the OZR group. In VAT, exercise decreased IRS1 in LZR, while increasing it in OZR. This suggests that in obesity, VAT is more responsive to exercise and subsequently becomes less insulin resistant compared with PAT. Stress increased PPAR-&#x3b3; expression in the VAT but decreased it in the PAT in the OZR group. This suggests that in obesity, stress increases adipogenesis more significantly in the VAT compared with PAT. To understand the role of leptin signaling in adipose tissue remodeling mechanistically, JAK2 autophosphorylation was inhibited using 5&#x2009;&#x3bc;M 1,2,3,4,5,6-hexabromocyclohexane (Hex) in cultured 3T3-derived adipocytes. Palmitate treatment was used to induce cellular hypertrophy. Hex blocked adipocyte hypertrophy in response to palmitate treatment but not the increase in lipid droplet size. These data suggest that leptin signaling is necessary for adipocyte cell remodeling, and its absence induces whitening. Taken together, our data suggest that leptin signaling is necessary for adipocyte remodeling in response to obesity, exercise, and psychosocial stress.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. The FASEB Journal published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ige</LastName><ForeName>Susan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Cardiovascular and Metabolic Research, School of Biological Sciences, University of Reading, Reading, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alaoui</LastName><ForeName>Kaouthar</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Cardiovascular and Metabolic Research, School of Biological Sciences, University of Reading, Reading, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Dibouni</LastName><ForeName>Alaa</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Cardiovascular and Metabolic Research, School of Biological Sciences, University of Reading, Reading, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dallas</LastName><ForeName>Mark L</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Cardiovascular and Metabolic Research, School of Biological Sciences, University of Reading, Reading, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cagampang</LastName><ForeName>Felino R</ForeName><Initials>FR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Developmental Sciences, Human Development and Health, Faculty of Medicine, University of Southampton, Southampton, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sellayah</LastName><ForeName>Dyan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Cardiovascular and Metabolic Research, School of Biological Sciences, University of Reading, Reading, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chantler</LastName><ForeName>Paul D</ForeName><Initials>PD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, West Virginia University, Morgantown, West Virginia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boateng</LastName><ForeName>Samuel Y</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Cardiovascular and Metabolic Research, School of Biological Sciences, University of Reading, Reading, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MR/P011683/1</GrantID><Acronym>MRC_</Acronym><Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS117754</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>FASEB J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8804484</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0892-6638</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D020738">Leptin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010168">Palmitates</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020738" MajorTopicYN="Y">Leptin</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011924" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats, Zucker</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000273" MajorTopicYN="Y">Adipose Tissue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010496" MajorTopicYN="N">Pericardium</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010168" MajorTopicYN="N">Palmitates</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013315" MajorTopicYN="N">Stress, Psychological</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006984" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38117486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.202300269RRR</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Eguren G, Sala-Vila A, Gir&#xf3; O, Vega-Beyhart A, Hanzu FA. Long-term hypercortisolism induces lipogenesis promoting palmitic acid accumulation and inflammation in visceral adipose tissue compared with HFD-induced obesity. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2020;318(6):E995-E1003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Yan C, Liu L, et&#xa0;al. 11&#x3b2;-Hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase type 1 shRNA ameliorates glucocorticoid-induced insulin resistance and lipolysis in mouse abdominal adipose tissue. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2015;308(1):E84-E95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dube S, Norby BJ, Pattan V, Carter RE, Basu A, Basu R. 11&#x3b2;-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase types 1 and 2 activity in subcutaneous adipose tissue in humans: implications in obesity and diabetes. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2015;100(1):E70-E76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alonso-Alonso M, Pascual-Leone A. The right brain hypothesis for obesity. JAMA. 2007;297(16):1819-1822.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ippoliti F, Canitano N, Businaro R. Stress and obesity as risk factors in cardiovascular diseases: a neuroimmune perspective. J Neuroimmune Pharmacol. 2013;8(1):212-226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi SY, Steffen LM, Terry JG, et&#xa0;al. Added sugar intake is associated with pericardial adipose tissue volume. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2020;27(18):2016-2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zs&#xf3;ri G, Ill&#xe9;s D, Iv&#xe1;ny E, et&#xa0;al. In new-onset diabetes mellitus, metformin reduces fat accumulation in the liver, but not in the pancreas or pericardium. Metab Syndr Relat Disord. 2019;17(5):289-295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Wit-Verheggen VHW, Altintas S, Spee RJM, et&#xa0;al. Pericardial fat and its influence on cardiac diastolic function. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2020;19(1):129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li SJ, Wu TW, Chien MJ, Mersmann HJ, Chen CY. Involvement of pericardial adipose tissue in cardiac fibrosis of dietary-induced obese minipigs-role of mitochondrial function. Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Cell Biol Lipids. 2019;1864(7):957-965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CY, Li SJ, Wu TW, et&#xa0;al. The role of pericardial adipose tissue in the heart of obese minipigs. Eur J Clin Invest. 2018;48(7):e12942.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dey D, Wong ND, Tamarappoo B, et&#xa0;al. Computer-aided non-contrast CT-based quantification of pericardial and thoracic fat and their associations with coronary calcium and metabolic syndrome. Atherosclerosis. 2010;209(1):136-141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brinkley TE, Hsu FC, Carr JJ, et&#xa0;al. Pericardial fat is associated with carotid stiffness in the multi-ethnic study of atherosclerosis. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2011;21(5):332-338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elie AG, Jensen PS, Nissen KD, et&#xa0;al. Adipokine imbalance in the pericardial cavity of cardiac and vascular disease patients. PLoS One. 2016;11(5):e0154693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Qi L, Li Y, et&#xa0;al. Association of pericardiac adipose tissue with coronary artery disease. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2021;12:724859.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JS, Kim SW, Lee JS, et&#xa0;al. Association of pericardial adipose tissue with left ventricular structure and function: a region-specific effect? Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2021;20(1):26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y, He Y, Li C, et&#xa0;al. RPS3A positively regulates the mitochondrial function of human periaortic adipose tissue and is associated with coronary artery diseases. Cell Discov. 2018;4:52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau FH, Deo RC, Mowrer G, et&#xa0;al. Pattern specification and immune response transcriptional signatures of pericardial and subcutaneous adipose tissue. PLoS One. 2011;6(10):e26092.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazemi F, Zahediasl S. Effects of exercise training on adipose tissue apelin expression in streptozotocin-nicotinamide induced diabetic rats. Gene. 2018;662:97-102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Sousa Neto IV, Prestes J, Pereira GB, et&#xa0;al. Protective role of intergenerational paternal resistance training on fibrosis, inflammatory profile, and redox status in the adipose tissue of rat offspring fed with a high-fat diet. Life Sci. 2022;295:120377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hausman DB, DiGirolamo M, Bartness TJ, Hausman GJ, Martin RJ. The biology of white adipocyte proliferation. Obes Rev. 2001;2(4):239-254.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers A, Dalton M, Gibbons C, Finlayson G, Blundell J. Structured, aerobic exercise reduces fat mass and is partially compensated through energy intake but not energy expenditure in women. Physiol Behav. 2019;199:56-65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutherland LN, Bomhof MR, Capozzi LC, Basaraba SAU, Wright DC. Exercise and adrenaline increase PGC-1{alpha} mRNA expression in rat adipose tissue. J Physiol. 2009;587(Pt 7):1607-1617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trevellin E, Scorzeto M, Olivieri M, et&#xa0;al. Exercise training induces mitochondrial biogenesis and glucose uptake in subcutaneous adipose tissue through eNOS-dependent mechanisms. Diabetes. 2014;63(8):2800-2811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu S, Tucker L, Wu C, Yang L. Beneficial effects of exercise on depression and anxiety during the Covid-19 pandemic: a narrative review. Front Psych. 2020;11:587557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yates BE, DeLetter MC, Parrish EM. Prescribed exercise for the treatment of depression in a college population: an interprofessional approach. Perspect Psychiatr Care. 2020;56(4):894-899.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arvidson E, Dahlman AS, B&#xf6;rjesson M, Gullstrand L, Jonsdottir IH. Exercise training and physiological responses to acute stress: study protocol and methodological considerations of a randomised controlled trial. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2018;4(1):e000393.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks S, Brnayan KW, DeVallance E, et&#xa0;al. Psychological stress-induced cerebrovascular dysfunction: the role of metabolic syndrome and exercise. Exp Physiol. 2018;103(5):761-776.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willner P. Validity, reliability and utility of the chronic mild stress model of depression: a 10-year review and evaluation. Psychopharmacology (Berl). 1997;134(4):319-329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mineur YS, Belzung C, Crusio WE. Functional implications of decreases in neurogenesis following chronic mild stress in mice. Neuroscience. 2007;150(2):251-259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toni LS, Garcia AM, Jeffrey DA, et&#xa0;al. Optimization of phenol-chloroform RNA extraction. MethodsX. 2018;5:599-608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansson B, Wasserstrom S, Mor&#xe9;n B, et&#xa0;al. Intact glucose uptake despite deteriorating signaling in adipocytes with high-fat feeding. J Mol Endocrinol. 2018;60(3):199-211.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansson B, Mor&#xe9;n B, Fryklund C, et&#xa0;al. Adipose cell size changes are associated with a drastic actin remodeling. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):12941.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poret JM, Souza-Smith F, Marcell SJ, et&#xa0;al. High fat diet consumption differentially affects adipose tissue inflammation and adipocyte size in obesity-prone and obesity-resistant rats. Int J Obes (Lond). 2018;42(3):535-541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs SAH, Gart E, Vreeken D, et&#xa0;al. Sex-specific differences in fat storage, development of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease and brain structure in juvenile HFD-induced obese Ldlr&#x2212;/&#x2212;.Leiden mice. Nutrients. 2019;11(8):1861.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galinier A, Carriere A, Fernandez Y, et&#xa0;al. Site specific changes of redox metabolism in adipose tissue of obese Zucker rats. FEBS Lett. 2006;580(27):6391-6398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu A, Sonmez A, Yee G, et&#xa0;al. Differential adipogenic and inflammatory properties of small adipocytes in Zucker obese and lean rats. Diab Vasc Dis Res. 2010;7(4):311-318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iannitti T, Graham A, Dolan S. Increased central and peripheral inflammation and inflammatory hyperalgesia in Zucker rat model of leptin receptor deficiency and genetic obesity. Exp Physiol. 2012;97(11):1236-1245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeVallance ER, Branyan KW, Olfert IM, et&#xa0;al. Chronic stress induced perivascular adipose tissue impairment of aortic function and the therapeutic effect of exercise. Exp Physiol. 2021;106(6):1343-1358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Ge J, Cao H, et&#xa0;al. Leptin promotes white adipocyte browning by inhibiting the Hh signaling pathway. Cells. 2019;8(4):372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yam KY, Naninck EFG, Abbink MR, et&#xa0;al. Exposure to chronic early-life stress lastingly alters the adipose tissue, the leptin system and changes the vulnerability to western-style diet later in life in mice. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2017;77:186-195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delker E, AlYami B, Gallo LC, Ruiz JM, Szklo M, Allison MA. Chronic stress burden, visceral adipose tissue, and adiposity-related inflammation: the multi-ethnic study of atherosclerosis. Psychosom Med. 2021;83(8):834-842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarty R, Horwatt K, Konarska M. Chronic stress and sympathetic-adrenal medullary responsiveness. Soc Sci Med. 1988;26(3):333-341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warne JP. Shaping the stress response: interplay of palatable food choices, glucocorticoids, insulin and abdominal obesity. Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2009;300(1-2):137-146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michel C, Duclos M, Cabanac M, Richard D. Chronic stress reduces body fat content in both obesity-prone and obesity-resistant strains of mice. Horm Behav. 2005;48(2):172-179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reich CG, Taylor ME, McCarthy MM. Differential effects of chronic unpredictable stress on hippocampal CB1 receptors in male and female rats. Behav Brain Res. 2009;203(2):264-269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RB, Zhou J, Youngblood BD, Smagin GN, Ryan DH. Failure to change exploration or saccharin preference in rats exposed to chronic mild stress. Physiol Behav. 1997;63(1):91-100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieuwenhuizen AG, Rutters F. The hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal-axis in the regulation of energy balance. Physiol Behav. 2008;94(2):169-177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kivimaki M, Head J, Ferrie JE, et&#xa0;al. Work stress, weight gain and weight loss: evidence for bidirectional effects of job strain on body mass index in the Whitehall II study. Int J Obes (Lond). 2006;30(6):982-987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Block JP, He Y, Zaslavsky AM, Ding L, Ayanian JZ. Psychosocial stress and change in weight among US adults. Am J Epidemiol. 2009;170(2):181-192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyberg ST, Heikkil&#xe4; K, Fransson EI, et&#xa0;al. Job strain in relation to body mass index: pooled analysis of 160 000 adults from 13 cohort studies. J Intern Med. 2012;272(1):65-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomiyama AJ, Schamarek I, Lustig RH, et&#xa0;al. Leptin concentrations in response to acute stress predict subsequent intake of comfort foods. Physiol Behav. 2012;107(1):34-39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macedo DM, Diez-Garcia RW. Sweet craving and ghrelin and leptin levels in women during stress. Appetite. 2014;80:264-270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokkinos P. Physical activity, health benefits, and mortality risk. ISRN Cardiol. 2012;2012:718789.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Xu D. Effects of aerobic exercise on lipids and lipoproteins. Lipids Health Dis. 2017;16(1):132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stinkens R, Brouwers B, Jocken JW, et&#xa0;al. Exercise training-induced effects on the abdominal subcutaneous adipose tissue phenotype in humans with obesity. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2018;125(5):1585-1593.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otero-D&#xed;az B, Rodr&#xed;guez-Flores M, S&#xe1;nchez-Mu&#xf1;oz V, et&#xa0;al. Exercise induces white adipose tissue browning across the weight spectrum in humans. Front Physiol. 2018;9:1781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkins NT, Hagberg JM. Aerobic training effects on glucose tolerance in prediabetic and normoglycemic humans. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(12):2231-2240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;sing F, H&#xe4;gele FA, Nas A, Hasler M, M&#xfc;ller MJ, Bosy-Westphal A. Impact of energy turnover on the regulation of glucose homeostasis in healthy subjects. Nutr Diabetes. 2019;9(1):22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sothmann MS, Buckworth J, Claytor RP, Cox RH, White-Welkley JE, Dishman RK. Exercise training and the cross-stressor adaptation hypothesis. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 1996;24:267-287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanford KI, Middelbeek RJ, Goodyear LJ. Exercise effects on white adipose tissue: beiging and metabolic adaptations. Diabetes. 2015;64(7):2361-2368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magkos F, Mohammed BS, Patterson BW, Mittendorfer B. Free fatty acid kinetics in the late phase of postexercise recovery: importance of resting fatty acid metabolism and exercise-induced energy deficit. Metabolism. 2009;58(9):1248-1255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herd SL, Kiens B, Boobis LH, Hardman AE. Moderate exercise, postprandial lipemia, and skeletal muscle lipoprotein lipase activity. Metabolism. 2001;50(7):756-762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill JM, Frayn KN, Wootton SA, Miller GJ, Hardman AE. Effects of prior moderate exercise on exogenous and endogenous lipid metabolism and plasma factor VII activity. Clin Sci (Lond). 2001;100(5):517-527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill JM, Al-Mamari A, Ferrell WR, et&#xa0;al. Effects of prior moderate exercise on postprandial metabolism and vascular function in lean and centrally obese men. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2004;44(12):2375-2382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng H, Mu P, Li H, et&#xa0;al. Caveolin-1 is essential for the improvement of insulin sensitivity through AKT activation during glargine treatment on diabetic mice. J Diabetes Res. 2021;2021:9943344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karagiannides I, Golovatscka V, Bakirtzi K, et&#xa0;al. Chronic unpredictable stress regulates visceral adipocyte-mediated glucose metabolism and inflammatory circuits in male rats. Physiol Rep. 2014;2(5):e00284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahabadi AA, Massaro JM, Rosito GA, et&#xa0;al. Association of pericardial fat, intrathoracic fat, and visceral abdominal fat with cardiovascular disease burden: the Framingham heart study. Eur Heart J. 2009;30(7):850-856.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ueda Y, Shiga Y, Idemoto Y, et&#xa0;al. Association between the presence or severity of coronary artery disease and pericardial fat, paracardial fat, epicardial fat, visceral fat, and subcutaneous fat as assessed by multi-detector row computed tomography. Int Heart J. 2018;59(4):695-704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majka Z, Czamara K, Janus J, K&#x119;pczy&#x144;ski M, Kaczor A. Prominent hypertrophy of perivascular adipocytes due to short-term high fat diet. Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Basis Dis. 2022;1868(2):166315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotzbeck P, Giordano A, Mondini E, et&#xa0;al. Brown adipose tissue whitening leads to brown adipocyte death and adipose tissue inflammation. J Lipid Res. 2018;59(5):784-794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rutkowski JM, Stern JH, Scherer PE. The cell biology of fat expansion. J Cell Biol. 2015;208(5):501-512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshino J, Patterson BW, Klein S. Adipose tissue CTGF expression is associated with adiposity and insulin resistance in humans. Obesity (Silver Spring). 2019;27(6):957-962.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q, Xi W, Yin L, et&#xa0;al. Human epicardial adipose tissue cTGF expression is an independent risk factor for atrial fibrillation and highly associated with atrial fibrosis. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):3585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakazeki F, Nishiga M, Horie T, et&#xa0;al. Loss of periostin ameliorates adipose tissue inflammation and fibrosis in&#xa0;vivo. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):8553.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meissburger B, Stachorski L, R&#xf6;der E, Rudofsky G, Wolfrum C. Tissue inhibitor of matrix metalloproteinase 1 (TIMP1) controls adipogenesis in obesity in mice and in humans. Diabetologia. 2011;54(6):1468-1479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernot D, Barruet E, Poggi M, Bonardo B, Alessi MC, Peiretti F. Down-regulation of tissue inhibitor of metalloproteinase-3 (TIMP-3) expression is necessary for adipocyte differentiation. J Biol Chem. 2010;285(9):6508-6514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Divoux A, Tordjman J, Lacasa D, et&#xa0;al. Fibrosis in human adipose tissue: composition, distribution, and link with lipid metabolism and fat mass loss. Diabetes. 2010;59(11):2817-2825.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michaud A, Tordjman J, Pelletier M, et&#xa0;al. Relevance of omental pericellular adipose tissue collagen in the pathophysiology of human abdominal obesity and related cardiometabolic risk. Int J Obes (Lond). 2016;40(12):1823-1831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muir LA, Neeley CK, Meyer KA, et&#xa0;al. Adipose tissue fibrosis, hypertrophy, and hyperplasia: correlations with diabetes in human obesity. Obesity (Silver Spring). 2016;24(3):597-605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun K, Tordjman J, Cl&#xe9;ment K, Scherer PE. Fibrosis and adipose tissue dysfunction. Cell Metab. 2013;18(4):470-477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Beukel JC, Boon MR, Steenbergen J, et&#xa0;al. Cold exposure partially corrects disturbances in lipid metabolism in a male mouse model of glucocorticoid excess. Endocrinology. 2015;156(11):4115-4128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaikaew K, Steenbergen J, van Dijk TH, Grefhorst A, Visser JA. Sex difference in corticosterone-induced insulin resistance in mice. Endocrinology. 2019;160(10):2367-2387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrios V, Frago LM, Canelles S, et&#xa0;al. Leptin modulates the response of Brown adipose tissue to negative energy balance: implication of the GH/IGF-I Axis. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(6):2827.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leal LG, Lopes MA, Batista ML Jr. Physical exercise-induced Myokines and muscle-adipose tissue crosstalk: a review of current knowledge and the implications for health and metabolic diseases. Front Physiol. 2018;9:1307.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>