<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38828800</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1525-3163</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>102</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of animal science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Anim Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Influence of steroidal implants and zinc sulfate supplementation on growth performance, trace mineral status, circulating metabolites, and transcriptional changes in skeletal muscle of feedlot steers.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">skae154</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/jas/skae154</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Angus-cross steers (n&#x2005;=&#x2005;144; 362 kg&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;20.4) were used to determine the effect of Zn and steroidal implants on performance, trace mineral status, circulating metabolites, and transcriptional changes occurring in skeletal muscle. Steers (n&#x2005;=&#x2005;6 per pen) were stratified by body weight (BW) in a 3&#x2005;&#xd7;&#x2005;2 factorial. GrowSafe bunks recorded individual feed intake (steer as experimental unit; n&#x2005;=&#x2005;24 per treatment). Dietary treatments (ZINC; eight pens per treatment) included supplemental Zn as ZnSO4 at 1) 0 (analyzed 54&#xa0;mg Zn/kg DM; Zn0); 2) 30&#xa0;mg/kg DM (Zn30); 3) 100&#xa0;mg Zn/kg DM (Zn100). After 60 d of Zn treatment, steers received a steroidal implant treatment (IMP) on day 0: 1) no implant; NO; or 2) high-potency combination implant (TE-200, Elanco, Greenfield, IN; 200&#xa0;mg TBA, 20&#xa0;mg E2; TE200). BWs were taken at days -60, 0, and in 28 d increments thereafter. Liver biopsies for TM analysis and blood for TM, serum glucose, insulin, nonesterified fatty acids (NEFA), urea-N, and IGF-1 analysis were collected on days 0, 20, 40, and 84. Glucose, NEFA, and insulin were used to calculate the revised quantitative insulin sensitivity check index (RQUICKI). Linear and quadratic effects of ZINC were evaluated in SAS 9.4. Means for IMP were separated using the LSMEANS statement with the PDIFF option. Day -60 BW was a covariate for performance and carcass data. Growth performance, plasma, liver, and metabolite data were analyzed as repeated measures. TE200 tended to decrease plasma Zn by 8.4% from days 0 to 20 while NO decreased by 3.6% (IMP&#x2005;&#xd7;&#x2005;day; P&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.08). A tendency for a ZINC&#x2005;&#xd7;&#x2005;day effect on G:F was noted (P&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.06) driven by Zn30 and Zn100 decreasing significantly from period 0-28 to period 28-56 while Zn0 was similar in both periods. An IMP&#x2005;&#xd7;&#x2005;day effect was noted for RQUICKI where (P&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.02) TE200 was greater on day 40 compared to NO cattle, but by day 84 RQUICKI was not different between TE200 and NO. On day 20, increasing Zn supplementation linearly increased mRNA abundance (P&#x2005;&#x2264;&#x2005;0.09) of protein kinase B (AKT1), mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR), matrix metalloproteinase 2 (MMP2), and myogenic factor 5 (MYF5). In this study, Zn and implants differentially affected genes related to energy metabolism, satellite cell function, and TM homeostasis on days 20 and 84 postimplant. These results suggest steroidal implants increase demand for Zn immediately following implant administration to support growth and may influence insulin sensitivity in finishing cattle.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2024. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the American Society of Animal Science.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smerchek</LastName><ForeName>Dathan T</ForeName><Initials>DT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Science, Iowa State University, Ames, IA 50011, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rients</LastName><ForeName>Emma L</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0110-5985</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Science, Iowa State University, Ames, IA 50011, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McLaughlin</LastName><ForeName>Amy M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Science, Iowa State University, Ames, IA 50011, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thornton</LastName><ForeName>Kara J</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7506-5293</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal, Dairy and Veterinary Science, Utah State University, Logan, UT 84322, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hansen</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie L</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Science, Iowa State University, Ames, IA 50011, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Anim Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8003002</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0021-8812</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014131">Trace Elements</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>7733-02-0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019287">Zinc Sulfate</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004343">Drug Implants</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>RUD5Y4SV0S</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014204">Trenbolone Acetate</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002417" MajorTopicYN="N">Cattle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019587" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dietary Supplements</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014131" MajorTopicYN="Y">Trace Elements</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019287" MajorTopicYN="Y">Zinc Sulfate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004343" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Implants</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004032" MajorTopicYN="N">Diet</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000662" MajorTopicYN="N">veterinary</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000821" MajorTopicYN="N">Animal Feed</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014204" MajorTopicYN="N">Trenbolone Acetate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Steroidal implants are a commonly used growth-enhancing technology that improves the efficiency of beef production. Steroidal implants increase muscle growth via increased net protein synthesis and skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Various trace minerals (TM) are important in supporting growth and development. Zinc (Zn) is an essential TM that influences numerous enzymes, transcription factors, and is involved in nearly every signaling pathway in the body. Nutritionists routinely supplement Zn, amongst other TM, at concentrations greater than current recommendations. Previous work shows that increased Zn supplementation improves growth performance in steers given a steroidal implant. The objective of this study was to better understand the effects of steroidal implants and zinc sulfate supplementation on growth, carcass characteristics, TM status, blood metabolites, and skeletal muscle mRNA abundance. In this study, there is evidence that steroidal implant administration increases tissue Zn demand as plasma Zn decreases following implant administration when growth rates are greatest. Our results also provide preliminary data outlining the impact of zinc and steroidal implants on mRNA abundance of skeletal muscle gene expression.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2024. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the American Society of Animal Science.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cattle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">feedlot</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">implant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">zinc</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors Dathan T. Smerchek, Emma. L. Rients, Amy M. McLaughlin, Kara J. Thornton, and Stephanie L. Hansen declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38828800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11190378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skae154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">7686748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Capper, J. L., and Hayes D. J... 2012. The environmental and economic impact of removing growth-enhancing technologies from US beef production. J. Anim. Sci. 90:3527&#x2013;3537. doi: 10.2527/jas.2011-4870</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2527/jas.2011-4870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22665660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crawford, D. M., Richeson J. T., Perkins T. L., and Samuelson K. L... 2022. Feeding a high-energy finishing diet upon arrival to high-risk feedlot calves: effects on health, performance, ruminal pH, rumination, serum metabolites, and carcass traits. J. Anim. Sci. 100:skac194. doi: 10.1093/jas/skac194</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skac194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9467027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35639878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dayton, W. R., and White M. E... 2013. Mechanisms of anabolic steroid action in bovine skeletal muscle, evaluating veterinary pharmaceutical behavior in the environment. American Chemical Society. (ACS Symposium Series; vol. 1126; ). p. 1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Sousa, O. A., Cappellozza B. I., Fonseca V. G., and Cooke R. F... 2022. Insulin resistance increases as days on feed advance in feedlot Bos indicus beef cattle offered a high-concentrate finishing diet. J. Anim. Sci. 100:skac182.&#xa0;doi: 10.1093/jas/skac182</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skac182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9259595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35580854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drouillard, J. S. 2018. Current situation and future trends for beef production in the United States of America&#x2014;a review. Asian-Australas. J. Anim. Sci. 31:1007&#x2013;1016. doi: 10.5713/ajas.18.0428</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5713/ajas.18.0428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6039332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29973030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engle, T. E., and Spears J. W... 2000. Effects of dietary copper concentration and source on performance and copper status of growing and finishing steers. J. Anim. Sci. 78:2446&#x2013;2451. doi: 10.2527/2000.7892446x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2527/2000.7892446x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10985420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galyean, M., Nichols W., Streeter M., and Hutcheson J... 2023. Effects of extended days on feed on rate of change in performance and carcass characteristics of feedlot steers and heifers and Holstein steers. Appl. Anim. Sci. 39:69&#x2013;78. doi: 10.15232/aas.2022-02366</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15232/aas.2022-02366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genther-Schroeder, O., Branine M., and Hansen S... 2016. The effects of increasing supplementation of zinc-amino acid complex on growth performance, carcass characteristics, and inflammatory response of beef cattle fed ractopamine hydrochloride. J. Anim. Sci. 94:3389&#x2013;3398. doi: 10.2527/jas.2015-0209</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2527/jas.2015-0209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27695784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guiroy, P., Tedeschi L., Fox D., and Hutcheson J... 2002. The effects of implant strategy on finished body weight of beef cattle. J. Anim. Sci. 80:1791&#x2013;1800. doi: 10.2527/2002.8071791x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2527/2002.8071791x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12162646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halevy, O., Piestun Y., Allouh M. Z., Rosser B. W., Rinkevich Y., Reshef R., Rozenboim I., Wleklinski&#x2010;Lee M., and Yablonka&#x2010;Reuveni Z... 2004. Pattern of Pax7 expression during myogenesis in the posthatch chicken establishes a model for satellite cell differentiation and renewal. Dev. Dyn 231:489&#x2013;502. doi: 10.1002/dvdy.20151</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/dvdy.20151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15390217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamza, R. T., Hamed A. I., and Sallam M. T... 2012. Effect of zinc supplementation on growth Hormone Insulin growth factor axis in short Egyptian children with zinc deficiency. Ital. J. Pediatr. 38:21&#x2013;27. doi: 10.1186/1824-7288-38-21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1824-7288-38-21</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3453500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22625223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, L., Kirschke C. P., Lay Y. -A. E., Levy L. B., Lamirande D. E., and Zhang P. H... 2012. Znt7-null mice are more susceptible to diet-induced glucose intolerance and insulin resistance. J. Biol. Chem. 287:33883&#x2013;33896. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M111.309666</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M111.309666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3460483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22854958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson, B., and Beckett J... 2014. Application of growth enhancing compounds in modern beef production executive summary. Reference Paper. Champaign (IL): American Meat Science Association. p. 1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson, B. J., Halstead N., White M. E., Hathaway M. R., DiCostanzo A., and Dayton W. R... 1998. Activation state of muscle satellite cells isolated from steers implanted with a combined trenbolone acetate and estradiol implant. J. Anim. Sci. 76:2779&#x2013;2786. doi: 10.2527/1998.76112779x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2527/1998.76112779x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9856386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelishadi, R., Hashemipour M., Adeli K., Tavakoli N., Movahedian-Attar A., Shapouri J., Poursafa P., and Rouzbahani A... 2010. Effect of zinc supplementation on markers of insulin resistance, oxidative stress, and inflammation among prepubescent children with metabolic syndrome. Metab. Syndr. Relat. Disord. 8:505&#x2013;510. doi: 10.1089/met.2010.0020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/met.2010.0020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21028969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kincaid, R. 1999. Assessment of trace mineral status of ruminants: a review. In: Proceedings of the American Society of Animal Science. p 1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messersmith, E. M. 2018. The effect of copper supplementation on performance and carcass characteristics of cattle utilizing growth promoting technologies. Ames, IA:&#xa0;Iowa State University.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messersmith, E. M., and Hansen S. L... 2021a. 162 Increasing concentrations of supplemental zinc influence performance, carcass characteristics, and trace mineral status of non-implanted and implanted steers. J. Anim. Sci. 99:123&#x2013;123. doi: 10.1093/jas/skab054.204</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skab054.204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messersmith, E. M., and Hansen S. L... 2021b. Effect of zinc source and implant strategy on performance, carcass characteristics, and trace mineral concentrations in finishing feedlot steers. Transl. Anim. Sci. 5:txab218. doi: 10.1093/tas/txab218</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/tas/txab218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8665212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34909603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messersmith, E. M., Niedermayer E. K., Thornton K. J., Crawford G. I., and Hansen S. L... 2021. Zinc supplementation strategies in feedlot heifers receiving an extended-release implant or an aggressive re-implant program. J. Anim. Sci. 99:1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1093/jas/skab212</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skab212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8363036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34261132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messersmith, E. M., Smerchek D. T., and Hansen S. L... 2022. Effects of increasing supplemental zinc in beef feedlot steers administered a steroidal implant and beta agonist. Transl. Anim. Sci. 6:txac029. doi: 10.1093/tas/txac029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/tas/txac029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8974338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35382158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NASEM. 2016. Nutrient requirements of beef cattle. 8th rev. ed. Washington (DC): The National Academies Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niedermayer, E. K., Genther-Schroeder O. N., Loy D. D., and Hansen S. L... 2018. Effect of varying trace mineral supplementation of steers with or without hormone implants on growth and carcass characteristics. J. Anim. Sci. 96:1159&#x2013;1170. doi: 10.1093/jas/skx063</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skx063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6093529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29506086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nimmanon, T., Ziliotto S., Morris S., Flanagan L., and Taylor K... 2017. Phosphorylation of zinc channel ZIP7 drives MAPK, PI3K and mTOR growth and proliferation signalling. Metallomics. 9:471&#x2013;481. doi: 10.1039/c6mt00286b</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c6mt00286b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5451890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28205653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ninh, N. X., Thissen J. -P., Collette L., Gerard G., Khoi H. H., and Ketelslegers J. -M... 1996. Zinc supplementation increases growth and circulating insulin-like growth factor I (IGF-I) in growth-retarded Vietnamese children. Am. J. Clin. Nutr. 63:514&#x2013;519. doi: 10.1093/ajcn/63.4.514</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/63.4.514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8599314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishi, Y., Hatano S., Aihara K., Fujie A., and Kihara M... 1989. Transient partial growth hormone deficiency due to zinc deficiency. J. Am. Coll. Nutr. 8:93&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1080/07315724.1989.10720283</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07315724.1989.10720283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2708733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pampusch, M., Johnson B., White M., Hathaway M., Dunn J., Waylan A., and Dayton W... 2003. Time course of changes in growth factor mRNA levels in muscle of steroid-implanted and nonimplanted steers. J. Anim. Sci. 81:2733&#x2013;2740. doi: 10.2527/2003.81112733x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2527/2003.81112733x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14601876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parr, S. L., Brown T. R., Ribeiro F. R. B., Chung K. Y., Hutcheson J. P., Blackwell B. R., Smith P. N., and Johnson B. J... 2014. Biological responses of beef steers to steroidal implants and zilpaterol hydrochloride. J. Anim. Sci. 92:3348&#x2013;3363. doi: 10.2527/jas.2013-7221</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2527/jas.2013-7221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24987078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paskavitz, A. L., Quintana J., Cangussu D., Tavera-Monta&#xf1;ez C., Xiao Y., Ortiz-Miranda S., Navea J. G., and Padilla-Benavides T... 2018. Differential expression of zinc transporters accompanies the differentiation of C2C12 myoblasts. J. Trace Elem. Med Biol. 49:27&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1016/j.jtemb.2018.04.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtemb.2018.04.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6082398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29895369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen, M. C., and Shulman G. I... 2018. Mechanisms of insulin action and insulin resistance. Physiol. Rev. 98:2133&#x2013;2223. doi: 10.1152/physrev.00063.2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00063.2017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6170977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30067154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pogge, D., and Hansen S... 2013. Supplemental vitamin C improves marbling in feedlot cattle consuming high sulfur diets. J. Anim. Sci. 91:4303&#x2013;4314. doi: 10.2527/jas.2012-5638</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2527/jas.2012-5638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23851995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preston, R. L. 1999. Hormone containing growth promoting implants in farmed livestock. Adv. Drug Deliv. Rev. 38:123&#x2013;138. doi: 10.1016/s0169-409x(99)00012-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0169-409x(99)00012-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10837752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranasinghe, P., Pigera S., Galappatthy P., Katulanda P., and Constantine G. R... 2015. Zinc and diabetes mellitus: understanding molecular mechanisms and clinical implications. Daru. 23:1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1186/s40199-015-0127-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40199-015-0127-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4573932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26381880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reichhardt, C. C., Messersmith E. M., Brady T. J., Motsinger L. A., Briggs R. K., Bowman B. R., Hansen S. L., and Thornton K. J... 2021a. Anabolic implants varying in hormone type and concentration influence performance, feeding behavior, carcass characteristics, plasma trace mineral concentrations, and liver trace mineral concentrations of angus sired steers. Animals (Basel). 11:1964. doi: 10.3390/ani11071964</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani11071964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8300420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34209116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reichhardt, C. C., Okamoto L. L., Motsinger L. A., Griffin B. P., Murdoch G. K., and Thornton K. J... 2021b. The impact of polyamine precursors, polyamines, and steroid hormones on temporal messenger RNA abundance in bovine satellite cells induced to differentiate. Animals (Basel). 11:764. doi: 10.3390/ani11030764</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani11030764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8001141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33801966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reichhardt, C. C., Cuthbert J. M., Motsinger L. A., Brady T. J., Briggs R. K., Thomas A. J., and Thornton K. J... 2022. Anabolic implants alter abundance of mRNA involved in muscle growth, metabolism, and inflammation in the longissimus of Angus steers in the feedlot. Domest. Anim. Endocrinol. 82:106773. doi: 10.1016/j.domaniend.2022.106773</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.domaniend.2022.106773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36375404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, X., Lamb G. D., and Murphy R. M... 2019. Distribution and activation of matrix metalloproteinase-2 in skeletal muscle fibers. Am. J. Physiol. Cell Physiol. 317:C613&#x2013;C625. doi: 10.1152/ajpcell.00113.2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.00113.2019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6766614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31241984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, Z. K., Thompson A. J., Hutcheson J. P., Nichols W. T., and Johnson B. J... 2018. Evaluation of coated steroidal implants containing trenbolone acetate and estradiol-17&#x3b2; on live performance, carcass traits, and sera metabolites in finishing steers. J. Anim. Sci. 96:1704&#x2013;1723. doi: 10.1093/jas/sky095</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/sky095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6140838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29534183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzuki, T., Ishihara K., Migaki H., Matsuura W., Kohda A., Okumura K., Nagao M., Yamaguchi-Iwai Y., and Kambe T... 2005. Zinc transporters, ZnT5 and ZnT7, are required for the activation of alkaline phosphatases, zinc-requiring enzymes that are glycosylphosphatidylinositol-anchored to the cytoplasmic membrane. J. Biol. Chem. 280:637&#x2013;643. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M411247200</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M411247200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15525635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace, T., and Matthews D... 2002. The assessment of insulin resistance in man. Diabet. Med. 19:527&#x2013;534. doi: 10.1046/j.1464-5491.2002.00745.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1464-5491.2002.00745.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12099954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Y., Lu H., Yang H., Li C., Sang Q., Liu X., Liu Y., Wang Y., and Sun Z... 2016. Zinc stimulates glucose consumption by modulating the insulin signaling pathway in L6 myotubes: essential roles of Akt&#x2013;GLUT4, GSK3&#x3b2; and mTOR&#x2013;S6K1. J. Nutr. Biochem. 34:126&#x2013;135. doi: 10.1016/j.jnutbio.2016.05.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnutbio.2016.05.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27295130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin, H., Price F., and Rudnicki M. A... 2013. Satellite cells and the muscle stem cell niche. Physiol. Rev. 93:23&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1152/physrev.00043.2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00043.2011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4073943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23303905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x17b;ochowska-Kujawska, J. 2016. Effects of fibre type and structure of longissimus lumborum (Ll), biceps femoris (Bf) and semimembranosus (Sm) deer muscles salting with different NaCl addition on proteolysis index and texture of dry-cured meats. Meat Sci. 121:390&#x2013;396. doi: 10.1016/j.meatsci.2016.07.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.meatsci.2016.07.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27442183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zorzano, A., Palacin M., and Guma A... 2005. Mechanisms regulating GLUT4 glucose transporter expression and glucose transport in skeletal muscle. Acta Physiol. Scand. 183:43&#x2013;58. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-201X.2004.01380.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-201X.2004.01380.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15654919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>