<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31552263</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-861X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>6</Volume><PubDate><Year>2019</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Maximizing Post-exercise Anabolism: The Case for Relative Protein Intakes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>147</StartPage><MedlinePgn>147</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">147</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fnut.2019.00147</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Maximizing the post-exercise increase in muscle protein synthesis, especially of the contractile myofibrillar protein fraction, is essential to facilitate effective muscle remodeling, and enhance hypertrophic gains with resistance training. MPS is the primary regulated variable influencing muscle net balance with dietary amino acid ingestion representing the single most important nutritional variable enhancing post-exercise rates of muscle protein synthesis. Dose-response studies in average (i.e., ~80 kg) males have reported an absolute 20 g dose of high quality, rapidly digested protein maximizes mixed, and myofibrillar protein synthetic rates. However, it is unclear if these absolute protein intakes can be viewed in a "one size fits all" solution. Re-analysis of published literature in young adults suggests a relative single meal intake of ~0.31 g/kg of rapidly digested, high quality protein (i.e., whey) should be considered as a nutritional guideline for individuals of average body composition aiming to maximize post-exercise myofibrillar protein synthesis while minimizing irreversible amino acid oxidative catabolism that occurs with excessive intakes of this macronutrient. This muscle-specific bolus intake is lower than that reported to maximize whole body anabolism (i.e., &#x2265;0.5 g/kg). Review of the available literature suggests that potential confounders such as the co-ingestion of carbohydrate, sex, and amount of active muscle mass do not represent significant barriers to the translation of this objectively determined relative protein intake. Additional research is warranted to elucidate the effective dose for proteins with suboptimal amino acid compositions (e.g., plant-based), and/or slower digestion rates as well as whether recommendations are appreciably affected by other physiological conditions such endurance exercise, high habitual daily protein ingestion, aging, obesity, and/or periods of chronic negative energy balance.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moore</LastName><ForeName>Daniel R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Kinesiology and Physical Education, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101642264</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-861X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dietary protein</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">essential amino acids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lean body mass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle protein synthesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resistance training</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31552263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6746967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2019.00147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Tipton KD, Aarsland A, Wolf SE, Wolfe RR. Mixed muscle protein synthesis and breakdown after resistance exercise in humans. Am J Physiol. (1997) 273(1 Pt 1):E99&#x2013;107. 10.1152/ajpendo.1997.273.1.E99</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.1997.273.1.E99</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biolo G, Maggi SP, Williams BD, Tipton KD, Wolfe RR. Increased rates of muscle protein turnover and amino acid transport after resistance exercise in humans. Am J Physiol. (1995) 268(3 Pt 1):E514&#x2013;20. 10.1152/ajpendo.1995.268.3.E514</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.1995.268.3.E514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7900797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biolo G, Tipton KD, Klein S, Wolfe RR. An abundant supply of amino acids enhances the metabolic effect of exercise on muscle protein. Am J Physiol. (1997) 273(1 Pt 1):E122&#x2013;9. 10.1152/ajpendo.1997.273.1.E122</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.1997.273.1.E122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Atherton P, Smith K, Rennie MJ. Human muscle protein synthesis and breakdown during and after exercise. J Appl Physiol. (2009) 106:2026&#x2013;39. 10.1152/japplphysiol.91481.2008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.91481.2008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19164770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rennie MJ, Wackerhage H, Spangenburg EE, Booth FW. Control of the size of the human muscle mass. Annu Rev Physiol. (2004) 66:799&#x2013;828. 10.1146/annurev.physiol.66.052102.134444</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.physiol.66.052102.134444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14977422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen BB, Phillips SM. Contractile and nutritional regulation of human muscle growth. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. (2003) 31:127&#x2013;31 10.1097/00003677-200307000-00005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00003677-200307000-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12882478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartman JW, Tang JE, Wilkinson SB, Tarnopolsky MA, Lawrence RL, Fullerton AV, et al. Consumption of fat-free fluid milk after resistance exercise promotes greater lean mass accretion than does consumption of soy or carbohydrate in young, novice, male weightlifters. Am J Clin Nutr. (2007) 86:373&#x2013;81. 10.1093/ajcn/86.2.373</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/86.2.373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17684208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson SB, Tarnopolsky MA, Macdonald MJ, Macdonald JR, Armstrong D, Phillips SM. Consumption of fluid skim milk promotes greater muscle protein accretion after resistance exercise than does consumption of an isonitrogenous and isoenergetic soy-protein beverage. Am J Clin Nutr. (2007) 85:1031&#x2013;40. 10.1093/ajcn/85.4.1031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/85.4.1031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17413102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Josse AR, Tang JE, Tarnopolsky MA, Phillips SM. Body composition and strength changes in women with milk and resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2010) 42:1122&#x2013;30. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181c854f6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181c854f6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19997019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, West DW, Moore DR, Atherton PJ, Staples AW, Prior T, et al. Enhanced amino acid sensitivity of myofibrillar protein synthesis persists for up to 24 h after resistance exercise in young men. J Nutr. (2011) 141:568&#x2013;73. 10.3945/jn.110.135038</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.110.135038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21289204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, West DW, Staples AW, Atherton PJ, Baker JM, Moore DR, et al. Low-load high volume resistance exercise stimulates muscle protein synthesis more than high-load low volume resistance exercise in young men. PLoS ONE. (2010) 5:e12033. 10.1371/journal.pone.0012033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0012033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2918506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20711498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Tang JE, Burd NA, Rerecich T, Tarnopolsky MA, Phillips SM. Differential stimulation of myofibrillar and sarcoplasmic protein synthesis with protein ingestion at rest and after resistance exercise. J Physiol. (2009) 587(Pt 4):897&#x2013;904. 10.1113/jphysiol.2008.164087</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2008.164087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2669978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19124543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damas F, Phillips SM, Libardi CA, Vechin FC, Lixandrao ME, Jannig PR, et al. Resistance training-induced changes in integrated myofibrillar protein synthesis are related to hypertrophy only after attenuation of muscle damage. J Physiol. (2016) 594:5209&#x2013;22. 10.1113/JP272472</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP272472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5023708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27219125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen BB, Tipton KD, Miller SL, Wolf SE, Wolfe RR. An oral essential amino acid-carbohydrate supplement enhances muscle protein anabolism after resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. (2000) 88:386&#x2013;92 10.1152/jappl.2000.88.2.386</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.2000.88.2.386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10658002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton KD, Ferrando AA, Phillips SM, Doyle D, Jr, Wolfe RR. Postexercise net protein synthesis in human muscle from orally administered amino acids. Am J Physiol. (1999) 276(4 Pt 1):E628&#x2013;34. 10.1152/ajpendo.1999.276.4.E628</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.1999.276.4.E628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10198297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton KD, Borsheim E, Wolf SE, Sanford AP, Wolfe RR. Acute response of net muscle protein balance reflects 24-h balance after exercise and amino acid ingestion. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. (2003) 284:E76&#x2013;89. 10.1152/ajpendo.00234.2002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00234.2002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12388164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borsheim E, Tipton KD, Wolf SE, Wolfe RR. Essential amino acids and muscle protein recovery from resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. (2002) 283:E648&#x2013;57. 10.1152/ajpendo.00466.2001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00466.2001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12217881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller SL, Tipton KD, Chinkes DL, Wolf SE, Wolfe RR. Independent and combined effects of amino acids and glucose after resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2003) 35:449&#x2013;55. 10.1249/01.MSS.0000053910.63105.45</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000053910.63105.45</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12618575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Robinson MJ, Fry JL, Tang JE, Glover EI, Wilkinson SB, et al. Ingested protein dose response of muscle and albumin protein synthesis after resistance exercise in young men. Am J Clin Nutr. (2009) 89:161&#x2013;8. 10.3945/ajcn.2008.26401</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.2008.26401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19056590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang JE, Manolakos JJ, Kujbida GW, Lysecki PJ, Moore DR, Phillips SM. Minimal whey protein with carbohydrate stimulates muscle protein synthesis following resistance exercise in trained young men. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. (2007) 32:1132&#x2013;8. 10.1139/H07-076</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/H07-076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18059587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond MJ, Dreyer HC, Fry CS, Glynn EL, Rasmussen BB. Nutritional and contractile regulation of human skeletal muscle protein synthesis and mTORC1 signaling. J Appl Physiol. (2009) 106:1374&#x2013;84. 10.1152/japplphysiol.91397.2008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.91397.2008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2698645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19150856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deldicque L, Sanchez Canedo C, Horman S, De Potter I, Bertrand L, Hue L, et al. Antagonistic effects of leucine and glutamine on the mTOR pathway in myogenic C2C12 cells. Amino Acids. (2008) 35:147&#x2013;55. 10.1007/s00726-007-0607-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-007-0607-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17978888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witard OC, Jackman SR, Breen L, Smith K, Selby A, Tipton KD. Myofibrillar muscle protein synthesis rates subsequent to a meal in response to increasing doses of whey protein at rest and after resistance exercise. Am J Clin Nutr. (2014) 99:86&#x2013;95. 10.3945/ajcn.112.055517</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.112.055517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24257722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke LM, Slater G, Broad EM, Haukka J, Modulon S, Hopkins WG. Eating patterns and meal frequency of elite Australian athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. (2003) 13:521&#x2013;38. 10.1123/ijsnem.13.4.521</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.13.4.521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14967874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM. A brief review of critical processes in exercise-induced muscular hypertrophy. Sports Med. (2014) 44(Suppl 1):S71&#x2013;7. 10.1007/s40279-014-0152-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0152-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24791918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pencharz PB, Elango R, Ball RO. An approach to defining the upper safe limits of amino acid intake. J Nutr. (2008) 138:1996s&#x2212;2002s. 10.1093/jn/138.10.1996S</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jn/138.10.1996S</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18806114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith GI, Patterson BW, Mittendorfer B. Human muscle protein turnover&#x2013;why is it so variable? J Appl Physiol. (2011) 110:480&#x2013;91. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00125.2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00125.2010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3043790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21109595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Areta JL, Burke LM, Ross ML, Camera DM, West DW, Broad EM, et al. Timing and distribution of protein ingestion during prolonged recovery from resistance exercise alters myofibrillar protein synthesis. J Physiol. (2013) 591:2319&#x2013;31. 10.1113/jphysiol.2012.244897</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2012.244897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3650697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23459753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Holwerda AM, Selby KC, West DW, Staples AW, Cain NE, et al. Resistance exercise volume affects myofibrillar protein synthesis and anabolic signalling molecule phosphorylation in young men. J Physiol. (2010) 588(Pt 16):3119&#x2013;30. 10.1113/jphysiol.2010.192856</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2010.192856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2956949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20581041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchward-Venne TA, Burd NA, Mitchell CJ, West DW, Philp A, Marcotte GR, et al. Supplementation of a suboptimal protein dose with leucine or essential amino acids: effects on myofibrillar protein synthesis at rest and following resistance exercise in men. J Physiol. (2012) 590:2751&#x2013;65. 10.1113/jphysiol.2012.228833</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2012.228833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3424729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22451437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macnaughton LS, Wardle SL, Witard OC, McGlory C, Hamilton DL, Jeromson S, et al. The response of muscle protein synthesis following whole-body resistance exercise is greater following 40 g than 20 g of ingested whey protein. Physiol Rep. (2016) 4:e12893. 10.14814/phy2.12893</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.12893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4985555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27511985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGlory C, Wardle SL, Macnaughton LS, Witard OC, Scott F, Dick J, et al. Fish oil supplementation suppresses resistance exercise and feeding-induced increases in anabolic signaling without affecting myofibrillar protein synthesis in young men. Physiol Rep. (2016) 4:e12715. 10.14814/phy2.12715</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.12715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4814892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27009278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKendry J, Perez-Lopez A, McLeod M, Luo D, Dent JR, Smeuninx B, et al. Short inter-set rest blunts resistance exercise-induced increases in myofibrillar protein synthesis and intracellular signalling in young males. Exp Physiol. (2016) 101:866&#x2013;82. 10.1113/EP085647</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP085647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27126459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reidy PT, Walker DK, Dickinson JM, Gundermann DM, Drummond MJ, Timmerman KL, et al. Soy-dairy protein blend and whey protein ingestion after resistance exercise increases amino acid transport and transporter expression in human skeletal muscle. J Appl Physiol. (2014) 116:1353&#x2013;64. 10.1152/japplphysiol.01093.2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01093.2013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4044402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24699854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reitelseder S, Agergaard J, Doessing S, Helmark IC, Lund P, Kristensen NB, et al. Whey and casein labeled with L-[1&#x2013;13C]leucine and muscle protein synthesis: effect of resistance exercise and protein ingestion. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. (2011) 300:E231&#x2013;42. 10.1152/ajpendo.00513.2010Percent-change from fasted (i.e., 0 g protein ingestion) of mixed muscle protein synthesis (A) and whole body leucine oxidation (B) after resistance</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00513.2010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21045172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DW, Kujbida GW, Moore DR, Atherton P, Burd NA, Padzik JP, et al. Resistance exercise-induced increases in putative anabolic hormones do not enhance muscle protein synthesis or intracellular signalling in young men. J Physiol. (2009) 587(Pt 21):5239&#x2013;47. 10.1113/jphysiol.2009.177220</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2009.177220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2790261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19736298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DW, Burd NA, Coffey VG, Baker SK, Burke LM, Hawley JA, et al. Rapid aminoacidemia enhances myofibrillar protein synthesis and anabolic intramuscular signaling responses after resistance exercise. Am J Clin Nutr. (2011) 94:795&#x2013;803. 10.3945/ajcn.111.013722</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.111.013722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21795443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DW, Burd NA, Churchward-Venne TA, Camera DM, Mitchell CJ, Baker SK, et al. Sex-based comparisons of myofibrillar protein synthesis after resistance exercise in the fed state. J Appl Physiol. (2012) 112:1805&#x2013;13. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00170.2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00170.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22383503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Churchward-Venne TA, Witard O, Breen L, Burd NA, Tipton KD, et al. Protein ingestion to stimulate myofibrillar protein synthesis requires greater relative protein intakes in healthy older versus younger men. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. (2015) 70:57&#x2013;62. 10.1093/gerona/glu103</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glu103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25056502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher D, Visser M, De Meersman RE, Sepulveda D, Baumgartner RN, Pierson RN, et al. Appendicular skeletal muscle mass: effects of age, gender, and ethnicity. J Appl Physiol. (1997) 83:229&#x2013;39. 10.1152/jappl.1997.83.1.229</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1997.83.1.229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9216968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aragon AA, Schoenfeld BJ. Nutrient timing revisited: is there a post-exercise anabolic window? J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2013) 10:5. 10.1186/1550-2783-10-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-10-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3577439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23360586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuthbertson D, Smith K, Babraj J, Leese G, Waddell T, Atherton P, et al. Anabolic signaling deficits underlie amino acid resistance of wasting, aging muscle. Faseb J. (2005) 19:422&#x2013;4. 10.1096/fj.04-2640fje</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.04-2640fje</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15596483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kriengsinyos W, Wykes LJ, Goonewardene LA, Ball RO, Pencharz PB. Phase of menstrual cycle affects lysine requirement in healthy women. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. (2004) 287:E489&#x2013;96. 10.1152/ajpendo.00262.2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00262.2003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15308475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Atkinson SA, Tarnopolsky MA, MacDougall JD. Gender differences in leucine kinetics and nitrogen balance in endurance athletes. J Appl Physiol. (1993) 75:2134&#x2013;41. 10.1152/jappl.1993.75.5.2134</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1993.75.5.2134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8307870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller BF, Hansen M, Olesen JL, Flyvbjerg A, Schwarz P, Babraj JA, et al. No effect of menstrual cycle on myofibrillar and connective tissue protein synthesis in contracting skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. (2006) 290:E163&#x2013;8. 10.1152/ajpendo.00300.2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00300.2005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16131512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita S, Rasmussen BB, Bell JA, Cadenas JG, Volpi E. Basal muscle intracellular amino acid kinetics in women and men. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. (2007) 292:E77&#x2013;83. 10.1152/ajpendo.00173.2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00173.2006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2804963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16896165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahn LA, Barrett EJ, Genco ML, Wei L, Spraggins TA, Fryburg DA. Tissue composition affects measures of postabsorptive human skeletal muscle metabolism: comparison across genders. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. (1999) 84:1007&#x2013;10. 10.1210/jc.84.3.1007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.84.3.1007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10084587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreyer HC, Fujita S, Glynn EL, Drummond MJ, Volpi E, Rasmussen BB. Resistance exercise increases leg muscle protein synthesis and mTOR signalling independent of sex. Acta Physiol. (2010) 199:71&#x2013;81. 10.1111/j.1748-1716.2010.02074.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1748-1716.2010.02074.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2881180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20070283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Areta JL, Burke LM, Camera DM, West DW, Crawshay S, Moore DR, et al. Reduced resting skeletal muscle protein synthesis is rescued by resistance exercise and protein ingestion following short-term energy deficit. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. (2014) 306:E989&#x2013;97. 10.1152/ajpendo.00590.2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00590.2013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24595305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alghannam AF, Gonzalez JT, Betts JA. Restoration of muscle glycogen and functional capacity: role of post-exercise carbohydrate and protein co-ingestion. Nutrients. (2018) 10:E253. 10.3390/nu10020253</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10020253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5852829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29473893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke LM, Hawley JA, Wong SH, Jeukendrup AE. Carbohydrates for training and competition. J Sports Sci. (2011) 29(Suppl 1):S17&#x2013;27. 10.1080/02640414.2011.585473</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2011.585473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21660838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glynn EL, Fry CS, Drummond MJ, Dreyer HC, Dhanani S, Volpi E, et al. Muscle protein breakdown has a minor role in the protein anabolic response to essential amino acid and carbohydrate intake following resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. (2010) 299:R533&#x2013;40. 10.1152/ajpregu.00077.2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00077.2010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2928613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20519362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borsheim E, Cree MG, Tipton KD, Elliott TA, Aarsland A, Wolfe RR. Effect of carbohydrate intake on net muscle protein synthesis during recovery from resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. (2004) 96:674&#x2013;8. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00333.2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00333.2003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14594866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staples AW, Burd NA, West DW, Currie KD, Atherton PJ, Moore DR, et al. Carbohydrate does not augment exercise-induced protein accretion versus protein alone. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2011) 43:1154&#x2013;61. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31820751cbPercent-change from fasted (i.e., 0 g protein ingestion) of mixed muscle protein synthesis (A) and whole body leucine oxidation (B) after resistance</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31820751cb</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21131864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman R, Beelen M, Stellingwerff T, Pennings B, Saris WH, Kies AK, et al. Coingestion of carbohydrate with protein does not further augment postexercise muscle protein synthesis. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. (2007) 293:E833&#x2013;42. 10.1152/ajpendo.00135.2007Percent-change from fasted (i.e., 0 g protein ingestion) of mixed muscle protein synthesis (A) and whole body leucine oxidation (B) after resistance</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00135.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17609259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West DW, Cotie LM, Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, MacDonald MJ, Phillips SM. Resistance exercise order does not determine postexercise delivery of testosterone, growth hormone, and IGF-1 to skeletal muscle. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. (2013) 38:220&#x2013;6. 10.1139/apnm-2012-0397Percent-change from fasted (i.e., 0 g protein ingestion) of mixed muscle protein synthesis (A) and whole body leucine oxidation (B) after resistance</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2012-0397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23438236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deutz NE, Wolfe RR. Is there a maximal anabolic response to protein intake with a meal? Clin Nutr. (2013) 32:309&#x2013;13. 10.1016/j.clnu.2012.11.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2012.11.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3595342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23260197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim IY, Deutz NEP, Wolfe RR. Update on maximal anabolic response to dietary protein. Clin Nutr. (2018) 37:411&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.clnu.2017.05.029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2017.05.029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9218947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28807333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim IY, Schutzler S, Schrader A, Spencer HJ, Azhar G, Ferrando AA, et al. The anabolic response to a meal containing different amounts of protein is not limited by the maximal stimulation of protein synthesis in healthy young adults. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. (2016) 310:E73&#x2013;80. 10.1152/ajpendo.00365.2015Percent-change from fasted (i.e., 0 g protein ingestion) of mixed muscle protein synthesis (A) and whole body leucine oxidation (B) after resistance</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00365.2015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4675798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26530155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim IY, Schutzler S, Schrader A, Spencer H, Kortebein P, Deutz NE, et al. Quantity of dietary protein intake, but not pattern of intake, affects net protein balance primarily through differences in protein synthesis in older adults. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. (2015) 308:E21&#x2013;8. 10.1152/ajpendo.00382.2014Percent-change from fasted (i.e., 0 g protein ingestion) of mixed muscle protein synthesis (A) and whole body leucine oxidation (B) after resistance</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00382.2014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4280213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25352437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Aragon AA. How much protein can the body use in a single meal for muscle-building? Implications for daily protein distribution. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2018) 15:10. 10.1186/s12970-018-0215-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-018-0215-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5828430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29497353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malowany JM, West DWD, Williamson E, Volterman KA, Abou Sawan S, Mazzulla M, et al. Protein to maximize whole-body anabolism in resistance-trained females after exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2019) 51:798&#x2013;804. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000001832</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30395050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzulla M, Volterman KA, Packer JE, Wooding DJ, Brooks JC, Kato H, et al. Whole-body net protein balance plateaus in response to increasing protein intakes during post-exercise recovery in adults and adolescents. Nutr Metab. (2018) 15:62. 10.1186/s12986-018-0301-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12986-018-0301-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6154919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30258470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almoosawi S, Winter J, Prynne CJ, Hardy R, Stephen AM. Daily profiles of energy and nutrient intakes: are eating profiles changing over time? Eur J Clin Nutr. (2012) 66:678&#x2013;86. 10.1038/ejcn.2011.210</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ejcn.2011.210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3389619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22190135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorissen SH, Remond D, van Loon LJ. The muscle protein synthetic response to food ingestion. Meat Sci. (2015) 109:96&#x2013;100. 10.1016/j.meatsci.2015.05.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.meatsci.2015.05.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26021783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Beals JW, Martinez IG, Salvador AF, Skinner SK. Food-first approach to enhance the regulation of post-exercise skeletal muscle protein synthesis and remodeling. Sports Med. (2019) 49(Suppl 1):59&#x2013;68. 10.1007/s40279-018-1009-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-018-1009-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6445816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30671904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, McKenna CF, Salvador AF, Paulussen KJM, Moore DR. Dietary protein quantity, quality, and exercise are key to healthy living: a muscle-centric perspective across the lifespan. Front Nutr. (2019) 6:83. 10.3389/fnut.2019.00083</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2019.00083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6563776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31245378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coffey VG, Moore DR, Burd NA, Rerecich T, Stellingwerff T, Garnham AP, et al. Nutrient provision increases signalling and protein synthesis in human skeletal muscle after repeated sprints. Eur J Appl Physiol. (2011) 111:1473&#x2013;83. 10.1007/s00421-010-1768-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-010-1768-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21165642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breen L, Philp A, Witard OC, Jackman SR, Selby A, Smith K, et al. The influence of carbohydrate-protein co-ingestion following endurance exercise on myofibrillar and mitochondrial protein synthesis. J Physiol. (2011) 589(Pt 16):4011&#x2013;25. 10.1113/jphysiol.2011.211888</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2011.211888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3179999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21746787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camera DM, West DW, Phillips SM, Rerecich T, Stellingwerff T, Hawley JA, et al. Protein ingestion increases myofibrillar protein synthesis after concurrent exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2015) 47:82&#x2013;91. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000000390</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24870574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchward-Venne TA, Pinckaers PJM, Smeets JSJ, Peeters WM, Zorenc AH, Schierbeek H, et al. Myofibrillar and mitochondrial protein synthesis rates do not differ in young men following the ingestion of carbohydrate with milk protein, whey, or micellar casein after concurrent resistance- and endurance-type exercise. J Nutr. (2019) 149:198&#x2013;209. 10.1093/jn/nxy244Percent-change from fasted (i.e., 0 g protein ingestion) of mixed muscle protein synthesis (A) and whole body leucine oxidation (B) after resistance</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jn/nxy244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6561606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30698725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy BD, Fowles JR, Hill R, Tarnopolsky MA. Macronutrient intake and whole body protein metabolism following resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2000) 32:1412&#x2013;8. 10.1097/00005768-200008000-00009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200008000-00009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10949007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzulla M, Parel JT, Beals JW, Van VS, Abou Sawan S, West DWD, et al. Endurance exercise attenuates postprandial whole-body leucine balance in trained men. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2017) 49:2585&#x2013;92. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000001394</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28767524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato H, Suzuki K, Bannai M, Moore DR. Branched-chain amino acids are the primary limiting amino acids in the diets of endurance-trained men after a bout of prolonged exercise. J Nutr. (2018) 148:925&#x2013;31. 10.1093/jn/nxy048</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jn/nxy048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29746639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato H, Suzuki K, Bannai M, Moore DR. Protein requirements are elevated in endurance athletes after exercise as determined by the indicator amino acid oxidation method. PLoS ONE. (2016) 11:e0157406. 10.1371/journal.pone.0157406</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0157406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4913918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27322029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witard OC, Turner JE, Jackman SR, Kies AK, Jeukendrup AE, Bosch JA, et al. High dietary protein restores overreaching induced impairments in leukocyte trafficking and reduces the incidence of upper respiratory tract infection in elite cyclists. Brain Behav Immun. (2014) 39:211&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.bbi.2013.10.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2013.10.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24120932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson E, Kato H, Volterman KA, Suzuki K, Moore DR. The effect of dietary protein on protein metabolism and performance in endurance-trained males. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2019) 51:352&#x2013;60. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000001791</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000001791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30252774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Selby A, Rankin D, Patel R, Atherton P, Hildebrandt W, et al. Age-related differences in the dose-response relationship of muscle protein synthesis to resistance exercise in young and old men. J Physiol. (2009) 587:211&#x2013;7. 10.1113/jphysiol.2008.164483</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2008.164483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2670034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19001042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balagopal P, Schimke JC, Ades P, Adey D, Nair KS. Age effect on transcript levels and synthesis rate of muscle MHC and response to resistance exercise. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. (2001) 280:E203&#x2013;8. 10.1152/ajpendo.2001.280.2.E203</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.2001.280.2.E203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11158921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth SM, Ivey FM, Martel GF, Lemmer JT, Hurlbut DE, Siegel EL, et al. Muscle size responses to strength training in young and older men and women. J Am Geriatr Soc. (2001) 49:1428&#x2013;33. 10.1046/j.1532-5415.2001.4911233.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1532-5415.2001.4911233.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11890579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drummond MJ, Dreyer HC, Pennings B, Fry CS, Dhanani S, Dillon EL, et al. Skeletal muscle protein anabolic response to resistance exercise and essential amino acids is delayed with aging. J Appl Physiol. (2008) 104:1452&#x2013;61. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00021.2008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00021.2008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2715298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18323467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Breen L, Burd NA, Hector AJ, Churchward-Venne TA, Josse AR, et al. Resistance exercise enhances myofibrillar protein synthesis with graded intakes of whey protein in older men. Br J Nutr. (2012) 108:1780&#x2013;8. 10.1017/S0007114511007422</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0007114511007422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22313809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchward-Venne TA, Holwerda AM, Phillips SM, van Loon LJ. What is the optimal amount of protein to support post-exercise skeletal muscle reconditioning in the older adult? Sports Med. (2016) 46:1205&#x2013;12. 10.1007/s40279-016-0504-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0504-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26894275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holwerda AM, Paulussen KJM, Overkamp M, Goessens JPB, Kramer IF, Wodzig W, et al. Dose-dependent increases in whole-body net protein balance and dietary protein-derived amino acid incorporation into myofibrillar protein during recovery from resistance exercise in older men. J Nutr. (2019) 149:221&#x2013;30. 10.1093/jn/nxy263</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jn/nxy263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6374151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30722014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Wall BT, van Loon LJ. The curious case of anabolic resistance: old wives' tales or new fables? J Appl Physiol. (2012) 112:1233&#x2013;5. 10.1152/japplphysiol.01343.2011Percent-change from fasted (i.e., 0 g protein ingestion) of mixed muscle protein synthesis (A) and whole body leucine oxidation (B) after resistance</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.01343.2011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22134695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR Keeping older muscle &#x201c;young&#x201d; through dietary protein and physical activity. Adv Nutr. (2014) 5:599s&#x2212;607s. 10.3945/an.113.005405Percent-change from fasted (i.e., 0 g protein ingestion) of mixed muscle protein synthesis (A) and whole body leucine oxidation (B) after resistance</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/an.113.005405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4188243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25469405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchward-Venne TA, Breen L, Di Donato DM, Hector AJ, Mitchell CJ, Moore DR, et al. Leucine supplementation of a low-protein mixed macronutrient beverage enhances myofibrillar protein synthesis in young men: a double-blind, randomized trial. Am J Clin Nutr. (2014) 99:276&#x2013;86. 10.3945/ajcn.113.068775</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.113.068775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24284442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang JE, Moore DR, Kujbida GW, Tarnopolsky MA, Phillips SM. Ingestion of whey hydrolysate, casein, or soy protein isolate: effects on mixed muscle protein synthesis at rest and following resistance exercise in young men. J Appl Physiol. (2009) 107:987&#x2013;92. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00076.2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00076.2009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19589961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan AH, D'Souza RF, Beals JW, Zeng N, Prodhan U, Fanning AC, et al. The degree of aminoacidemia after dairy protein ingestion does not modulate the postexercise anabolic response in young men: a randomized controlled trial. J Nutr. (2019). 10.1093/jn/nxz099. [Epub ahead of print].Percent-change from fasted (i.e., 0 g protein ingestion) of mixed muscle protein synthesis (A) and whole body leucine oxidation (B) after resistance</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jn/nxz099.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7443755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31152658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reidy PT, Walker DK, Dickinson JM, Gundermann DM, Drummond MJ, Timmerman KL, et al. Protein blend ingestion following resistance exercise promotes human muscle protein synthesis. J Nutr. (2013) 143:410&#x2013;6. 10.3945/jn.112.168021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.112.168021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3738242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23343671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke LM, Winter JA, Cameron-Smith D, Enslen M, Farnfield M, Decombaz J. Effect of intake of different dietary protein sources on plasma amino acid profiles at rest and after exercise. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. (2012) 22:452&#x2013;62. 10.1123/ijsnem.22.6.452</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.22.6.452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22807528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burd NA, Gorissen SH, van Vliet S, Snijders T, van Loon LJ. Differences in postprandial protein handling after beef compared with milk ingestion during postexercise recovery: a randomized controlled trial. Am J Clin Nutr. (2015) 102:828&#x2013;36. 10.3945/ajcn.114.103184</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.114.103184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26354539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliot TA, Cree MG, Sanford AP, Wolfe RR, Tipton KD. Milk ingestion stimulates net muscle protein synthesis following resistance exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2006) 38:667&#x2013;74. 10.1249/01.mss.0000210190.64458.25</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000210190.64458.25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16679981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abou Sawan S, van Vliet S, Parel JT, Beals JW, Mazzulla M, West DWD, et al. Translocation and protein complex co-localization of mTOR is associated with postprandial myofibrillar protein synthesis at rest and after endurance exercise. Physiol Rep. (2018) 6. 10.14814/phy2.13628</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14814/phy2.13628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5840389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29512299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Vliet S, Shy EL, Abou Sawan S, Beals JW, West DW, Skinner SK, et al. Consumption of whole eggs promotes greater stimulation of postexercise muscle protein synthesis than consumption of isonitrogenous amounts of egg whites in young men. Am J Clin Nutr. (2017) 106:1401&#x2013;12. 10.3945/ajcn.117.159855</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.117.159855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28978542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DT, Erdman KA, Burke LM. American college of sports medicine joint position statement. nutrition and athletic performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2016) 48:543&#x2013;68. 10.1249/MSS.0000000000000852</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26891166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM. Protein requirements and supplementation in strength sports. Nutrition. (2004) 20:689&#x2013;95. 10.1016/j.nut.2004.04.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2004.04.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15212752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Millward DJ. Metabolic demands for amino acids and the human dietary requirement: millward and rRvers (1988) revisited. J Nutr. (1998) 128(12 Suppl):2563s&#x2212;76s. 10.1093/jn/128.12.2563S</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jn/128.12.2563S</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9868206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morens C, Gaudichon C, Fromentin G, Marsset-Baglieri A, Bensaid A, Larue-Achagiotis C, et al. Daily delivery of dietary nitrogen to the periphery is stable in rats adapted to increased protein intake. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. (2001) 281:E826&#x2013;36. 10.1152/ajpendo.2001.281.4.E826</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.2001.281.4.E826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11551861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorissen SH, Horstman AM, Franssen R, Kouw IW, Wall BT, Burd NA, et al. Habituation to low or high protein intake does not modulate basal or postprandial muscle protein synthesis rates: a randomized trial. Am J Clin Nutr. (2017) 105:332&#x2013;42. 10.3945/ajcn.115.129924Percent-change from fasted (i.e., 0 g protein ingestion) of mixed muscle protein synthesis (A) and whole body leucine oxidation (B) after resistance</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.115.129924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27903518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasiakos SM, Cao JJ, Margolis LM, Sauter ER, Whigham LD, McClung JP, et al. Effects of high-protein diets on fat-free mass and muscle protein synthesis following weight loss: a randomized controlled trial. Faseb J. (2013) 27:3837&#x2013;47. 10.1096/fj.13-230227</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.13-230227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23739654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasiakos SM, Vislocky LM, Carbone JW, Altieri N, Konopelski K, Freake HC, et al. Acute energy deprivation affects skeletal muscle protein synthesis and associated intracellular signaling proteins in physically active adults. J Nutr. (2010) 140:745&#x2013;51. 10.3945/jn.109.118372</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.109.118372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20164371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camera DM, West DW, Burd NA, Phillips SM, Garnham AP, Hawley JA, et al. Low muscle glycogen concentration does not suppress the anabolic response to resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol. (2012) 113:206&#x2013;14. 10.1152/japplphysiol.00395.2012Percent-change from fasted (i.e., 0 g protein ingestion) of mixed muscle protein synthesis (A) and whole body leucine oxidation (B) after resistance</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00395.2012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22628371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hector AJ, McGlory C, Damas F, Mazara N, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Pronounced energy restriction with elevated protein intake results in no change in proteolysis and reductions in skeletal muscle protein synthesis that are mitigated by resistance exercise. Faseb J. (2018) 32:265&#x2013;75. 10.1096/fj.201700158RR</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.201700158RR</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28899879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longland TM, Oikawa SY, Mitchell CJ, Devries MC, Phillips SM. Higher compared with lower dietary protein during an energy deficit combined with intense exercise promotes greater lean mass gain and fat mass loss: a randomized trial. Am J Clin Nutr. (2016) 103:738&#x2013;46. 10.3945/ajcn.115.119339</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.115.119339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26817506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paddon-Jones D, Westman E, Mattes RD, Wolfe RR, Astrup A, Westerterp-Plantenga W. Protein, weight management, and satiety. Am J Clin Nutr. (2008) 87:1558s&#x2212;61s. 10.1093/ajcn/87.5.1558S</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/87.5.1558S</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18469287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy CH, Hector AJ, Phillips SM. Considerations for protein intake in managing weight loss in athletes. Eur J Sport Sci. (2015) 15:21&#x2013;8. 10.1080/17461391.2014.936325</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17461391.2014.936325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25014731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beals JW, Burd NA, Moore DR, van Vliet S. Obesity alters the muscle protein synthetic response to nutrition and exercise. Front Nutr. (2019) 6:87. 10.3389/fnut.2019.00087</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2019.00087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6584965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31263701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beals JW, Sukiennik RA, Nallabelli J, Emmons RS, van Vliet S, Young JR, et al. Anabolic sensitivity of postprandial muscle protein synthesis to the ingestion of a protein-dense food is reduced in overweight and obese young adults. Am J Clin Nutr. (2016) 104:1014&#x2013;22. 10.3945/ajcn.116.130385</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.116.130385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27604771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beals JW, Skinner SK, McKenna CF, Poozhikunnel EG, Farooqi SA, van Vliet S, et al. Altered anabolic signalling and reduced stimulation of myofibrillar protein synthesis after feeding and resistance exercise in people with obesity. J Physiol. (2018) 596:5119&#x2013;33. 10.1113/JP276210</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP276210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6209748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30113718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kouw IWK, van Dijk JW, Horstman AMH, Kramer IF, Goessens JPB, van Dielen FMH, et al. Basal and postprandial myofibrillar protein synthesis rates do not differ between lean and obese middle-aged men. J Nutr. (2019). 10.1093/jn/nxz104. [Epub ahead of print].Percent-change from fasted (i.e., 0 g protein ingestion) of mixed muscle protein synthesis (A) and whole body leucine oxidation (B) after resistance</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jn/nxz104.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6736155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31174213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smeuninx B, McKendry J, Wilson D, Martin U, Breen L. Age-related anabolic resistance of myofibrillar protein synthesis is exacerbated in obese inactive individuals. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. (2017) 102:3535&#x2013;45. 10.1210/jc.2017-00869</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2017-00869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5587073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28911148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang JE, Perco JG, Moore DR, Wilkinson SB, Phillips SM. Resistance training alters the response of fed state mixed muscle protein synthesis in young men. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. (2008) 294:R172&#x2013;8. 10.1152/ajpregu.00636.2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpregu.00636.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18032468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, Parise G, Bellamy L, Baker SK, Smith K, et al. Acute post-exercise myofibrillar protein synthesis is not correlated with resistance training-induced muscle hypertrophy in young men. PLoS ONE. (2014) 9:e89431 10.1371/journal.pone.0089431Percent-change from fasted (i.e., 0 g protein ingestion) of mixed muscle protein synthesis (A) and whole body leucine oxidation (B) after resistance</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0089431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3933567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24586775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernbom M, Augustsson J, Thomee R. The influence of frequency, intensity, volume and mode of strength training on whole muscle cross-sectional area in humans. Sports Med. (2007) 37:225&#x2013;64. 10.2165/00007256-200737030-00004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200737030-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17326698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mamerow MM, Mettler JA, English KL, Casperson SL, Arentson-Lantz E, Sheffield-Moore M, et al. Dietary protein distribution positively influences 24-h muscle protein synthesis in healthy adults. J Nutr. (2014) 144:876&#x2013;80. 10.3945/jn.113.185280</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.113.185280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4018950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24477298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Areta J, Coffey VG, Stellingwerff T, Phillips SM, Burke LM, et al. Daytime pattern of post-exercise protein intake affects whole-body protein turnover in resistance-trained males. Nutr Metab. (2012) 9:91. 10.1186/1743-7075-9-91</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1743-7075-9-91</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3514209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23067428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Res PT, Groen B, Pennings B, Beelen M, Wallis GA, Gijsen AP, et al. Protein ingestion before sleep improves postexercise overnight recovery. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2012) 44:1560&#x2013;9. 10.1249/MSS.0b013e31824cc363</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e31824cc363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22330017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Murphy KT, McKellar SR, Schoenfeld BJ, Henselmans M, Helms E, et al. A systematic review, meta-analysis and meta-regression of the effect of protein supplementation on resistance training-induced gains in muscle mass and strength in healthy adults. Br J Sports Med. (2018) 52:376&#x2013;84. 10.1136/bjsports-2017-097608</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-097608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5867436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28698222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>