<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38859872</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2050-313X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>SAGE open medical case reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>SAGE Open Med Case Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Continued elevation of creatinine and uric acid in a male athlete: A case report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2050313X241260229</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2050313X241260229</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2050313X241260229</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/2050313X241260229</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Whey protein and other protein-fortified supplements are frequently consumed as nutritional supplements to aid in muscle hypertrophy and myogenesis. This case presents a 36-year-old athletic male with elevated creatinine and uric acid levels during routine laboratory evaluation. The patient had no history of kidney disease, diabetes, or hypertension. It was revealed that the patient had been regularly consuming whey protein as a dietary supplement for 2&#x2009;months. Given the potential association between the elevated creatinine and uric acid levels and the use of whey protein, the patient was advised to discontinue the supplement. The patient then switched to protein-fortified milk to mitigate the possible harmful connection between the dietary intake and the laboratory findings. However, despite the dietary change, the increased levels of creatinine and uric acid persisted. This observation suggests that the elevated levels may be attributed to chronic whey protein consumption along with high-protein dietary consumption.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2024.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alaseem</LastName><ForeName>Ali M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2015-9161</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, College of Medicine, Imam Mohammad Ibn Saud Islamic University (IMSIU), Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>SAGE Open Med Case Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101638686</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2050-313X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sports medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">creatine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">creatinine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nephrology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">whey protein</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38859872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11163930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2050313X241260229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_2050313X241260229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Daher J, Mallick M, El Khoury D. Prevalence of dietary supplement use among athletes worldwide: a scoping review. Nutrients 2022; 14(19): 4109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9570738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36235761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knapik JJ, Trone DW, Steelman RA, et al. Adverse effects associated with use of specific dietary supplements: the US Military Dietary Supplement Use Study. Food Chem Toxicol 2022; 161: 112840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35093428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denham BE. Dietary supplements&#x2014;regulatory issues and implications for public health. JAMA 2011; 306(4): 428&#x2013;429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21730229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen W-C, Huang W-C, Chiu C-C, et al. Whey protein improves exercise performance and biochemical profiles in trained mice. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2014; 46(8): 1517&#x2013;1524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4186725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24504433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krissansen GW. Emerging health properties of whey proteins and their clinical implications. J Am Coll Nutr 2007; 26(6): 713S&#x2013;23S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18187438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madureira AR, Tavares T, Gomes AMP, et al. Invited review: physiological properties of bioactive peptides obtained from whey proteins. J Dairy Sci 2010; 93(2): 437&#x2013;455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20105516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farup J, Rahbek SK, Vendelbo MH, et al. Whey protein hydrolysate augments tendon and muscle hypertrophy independent of resistance exercise contraction mode. Scand J Med Sci Sports 2014; 24(5): 788&#x2013;798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23647357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morifuji M, Kanda A, Koga J, et al. Post-exercise carbohydrate plus whey protein hydrolysates supplementation increases skeletal muscle glycogen level in rats. Amino Acids 2010; 38(4): 1109&#x2013;1115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19593593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elia D, Stadler K, Horv&#xe1;th V, et al. Effect of soy- and whey protein-isolate supplemented diet on the redox parameters of trained mice. Eur J Nutr 2006; 45(5): 259&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16575496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam F-C, Khan TM, Faidah H, et al. Effectiveness of whey protein supplements on the serum levels of amino acid, creatinine kinase and myoglobin of athletes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Syst Rev 2019; 8(1): 130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6544960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31151484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasconcelos QDJS, Bachur TPR, Arag&#xe3;o GF. Whey protein supplementation and its potentially adverse effects on health: a systematic review. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 2021; 46(1): 27&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32702243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovesdy CP. Epidemiology of chronic kidney disease: an update 2022. Kidney Int Suppl 2022; 12(1): 7&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9073222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35529086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalantar-Zadeh K, Moore LW, Tortorici AR, et al. North American experience with Low protein diet for Non-dialysis-dependent chronic kidney disease. BMC Nephrol 2016; 17(1): 90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4952055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27435088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fouque D, Aparicio M. Eleven reasons to control the protein intake of patients with chronic kidney disease. Nat Clin Pract Nephrol 2007; 3(7): 383&#x2013;392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17592471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenner BM, Meyer TW, Hostetter TH. Dietary protein intake and the progressive nature of kidney disease: the role of hemodynamically mediated glomerular injury in the pathogenesis of progressive glomerular sclerosis in aging, renal ablation, and intrinsic renal disease. N Engl J Med 1982; 307(11): 652&#x2013;659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7050706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwingshackl L, Hoffmann G. Comparison of high vs. normal/low protein diets on renal function in subjects without chronic kidney disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One 2014; 9(5): e97656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4031217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24852037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman AN. High-protein diets: potential effects on the kidney in renal health and disease. Am J Kidney Dis 2004; 44(6): 950&#x2013;962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15558517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Evans C, Ferrando AA, et al. Common questions and misconceptions about protein supplementation: what does the scientific evidence really show? J Int Soc Sports Nutr 2024; 21(1): 2341903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11022925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38626029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davani-Davari D, Karimzadeh I, Ezzatzadegan-Jahromi S, et al. Potential adverse effects of creatine supplement on the kidney in athletes and bodybuilders. Iran J Kidney Dis 2018; 12(5): 253&#x2013;260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30367015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Candow DG, Forbes SC, et al. Common questions and misconceptions about creatine supplementation: what does the scientific evidence really show? J Int Soc Sports Nutr 2021; 18(1): 13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7871530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33557850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyss M, Kaddurah-Daouk R. Creatine and creatinine metabolism. Physiol Rev 2000; 80(3): 1107&#x2013;1213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10893433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronco C, Bellomo R, Kellum JA. Acute kidney injury. Lancet (London, England) 2019; 394(10212): 1949&#x2013;1964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31777389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreev E, Koopman M, Arisz L. A rise in plasma creatinine that is not a sign of renal failure: which drugs can be responsible? J Intern Med 1999; 246(3): 247&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10475992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pritchard NR, Kalra PA. Renal dysfunction accompanying oral creatine supplements. Lancet (London, England) 1998; 351(9111): 1252&#x2013;1253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9643752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joo HJ, Kim GR, Choi D-W, et al. Uric acid level and kidney function: a cross-sectional study of the Korean national health and nutrition examination survey (2016&#x2013;2017). Sci Rep 2020; 10(1): 21672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7730446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33303792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong T-D, Hong J, Lee W, et al. Accuracy of the new creatinine-based equations for estimating glomerular filtration rate in Koreans. Ann Lab Med 2023; 43(3): 244&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9791020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36544336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persky AM, Rawson ES. Safety of creatine supplementation. Subcell Biochem 2007; 46: 275&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18652082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko GJ, Obi Y, Tortorici AR, et al. Dietary protein intake and chronic kidney disease. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care 2017; 20(1): 77&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5962279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27801685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellizzi V. Low-protein diet or nutritional therapy in chronic kidney disease? Blood Purif 2013; 36(1): 41&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23735624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tidmas V, Brazier J, Hawkins J, et al. Nutritional and non-nutritional strategies in bodybuilding: impact on kidney function. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2022; 19(7): 4288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8998289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35409969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Falvo MJ. Protein&#x2014;which is best? J Sports Sci Med 2004; 3(3): 118&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3905294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24482589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poortmans JR, Dellalieux O. Do regular high protein diets have potential health risks on kidney function in athletes? Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab 2000; 10(1): 28&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10722779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jhee JH, Kee YK, Park S, et al. High-protein diet with renal hyperfiltration is associated with rapid decline rate of renal function: a community-based prospective cohort study. Nephrol Dial Transplant 2020; 35(1): 98&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31172186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amanzadeh J, Gitomer WL, Zerwekh JE, et al. Effect of high protein diet on stone-forming propensity and bone loss in rats. Kidney Int 2003; 64(6): 2142&#x2013;2149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14633136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Treyzon L, Chen S, et al. Protein-enriched meal replacements do not adversely affect liver, kidney or bone density: an outpatient randomized controlled trial. Nutr J 2010; 9: 72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3023677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21194471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin WF, Armstrong LE, Rodriguez NR. Dietary protein intake and renal function. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2005; 2: 25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1262767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16174292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gualano B, Ferreira DC, Sapienza MT, et al. Effect of short-term high-dose creatine supplementation on measured GFR in a young man with a single kidney. Am J Kidney Dis 2010; 55(3): e7&#x2013;e9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20060630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gualano B, de Salles Painelli V, Roschel H, et al. Creatine supplementation does not impair kidney function in type 2 diabetic patients: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, clinical trial. Eur J Appl Physiol 2011; 111(5): 749&#x2013;756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20976468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neves M, Gualano B, Roschel H, et al. Effect of creatine supplementation on measured glomerular filtration rate in postmenopausal women. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab 2011; 36(3): 419&#x2013;422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21574777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza E Silva A, Pertille A, Reis Barbosa CG, et al. Effects of creatine supplementation on renal function: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Ren Nutr 2019; 29(6): 480&#x2013;489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31375416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>