<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38846541</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-861X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Timing matters? The effects of two different timing of high protein diets on body composition, muscular performance, and biochemical markers in resistance-trained males.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1397090</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1397090</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1397090</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fnut.2024.1397090</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">It is unclear whether resistance training in combination with different timing of protein intake might have differential effects on muscle hypertrophy, strength, and performance. Therefore, we compared the effects of 8&#x2009;weeks of resistance training combined with two different high-protein diet strategies (immediately pre-and after, or 3&#x2009;h pre and after exercise) in resistance-trained males.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Forty resistance-trained males (24 &#xb1;&#x2009;4&#x2009;years) performed 8&#x2009;weeks of resistance training combined with 2&#x2009;g&#x2009;kg<sup>-1</sup> d<sup>-1</sup> protein. Body composition, muscular performance, and biochemical markers were assessed pre and post-intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Nine participants (four from 3&#x2009;h group and five from the immediate group) withdrew from the study. Therefore, 31 participants completed the study. All measures of skeletal muscle mass, Australian pull-up, and muscle strength, significantly increased post-intervention in both groups (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). The biochemical marker urea also significantly increased from pre to post in both groups (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). There were no significant between-group differences (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">High-protein diet enhances muscular performance and skeletal muscle mass in resistance-trained males, irrespective of intake time. Consequently, the total daily protein intake appears to be the primary factor in facilitating muscle growth induced by exercise.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Lak, Bagheri, Ghobadi, Campbell, Wong, Shahrbaf, Shariatzadeh and Dutheil.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lak</LastName><ForeName>Mohammadyasin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Sciences Research Institute of Iran, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bagheri</LastName><ForeName>Reza</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, University of Isfahan, Isfahan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghobadi</LastName><ForeName>Hamid</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Physiology, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Mashhad, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campbell</LastName><ForeName>Bill</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Performance and Physique Enhancement Laboratory, University of South Florida, Tampa, FL, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wong</LastName><ForeName>Alexei</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Human Performance, Marymount University, Arlington, TX, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shahrbaf</LastName><ForeName>Amin</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shariatzadeh</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Sciences Research Institute of Iran, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dutheil</LastName><ForeName>Fred</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; Clermont Auvergne CNRS, LaPSCo, Physiological and Psychosocial Stress, CHU Clermont-Ferrand, University Hospital of Clermont-Ferrand, Preventive and Occupational Medicine, Clermont-Ferrand, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101642264</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-861X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn"><RefSource>Front Nutr. 2025 Aug 14;12:1675832. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2025.1675832.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">40896187</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dietary protein</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutrition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38846541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11156191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2024.1397090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bagheri R, Kargarfard M, Sadeghi R, Scott D, Camera DM. Effects of 16 weeks of two different high-protein diets with either resistance or concurrent training on body composition, muscular strength and performance, and markers of liver and kidney function in resistance-trained males. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2023) 20:2236053. doi: 10.1080/15502783.2023.2236053, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15502783.2023.2236053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10388821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37516903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pourabbas M, Bagheri R, Hooshmand Moghadam B, Willoughby DS, Candow DG, Elliott BT, et al. Strategic ingestion of high-protein dairy milk during a resistance training program increases lean mass, strength, and power in trained young males. Nutrients. (2021) 13:948. doi: 10.3390/nu13030948, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13030948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7999866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33804259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bern&#xe1;rdez-V&#xe1;zquez R, Raya-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Castillo D, Beato M. Resistance training variables for optimization of muscle hypertrophy: an umbrella review. Front Sports Act Living. (2022) 4:949021. doi: 10.3389/fspor.2022.949021, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2022.949021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9302196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35873210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagheri R, Moghadam BH, Ashtary-Larky D, Forbes SC, Candow DG, Galpin AJ, et al. Whole egg vs. egg white ingestion during 12 weeks of resistance training in trained young males: a randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res. (2021) 35:411&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003922, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33306586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hudson JL, Bergia Iii RE, Campbell WW. Protein distribution and muscle-related outcomes: does the evidence support the concept? Nutrients. (2020) 12:1441. doi: 10.3390/nu12051441, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu12051441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7285146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32429355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagheri R, Shakibaee A, Camera DM, Sobhani V, Ghobadi H, Nazar E, et al. Effects of 8 weeks of resistance training in combination with a high protein diet on body composition, muscular performance, and markers of liver and kidney function in untrained older ex-military men. Front Nutr. (2023) 10:1205310. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2023.1205310</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2023.1205310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10342203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37457969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell BI, Aguilar D, Conlin L, Vargas A, Schoenfeld BJ, Corson A, et al. Effects of high versus low protein intake on body composition and maximal strength in aspiring female physique athletes engaging in an 8-week resistance training program. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. (2018) 28:580&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0389, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.2017-0389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29405780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xe4;ger R, Kerksick CM, Campbell BI, Cribb PJ, Wells SD, Skwiat TM, et al. International Society of Sports Nutrition Position Stand: protein and exercise. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2017) 14:20. doi: 10.1186/s12970-017-0177-8, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-017-0177-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5477153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28642676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Murphy KT, Mckellar SR, Schoenfeld BJ, Henselmans M, Helms E, et al. A systematic review, meta-analysis and meta-regression of the effect of protein supplementation on resistance training-induced gains in muscle mass and strength in healthy adults. Br J Sports Med. (2018) 52:376&#x2013;84. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2017-097608, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2017-097608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5867436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28698222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Ellerbroek A, Silver T, Orris S, Scheiner M, Gonzalez A, et al. A high protein diet (3.4&#x2009;g/kg/d) combined with a heavy resistance training program improves body composition in healthy trained men and women&#x2014;a follow-up investigation. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2015) 12:39. doi: 10.1186/s12970-015-0100-0, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-015-0100-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4617900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26500462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonio J, Peacock CA, Ellerbroek A, Fromhoff B, Silver T. The effects of consuming a high protein diet (4.4 g/kg/d) on body composition in resistance-trained individuals. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2014) 11:19. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-11-19, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-11-19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4022420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24834017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Areta JL, Burke LM, Ross ML, Camera DM, West DW, Broad EM, et al. Timing and distribution of protein ingestion during prolonged recovery from resistance exercise alters myofibrillar protein synthesis. J Physiol. (2013) 591:2319&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1113/jphysiol.2012.244897, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.2012.244897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3650697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23459753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda J, Tomita T, Arimitsu T, Fujita S. Evenly distributed protein intake over 3 meals augments resistance exercise-induced muscle hypertrophy in healthy young men. J Nutr. (2020) 150:1845&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1093/jn/nxaa101, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jn/nxaa101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7330467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32321161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cribb PJ, Hayes A. Effects of supplement timing and resistance exercise on skeletal muscle hypertrophy. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2006) 38:1918&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1249/01.mss.0000233790.08788.3e, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.mss.0000233790.08788.3e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17095924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman JR, Ratamess NA, Tranchina CP, Rashti SL, Kang J, Faigenbaum AD. Effect of protein-supplement timing on strength, power, and body-composition changes in resistance-trained men. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. (2009) 19:172&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.19.2.172, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/ijsnem.19.2.172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19478342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Aragon AA, Krieger JW. The effect of protein timing on muscle strength and hypertrophy: a meta-analysis. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2013) 10:53. doi: 10.1186/1550-2783-10-53, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1550-2783-10-53</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3879660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24299050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth J, Hillesheim E, Brennan L. The role of protein intake and its timing on body composition and muscle function in healthy adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Nutr. (2020) 150:1443&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1093/jn/nxaa049, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jn/nxaa049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32232404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent W. (1995). Statistics in kinesiology. Human Kinetics, Champaign, IL, 178&#x2013;181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Nickerson BS, Wilborn CD, Urbina SL, Hayward SB, Krieger J, et al. Comparison of multifrequency bioelectrical impedance vs. dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry for assessing body composition changes after participation in a 10-week resistance training program. J Strength Cond Res. (2020) 34:678&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002708, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29927888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alver BA, Sell K, Deuster PA. NSCA&#x2019;s essentials of tactical strength and conditioning Human Kinetics; (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murach KA, Bagley JR. Skeletal muscle hypertrophy with concurrent exercise training: contrary evidence for an interference effect. Sports Med. (2016) 46:1029&#x2013;39. doi: 10.1007/s40279-016-0496-y, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0496-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26932769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilborn CD, Taylor LW, Outlaw J, Williams L, Campbell B, Foster CA, et al. The effects of pre-and post-exercise whey vs. casein protein consumption on body composition and performance measures in collegiate female athletes. J Sports Sci Med. (2013) 12:74&#x2013;9. PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aube D, Wadhi T, Rauch J, Anand A, Barakat C, Pearson J, et al. Progressive resistance training volume: effects on muscle thickness, mass, and strength adaptations in resistance-trained individuals. J Strength Cond Res. (2022) 36:600&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003524, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32058362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer WJ, Hatfield DL, Volek JS, Fragala MS, Vingren JL, Anderson JM, et al. Effects of amino acids supplement on physiological adaptations to resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. (2009) 41:1111&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e318194cc75, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e318194cc75</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19346975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha PM, Nunes JP, Tomeleri CM, Nascimento MA, Schoenfeld BJ, Antunes M, et al. Resistance training performed with single and multiple sets induces similar improvements in muscular strength, muscle mass, muscle quality, and IGF-1 in older women: a randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res. (2020) 34:1008&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000002847, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000002847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30272625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DT, Erdman KA, Burke LM. Position of the Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics, Dietitians of Canada, and the American College of Sports Medicine: Nutrition and Athletic Performance. J Acad Nutr Diet. (2016) 116:501&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1016/j.jand.2015.12.006, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jand.2015.12.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26920240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Robinson MJ, Fry JL, Tang JE, Glover EI, Wilkinson SB, et al. Ingested protein dose response of muscle and albumin protein synthesis after resistance exercise in young men. Am J Clin Nutr. (2009) 89:161&#x2013;8. doi: 10.3945/ajcn.2008.26401, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.2008.26401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19056590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snijders T, Res PT, Smeets JS, Van Vliet S, Van Kranenburg J, Maase K, et al. Protein ingestion before sleep increases muscle mass and strength gains during prolonged resistance-type exercise training in healthy young men. J Nutr. (2015) 145:1178&#x2013;84. doi: 10.3945/jn.114.208371, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/jn.114.208371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25926415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratner B. The correlation coefficient: its values range between+ 1/&#x2212;1, or do they? J Target Meas Anal Mark. (2009) 17:139&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1057/jt.2009.5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1057/jt.2009.5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cintineo HP, Arent MA, Antonio J, Arent SM. Effects of protein supplementation on performance and recovery in resistance and endurance training. Front Nutr. (2018) 5:83. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2018.00083, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2018.00083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6142015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30255023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearson AG, Hind K, Macnaughton LS. The impact of dietary protein supplementation on recovery from resistance exercise-induced muscle damage: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Eur J Clin Nutr. (2023) 77:767&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1038/s41430-022-01250-y, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41430-022-01250-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10393778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36513777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasiakos SM, Mclellan TM, Lieberman HR. The effects of protein supplements on muscle mass, strength, and aerobic and anaerobic power in healthy adults: a systematic review. Sports Med. (2015) 45:111&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1007/s40279-014-0242-2, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-014-0242-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25169440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick CM, Arent S, Schoenfeld BJ, Stout JR, Campbell B, Wilborn CD, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: nutrient timing. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2017) 14:33. doi: 10.1186/s12970-017-0189-4, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-017-0189-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5596471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28919842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deldicque L. Protein intake and exercise-induced skeletal muscle hypertrophy: an update. Nutrients. (2020) 12:2023. doi: 10.3390/nu12072023, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu12072023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7400877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32646013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HK, Chijiki H, Fukazawa M, Okubo J, Ozaki M, Nanba T, et al. Supplementation of protein at breakfast rather than at dinner and lunch is effective on skeletal muscle mass in older adults. Front Nutr. (2021) 8:797004. doi: 10.3389/fnut.2021.797004, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2021.797004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8724572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34993224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arent SM, Cintineo HP, Mcfadden BA, Chandler AJ, Arent MA. Nutrient timing: a garage door of opportunity? Nutrients. (2020) 12:1948. doi: 10.3390/nu12071948, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu12071948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7400240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32629950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Aragon AA. Is there a postworkout anabolic window of opportunity for nutrient consumption? Clearing up controversies. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. (2018) 48:911&#x2013;4. doi: 10.2519/jospt.2018.0615, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2519/jospt.2018.0615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30702982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Aragon AA, Wilborn C, Urbina SL, Hayward SE, Krieger J. Pre-versus post-exercise protein intake has similar effects on muscular adaptations. PeerJ. (2017) 5:e2825. doi: 10.7717/peerj.2825, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.2825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5214805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28070459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo X, Zhang H, Cao X, Yang D, Yan Y, Lu J, et al. Endurance exercise-induced Fgf21 promotes skeletal muscle fiber conversion through TGF-&#x3b2;1 and p38 MAPK signaling pathway. Int J Mol Sci. (2023) 24:11401. doi: 10.3390/ijms241411401, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms241411401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10379449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37511159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson EP, Noordhof DA, De Koning JJ, St&#xf6;ggl TL, Bj&#xf6;rklund G. Editorial: anaerobic energy/work supply in endurance activities-the importance and effect of computational method. Front Sports Act Living. (2021) 3:777419. doi: 10.3389/fspor.2021.777419, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fspor.2021.777419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8632757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34870199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupuy O, Douzi W, Theurot D, Bosquet L, Dugu&#xe9; B. An evidence-based approach for choosing post-exercise recovery techniques to reduce markers of muscle damage, soreness, fatigue, and inflammation: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Front Physiol. (2018) 9:403. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2018.00403, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2018.00403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5932411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29755363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>