<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37415906</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-042X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hibiscus attenuates renovascular hypertension-induced aortic remodeling dose dependently: the oxidative stress role and Ang II/cyclophilin A/ERK1/2 signaling.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1116705</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1116705</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1116705</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fphys.2023.1116705</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Introduction:</b> The high levels of angiotensin II (Ang II) can modify the vascular tone, enhance vascular smooth muscle cells (VSMCs) proliferation and hypertrophy and increase the inflammatory cellular infiltration into the vessel wall. The old herbal nonpharmacological agent, Hibiscus (HS) sabdariffa L has multiple cardioprotective impacts; thus, we investigated the role of HS extract in amelioration of renovascular hypertension (RVH)-induced aortic remodeling. <b>Materials and methods:</b> Thirty-five rats (7/group) were randomly allocated into 5 groups; group: I: Control-sham group, and RVH groups; II, III, IV, and V. The rats in RVH groups were subjected to the modified Goldblatt two-kidneys, one clip (2K1C) for induction of hypertension. In group: II, the rats were left untreated whereas in group III, IV, and V: RVH-rats were treated for 6&#xa0;weeks with low dose hibiscus (LDH), medium dose hibiscus (MDH), and high dose hibiscus (HDH) respectively. <b>Results:</b> We found that the augmented pro-contractile response of the aortic rings was ameliorated secondary to the <i>in-vivo</i> treatment with HS dose dependently. The cyclophilin A (CyPA) protein levels positively correlated with the vascular adhesion molecule-1 (VCAM-1) and ERK1/2, which, in turn, contribute to the reactive oxygen species (ROS) production. Daily HS intake modified aortic renovation by enhancing the antioxidant capacity, restraining hypertrophy and fibrosis, downregulation of the metastasis associated lung adenocarcinoma transcript (MALAT1), and cyclophilin A (CyPA)/ERK1/2 levels. <b>Discussion:</b> Adding to the multiple beneficial effects, HS aqueous extract was able to inhibit vascular smooth muscle cell proliferation induced by 2K1C model. Thus, adding more privilege for the utilization of the traditional herbal extracts to attenuate RVH-induced aortopathy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 ShamsEldeen, Fawzy, Ashour, Abdel-Rahman, Nasr, Mohammed, Abdel Latif, Mahrous and Abdelfattah.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>ShamsEldeen</LastName><ForeName>Asmaa Mohammed</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Faculty of Medicine, Cairo University, Giza, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fawzy</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Faculty of Medicine, Cairo University, Giza, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ashour</LastName><ForeName>Hend</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Faculty of Medicine, Cairo University, Giza, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Faculty of Medicine, King Khalid University, Abha, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdel-Rahman</LastName><ForeName>Marwa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Faculty of Medicine, Cairo University, Giza, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nasr</LastName><ForeName>Hend Elsayed</ForeName><Initials>HE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, Benha University, Benha, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohammed</LastName><ForeName>Lina Abdelhady</ForeName><Initials>LA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, Benha University, Benha, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdel Latif</LastName><ForeName>Noha Samir</ForeName><Initials>NS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, Faculty of Medicine, Cairo University, Giza, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahrous</LastName><ForeName>Amr M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacognosy, Faculty of Pharmacy, El Saleheya El Gadida University, Al Sharquia, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdelfattah</LastName><ForeName>Shereen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anatomy and Embryology Faculty of Medicine, Cairo University, Giza, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101549006</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-042X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">2K1C</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ERK1/2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MALAT1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aortic response</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cyclophilin A</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hibiscus</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest. The reviewer SE declared a shared affiliation with the author(s) AS, AF, HA, and MA-R to the handling editor at the time of review.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37415906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10321301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2023.1116705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1116705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alam M. A., Hasan Chowdhury M. R., Jain P., Sagor M. A. T., Reza H. M. (2015). DPP-4 inhibitor sitagliptin prevents inflammation and oxidative stress of heart and kidney in two kidney and one clip (2K1C) rats. Diabetol. Metab. Syndr. 7 (1), 107. 10.1186/s13098-015-0095-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13098-015-0095-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4658771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26609328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alarc&#xf3;n-Alonso J., Zamilpa A., Aguilar F. A., Herrera-Ruiz M., Tortoriello J., Jimenez-Ferrer E. (2012). Pharmacological characterization of the diuretic effect of Hibiscus sabdariffa Linn (Malvaceae) extract. J. Ethnopharmacol. 139 (3), 751&#x2013;756. 10.1016/j.jep.2011.12.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2011.12.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22178178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albro P. W., Corbett J. T., Schroeder J. L. (1986). Application of the thiobarbiturate assay to the measurement of lipid peroxidation products in microsomes. J. Biochem. Biophys. Methods 13 (3), 185&#x2013;194. 10.1016/0165-022x(86)90092-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0165-022x(86)90092-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3782721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson Z., Thisted E., Andersen U. B. (2017). Renal branch artery stenosis: A diagnostic challenge? A case report with review of the literature. Urology 100, 218&#x2013;220. 10.1016/j.urology.2016.06.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.urology.2016.06.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27369816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Banwo K., Sanni A., Sarkar D., Ale O. (2022). Phenolics-linked antioxidant and anti-hyperglycemic properties of edible roselle (<i>Hibiscus sabdariffa</i> linn) calyces targeting type 2 diabetes nutraceutical benefits <i>in vitro</i>
. Front. Sustain. Food. Syst.
6, 1&#x2013;13. 10.3389/fsufs.2022.660831
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fsufs.2022.660831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basu P., Sen U., Tyagi N., Tyagi S. C. (2010). Blood flow interplays with elastin: Collagen and MMP: TIMP ratios to maintain healthy vascular structure and function. Vasc. health risk Manag. 6, 215&#x2013;228. 10.2147/vhrm.s9472</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/vhrm.s9472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2856577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20407629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biancardi V. C., Son S. J., Ahmadi S., Filosa J. A., Stern J. E. (2014). Circulating angiotensin II gains access to the hypothalamus and brain stem during hypertension via breakdown of the blood-brain barrier. Hypertension 63 (3), 572&#x2013;579. 10.1161/HYPERTENSIONAHA.113.01743</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/HYPERTENSIONAHA.113.01743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4080808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24343120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng C., Xu B. L., Sheng J. L., He F., Yang T., Shen S. C. (2019). LncRNA MALAT1 regulates proliferation and apoptosis of vascular smooth muscle cells by targeting miRNA-124-3p/PPAR&#x3b1; axis. Eur. Rev. Med. Pharmacol. Sci. 23 (20), 9025&#x2013;9032. 10.26355/eurrev_201910_19304</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26355/eurrev_201910_19304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31696492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi S., Shin H. R., Kim S. H., Lee M. J., Jun J. Y., Kim H. L., et al. (2014). Effects of oxidative stress on endothelial modulation of contractions in aorta from renal hypertensive rats. Kidney Res. Clin. Pract. 33 (1), 19&#x2013;25. 10.1016/j.krcp.2013.12.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.krcp.2013.12.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4714182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26877946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choopani S., Nematbakhsh M. (2021). Renal vascular response to angiotensin II administration in two kidneys-one clip hypertensive rats treated with high dose of estradiol: The role of mas receptor. Int. J. Vasc. Med., 2021, 6643485, 10.1155/2021/6643485</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/6643485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7943267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33747565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou C. C., Wang C. P., Chen J. H., Lin H. H. (2019). Anti-atherosclerotic effect of Hibiscus leaf polyphenols against tumor necrosis factor-alpha-induced abnormal vascular smooth muscle cell migration and proliferation. Antioxidants 8 (12), 620. 10.3390/antiox8120620</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox8120620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6943519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31817413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Csanyi G., Lepran I., Flesch T., Telegdy G., Szabo G., Mezei Z. (2007). Lack of endothelium-derived hyperpolarizing factor (EDHF) up-regulation in endothelial dysfunction in aorta in diabetic rats. Pharmacol. Rep. 59 (4), 447&#x2013;455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17901574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Miguel C., Guo C., Lund H., Feng D., Mattson D. L. (2011). Infiltrating T lymphocytes in the kidney increase oxidative stress and participate in the development of hypertension and renal disease. Am. J. Physiol. - Ren. Physiol. 300 (3), 734&#x2013;742. 10.1152/ajprenal.00454.2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajprenal.00454.2010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3064138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21159736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhingra S., Sharma A. K., Arora R. C., Slezak J., Singal P. K. (2009). IL-10 attenuates TNF-alpha-induced NF kappaB pathway activation and cardiomyocyte apoptosis. Cardiovasc. Res. 82 (1), 59&#x2013;66. 10.1093/cvr/cvp040</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cvr/cvp040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19181934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglas J. R., Johnson E. M., Heist J. F., Marshall G. R., Needleman P. (1976). Is the peripheral sympatho-adrenal nervous system necessary for renal hypertension? J. Pharmacol. Exp. Ther. 196 (1), 35&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1246014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flecknell P. (2009). Laboratory animal anaesthesia. Elsevier.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gesche H., Grosskurth D., K&#xfc;chler G., Patzak A. (2012). Continuous blood pressure measurement by using the pulse transit time: Comparison to a cuff-based method. Eur. J. Appl. Physiol. 112 (1), 309&#x2013;315. 10.1007/s00421-011-1983-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-011-1983-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21556814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldblatt B. Y. H., Lynch J., Ramon F., Ph D., Summerville W. W. (1934). Studies on E xperimental H hypertention, the production of persistent elevation of systolic blood pressure by means of renal ischemia. J. Exp. Med. 59 (3), 347&#x2013;379. 10.1084/jem.59.3.347</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1084/jem.59.3.347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2132360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19870251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirunpanich V., Utaipat A., Morales N. P., Bunyapraphatsara N., Sato H., Herunsale A., et al. (2006). Hypocholesterolemic and antioxidant effects of aqueous extracts from the dried calyx of Hibiscus sabdariffa L. in hypercholesterolemic rats. J. Ethnopharmacol. 103 (2), 252&#x2013;260. 10.1016/j.jep.2005.08.033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2005.08.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16213683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humphrey J. D. (2021). Mechanisms of vascular remodeling in hypertension. Am. J. Hypertens. 34 (5), 432&#x2013;441. 10.1093/ajh/hpaa195</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajh/hpaa195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8140657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33245319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inuwa I., Ali B. H., Al-Lawati I., Beegam S., Ziada A., Blunden G. (2012). Long-term ingestion of Hibiscus sabdariffa calyx extract enhances myocardial capillarization in the spontaneously hypertensive rat. Exp. Biol. Med. 237 (5), 563&#x2013;569. 10.1258/ebm.2012.011357</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1258/ebm.2012.011357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22678012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irvine R. J., White J., Chan R. (1997). The influence of restraint on blood pressure in the rat. J. Pharmacol. Toxicol. Methods 38 (3), 157&#x2013;162. 10.1016/s1056-8719(97)00081-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1056-8719(97)00081-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9523769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Z. G., Melaragno M. G., Liao D. F., Yan C., Haendeler J., Suh Y. A., et al. (2000). Cyclophilin A is a secreted growth factor induced by oxidative stress. Circulation Res. 87 (9), 789&#x2013;796. 10.1161/01.res.87.9.789</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.res.87.9.789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11055983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamal A. M., Haggag E. G., Abdelhady M. I. S., Youssif K. A., Sleem A. A. (2017). Quality control of herbal products in the Egyptian market used for some gastro-intestinal tract disorders. Gastro-Intest. Tract. Disord. 0547 (1), 43&#x2013;57. 10.21608/aprh.2016.859</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/aprh.2016.859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y. G., Lee S. H., Kim S. Y., Lee A., Moon J. Y., Jeong K. H., et al. (2016). Sequential activation of the intrarenal renin-angiotensin system in the progression of hypertensive nephropathy in Goldblatt rats. Am. J. Physiol. - Ren. Physiol. 311 (1), F195&#x2013;F206. 10.1152/ajprenal.00001.2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajprenal.00001.2015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26823279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D., Zhang C., Li J., Che J., Yang X., Xian Y., et al. (2019). Long non-coding RNA MALAT1 promotes cardiac remodeling in hypertensive rats by inhibiting the transcription of MyoD. Aging 11 (20), 8792&#x2013;8809. 10.18632/aging.102265</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/aging.102265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6834407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31619581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim Y. C., Budin S. B., Othman F., Latip J., Zainalabidin S. (2017). Roselle polyphenols exert potent negative inotropic effects via modulation of intracellular calcium regulatory channels in isolated rat heart. Cardiovasc. Toxicol. 17 (3), 251&#x2013;259. 10.1007/s12012-016-9379-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12012-016-9379-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27402292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorenz J. N., Lasko V. M., Nieman M. L., Damhoff T., Prasad V., Beierwaltes W. H., et al. (2011). Renovascular hypertension using a modified two-kidney, one-clip approach in mice is not dependent on the &#x3b1;1 or &#x3b1;2 Na-K-ATPase ouabain-binding site. Am. J. Physiology - Ren. Physiology 301 (3), 615&#x2013;621. 10.1152/ajprenal.00158.2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajprenal.00158.2011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3174550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21632957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mamun F., Rahman M. M., Zamila M., Subhan N., Hossain H., Raquibul Hasan S. M., et al. (2020). Polyphenolic compounds of litchi leaf augment kidney and heart functions in 2K1C rats. J. Funct. Foods 64, 103662. 10.1016/j.jff.2019.103662</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jff.2019.103662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Quinones P., McCarthy C. G., Watts S. W., Klee N. S., Komic A., Calmasini F. B., et al. (2018). Hypertension induced morphological and physiological changes in cells of the arterial wall. Am. J. Hypertens. 31 (10), 1067&#x2013;1078. 10.1093/ajh/hpy083</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajh/hpy083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6132119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29788246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mensah J. K., Golomeke D. (2015). Antioxidant and antimicrobial activities of the extracts of the calyx of Hibiscus sabdariffa linn. Curr. Sci. Perspect. 2 (1), 69&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michalik K. M., You X., Manavski Y., Doddaballapur A., Z&#xf6;rnig M., Braun T., et al. (2014). Long noncoding RNA MALAT1 regulates endothelial cell function and vessel growth. Circ. Res. 114 (9), 1389&#x2013;1397. 10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.114.303265</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.114.303265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24602777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moinuddin G., Inamdar M. N., Kulkarni K. S., Kulkarni C. (2013). Modulation of haemodynamics, endogeneous antioxidant enzymes, and pathophysiological changes by selective inhibition of angiotensin II type 1 receptors in pressureoverload rats. Cardiovasc. J. Afr. 24 (3), 58&#x2013;65. 10.5830/CVJA-2012-080</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5830/CVJA-2012-080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3721829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23736127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagura J., Yamamoto M., Hui C., Yasuda S., Hachisu M., Konno F. (1996). Protective effects of ME3221 on hypertensive complications and lifespan in salt-loaded stroke-prone spontaneously hypertensive rats. Clin. Exp. Pharmacol. Physiol. 23 (3), 229&#x2013;235. 10.1111/j.1440-1681.1996.tb02601.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1440-1681.1996.tb02601.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8934613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathak A. S., Huang J., Rojas M., Bazemore T. C., Zhou R., Stouffer G. A. (2016). Effects of restoration of blood flow on the development of aortic atherosclerosis in apoe-/- mice with unilateral renal artery stenosis. J. Am. Heart Assoc. 5 (4), e002953&#x2013;e002959. 10.1161/JAHA.115.002953</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.115.002953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4859283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27039929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng H., Herzog E. L. (2012). Fibrocytes: Emerging effector cells in chronic inflammation. Curr. Opin. Pharmacol. 12 (4), 491&#x2013;496. 10.1016/j.coph.2012.03.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coph.2012.03.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3651702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22465542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pothen L., Verdoy R., De Mulder D., Esfahani H., Farah C., Michel L. Y. M., et al. (2022). Sustained downregulation of vascular smooth muscle Acta2 after transient angiotensin II infusion: A new model of &#x201c;vascular memory&#x201d;. Front. Cardiovasc. Med. 9, 854361&#x2013;854413. 10.3389/fcvm.2022.854361</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2022.854361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8964264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35360022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro R. A., Raineki C., Gon&#xe7;alves O., Franci C. R., Lucion A. B., Sanvitto G. L. (2013). Reproductive dysfunction in female rats with renovascular hypertension. Am. J. Hypertens. 26 (1), 104&#x2013;110. 10.1093/ajh/hps026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajh/hps026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23382333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rietjens S. J., Bast A., De Vente J., Haenen G. R. M. M. (2007). The olive oil antioxidant hydroxytyrosol efficiently protects against the oxidative stress-induced impairment of the NO&#x2022; response of isolated rat aorta. Am. J. Physiol. - Heart Circ. Physiol. 292 (4), 1931&#x2013;1936. 10.1152/ajpheart.00755.2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpheart.00755.2006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17172277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigo R., Libuy M., Feli&#xfa; F., Hasson D. (2013). Oxidative stress-related biomarkers in essential hypertension and ischemia-reperfusion myocardial damage. Dis. Markers 35 (6), 773&#x2013;790. 10.1155/2013/974358</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2013/974358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3856219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24347798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Salem M. A., Ezzat S. M., Ahmed K. A., Alseekh S., Fernie A. R., Essam R. M. (2022). A comparative study of the antihypertensive and cardioprotective potentials of hot and cold aqueous extracts of<i>Hibiscus sabdariffa</i> L. In relation to their metabolic profiles. Front. Pharmacol.
13, 840478. 10.3389/fphar.2022.840478
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.840478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8905494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35281911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satoh K., Matoba T., Suzuki J., O&#x2019;Dell M. R., Nigro P., Cui Z., et al. (2008). Cyclophilin a mediates vascular remodeling by promoting inflammation and vascular smooth muscle cell proliferation. Circulation 117 (24), 3088&#x2013;3098. 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.107.756106</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.107.756106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2775430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18541741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satoh K., Nigro P., Matoba T., O&#x2019;Dell M. R., Cui Z., Shi X., et al. (2009). Cyclophilin A enhances vascular oxidative stress and the development of angiotensin II&#x2013;induced aortic aneurysms. Nat. Med. 15 (6), 649&#x2013;656. 10.1038/nm.1958</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm.1958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2704983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19430489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satoh K. (2014). Cyclophilin A in cardiovascular homeostasis and diseases. Tohoku J. Exp. Med. 235 (1), 1&#x2013;15. 10.1620/tjem.235.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1620/tjem.235.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25743766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiffrin E. L. (2015). Mechanisms of remodelling of small arteries, antihypertensive therapy and the immune system in hypertension. Clin. Invest. Med. 38 (6), E394&#x2013;E402. 10.25011/cim.v38i6.26202</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25011/cim.v38i6.26202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26654522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Si L. Y. N., Ramalingam A., Ali S. S., Aminuddin A., Ng P. Y., Latip J. (2019). Roselle attenuates cardiac hypertrophy After <i>in vivo and in vitro</i>
. Excli J.
18, 876&#x2013;892. 10.17179/excli2019-1792
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17179/excli2019-1792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6806200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31645847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh M., Thrimawithana T., Shukla R., Adhikari B. (2021). Extraction and characterization of polyphenolic compounds and potassium hydroxycitrate from Hibiscus sabdariffa. Future Foods 4, 100087. 10.1016/j.fufo.2021.100087</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fufo.2021.100087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song T. F., Huang L. W., Yuan Y., Wang H. Q., He H. P., Ma W. J., et al. (2018). LncRNA MALAT1 regulates smooth muscle cell phenotype switch via activation of autophagy. Oncotarget 9 (4), 4411&#x2013;4426. 10.18632/oncotarget.23230</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/oncotarget.23230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5796983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29435112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soto M. E., Zu&#xf1;iga-Mu&#xf1;oz A., Guarner Lans V., Duran-Hern&#xe1;ndez E. J., P&#xe9;rez-Torres I. (2016). Infusion of Hibiscus sabdariffa L. modulates oxidative stress in patients with marfan syndrome. Mediat. Inflamm., 2016, 8625203. 10.1155/2016/8625203</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2016/8625203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4927999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27413258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spronck B., Latorre M., Wang M., Mehta S., Caulk A. W., Ren P., et al. (2021). Excessive adventitial stress drives inflammation-mediated fibrosis in hypertensive aortic remodelling in mice.J. R. Soc. Interface, 18(180), 20210336. 10.1098/rsif.2021.0336</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rsif.2021.0336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8315831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34314650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szasz T., Tostes R. C. A. (2016). Vascular smooth muscle function in hypertension. Colloquium Ser. Integr. Syst. Physiology Mol. Funct. 8 (3), i&#x2013;96. 10.4199/c00129ed1v01y201503isp061</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4199/c00129ed1v01y201503isp061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanhoutte P. M., Shimokawa H., Feletou M., Tang E. H. C. (2017). Endothelial dysfunction and vascular disease &#x2013; A 30th anniversary update. Acta Physiol. 219 (1), 22&#x2013;96. 10.1111/apha.12646</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apha.12646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26706498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaziri N. D., Ni Z., Oveisi F. (1998). Upregulation of renal and vascular nitric oxide synthase in young spontaneously hypertensive rats. Hypertension 31 (6), 1248&#x2013;1254. 10.1161/01.hyp.31.6.1248</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.hyp.31.6.1248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9622137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D., Xu H., Wu B., Jiang S., Pan H., Wang R., et al. (2019). Long non-coding RNA MALAT1 sponges miR-124-3p.1/KLF5 to promote pulmonary vascular remodeling and cell cycle progression of pulmonary artery hypertension. Int. J. Mol. Med. 44 (3), 871&#x2013;884. 10.3892/ijmm.2019.4256</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/ijmm.2019.4256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6657969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31257528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J., Montaniel K. R. C., Saleh M. A., Xiao L., Chen W., Owens G. K., et al. (2016). Origin of matrix-producing cells that contribute to aortic fibrosis in hypertension. Hypertension 67 (2), 461&#x2013;468. 10.1161/HYPERTENSIONAHA.115.06123</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/HYPERTENSIONAHA.115.06123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4713264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26693821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue Y. Z., Li Z. J., Liu W. T., Shan J. J., Wang L., Su Q. (2019). Down-regulation of lncRNA MALAT1 alleviates vascular lesion and vascular remodeling of rats with hypertension. Aging 11 (14), 5192&#x2013;5205. 10.18632/aging.102113</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/aging.102113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6682528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31343412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin W., Zhao Y., Kang X., Zhao P., Fu X., Mo X., et al. (2020). BBB-penetrating codelivery liposomes treat brain metastasis of non-small cell lung cancer with EGFRT790M mutation. Theranostics 10 (14), 6122&#x2013;6135. 10.7150/thno.42234</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/thno.42234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7255027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32483443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan W., Liu W., Li J., Li X., Sun X., Xu F., et al. (2014). Effects of BMSCs interactions with adventitial fibroblasts in transdifferentiation and ultrastructure processes. Int. J. Clin. Exp. Pathol. 7 (7), 3957&#x2013;3965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4129007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25120772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Luo X., Zhou Y., Wu H., Chen J., Wang Y., et al. (2017). 2K1C-activated Angiotensin II (Ang II) exacerbates vascular damage in a rat model of arthritis through the ATR/ERK1/2 signaling pathway. Inflamm. Res. 66 (10), 881&#x2013;890. 10.1007/s00011-017-1069-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00011-017-1069-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28653218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>