<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39678580</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1943-8141</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of translational research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Transl Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Factors affecting aesthetic results in patients undergoing craniofacial reconstruction following maxillofacial trauma.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>6540</StartPage><EndPage>6551</EndPage><MedlinePgn>6540-6551</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.62347/OGLU3531</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To investigate the factors influencing the cosmetic outcomes and prognosis of patients undergoing maxillofacial trauma reconstruction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A retrospective analysis was conducted on the clinical data of 335 patients who underwent maxillofacial trauma surgery criteria at Yunfu People's Hospital from March 2016 to June 2023. The Face-Q facial cosmetic rating scale was utilized to evaluate outcomes, with scores above 60 deemed the good prognosis group (n=234) and scores below 60 as the poor prognosis group (n=101). Two groups were compared in terms of demographic data, type of trauma, clinical presentation, intraoperative indicators, postoperative serum parameters and nutritional levels, Hamilton Anxiety Scale (HAS), Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI) sleep quality scores. Postoperative recovery and the incidence of complications were documented. Correlation analysis was performed, and Logistic regression analysis was used to determine influencing factors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Patients in the good prognosis group were significantly younger than those in the poor prognosis group (38.15 &#xb1; 10.32 vs. 46.69 &#xb1; 12.15, P &lt; 0.001). Postoperative protein intake (65.81% vs. 33.66%, P &lt; 0.001) and levels of anxiety (5.57 &#xb1; 1.52 vs. 6.61 &#xb1; 1.47, P &lt; 0.001) were also better in the good prognosis group. There were significant differences in scar formation (5.57 &#xb1; 1.52 vs. 6.61 &#xb1; 1.47, P &lt; 0.001), postoperative complications (2.56% vs. 8.91%, P=0.022) and scar hypertrophy (1.28% vs. 6.93%, P=0.015) between the two groups. Logistic regression analysis revealed that age (OR=1.07, 95% CI: 1.039-1.109), protein intake adequacy (OR=0.297, 95% CI: 0.141-0.625), HAS scores (OR=1.295, 95% CI: 1.011-1.658), infection (OR=11.579, 95% CI: 2.656-52.274), and Vancouver Scar Scale (VSS) score (OR=15.672, 95% CI: 7.379-33.285) were significantly associated with aesthetic outcomes. The ROC analysis showed that their combined prediction had an AUC of 0.920, indicating good predictive value.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Younger age, adequate protein intake, lower anxiety scores, better scar assessment, and lower infection rates were associated with better prognosis. These findings emphasize the importance of addressing these factors to optimize outcome in craniofacial trauma reconstruction.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>AJTR Copyright &#xa9; 2024.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zhisheng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Yunfu People's Hospital Yunfu 527300, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Plastic Surgery, Beijing Yuemu Medical Cosmetology Hospital Beijing 101318, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meng</LastName><ForeName>Fanting</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chinese PLA Medical School Beijing 100039, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jin</LastName><ForeName>Mingzhu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chinese PLA Medical School Beijing 100039, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kwon</LastName><ForeName>Hyeogjin</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Plastic Surgery, Beijing Yuemu Medical Cosmetology Hospital Beijing 101318, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhong</LastName><ForeName>Kai</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Yunfu People's Hospital Yunfu 527300, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Transl Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101493030</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1943-8141</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">maxillofacial injuries</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">plastic surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prognosis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39678580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11645561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.62347/OGLU3531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sharifi F, Samieirad S, Grillo R, Da Gra&#xe7;a Nacl&#xe9;rio-Homem M, Bardideh E, Manafi A, Mohammadi Z, Eshghpour M. The causes and prevalence of maxillofacial fractures in Iran: a systematic review. World J Plast Surg. 2023;12:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10200082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37220578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AlMofreh AlQahtani F, Bishawi K, Jaber M, Thomas S. Maxillofacial trauma in the gulf countries: a systematic review. Eur J Trauma Emerg Surg. 2021;47:397&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32572511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gokdogan O. Bone grafting in maxillofacial trauma. Curr Opin Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2022;30:260&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35906979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Othman A, Al-Mofreh Al-Qahtani F, Al-Qahtani H, Jaber M, Bishawi K, Hassan Khamis A, Al-Shanably A. Traumatic brain injuries and maxillofacial fractures: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2023;27:373&#x2013;385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35610526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sifuentes-Cervantes JS, Muzzi D, Castro-N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez J, Guerrero LM, Cunningham LL. Maxillofacial trauma patterns in bare-knuckle fighting. J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2022;80:1663&#x2013;1669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35985420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansod AV, Pisulkar SG, Dahihandekar C, Beri A. Rapid prototyping in maxillofacial rehabilitation: a review of literature. Cureus. 2022;14:e28969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9548214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36237787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S, Kashyap S, Singh S, Sharma R, Singh YP, Naik HY. Maxillofacial trauma among Indians. Bioinformation. 2023;19:876&#x2013;880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10613808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37908612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan TU, Rahat S, Khan ZA, Shahid L, Banouri SS, Muhammad N. Etiology and pattern of maxillofacial trauma. PLoS One. 2022;17:e0275515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9522305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36174089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaber MA, AlQahtani F, Bishawi K, Kuriadom ST. Patterns of maxillofacial injuries in the Middle East and North Africa: a systematic review. Int Dent J. 2021;71:292&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9275196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34286698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omami G, Branstetter BF 4th. Imaging of maxillofacial injuries. Dent Clin North Am. 2024;68:393&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38417997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YH, Wang DR, Liu JY, Pan J. Local anesthesia in oral and maxillofacial surgery: a review of current opinion. J Dent Sci. 2021;16:1055&#x2013;1065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8403808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34484571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou HH, Lv K, Rong-TaoYang, Li Z, Li ZB. Maxillofacial injuries in pediatric patients. J Craniofac Surg. 2021;32:1476&#x2013;1479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33405454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim EJ, Kim CH, Yoon JY, Byeon GJ, Kim HY, Choi EJ. Comparison of postoperative nausea and vomiting between Remimazolam and Propofol in patients undergoing oral and maxillofacial surgery: a prospective randomized controlled trial. BMC Anesthesiol. 2023;23:132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10122311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37085760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preda F, Morgan N, Van Gerven A, Nogueira-Reis F, Smolders A, Wang X, Nomidis S, Shaheen E, Willems H, Jacobs R. Deep convolutional neural network-based automated segmentation of the maxillofacial complex from cone-beam computed tomography: a validation study. J Dent. 2022;124:104238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35872223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanan J, Hui D, Jianwei G, Ronglin L, Lijuan Z, Jing Z. A comparative study on sedation efficacy between general and regional anesthesia with dexmedetomidine in patients under maxillofacial surgery. Curr Drug Metab. 2022;23:920&#x2013;927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35422208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ottenhof MJ, Veldhuizen IJ, Hensbergen LJV, Blankensteijn LL, Bramer W, Lei BV, Hoogbergen MM, Hulst RRWJ, Sidey-Gibbons CJ. The use of the FACE-Q aesthetic: a narrative review. Aesthetic Plast Surg. 2022;46:2769&#x2013;2780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9729314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35764813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerman M, Martinez JH, Young D, Chelminski I, Dalrymple K. Severity classification on the Hamilton Depression Rating Scale. J Affect Disord. 2013;150:384&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23759278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho KY, Lam KKW, Xia W, Chung JOK, Cheung AT, Ho LLK, Chiu SY, Chan GCF, Li WHC. Psychometric properties of the Chinese version of the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI) among Hong Kong Chinese childhood cancer survivors. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2021;19:176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8261921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34229705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pullos AN, Krishnan DG. Complicated maxillofacial fractures: pediatric and geriatric. Atlas Oral Maxillofac Surg Clin North Am. 2019;27:113&#x2013;118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31345486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfaardt JF, Brecht LE, Taft RM. The future of maxillofacial prosthodontics in North America: part I-journey to the present. J Prosthet Dent. 2022;127:345&#x2013;350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33431175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wusiman P, Maimaitituerxun B, Guli, Saimaiti A, Moming A. Epidemiology and pattern of oral and maxillofacial trauma. J Craniofac Surg. 2020;31:e517&#x2013;e520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32569059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benton MJ, Hutchins AM. The relationship between resting metabolic rate and quality of life is moderated by age and body composition in women: a cross-sectional study. BMC Womens Health. 2024;24:235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11015637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38615006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen K, Dai J, Kl&#xf6;ting N, Cao X, Jin S, Chen L, Wang Y, Liu S, Hu Y, Jiang L, Liew CW, Bl&#xfc;her M, Wang X. Serum scEMC10 levels are negatively associated with resting metabolic rate and age in humans. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2023;108:e1074&#x2013;e1081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37071730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe1;squez-Alvarez S, Bustamante-Villagomez SK, Vazquez-Marroquin G, Porchia LM, P&#xe9;rez-Fuentes R, Torres-Rasgado E, Herrera-Fomperosa O, Montes-Arana I, Gonzalez-Mejia ME. Metabolic age, an index based on basal metabolic rate, can predict individuals that are high risk of developing metabolic syndrome. High Blood Press Cardiovasc Prev. 2021;28:263&#x2013;270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33666897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Wang T. Understanding protein functions in the biological context. Protein Pept Lett. 2023;30:449&#x2013;458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37151077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franco-Valencia K, N&#xf3;brega IBC, Cantaruti T, Barra A, Klein A, Azevedo-Jr GM, Costa RA, Carvalho CR. Subcutaneous injection of an immunologically tolerated protein up to 5 days before skin injuries improves wound healing. Braz J Med Biol Res. 2022;55:e11735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8851940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35170683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He W, Xu J, Zheng Y, Chen J, Yin Y, Mosselhy DA, Zou F, Ma M, Liu X. Bacterial cellulose/soybean protein isolate composites with promoted inflammation inhibition, angiogenesis and hair follicle regeneration for wound healing. Int J Biol Macromol. 2022;211:754&#x2013;766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35469946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thederan I, Zyriax BC, Heinzer H. Role of nutrition in urological prehabilitation. Urologie. 2023;62:1017&#x2013;1024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37704860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basu S, Goswami AG, David LE, Mudge E. Psychological stress on wound healing: a silent player in a complex background. Int J Low Extrem Wounds. 2022 [Epub ahead of print]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35102769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedayati J, Bagheri-Nesami M, Elyasi F, Hosseinnataj A. The effect of music therapy on the pain and anxiety levels of patients experiencing wound healing by suturing in the emergency wards. Anesth Pain Med. 2023;13:e132943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10319044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37409003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar N, Huda F, Mani R, Singla T, Kundal A, Sharma J, Gajula B. Role of hospital anxiety and depression on the healing of chronic leg ulcer: a prospective study. Int Wound J. 2020;17:1941&#x2013;1947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7948636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32844523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry A, Dawoud B, Kent S, McDonald C, Logan G, Hennedige A, Exely R, Regan A, Kulkarni R, Gilbert K, Basyuni S, Young D, Kyzas P, Morrison R, McCaul J List of collaborators who participated in the Cervicofacial Infection Study. Clinical features and presentation of cervicofacial infection: a maxillofacial trainee research collaborative (MTReC) study. Br J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2021;59:433&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33715891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu B, Tong G, Gao P, Yan M. Evaluating the impact of recombinant human epidermal growth factor on scar formation in oral and maxillofacial traumatic wound healing. Int Wound J. 2024;21:e14851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10985544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38563121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>