<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">23430911</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2192-8304</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>5</Volume><PubDate><Year>2012</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JIMD reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JIMD Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Heart Failure Due to Severe Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy Reversed by Low Calorie, High Protein Dietary Adjustments in a Glycogen Storage Disease Type IIIa Patient.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>13</StartPage><EndPage>16</EndPage><MedlinePgn>13-6</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/8904_2011_111</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In glycogen storage disease type III (GSD III), deficiency of the debranching enzyme causes storage of an intermediate glycogen molecule (limit dextrin) in the affected tissues. In subtype IIIa hepatic tissue, skeletal- and cardiac muscle tissue is affected, while in subtype IIIb only hepatic tissue is affected. Cardiac storage of limit dextrin causes a form of cardiomyopathy, which resembles primary hypertrophic cardiomyopathy on cardiac ultrasound. We present a 32-year-old GSD IIIa patient with severe left ventricular hypertrophy (LVH) first diagnosed at the age of 8 years. LVH remained stable and symptomless until the patient presented at age 25 years with increasing dyspnea, fatigue, obesity, and NYHA (New York Heart Association) functional classification two out of four. Dyspnea, fatigue, and obesity progressed, and at age 28 years she was severely symptomatic with NYHA classification 3+ out of 4. On echocardiogram and electrocardiogram, the LVH had progressed as well. Initially, she was rejected for cardiac transplantation because of severe obesity. Therefore, a 900 cal, high protein diet providing 37% of total energy was prescribed during 4 months on which 10 kg weight loss was achieved. However, her symptoms as well as the electrocardiographic and echocardiographic LVH indices had improved dramatically - ultimately deferring cardiac transplantation. Thereafter, the caloric intake was increased to 1,370 cal per day, and the high protein intake was continued providing 43% of total energy. After 3 years of follow-up, the patient remains satisfied with reasonable exercise tolerance and minor symptoms in daily life.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sentner</LastName><ForeName>Christiaan P</ForeName><Initials>CP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Metabolic Diseases, Beatrix Children's Hospital, University Medical Centre Groningen, Hanzeplein 1, 30.001, 9700 RB, Groningen, The Netherlands, c.p.sentner@bkk.umcg.nl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caliskan</LastName><ForeName>Kadir</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vletter</LastName><ForeName>Wim B</ForeName><Initials>WB</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smit</LastName><ForeName>G Peter A</ForeName><Initials>GP</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JIMD Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101568557</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2192-8304</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2011</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2011</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2011</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23430911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3509915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/8904_2011_111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Akazawa H, Kuroda T, Kim S, Mito H, Kojo T, Shimada K. Specific heart muscle disease associated with glycogen storage disease type III: clinical similarity to the dilated phase of hypertrophic cardiomyopathy. Eur Heart J. 1997;18:532&#x2013;533. doi: 10.1093/oxfordjournals.eurheartj.a015283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/oxfordjournals.eurheartj.a015283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9076400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho JS, Matthews EE, Leonard JV, Deanfield J. Cardiomyopathy of glycogen storage disease type III. Heart Vessels. 1993;8:155&#x2013;159. doi: 10.1007/BF01744800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01744800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8407725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YT, et al. Glycogen storage diseases. In: Scriver CR, et al., editors. The metabolic and molecular bases of inherited disease. New York: McGraw-Hill Professional; 2001. pp. 1521&#x2013;1551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coleman RA, Winter HS, Wolf B, Gilchrist JM, Chen YT. Glycogen storage disease type III (glycogen debranching enzyme deficiency): correlation of biochemical defects with myopathy and cardiomyopathy. Ann Intern Med. 1992;116:896&#x2013;900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1580445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dagli AI, Zori RT, McCune H, Ivsic T, Maisenbacher MK, Weinstein DA (2009) Reversal of glycogen storage disease type IIIa-related cardiomyopathy with modification of diet. J Inherit Metab Dis Epub Mar 30</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3808093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19322675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodpaster BH, Kelley DE, Wing RR, Meier A, Theate FL. Effects of weight loss on insulin sensitivity in obesity &#x2013; influence of regional adiposity. Diabetes. 1999;48:839&#x2013;847. doi: 10.2337/diabetes.48.4.839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diabetes.48.4.839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10102702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gremse DA, Bucuvalas JC, Balisteri WF. Efficacy of cornstarch therapy in type III glycogen-storage disease. Am J Clin Nutr. 1990;52:671&#x2013;674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2403059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley DE, Slasky S, Janosky J. Effects of obesity and non-insulin dependent diabetes mellitus. Am J Clin Nutr. 1991;54:509&#x2013;515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1877507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiechl S, Willeit J, Vogel W, Kohlendorfer U, Poewe W. Reversible severe myopathy of respiratory muscles due to adult-onset type III glycogenosis. Neuromuscul Disord. 1999;9:408&#x2013;410. doi: 10.1016/S0960-8966(99)00038-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0960-8966(99)00038-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10545045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labrune P, Huguet P, Odievre M. Cardiomyopathy in glycogen-storage disease type III: clinical and echographic study of 18 patients. Pediatr Cardiol. 1991;12:161&#x2013;163. doi: 10.1007/BF02238523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02238523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1876514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee PJ, Deanfield JE, Burch M, Baig K, McKenna WJ, Leonard JV. Comparison of the functional significance of left ventricular hypertrophy in hypertrophic cardiomyopathy and glycogenosis type III. Am J Cardiol. 1997;79:834&#x2013;838. doi: 10.1016/S0002-9149(96)00885-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0002-9149(96)00885-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9070576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucchiari S, Pagliarani S, Salani S, et al. Hepatic and neuromuscular forms of glycogenosis type III: nine mutations in AGL. Hum Mutat. 2006;27:600&#x2013;601. doi: 10.1002/humu.9426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/humu.9426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16705713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moses SW, Wanderman KL, Myroz A, Frydman M. Cardiac involvement in glycogen storage disease type III. Eur J Pediatr. 1989;148:764&#x2013;766. doi: 10.1007/BF00443106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00443106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2792130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olson LJ, Reeder GS, Noller KL, Edwards WD, Howell RR, Michels VV. Cardiac involvement in glycogen storage disease III: morphologic and biochemical characterization with endomyocardial biopsy. Am J Cardiol. 1984;53:980&#x2013;981. doi: 10.1016/0002-9149(84)90551-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0002-9149(84)90551-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6584026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen J, Bao Y, Liu HM, Lee PJ, Leonard JV, Chen YT. Mutations in exon 3 of the glycogen debranching enzyme gene are associated with glycogen storage disease type III that is differentially expressed in liver and muscle. J Clin Invest. 1996;98:352&#x2013;357. doi: 10.1172/JCI118799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI118799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC507437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8755644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slonim AE, Weisberg C, Benke P, Evans OB, Burr IM. Reversal of debrancher deficiency myopathy by the use of high-protein nutrition. Ann Neurol. 1982;11:420&#x2013;422. doi: 10.1002/ana.410110417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.410110417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7049057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slonim AE, Coleman RA, Moses SW. Myopathy and growth failure in debrancher enzyme deficiency: improvement with high protein noctural enteral therapy. J Pediatr. 1984;105:906&#x2013;911. doi: 10.1016/S0022-3476(84)80075-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-3476(84)80075-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6438290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smit GP, Fernandes J, Leonard JV, et al. The long-term outcome of patients with glycogen storage diseases. J Inherit Metab Dis. 1990;13:411&#x2013;418. doi: 10.1007/BF01799498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01799498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2122109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smit GPA, Rake JP, Akman HO, DiMauro S. The glycogen storage diseases and related disorders. In: Fernandes J, Saudubray J-M, van den Berghe G, Walter JH, editors. Inborn metabolic diseases: diagnosis and treatment. Heidelberg: Springer Medizin; 2006. pp. 103&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talente GM, Coleman RA, Alter C, et al. Glycogen storage disease in adults. Ann Intern Med. 1994;120:218&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8273986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valayannopoulos V, Bajolle F, Arnoux JB, et al. Successful treatment of severe cardiomyopathy in glycogen storage disease type III with D,L-3-hydroxybutyrate, ketogenic and high protein diet. Pediatr Res. 2011;70(6):638&#x2013;641. doi: 10.1203/PDR.0b013e318232154f.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1203/PDR.0b013e318232154f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21857385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfsdorf JI, Weinstein DA. Glycogen storage diseases. Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2003;4:95&#x2013;102. doi: 10.1023/A:1021831621210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1021831621210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12618563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>