<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">25172377</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2015</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-0739</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2014</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nutrition research (New York, N.Y.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nutr Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Dietary fatty acids alter left ventricular myocardial gene expression in Wistar rats.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>694</StartPage><EndPage>706</EndPage><MedlinePgn>694-706</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.nutres.2014.07.011</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0271-5317(14)00118-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Obesity increases the risk for cardiomyopathy in the absence of comorbidities. Myocardial structure is modified by dietary fatty acids. Left ventricular hypertrophy is associated with Western (WES) diet consumption, whereas intake of n-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids is associated with antihypertrophic effects. We previously observed no attenuation of left ventricular thickening after 3 months of docosahexaenoic acid (DHA) supplementation of a WES diet, compared with WES diet intake alone, in rats that had similar weight, adiposity, and insulin sensitivity to control animals. The objective of this study was to define left ventricular gene expression in these animals to determine whether diet alone was associated with a physiologic or pathologic hypertrophic response. We hypothesized that WES diet consumption would favor a pathologic or maladaptive myocardial gene expression pattern and that DHA supplementation would favor a physiologic or adaptive response. Microarray analysis identified 64 transcripts that were differentially expressed (P &#x2264; .001) within one or more treatment comparisons. Using quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction, 29 genes with fold change at least 1.74 were successfully validated; all but 3 had similar directionality to that observed using microarray, and 2 genes, connective tissue growth factor and cathepsin M, were differentially expressed according to diet. WES blot analysis was performed on 4 proteins relevant to myocardial hypertrophy and metabolism. Acyl-CoA thioesterase 1, B-cell translocation gene 2, and carbonic anhydrase III showed directional change consistent with gene expression. Retinol saturase (all-trans-retinol 13,14-reductase), although not consistent with gene expression, was different according to diet, with increased concentrations in WES-fed rats compared with control and DHA-supplemented animals. Diet did not distinguish a transcriptome reflecting physiologic or pathologic myocardial hypertrophy; furthermore, the modest changes observed suggest that obesity and associated comorbidities may play a larger role than mere dietary fatty acid composition in development of cardiomyopathy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2014 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeckel</LastName><ForeName>Kimberly M</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, College of Veterinary Medicine and Biomedical Sciences, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO 80523. Electronic address: kjeckel@mail.colostate.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bouma</LastName><ForeName>Gerrit J</ForeName><Initials>GJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, College of Veterinary Medicine and Biomedical Sciences, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO 80523.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hess</LastName><ForeName>Ann M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics, College of Natural Sciences, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO 80523.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Petrilli</LastName><ForeName>Erin B</ForeName><Initials>EB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infectious Disease Research Center, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO 80523.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Frye</LastName><ForeName>Melinda A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, College of Veterinary Medicine and Biomedical Sciences, Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO 80523.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K01 OD010971</GrantID><Acronym>OD</Acronym><Agency>NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K01-0D010971-03</GrantID><Agency>PHS HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2014</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Nutr Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8303331</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0271-5317</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004041">Dietary Fats</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005227">Fatty Acids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>25167-62-8</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004281">Docosahexaenoic Acids</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009202" MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiomyopathies</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066273" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diet, Western</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004041" MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary Fats</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019587" MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary Supplements</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004281" MajorTopicYN="N">Docosahexaenoic Acids</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005227" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatty Acids</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015870" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Expression</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006352" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Ventricles</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D046228" MajorTopicYN="N">Microarray Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009206" MajorTopicYN="N">Myocardium</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017208" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats, Wistar</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060888" MajorTopicYN="N">Real-Time Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059467" MajorTopicYN="N">Transcriptome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiomyopathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Docosahexaenoic acid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gene expression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High-fat diet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Left ventricular hypertrophy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rat</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2014</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2014</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2014</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2014</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2015</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25172377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS624589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4265552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nutres.2014.07.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0271-5317(14)00118-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Poudyal H, Campbell F, Brown L. Olive leaf extract attenuates cardiac, hepatic, and metabolic changes in high carbohydrate-, high fat-fed rats. J Nutr. 2010;140:946&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20335636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyer A, Brown L. Fermented wheat germ extract (avemar) in the treatment of cardiac remodeling and metabolic symptoms in rats. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2011;2011:508957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3135775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19622599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeckel KM, Veeramachaneni DN, Chicco AJ, Chapman PL, Mulligan CM, Hegarty JR, et al. Docosahexaenoic acid supplementation does not improve Western diet-induced cardiomyopathy in rats. PLoS One. 2012;7:e51994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3530602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23300587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duda MK, O&#x2019;Shea KM, Tintinu A, Xu W, Khairallah RJ, Barrows BR, et al. Fish oil, but not flaxseed oil, decreases inflammation and prevents pressure overload-induced cardiac dysfunction. Cardiovasc Res. 2008;81:319&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2721645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19015135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Y, Favre J, Vercauteren M, Laillet B, Remy-Jouet I, Skiba M, et al. Reduced cardiac remodelling and prevention of glutathione deficiency after omega-3 supplementation in chronic heart failure. Fundam Clin Pharmacol. 2011;25:323&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20584202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halade GV, Williams PJ, Lindsey ML, Fernandes G. Fish oil decreases inflammation and reduces cardiac remodeling in rosiglitazone treated aging mice. Pharmacol Res. 2011;63:300&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3326603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21193042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poudyal H, Panchal SK, Waanders J, Ward L, Brown L. Lipid redistribution by alpha-linolenic acid-rich chia seed inhibits stearoyl-CoA desaturase-1 and induces cardiac and hepatic protection in diet-induced obese rats. J Nutr Biochem. 2011;23:153&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21429727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong SW, Bodyak N, Yue P, Liu Z, Brown J, Izumo S, et al. Genetic expression profiles during physiological and pathological cardiac hypertrophy and heart failure in rats. Physiol Genomics. 2005;21:34&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15623566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luczak ED, Barthel KK, Stauffer BL, Konhilas JP, Cheung TH, Leinwand LA. Remodeling the cardiac transcriptional landscape with diet. Physiol Genomics. 2011;43:772&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3121157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21487031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bordoni A, Astolfi A, Morandi L, Pession A, Danesi F, Di Nunzio M, et al. N-3 PUFAs modulate global gene expression profile in cultured rat cardiomyocytes. Implications in cardiac hypertrophy and heart failure. FEBS Lett. 2007;581:923&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17303130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgiadi A, Boekschoten MV, Muller M, Kersten S. Detailed transcriptomics analysis of the effect of dietary fatty acids on gene expression in the heart. Physiol Genomics. 2012;44:352&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22274564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayalew-Pervanchon A, Rousseau D, Moreau D, Assayag P, Weill P, Grynberg A. Long-term effect of dietary {alpha}-linolenic acid or decosahexaenoic acid on incorporation of decosahexaenoic acid in membranes and its influence on rat heart in vivo. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2007;293:H2296&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17526653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendziorski C, Irizarry RA, Chen KS, Haag JD, Gould MN. On the utility of pooling biological samples in microarray experiments. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2005;102:4252&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC552978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15755808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentleman RC, Carey VJ, Bates DM, Bolstad B, Dettling M, Dudoit S, et al. Bioconductor: open software development for computational biology and bioinformatics. Genome Biol. 2004;5:R80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC545600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15461798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irizarry RA, Hobbs B, Collin F, Beazer-Barclay YD, Antonellis KJ, Scherf U, et al. Exploration, normalization, and summaries of high density oligonucleotide array probe level data. Biostatistics. 2003;4:249&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12925520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smyth GK. Linear models and empirical bayes methods for assessing differential expression in microarray experiments. Stat Appl Genet Mol Biol. 2004;3:Article3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16646809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamini Y, Hochberg Y. Controlling the false discovery rate: A practical and powerful approach to multiple testing. J R Stat Series B Stat Methodol. 1995;57:289&#x2013;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edgar R, Domrachev M, Lash AE. Gene Expression Omnibus: NCBI gene expression and hybridization array data repository. Nucleic Acids Res. 2002;30:207&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC99122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11752295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robert P, Tsui P, Laville MP, Livi GP, Sarau HM, Bril A, et al. EDG1 receptor stimulation leads to cardiac hypertrophy in rat neonatal myocytes. J Mol Cell Cardiol. 2001;33:1589&#x2013;606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11549339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore XL, Tan SL, Lo CY, Fang L, Su YD, Gao XM, et al. Relaxin antagonizes hypertrophy and apoptosis in neonatal rat cardiomyocytes. Endocrinology. 2007;148:1582&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17204550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takefuji M, Wirth A, Lukasova M, Takefuji S, Boettger T, Braun T, et al. G(13)-mediated signaling pathway is required for pressure overload-induced cardiac remodeling and heart failure. Circulation. 2012;126:1972&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22972902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larocca TJ, Jeong D, Kohlbrenner E, Lee A, Chen J, Hajjar RJ, et al. CXCR4 gene transfer prevents pressure overload induced heart failure. J Mol Cell Cardiol. 2012;53:223&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3409693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22668785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White DE, Coutu P, Shi YF, Tardif JC, Nattel S, St Arnaud R, et al. Targeted ablation of ILK from the murine heart results in dilated cardiomyopathy and spontaneous heart failure. Genes Dev. 2006;20:2355&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1560410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16951252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schram K, Ganguly R, No EK, Fang X, Thong FS, Sweeney G. Regulation of MT1-MMP and MMP-2 by leptin in cardiac fibroblasts involves Rho/ROCK-dependent actin cytoskeletal reorganization and leads to enhanced cell migration. Endocrinology. 2011;152:2037&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21385940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vistnes M, Waehre A, Nygard S, Sjaastad I, Andersson KB, Husberg C, et al. Circulating cytokine levels in mice with heart failure are etiology dependent. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2010;108:1357&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20224000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappuzzello C, Di Vito L, Melchionna R, Melillo G, Silvestri L, Cesareo E, et al. Increase of plasma IL-9 and decrease of plasma IL-5, IL-7, and IFN-gamma in patients with chronic heart failure. J Transl Med. 2011;9:28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3068954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21418620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatterjee A, Mir SA, Dutta D, Mitra A, Pathak K, Sarkar S. Analysis of p53 and NF-kappaB signaling in modulating the cardiomyocyte fate during hypertrophy. J Cell Physiol. 2011;226:2543&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21792911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sano M, Minamino T, Toko H, Miyauchi H, Orimo M, Qin Y, et al. p53-induced inhibition of Hif-1 causes cardiac dysfunction during pressure overload. Nature. 2007;446:444&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17334357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Ichikawa T, Villacorta L, Janicki JS, Brower GL, Yamamoto M, et al. Nrf2 protects against maladaptive cardiac responses to hemodynamic stress. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2009;29:1843&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19592468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guleria RS, Singh AB, Nizamutdinova IT, Souslova T, Mohammad AA, Kendall JA, Jr, et al. Activation of retinoid receptor-mediated signaling ameliorates diabetes-induced cardiac dysfunction in Zucker diabetic rats. J Mol Cell Cardiol. 2013;57:106&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3594065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23395853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagai R, Shindo T, Manabe I, Suzuki T, Kurabayashi M. KLF5/BTEB2, a Kruppel-like zinc-finger type transcription factor, mediates both smooth muscle cell activation and cardiac hypertrophy. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2003;538:57&#x2013;65. discussion 6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15098654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McManus DD, Lyass A, Ingelsson E, Massaro JM, Meigs JB, Aragam J, et al. Relations of Circulating Resistin and Adiponectin and Cardiac Structure and Function: The Framingham Offspring Study. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3716016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21350435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin RH, Mathews ST, Alli A, Leff T. Endogenously produced adiponectin protects cardiomyocytes from hypertrophy by a PPARgamma-dependent autocrine mechanism. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2010;299:H690&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2944479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20622112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Essick EE, Ouchi N, Wilson RM, Ohashi K, Ghobrial J, Shibata R, et al. Adiponectin mediates cardioprotection in oxidative stress-induced cardiac myocyte remodeling. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2011;301:H984&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3191107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21666115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hein S, Kostin S, Heling A, Maeno Y, Schaper J. The role of the cytoskeleton in heart failure. Cardiovasc Res. 2000;45:273&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10728347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philip-Couderc P, Smih F, Pelat M, Vidal C, Verwaerde P, Pathak A, et al. Cardiac transcriptome analysis in obesity-related hypertension. Hypertension. 2003;41:414&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12623937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philip-Couderc P, Smih F, Hall JE, Pathak A, Roncalli J, Harmancey R, et al. Kinetic analysis of cardiac transcriptome regulation during chronic high-fat diet in dogs. Physiol Genomics. 2004;19:32&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15226482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moise AR, Kuksa V, Imanishi Y, Palczewski K. Identification of all-trans-retinol:all-trans-13,14-dihydroretinol saturase. J Biol Chem. 2004;279:50230&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2665716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15358783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schupp M, Lefterova MI, Janke J, Leitner K, Cristancho AG, Mullican SE, et al. Retinol saturase promotes adipogenesis and is downregulated in obesity. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2009;106:1105&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2633572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19139408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kline KG, Frewen B, Bristow MR, Maccoss MJ, Wu CC. High quality catalog of proteotypic peptides from human heart. J Proteome Res. 2008;7:5055&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2765113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18803417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tikellis C, Thomas MC, Harcourt BE, Coughlan MT, Pete J, Bialkowski K, et al. Cardiac inflammation associated with a Western diet is mediated via activation of RAGE by AGEs. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2008;295:E323&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2652498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18477705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poudyal H, Panchal SK, Ward LC, Brown L. Effects of ALA, EPA and DHA in high-carbohydrate, high-fat diet-induced metabolic syndrome in rats. J Nutr Biochem. 2013;24:1041&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23026492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagaoka-Yasuda R, Matsuo N, Perkins B, Limbaeck-Stokin K, Mayford M. An RNAi-based genetic screen for oxidative stress resistance reveals retinol saturase as a mediator of stress resistance. Free Radic Biol Med. 2007;43:781&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17664141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#x2019;Abbe MR, Trick KD, Beare-Rogers JL. Dietary (n-3) fatty acids affect rat heart, liver and aorta protective enzyme activities and lipid peroxidation. J Nutr. 1991;121:1331&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1880611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunkar T, Aktan F, Ceylan A, Karasu C. Effects of cod liver oil on tissue antioxidant pathways in normal and streptozotocin-diabetic rats. Cell Biochem Funct. 2002;20:297&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12415563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballal K, Wilson CR, Harmancey R, Taegtmeyer H. Obesogenic high fat western diet induces oxidative stress and apoptosis in rat heart. Mol Cell Biochem. 2010;344:221&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3656656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20676734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutknecht J, Bisson MA, Tosteson FC. Diffusion of carbon dioxide through lipid bilayer membranes: effects of carbonic anhydrase, bicarbonate, and unstirred layers. J Gen Physiol. 1977;69:779&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2215341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">408462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughan-Jones RD, Spitzer KW, Swietach P. Intracellular pH regulation in heart. J Mol Cell Cardiol. 2009;46:318&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19041875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterling D, Reithmeier RA, Casey JR. A transport metabolon. Functional interaction of carbonic anhydrase II and chloride/bicarbonate exchangers. J Biol Chem. 2001;276:47886&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11606574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orchard CH, Kentish JC. Effects of changes of pH on the contractile function of cardiac muscle. Am J Physiol. 1990;258:C967&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2193525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen DG, Orchard CH. The effects of changes of pH on intracellular calcium transients in mammalian cardiac muscle. J Physiol. 1983;335:555&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1197369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6410050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schroeder MA, Ali MA, Hulikova A, Supuran CT, Clarke K, Vaughan-Jones RD, et al. Extramitochondrial domain rich in carbonic anhydrase activity improves myocardial energetics. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2013;110:E958&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3593844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23431149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvarez BV, Quon AL, Mullen J, Casey JR. Quantification of carbonic anhydrase gene expression in ventricle of hypertrophic and failing human heart. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2013;13:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3570296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23297731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koester MK, Pullan LM, Noltmann EA. The p-nitrophenyl phosphatase activity of muscle carbonic anhydrase. Arch Biochem Biophys. 1981;211:632&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6272648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raisanen SR, Lehenkari P, Tasanen M, Rahkila P, Harkonen PL, Vaananen HK. Carbonic anhydrase III protects cells from hydrogen peroxide-induced apoptosis. FASEB J. 1999;13:513&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10064618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvarez BV, Johnson DE, Sowah D, Soliman D, Light PE, Xia Y, et al. Carbonic anhydrase inhibition prevents and reverts cardiomyocyte hypertrophy. J Physiol. 2007;579:127&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2075384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17124262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vargas LA, Alvarez BV. Carbonic anhydrase XIV in the normal and hypertrophic myocardium. J Mol Cell Cardiol. 2012;52:741&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22227327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tashian RE. The carbonic anhydrases: widening perspectives on their evolution, expression and function. Bioessays. 1989;10:186&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2500929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunt MC, Alexson SE. The role Acyl-CoA thioesterases play in mediating intracellular lipid metabolism. Prog Lipid Res. 2002;41:99&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11755680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durgan DJ, Smith JK, Hotze MA, Egbejimi O, Cuthbert KD, Zaha VG, et al. Distinct transcriptional regulation of long-chain acyl-CoA synthetase isoforms and cytosolic thioesterase 1 in the rodent heart by fatty acids and insulin. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2006;290:H2480&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16428347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita M, Momose A, Ohtomo T, Nishinosono A, Tanonaka K, Toyoda H, et al. Upregulation of fatty acyl-CoA thioesterases in the heart and skeletal muscle of rats fed a high-fat diet. Biol Pharm Bull. 2011;34:87&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21212523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson CR, Tran MK, Salazar KL, Young ME, Taegtmeyer H. Western diet, but not high fat diet, causes derangements of fatty acid metabolism and contractile dysfunction in the heart of Wistar rats. Biochem J. 2007;406:457&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2049036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17550347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Nunzio M, Danesi F, Bordoni A. n-3 PUFA as regulators of cardiac gene transcription: a new link between PPAR activation and fatty acid composition. Lipids. 2009;44:1073&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19859757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donato LJ, Suh JH, Noy N. Suppression of mammary carcinoma cell growth by retinoic acid: the cell cycle control gene Btg2 is a direct target for retinoic acid receptor signaling. Cancer Res. 2007;67:609&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17234770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawakubo H, Brachtel E, Hayashida T, Yeo G, Kish J, Muzikansky A, et al. Loss of B-cell translocation gene-2 in estrogen receptor-positive breast carcinoma is associated with tumor grade and overexpression of cyclin d1 protein. Cancer Res. 2006;66:7075&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16849553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Z, Tang ZL, Li K, Liu B, Yu M, Zhao SH. Molecular characterization of the BTG2 and BTG3 genes in fetal muscle development of pigs. Gene. 2007;403:170&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17890019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karve TM, Rosen EM. B-cell translocation gene 2 (BTG2) stimulates cellular antioxidant defenses through the antioxidant transcription factor NFE2L2 in human mammary epithelial cells. J Biol Chem. 2012;287:31503&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3438983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22493435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>