<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">18799550</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2009</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1931-857X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>295</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2008</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of physiology. Renal physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Physiol Renal Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>VEGF-121 preserves renal microvessel structure and ameliorates secondary renal disease following acute kidney injury.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>F1648</StartPage><EndPage>F1657</EndPage><MedlinePgn>F1648-57</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1152/ajprenal.00099.2008</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Acute kidney injury induced by renal ischemia-reperfusion (I/R) compromises microvascular density and predisposes to chronic kidney disease (CKD) and sodium-dependent hypertension. VEGF-121 was administered to rats fed a standard (0.4%) sodium diet at various times following recovery from I/R injury for up to 35 days. VEGF-121 had no effect on the initial loss of renal function, as indicated by serum creatinine levels measured 24 h after injury. Serum creatinine levels declined thereafter, indicative of renal repair. Rats were then switched to an elevated (4.0%) sodium diet for an additional 28 days to induce CKD. The 4.0% sodium diet enhanced renal hypertrophy, interstitial volume, albuminuria, and cardiac hypertrophy relative to postischemic animals maintained on the 0.4% sodium diet. Administration of VEGF-121 from day 0 to 14, day 0 to 35, or day 3 to 35 after I/R suppressed the effects of sodium diet on CKD development, while delayed administration of VEGF-121 from day 21 to 35 had no effect. Endothelial nitric oxide synthase protein levels were upregulated in postischemic animals, and this effect was significantly increased by the 4.0% sodium diet but was not influenced by prior treatment with VEGF. Conversely, microvascular density was preserved in postischemic animals treated with VEGF-121 relative to vehicle-treated postischemic animals. These data suggest that early, but not delayed, treatment with VEGF-121 can preserve vascular structure after ischemia and influence chronic renal function in response to elevated sodium intake.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leonard</LastName><ForeName>Ellen C</ForeName><Initials>EC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dept. of Cellular and Integrative Physiology, Indiana Univ. School of Medicine, 635 Barnhill Dr. MS 334, Indianapolis, IN 46202, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Friedrich</LastName><ForeName>Jessica L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Basile</LastName><ForeName>David P</ForeName><Initials>DP</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 DK063114</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>DK-63114</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2008</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Physiol Renal Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100901990</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1522-1466</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017673">Sodium Chloride, Dietary</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D042461">Vascular Endothelial Growth Factor A</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C467498">vascular endothelial growth factor A, rat</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>AYI8EX34EU</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003404">Creatinine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058186" MajorTopicYN="N">Acute Kidney Injury</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="Y">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003404" MajorTopicYN="N">Creatinine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007668" MajorTopicYN="N">Kidney</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000293" MajorTopicYN="Y">injuries</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007677" MajorTopicYN="N">Kidney Function Tests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008833" MajorTopicYN="N">Microcirculation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017207" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats, Sprague-Dawley</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012079" MajorTopicYN="N">Renal Circulation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017673" MajorTopicYN="N">Sodium Chloride, Dietary</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D042461" MajorTopicYN="N">Vascular Endothelial Growth Factor A</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2008</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2009</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2008</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2009</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18799550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2604827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajprenal.00099.2008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00099.2008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bacallao R, Fine LG. Molecular events in the organization of renal tubular epithelium: from nephrogenesis to regeneration. Am J Physiol Renal Fluid Electrolyte Physiol 257: F913&#x2013;F924, 1989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2690642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basile DP The endothelial cell in ischemic acute kidney injury: implications for acute and chronic function. Kidney Int 72: 151&#x2013;156, 2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17495858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basile DP Rarefaction of peritubular capillaries following ischemic acute renal failure: a potential factor predisposing progressive nephropathy. Curr Opin Nephrol Hypertens 13: 1&#x2013;13, 2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15090853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basile DP, Donohoe DL, Roethe K, Mattson DL. Chronic renal hypoxia following ischemia/reperfusion injury: effects of l-arginine on hypoxia and secondary damage. Am J Physiol Renal Physiol 284: F338&#x2013;F348, 2003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12388385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basile DP, Donohoe DL, Roethe K, Osborn JL. Renal ischemic injury results in permanent damage to peritubular capillaries and influences long-term function. Am J Physiol Renal Physiol 281: F887&#x2013;F899, 2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11592947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basile DP, Fredrich K, Chelladurai B, Leonard EC, Parrish AR. Renal ischemia reperfusion inhibits VEGF expression and induces ADAMTS-1, a novel VEGF inhibitor. Am J Physiol Renal Physiol 294: F928&#x2013;F936, 2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18272597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basile DP, Fredrich K, Weihrauch DW, Hattan N, Chilian WM. Angiostatin and matrix metalloprotease expression following ischemic acute renal failure. Am J Physiol Renal Physiol 286: F893&#x2013;F902, 2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15075185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charron AJ, Xu W, Bacallao RL, Wandinger-Ness A. Cablin: a novel protein of the capillary basal lamina. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 277: H1985&#x2013;H1996, 1999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10564155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devarajan P Update on the mechanisms of ischemic acute kidney injury. J Am Soc Nephrol 17: 1503&#x2013;1517, 2006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16707563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammerman MR Growth factors and apoptosis in acute renal injury. Curr Opin Nephrol Hypertens 7: 419&#x2013;424, 1998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9690042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson RJ, Gordon KL, Suga S, Duijvestijn AM, Griffin K, Bidani A. Renal injury and salt-sensitive hypertension after exposure to catecholamines. Hypertension 34: 151&#x2013;159, 1999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10406839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson RJ, Schreiner GF. Hypothesis: the role of acquired tubulointerstitial disease in the pathogenesis of salt-dependent hypertension. Kidney Int 52: 1169&#x2013;1179, 1997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9350640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang DH, Hughes J, Mazzali M, Schreiner GF, Johnson RJ. Impaired angiogenesis in the remnant kidney model. II. Vascular endothelial growth factor administration reduces renal fibrosis and stabilizes renal function. J Am Soc Nephrol 12: 1448&#x2013;1457, 2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11423573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang DH, Kanellis J, Hugo C, Truong L, Anderson S, Kerjaschki D, Schreiner GF, Johnson R. Role of the microvascular endothelium in progressive renal disease. J Am Soc Nephrol 13: 806&#x2013;816, 2002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11856789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang DH, Kim YG, Andoh TF, Gordon KL, Suga S, Mazzali M, Jefferson JA, Hughes J, Bennett W, Schreiner GF, Johnson RJ. Post-cyclosporine-mediated hypertension and nephropathy: amelioration by vascular endothelial growth factor. Am J Physiol Renal Physiol 280: F727&#x2013;F736, 2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11249864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YG, Suga SI, Kang DH, Jefferson JA, Mazzali M, Gordon KL, Matsui K, Breiteneder-Geleff S, Shankland SJ, Hughes J, Kerjaschki D, Schreiner GF, Johnson RJ. Vascular endothelial growth factor accelerates renal recovery in experimental thrombotic microangiopathy. Kidney Int 58: 2390&#x2013;2399, 2000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11115072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lombardi D, Gordon KL, Polinsky P, Suga S, Schwartz SM, Johnson RJ. Salt-sensitive hypertension develops after short-term exposure to angiotensin II. Hypertension 33: 1013&#x2013;1019, 1999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10205240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long D, Mu W, Price K, Roncal C, Schreiner GF, Woolf AS, Johnson R. Vascular endothelial growth factor administration does not improve microvascular disease in the salt-dependent phase of post-angiotensin II hypertension. Am J Physiol Renal Physiol 291: F1248&#x2013;F1254, 2006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16804104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattson DL, Higgins DJ. Influence of dietary sodium intake on renal medullary nitric oxide synthase. Hypertension 27: 688&#x2013;692, 1996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8613226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nangaku M, Alpers CE, Pippin J, Shankland SJ, Adler S, Kurokawa K, Couser WG, Johnson RJ. A new model of renal microvascular endothelial injury. Kidney Int 52: 182&#x2013;194, 1997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9211361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nangaku M, Alpers CE, Pippin J, Shankland SJ, Kurokawa K, Adler S, Johnson RJ, Couser WG. Renal microvascular injury induced by antibody to glomerular endothelial cells is mediated by C5b-9. Kidney Int 52: 1570&#x2013;1578, 1997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9407502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nony P, Schnellmann RG. Mechanisms of renal cell repair and regeneration after acute renal failure. J Pharmacol Exp Ther 304: 905&#x2013;912, 2003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12604664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pechman K, Basile DP, Lund H, Mattson DL. Immune suppression blocks sodium-sensitive hypertension following recovery from acute renal failure. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 294: R1234&#x2013;R1239, 2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18256138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safirstein RL Cell cycle events during renal injury. Ren Fail 21: 427&#x2013;431, 1999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10416223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibuya M Structure and function of VEGF/VEGF-receptor system involved in angiogenesis. Cell Struct Funct 26: 25&#x2013;35, 2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11345501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spurgeon-Pechman KR, Donohoe DL, Mattson DL, Lund H, James L, Basile DP. Recovery from acute renal failure predisposes hypertension and secondary renal disease in response to elevated sodium. Am J Physiol Renal Physiol 293: F269&#x2013;F278, 2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17507599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spurgeon KS, Donohoe DL, Basile DP. Transforming growth factor-&#x3b2; in acute renal failure: receptor expression, effects on cell proliferation, cellularity and vascularization after recovery from injury. Am J Physiol Renal Physiol 288: F568&#x2013;F577, 2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15536165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suga S, Kim Y, Joly A, Puchacz E, Kang DH, Jefferson JA, Abraham JA, Hughes J, Johnson R, Schreiner GF. Vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF-121) protects rats from renal infarction in thrombotic microangiopathy. Kidney Int 60: 1297&#x2013;1308, 2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11576344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutton TA, Fisher CJ, Molitoris BA. Microvascular endothelial injury and dysfunction during ischemic acute renal failure. Kidney Int 62: 1539&#x2013;1549, 2002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12371954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutton TA, Mang HE, Campos SB, Sandoval RM, Yoder MC, Molitoris BA. Injury of the renal microvascular endothelium alters barrier function after ischemia. Am J Physiol Renal Physiol 285: F191&#x2013;F198, 2003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12684225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres V, Wang X, Qian Q, Somlo S, Harris PC, Gattone V. Effective treatment of an orthologous model of autosomal dominant polycystic kidney disease. Nat Med 10: 363&#x2013;364, 2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14991049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto T, Tada T, Brodsky SV, Tanaka H, Noiri E, Kajiya F, Goligorsky MS. Intravital videomicroscopy of peritubular capillaries in renal ischemia. Am J Physiol Renal Physiol 282: F1150&#x2013;F1155, 2002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11997332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>