<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">J Occup Health</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">J Occup Health</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">3162</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">joccuphealth</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">joh</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Journal of Occupational Health</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">1341-9145</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1348-9585</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Oxford University Press</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12491942</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC12491942.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">12491942</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">12491942</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">39853239</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/joccuh/uiaf003</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">uiaf003</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Invited Mini-Review</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="category-taxonomy-collection"><subject>AcademicSubjects/MED00010</subject><subject>AcademicSubjects/MED00640</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Oxidative and nitrative DNA damage induced by industrial chemicals in relation to carcinogenesis</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-4351-1498</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Hiraku</surname><given-names initials="Y">Yusuke</given-names></name><aff>
<institution>Department of Environmental Health, University of Fukui School of Medical Science</institution>, <addr-line>Eiheiji, Fukui</addr-line>, <country country="JP">Japan</country></aff><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp"/></contrib></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="cor1">Corresponding author: Yusuke Hiraku, (<email>y-hiraku@u-fukui.ac.jp</email>).</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><season>Jan-Dec</season><year>2025</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub" iso-8601-date="2025-01-24"><day>24</day><month>1</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><volume>67</volume><issue>1</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">479434</issue-id><elocation-id>uiaf003</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>03</day><month>12</month><year>2024</year></date><date date-type="rev-recd"><day>08</day><month>1</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>12</day><month>1</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="corrected-typeset"><day>18</day><month>2</month><year>2025</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>24</day><month>01</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>04</day><month>10</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2025-10-04 00:25:28.543"><day>04</day><month>10</month><year>2025</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>© The Author(s) [2025]. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Japan Society for Occupational Health</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2025</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbynclicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an Open Access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial License (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</ext-link>), which permits non-commercial re-use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work is properly cited. For commercial re-use, please contact reprints@oup.com for reprints and translation rights for reprints. All other permissions can be obtained through our RightsLink service via the Permissions link on the article page on our site-for further information please contact journals.permissions@oup.com.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="uiaf003.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="uiaf003.pdf"/><abstract><title>Abstract</title><p>Objectives: Many chemicals have been used for industrial purposes, and some of them are carcinogenic to humans. However, the molecular mechanisms of their carcinogenetic effects have not been well understood. Reactive oxygen species are generated from industrial chemicals and contribute to carcinogenesis. Particles and fibers are accumulated in respiratory systems by inhalation exposure and cause chronic inflammation. Under inflammatory conditions, reactive nitrogen species are generated from inflammatory and epithelial cells. These species cause oxidative and nitrative DNA damage, leading to carcinogenesis. We carried out experiments on DNA damage induced by various industrial chemicals and investigated their molecular mechanisms.</p><p>Methods: We examined oxidative DNA damage induced by industrial chemicals using DNA fragments derived from human cancer-relevant genes by polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis. Using immunohistochemistry and immunocytochemistry we also examined the formation of 8-nitroguanine (8-nitroG), a DNA lesion formed under inflammatory conditions, in lung tissues and cultured cells exposed to industrial chemicals.</p><p>Results: Benzene and <italic toggle="yes">o</italic>-toluidine metabolites caused oxidative damage to DNA fragments in the presence of Cu(II). H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> and Cu(I) were generated during oxidation of these chemicals and involved in DNA damage. 8-NitroG formation was observed in lung tissues of asbestos-exposed mice and humans. Carbon nanomaterials and indium compounds induced 8-nitroG formation in human lung epithelial cells via the release of damage-associated molecular patterns from exposed cells.</p><p>Conclusions: Various industrial chemicals are considered to induce carcinogenesis by causing oxidative and nitrative DNA damage. These findings provide an insight into risk assessment of industrial chemicals and prevention of carcinogenesis in workplaces.</p></abstract><abstract abstract-type="teaser"><p>Key points</p><p>What is already known on this topic: Some industrial chemicals are known to cause carcinogenesis by forming DNA adducts by the interaction of their metabolites with DNA bases. For example, carcinogenic aromatic amines are <italic toggle="yes">N</italic>-hydroxylated and converted to reactive nitrenium ions to form DNA adducts.</p><p>What this study adds: We performed experiments on DNA damage induced by industrial chemicals via the generation of reactive oxygen species and reactive nitrogen species. We found that reactive oxygen species are generated from industrial chemicals and their metabolites and cause oxidative DNA damage. In addition, particles and fibers cause inflammatory responses and the generation of nitric oxide, resulting in nitrative DNA damage.</p><p>How this study might affect research, practice, or policy: Our findings provide an insight into the evaluation of carcinogenic risks of industrial chemicals and prevention of carcinogenesis in workplaces.</p></abstract><kwd-group><kwd>industrial chemicals</kwd><kwd>DNA damage</kwd><kwd>reactive oxygen species</kwd><kwd>nitric oxide</kwd><kwd>cancer</kwd><kwd>inflammation</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group award-type="grant"><funding-source>
<institution-wrap><institution content-type="funder-name">Grants-in-Aid for Scientific Research from the Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology and the Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare of Japan</institution></institution-wrap>
</funding-source></award-group></funding-group><counts><page-count count="5"/></counts><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="sec8"><title>1. Carcinogenicity and DNA damage induced by industrial chemicals</title><p>A large number of chemicals have been used for various industrial purposes. Some chemical compounds are hazardous and capable of causing carcinogenesis in exposed workers. The International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC) has classified industrial chemicals, such as organic solvents (benzene, 1,2-dichloropropane, and trichloroethylene), metal compounds (chromium(VI), nickel, arsenic, beryllium, and cadmium), aromatic amines (benzidine, 4-aminobiphenyl, benzidine, and <italic toggle="yes">o</italic>-toluidine), and particulate and fibrous substances (asbestos and silica dust) as Group 1 carcinogens (carcinogenic to humans). However, the molecular mechanisms of carcinogenesis induced by these chemicals have not been well understood.</p><p>DNA damage, including base modification and strand breaks, is an important first step in the process of carcinogenesis. Some industrial chemicals are known to form DNA adducts by interaction of their metabolites with DNA bases. For example, carcinogenic aromatic amines, such as 4-aminobiphenyl and 2-naphthylamine, are <italic toggle="yes">N</italic>-hydroxylated by cytochrome P450 and converted to reactive nitrenium ions, which subsequently bind to DNA.<xref rid="ref1" ref-type="bibr"><sup>1</sup></xref> Reactive oxygen species (ROS) are highly reactive forms of molecular oxygen, including hydroxyl radical (•OH), superoxide (O<sub>2</sub>•<sup>−</sup>), hydrogen peroxide (H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>), and singlet oxygen (<sup>1</sup>O<sub>2</sub>). ROS are generated from multiple sources in biological systems, such as the mitochondrial matrix, inflammatory cells, metabolism of nucleic acids, and oxidation of chemical compounds. Excessive generation of ROS is involved in the pathogenesis of various human diseases, including cancer. ROS cause oxidative damage to cellular constituents, such as nucleic acids (DNA and RNA), proteins, and lipids. The representative product of oxidative DNA modification is 8-oxo-7,8-dihydro-2′-deoxyguanosine (8-oxodG). 8-OxodG is a mutagenic DNA lesion, because during DNA synthesis misincorporation of adenine occurs opposite 8-oxodG, leading to G → T transversions.<xref rid="ref2" ref-type="bibr"><sup>2</sup></xref></p><p>Chronic inflammation contributes to a substantial part (~25%) of all cancer cases worldwide.<xref rid="ref3" ref-type="bibr"><sup>3</sup></xref> In addition to infectious and inflammatory diseases, exposure to industrial chemicals, especially particulate and fibrous substances, causes chronic inflammation in biological systems. Under inflammatory conditions, reactive nitrogen species (RNS), including nitric oxide (NO), are generated from inflammatory and epithelial cells as well as ROS. 8-Nitroguanine (8-nitroG) is a mutagenic DNA lesion formed during inflammatory conditions. 8-NitroG is produced by the interaction of guanine with highly reactive peroxynitrite (ONOO<sup>−</sup>), which is formed by the reaction of O<sub>2</sub>•<sup>−</sup> with NO.<xref rid="ref4" ref-type="bibr"><sup>4</sup></xref></p><p>To clarify the mechanism of carcinogenesis, we investigated oxidative DNA damage induced by various industrial chemicals using DNA fragments derived from human cancer-relevant genes. In addition, we examined 8-nitroG formation in cultured cells and lung tissues of experimental animals and humans exposed to industrial chemicals. The overview of oxidative and nitrative DNA damage induced by these chemicals is shown in <xref rid="f1" ref-type="fig">Figure 1</xref>.</p></sec><sec id="sec9"><title>2. Oxidative DNA damage induced by industrial chemicals</title><p>ROS can be generated by oxidation and/or reduction of various chemicals. The Fenton reaction is a well-known iron-catalyzed reaction of H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> to generate •OH: Fe(II) + H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> → Fe(III) + OH<sup>-</sup> + •OH. The •OH radical is an extremely reactive species that damages all DNA bases (guanine, adenine, cytosine, and thymine) without marked site specificity. <sup>1</sup>O<sub>2</sub> is generated through reaction of carcinogenic metals with H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>,<xref rid="ref5" ref-type="bibr"><sup>5</sup></xref> and excitation of photosensitizers by ultraviolet irradiation.<xref rid="ref6" ref-type="bibr"><sup>6</sup></xref> Unlike •OH, <sup>1</sup>O<sub>2</sub> specifically causes damage to guanine, because guanine has the lowest oxidation potential among the DNA bases and is most likely to be oxidized.<xref rid="ref7" ref-type="bibr"><sup>7</sup></xref> Therefore, the site specificity of DNA damage is dependent on the types of ROS.</p><fig position="float" id="f1" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>Overview of DNA damage induced by industrial chemicals. Industrial chemicals not only form DNA adducts but also induce ROS and RNS generation. ROS can be generated directly from these chemicals and their metabolites. Industrial chemicals also induce inflammatory responses to generate ROS and RNS from inflammatory and epithelial cells. These reactive species cause oxidative and nitrative DNA damage. 8-OxodG and 8-nitroG are representative oxidative and nitrative DNA lesions, respectively. H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>, hydrogen peroxide; 8-nitroG, 8-nitroguanine; NO, nitric oxide; O<sub>2</sub>•<sup>−</sup>, superoxide; •OH, hydroxyl radical; ONOO<sup>−</sup>, peroxynitrite; 8-oxodG, 8-oxo-7,8-dihydro-2′-deoxyguanosine; RNS, reactive nitrogen species; ROS, reactive oxygen species.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="uiaf003f1.jpg"/></fig><p>Using polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis, we investigated DNA damage induced by industrial chemicals using <sup>32</sup>P-labeled DNA fragments obtained from human cancer-relevant genes, such as the c-Ha-<italic toggle="yes">ras</italic>-1 proto-oncogene and the <italic toggle="yes">p53</italic> tumor suppressor gene. Kawanishi et al<xref rid="ref8" ref-type="bibr"><sup>8</sup></xref> demonstrated that sodium chromate(VI) caused DNA damage in the presence of H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> by generating •OH and <sup>1</sup>O<sub>2</sub>, and first proposed that ROS participate in metal-induced carcinogenesis. Other carcinogenic metal compounds, including Fe(III)-nitrilotriacetate, cobalt(II), and nickel(II), also induced oxidative DNA damage in the presence of H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>.<xref rid="ref5" ref-type="bibr"><sup>5</sup></xref> Based on these studies, we investigated DNA damage mediated by ROS that are generated from the interaction of industrial chemicals with endogenous metal ions, as described below.</p><sec id="sec10"><title>2.1. Benzene metabolites</title><p>Benzene is a widely used organic solvent, a petroleum byproduct, and a ubiquitous environmental pollutant. Benzene causes hematological disorders, including aplastic anemia and leukemia, in exposed workers. Benzene metabolism is important in exerting its toxicity. Benzene is metabolized to phenol by cytochrome P450 in the liver and then to hydroquinone (HQ) and catechol. These metabolites are further converted to quinones by peroxidase in the bone marrow. We examined DNA damage in cultured cells treated with benzene metabolites, HQ and 1,4-benzoquinone (1,4-BQ). Both metabolites induced DNA strand breaks in HL60 cells, derived from human promyelocytic leukemia cells, and 1,4-BQ caused DNA damage at lower concentrations than HQ. We investigated the mechanism of DNA damage induced by these metabolites using DNA fragments obtained from the c-Ha-<italic toggle="yes">ras</italic>-1 proto-oncogene. HQ induced DNA damage at preferably thymine and guanine residues in the presence of Cu(II). 1,4-BQ induced DNA damage in the presence of both Cu(II) and NADH, and showed a similar site specificity. Catalase and bathocuproine inhibited DNA damage induced by these metabolites, suggesting the involvement of H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> and Cu(I). These benzene metabolites induced no or weak DNA damage in the presence of Fe(II) and Fe(III). These results suggest that HQ is oxidized to the semiquinone radical and 1,4-BQ, which undergoes NADH-mediated reduction to the semiquinone radical to form a redox cycle. H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> and Cu(I) are generated during oxidation of these metabolites and form a metal-oxygen complex capable of causing DNA damage.<xref rid="ref9" ref-type="bibr"><sup>9</sup></xref></p></sec><sec id="sec11"><title>2.2. o-Toluidine metabolites</title><p>
<italic toggle="yes">o</italic>-Toluidine is an aromatic amine that has been used in the chemical industry as an intermediate for dyes, rubber chemicals, pesticides, and pharmaceuticals. <italic toggle="yes">o</italic>-Toluidine causes bladder cancer in exposed workers and has been evaluated as a Group 1 carcinogen by the IARC. We examined DNA damage induced by its major metabolite, 4-amino-3-methylphenol (4-amino-<italic toggle="yes">m</italic>-cresol) using DNA fragments of the c-Ha-<italic toggle="yes">ras</italic>-1 proto-oncogene and the <italic toggle="yes">p53</italic> tumor suppressor gene. This metabolite caused DNA damage in the presence of Cu(II), but no or weak DNA damage occurred in the presence of iron. DNA damage was reduced by catalase and bathocuproine, similarly to benzene metabolites. It is speculated that H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> and Cu(I) are generated during the oxidation of 4-amino-3-methylphenol to the aminomethylphenoxyl radical to cause DNA damage.<xref rid="ref10" ref-type="bibr"><sup>10</sup></xref></p></sec><sec id="sec12"><title>2.3. δ-Aminolevulinic acid</title><p>Lead has been used in a wide variety of products, including paint, ceramics, pipes and plumbing materials, batteries, and cosmetics. Lead and inorganic lead compounds have been evaluated as Group 2B and 2A carcinogens by the IARC, respectively. Unlike carcinogenic metals, such as chromium(VI), cobalt(II), and nickel(II), lead itself is incapable of causing oxidative DNA damage in a cell-free system.<xref rid="ref5" ref-type="bibr"><sup>5</sup></xref> δ-Aminolevulinic acid (ALA) is a heme precursor, which is accumulated in lead-exposed subjects by inhibiting the activity of ALA dehydratase. We examined oxidative DNA damage induced by ALA as an indirect mechanism of lead carcinogenesis using DNA fragments obtained from the c-Ha-<italic toggle="yes">ras</italic>-1 proto-oncogene. ALA induced DNA damage at thymine residues and 8-oxodG formation in the presence of Cu(II), and DNA damage was reduced by catalase and bathocuproine. ALA caused no or weak DNA damage in the presence of iron. These results suggest that H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> and Cu(I) are generated during ALA auto-oxidation to 4,5-dioxovaleric acid and contribute to DNA damage. Alternatively, there is a possibility that two ALA molecules are condensed to a dihydropyrazine derivative and H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> and Cu(I) are generated during its oxidation.<xref rid="ref11" ref-type="bibr"><sup>11</sup></xref></p><p>Copper is an important trace element and a cofactor of diverse enzymes. A substantial amount of the copper is located in the mammalian cell nucleus where it contributes to high-order chromatin structures.<xref rid="ref12" ref-type="bibr"><sup>12</sup></xref> Therefore, endogenous copper ions may catalyze ROS generation from chemical compounds in biological systems to mediate oxidative DNA damage and play a role in carcinogenesis. In our studies, the above chemical compounds induced no or weak DNA damage in the presence of iron. Although the contribution of the Fenton reaction to DNA damage appears to be small in our experiments, its significance in biological systems needs further investigation.</p></sec></sec><sec id="sec13"><title>3. Nitrative DNA damage induced by industrial chemicals</title><p>Inhalation exposure of particulate and fibrous substances causes chronic inflammation by their accumulation in respiratory systems, resulting in carcinogenesis. Under inflammatory conditions, ROS and RNS are generated from inflammatory and epithelial cells. NO, a representative RNS, is produced in these cells via the expression of inducible NO synthase (iNOS), whereas ROS are generated from multiple sources in addition to inflammation. NO reacts with O<sub>2</sub>•<sup>−</sup> to form highly reactive ONOO<sup>−</sup>, which interacts with guanine to form 8-nitroG and 8-oxodG. 8-NitroG formed in DNA is chemically unstable and easily released, resulting in the formation of an apurinic site.<xref rid="ref4" ref-type="bibr"><sup>4</sup></xref> The apurinic site forms a pair preferably with adenine during DNA synthesis, resulting in G → T transversions. Alternatively, incorporation of adenine opposite 8-nitroG occurs during DNA synthesis, leading to G → T transversions. Therefore, 8-nitroG is a potentially mutagenic DNA lesion involved in inflammation-related carcinogenesis. Using immunohistochemistry and a specific antibody produced by our group,<xref rid="ref13" ref-type="bibr"><sup>13</sup></xref> we have demonstrated that 8-nitroG was formed at the sites of carcinogenesis in various animal models and in patients with cancer-prone infectious and inflammatory diseases. We also found that particles and fibers used in industry cause 8-nitroG formation in lung tissues and cultured cells as described below.</p><sec id="sec14"><title>3.1. Asbestos</title><p>Asbestos is a naturally occurring fiber that has been used for a wide variety of industrial purposes. Asbestos includes serpentine (chrysotile) and amphiboles (crocidolite, amosite, actinolite, anthophyllite, and tremolite), all of which are classified as Group 1 carcinogens by the IARC. Inhalation exposure of asbestos causes lung cancer and malignant mesothelioma of the pleura and peritoneum. Several possible mechanisms for asbestos-induced carcinogenesis have been proposed, such as irritation of the pleura, mitosis disruption, ROS generation, and activation of signaling pathways to upregulate proto-oncogenes.<xref rid="ref14" ref-type="bibr"><sup>14</sup></xref> However, the precise mechanisms of carcinogenesis are still unclear.</p><p>We examined 8-nitroG formation in lung tissues of asbestos-exposed mice and humans by immunohistochemistry. In an animal experiment, asbestos fibers (chrysotile and crocidolite) were intratracheally administered to mice, and 8-nitroG formation was observed in bronchial epithelial cells. Crocidolite induced significantly more intense 8-nitroG formation than chrysotile, consistent with their carcinogenic potentials.<xref rid="ref15" ref-type="bibr"><sup>15</sup></xref> We also examined the relationship between asbestos contents and the intensity of 8-nitroG formation in human lung tissues. In subjects without mesothelioma, staining intensity of 8-nitroG was significantly correlated with total asbestos and amphibole content, but not with chrysotile content. In mesothelioma patients, the staining intensity was not correlated with asbestos contents. These findings raise a possibility that 8-nitroG serves as a potential biomarker to estimate the extent of asbestos exposure.<xref rid="ref16" ref-type="bibr"><sup>16</sup></xref></p><p>In addition to DNA damage, we examined microRNA (miRNA) expression in lung tissues of asbestos-exposed mice. miRNAs are short noncoding RNAs that suppress gene expression and participate in various human diseases including cancer. Microarray analysis showed that miR-21, an oncogenic miRNA, was significantly upregulated by both chrysotile and crocidolite, and its target tumor suppressor genes—programmed cell death 4 (<italic toggle="yes">Pdcd4</italic>) and reversion-inducing-cysteine-rich protein with kazal motifs (<italic toggle="yes">Reck</italic>)—were downregulated. Using real-time polymerase chain reaction, western blotting, and immunohistochemistry, we confirmed that asbestos exposure downregulated these genes at the transcriptional and translational levels.<xref rid="ref17" ref-type="bibr"><sup>17</sup></xref> Alteration in miRNA expression patterns may contribute to asbestos-induced carcinogenesis in addition to DNA damage.</p></sec><sec id="sec15"><title>3.2. Carbon nanomaterials</title><p>Nanomaterials are defined as materials having structural features with at least 1 dimension of 100 nm or less. Carbon black (CB) is a nanomaterial used mainly in rubber products, and inhalation exposure causes lung tumors in experimental animals. CB has been evaluated as Group 2B by the IARC. We demonstrated that CB exposure induced 8-nitroG formation in RAW 264.7 macrophages and A549 lung epithelial cells. This process involves cellular uptake of CB through clathrin-mediated endocytosis.<xref rid="ref18" ref-type="bibr"><sup>18</sup></xref></p><p>Carbon nanotubes (CNTs) have been recently used for a wide range of industrial purposes and make up the majority of carbon nanomaterials. However, intraperitoneal administration of CNTs causes mesothelioma in experimental animals, raising a concern of carcinogenicity in humans. The IARC classified a certain type of multi-walled CNT (MWCNT) as a Group 2B carcinogen. We examined 8-nitroG formation in A549 human lung epithelial cells treated with MWCNTs. These significantly increased 8-nitroG formation in exposed cells, which was largely suppressed by inhibitors of caveola- and clathrin-mediated endocytosis. To clarify the mechanism of DNA damage, we examined the role of Toll-like receptor (TLR) 9, which resides in endosomes and lysosomes. Small interfering RNA (siRNA) for TLR9 and antibodies against high-mobility group box-1 (HMGB1) and receptor for advanced glycation end-products (RAGE) reduced MWCNT-induced 8-nitroG formation. MWCNT exposure increased the release of HMGB1 and double-stranded DNA into the culture supernatant from the cells. These results suggest that MWCNTs induce cell injury or necrosis, and HMGB1 and CpG DNA are released into the extracellular space. The HMGB1-DNA complex binds to RAGE on the surface of neighboring cells and is taken into lysosomes, where CpG DNA is recognized by TLR9, leading to NO generation and 8-nitroG formation (<xref rid="f2" ref-type="fig">Figure 2</xref>). Damage-associated molecular patterns (DAMPs) are endogenous molecules, including HMGB1, S100 proteins, heat-shock proteins, and DNA, that are released from damaged or dying cells. These molecules activate the innate immune system by interacting with pattern recognition receptors, such as TLRs. This study proposes a hypothesis that DAMPs released from exposed cells and the resulting inflammatory responses play a role in carcinogenesis induced by industrial chemicals.<xref rid="ref19" ref-type="bibr"><sup>19</sup></xref></p><fig position="float" id="f2" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>Proposed mechanism of DNA damage induced by industrial chemicals via inflammatory responses. Industrial chemicals induce cell injury or death, and then HMGB1 and CpG DNA are released from the cells. The HMGB1-DNA complex binds to RAGE on neighboring cells. This complex is taken into lysosomes, and CpG DNA is recognized by TLR9, leading to NO generation and DNA damage. HMGB1, high-mobility group box-1; RAGE, receptor for advanced glycation end-products; TLR, Toll-like receptor.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="uiaf003f2.jpg"/></fig><p>In this study, we did not observe an increase in 8-oxodG formation in MWCNT-treated lung epithelial cells.<xref rid="ref19" ref-type="bibr"><sup>19</sup></xref> This negative finding may be explained as follows. NO reacts with O<sub>2</sub>•<sup>−</sup> to form ONOO<sup>−</sup> and its conjugate acid ONOOH. ONOOH is decomposed into •OH and •NO<sub>2</sub>, which cause oxidative and nitrative DNA damage, respectively. Sodium bicarbonate (NaHCO<sub>3</sub>) exists abundantly in cell culture medium and under physiological conditions. Carbon dioxide (CO<sub>2</sub>) derived from bicarbonate reacts with ONOO<sup>−</sup> to form peroxynitrosocarbonate (ONOOCO<sub>2</sub><sup>−</sup>), which undergoes homolysis into •NO<sub>2</sub> and •CO<sub>3</sub><sup>−</sup>. Therefore, MWCNTs are considered to preferably induce 8-nitroG formation rather than 8-oxodG in biological systems.</p></sec><sec id="sec16"><title>3.3. Indium compounds</title><p>Indium compounds have been used in manufacturing the displays of mobile phones, computers, and televisions. However, these compounds cause interstitial pneumonia in exposed workers. Indium compounds also cause lung cancer in experimental animals, raising a serious concern about carcinogenicity to humans. Indium phosphide and indium tin oxide (ITO) have been classified as Group 2A and 2B carcinogens by the IARC, respectively. To clarify the mechanism of indium-induced carcinogenesis, we examined 8-nitroG formation in A549 human lung epithelial cells. We used indium compounds, including nanoparticles of indium oxide (In<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>) and ITO and water-soluble indium chloride (InCl<sub>3</sub>). All indium compounds significantly increased 8-nitroG formation at low concentration of 5 ng/mL, relevant to the working environment. 8-NitroG formation was largely suppressed by siRNA and antibodies against HMGB1, RAGE, and TLR9. These results suggests that indium compounds induce DNA damage mediated by inflammatory responses via the HMGB1-RAGE-TLR9 pathway regardless of chemical properties.<xref rid="ref20" ref-type="bibr"><sup>20</sup></xref> We examined 8-oxodG formation in calf thymus DNA treated with indium chloride (InCl<sub>3</sub>) and H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>, but 8-oxodG formation did not increase (Y. Hiraku, MD, PhD, unpublished data, June 2011). Therefore, indium has no ability to generate ROS in a cell-free system unlike other carcinogenic metals, such as nickel and cobalt.</p><p>We also performed microarray analysis of gene expression in lung tissues of indium-exposed rats, which were exposed to In<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> and ITO particles by intratracheal instillation. Microarray and bioinformatic analysis revealed that these indium compounds largely upregulated S100A9 and S100A8, which participate in immunomodulatory and inflammatory responses. Fluorescent immunohistochemistry revealed that S100A9 and S100A8 were expressed in alveolar epithelial cells and neutrophils in indium-exposed rats.<xref rid="ref21" ref-type="bibr"><sup>21</sup></xref> S100 proteins are involved in proliferation, differentiation, inflammation, and migration. S100A9 mediates various respiratory diseases, such as chronic obstructive pulmonary disorder, infectious diseases, and lung cancer by forming a heterodimer with S100A8. S100 proteins may serve as DAMPs that contribute to indium-induced lung diseases via neutrophil-mediated inflammatory responses in addition to HMGB1.</p></sec></sec><sec id="sec17"><title>4. Conclusions</title><p>We have investigated DNA damage induced by various industrial chemicals in relation to carcinogenesis. These chemicals cause oxidative and nitrative DNA damage via direct and indirect mechanisms. Benzene and <italic toggle="yes">o</italic>-toluidine metabolites caused oxidative DNA damage mediated by ROS directly generated through their oxidation. MWCNTs and indium compounds induced NO generation via DAMPs-mediated inflammatory responses and resulting nitrative DNA damage. These mechanisms may be ubiquitous in carcinogenesis induced by a wide variety of chemicals. Oxidative and nitrative DNA lesions, such as 8-oxodG and 8-nitroG, may serve as potential biomarkers to evaluate the carcinogenic risks of workers exposed to chemicals. In addition, the experimental systems to detect these DNA lesions may be used to evaluate the carcinogenicity of industrial chemicals. These findings provide an insight into the risk assessment and prevention of carcinogenesis in workplaces.</p></sec></body><back><ack id="uiaf003-ack"><title>Acknowledgments</title><p>The author is grateful to Professor Shosuke Kawanishi, Professor Mariko Murata (Suzuka University of Medical Sciences, Professor Emeritus at Mie University), and all collaborators for their encouragement throughout this work.</p></ack><sec id="sec18"><title>Funding</title><p>This work was supported by Grants-in-Aid for Scientific Research from the Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology and the Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare of Japan.</p></sec><sec sec-type="COI-statement" id="sec19"><title>Conflicts of interest</title><p>The author has no conflicts of interest.</p></sec><ref-list id="bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="ref1"><label>1.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Turesky</surname>
 <given-names>RJ</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Le Marchand</surname><given-names>L</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Metabolism and biomarkers of heterocyclic aromatic amines in molecular epidemiology studies: lessons learned from aromatic amines</article-title>. <source>Chem Res Toxicol</source>. <year>2011</year>;<volume>24</volume>(<issue>8</issue>):<fpage>1169</fpage>-<lpage>1214</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/tx200135s</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21688801</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3156293</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref2"><label>2.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Shibutani</surname>
 <given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Takeshita</surname><given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Grollman</surname><given-names>AP</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Insertion of specific bases during DNA synthesis past the oxidation-damaged base 8-oxodG</article-title>. <source>Nature</source>. <year>1991</year>;<volume>349</volume>(<issue>6308</issue>):<fpage>431</fpage>-<lpage>434</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/349431a0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1992344</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref3"><label>3.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Hussain</surname>
 <given-names>SP</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Harris</surname><given-names>CC</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Inflammation and cancer: an ancient link with novel potentials</article-title>. <source>Int J Cancer</source>. <year>2007</year>;<volume>121</volume>(<issue>11</issue>):<fpage>2373</fpage>-<lpage>2380</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/ijc.23173</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17893866</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref4"><label>4.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Yermilov</surname>
 <given-names>V</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Rubio</surname><given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ohshima</surname><given-names>H</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Formation of 8-nitroguanine in DNA treated with peroxynitrite in vitro and its rapid removal from DNA by depurination</article-title>. <source>FEBS Lett</source>. <year>1995</year>;<volume>376</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>207</fpage>-<lpage>210</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/0014-5793(95)01281-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7498543</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref5"><label>5.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Kawanishi</surname>
 <given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Hiraku</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Murata</surname><given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Oikawa</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>The role of metals in site-specific DNA damage with reference to carcinogenesis</article-title>. <source>Free Radic Biol Med</source>. <year>2002</year>;<volume>32</volume>(<issue>9</issue>):<fpage>822</fpage>-<lpage>832</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11978484</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/s0891-5849(02)00779-7</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref6"><label>6.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Hiraku</surname>
 <given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ito</surname><given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Hirakawa</surname><given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kawanishi</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Photosensitized DNA damage and its protection via a novel mechanism</article-title>. <source>Photochem Photobiol</source>. <year>2007</year>;<volume>83</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>205</fpage>-<lpage>212</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1562/2006-03-09-IR-840</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16965181</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref7"><label>7.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Sugiyama</surname>
 <given-names>H</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Saito</surname><given-names>I</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Theoretical studies of GG-specific photocleavage of DNA via electron transfer: significant lowering of ionization potential and 5′-localization of HOMO of stacked GG bases in B-form DNA</article-title>. <source>J Am Chem Soc</source>. <year>1996</year>;<volume>118</volume>(<issue>30</issue>):<fpage>7063</fpage>-<lpage>7068</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/ja9609821</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref8"><label>8.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Kawanishi</surname>
 <given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Inoue</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sano</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Mechanism of DNA cleavage induced by sodium chromate(VI) in the presence of hydrogen peroxide</article-title>. <source>J Biol Chem</source>. <year>1986</year>;<volume>261</volume>(<issue>13</issue>):<fpage>5952</fpage>-<lpage>5958</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0021-9258(17)38476-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">3009436</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref9"><label>9.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Hiraku</surname>
 <given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kawanishi</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Oxidative DNA damage and apoptosis induced by benzene metabolites</article-title>. <source>Cancer Res</source>. <year>1996</year>;<volume>56</volume>(<issue>22</issue>):<fpage>5172</fpage>-<lpage>5178</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8912853</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref10"><label>10.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Ohkuma</surname>
 <given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Hiraku</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Oikawa</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Yamashita</surname><given-names>N</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Murata</surname><given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kawanishi</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Distinct mechanisms of oxidative DNA damage by two metabolites of carcinogenic <italic toggle="yes">o</italic>-toluidine</article-title>. <source>Arch Biochem Biophys</source>. <year>1999</year>;<volume>372</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>97</fpage>-<lpage>106</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1006/abbi.1999.1461</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10562421</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref11"><label>11.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Hiraku</surname>
 <given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kawanishi</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Mechanism of oxidative DNA damage induced by δ-aminolevulinic acid in the presence of copper ion</article-title>. <source>Cancer Res</source>. <year>1996</year>;<volume>56</volume>(<issue>8</issue>):<fpage>1786</fpage>-<lpage>1793</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8620494</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref12"><label>12.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Linder</surname>
 <given-names>MC</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>. <article-title>The relationship of copper to DNA damage and damage prevention in humans</article-title>. <source>Mutat Res</source>. <year>2012</year>;<volume>733</volume>(<issue>1-2</issue>):<fpage>83</fpage>-<lpage>91</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.mrfmmm.2012.03.010</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23463874</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref13"><label>13.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Hiraku</surname>
 <given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>
</person-group>. <article-title>Formation of 8-nitroguanine, a nitrative DNA lesion, in inflammation-related carcinogenesis and its significance</article-title>. <source>Environ Health Prev Med</source>. <year>2010</year>;<volume>15</volume>(<issue>2</issue>):<fpage>63</fpage>-<lpage>72</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s12199-009-0118-5</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19921494</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2824100</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref14"><label>14.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Robinson</surname>
 <given-names>BW</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Lake</surname><given-names>RA</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>Advances in malignant mesothelioma</article-title>. <source>N Engl J Med</source>. <year>2005</year>;<volume>353</volume>(<issue>15</issue>):<fpage>1591</fpage>-<lpage>1603</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1056/NEJMra050152</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16221782</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref15"><label>15.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Hiraku</surname>
 <given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kawanishi</surname><given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ichinose</surname><given-names>T</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Murata</surname><given-names>M</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>The role of iNOS-mediated DNA damage in infection- and asbestos-induced carcinogenesis</article-title>. <source>Ann N Y Acad Sci</source>. <year>2010</year>;<volume>1203</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>15</fpage>-<lpage>22</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1749-6632.2010.05602.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20716278</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref16"><label>16.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Hiraku</surname>
 <given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Sakai</surname><given-names>K</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Shibata</surname><given-names>E</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al.</etal></person-group>
 <article-title>Formation of the nitrative DNA lesion 8-nitroguanine is associated with asbestos contents in human lung tissues: a pilot study</article-title>. <source>J Occup Health</source>. <year>2014</year>;<volume>56</volume>(<issue>3</issue>):<fpage>186</fpage>-<lpage>196</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1539/joh.13-0231-OA</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24598051</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref17"><label>17.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Hiraku</surname>
 <given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Watanabe</surname><given-names>J</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kaneko</surname><given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ichinose</surname><given-names>T</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Murata</surname><given-names>M</given-names></string-name></person-group>. <article-title>MicroRNA expression in lung tissues of asbestos-exposed mice: upregulation of miR-21 and downregulation of tumor suppressor genes <italic toggle="yes">Pdcd4</italic> and <italic toggle="yes">Reck</italic></article-title>. <source>J Occup Health</source>. <year>2021</year>;<volume>63</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>e12282</fpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/1348-9585.12282</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34679210</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8535435</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref18"><label>18.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Hiraku</surname>
 <given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Nishikawa</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>N</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al.</etal></person-group>
 <article-title>Nitrative DNA damage induced by carbon-black nanoparticles in macrophages and lung epithelial cells</article-title>. <source>Mutat Res</source>. <year>2017</year>;<volume>818</volume>:<fpage>7</fpage>-<lpage>16</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.mrgentox.2017.04.002</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28477879</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref19"><label>19.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Hiraku</surname>
 <given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>F</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>N</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al.</etal></person-group>
 <article-title>Multi-walled carbon nanotube induces nitrative DNA damage in human lung epithelial cells via HMGB1-RAGE interaction and toll-like receptor 9 activation</article-title>. <source>Part Fibre Toxicol</source>. <year>2016</year>;<volume>13</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>16</fpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12989-016-0127-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27026438</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4812657</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref20"><label>20.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Ahmed</surname>
 <given-names>S</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Kobayashi</surname><given-names>H</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Afroz</surname><given-names>T</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al.</etal></person-group>
 <article-title>Nitrative DNA damage in lung epithelial cells exposed to indium nanoparticles and indium ions</article-title>. <source>Sci Rep</source>. <year>2020</year>;<volume>10</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>10741</fpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-67488-3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32612147</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7329867</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="ref21"><label>21.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal">
<person-group person-group-type="author">
<string-name name-style="western">
<surname>Hiraku</surname>
 <given-names>Y</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>A</given-names></string-name>, <string-name name-style="western"><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>M</given-names></string-name>, <etal>et al.</etal></person-group>
 <article-title>Microarray analysis of gene expression in lung tissues of indium-exposed rats: possible roles of S100 proteins in lung diseases</article-title>. <source>Arch Toxicol</source>. <year>2025</year>;<volume>99</volume>(<issue>1</issue>):<fpage>245</fpage>-<lpage>258</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s00204-024-03897-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39516272</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11742277</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>