<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">J Vet Med Sci</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">J Vet Med Sci</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2350</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">jvms</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">JVMS</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>The Journal of Veterinary Medical Science</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">0916-7250</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1347-7439</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Japanese Society of Veterinary Science</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC13000429</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC13000429.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">13000429</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">13000429</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">41485945</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1292/jvms.25-0507</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">25-0507</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Surgery</subject><subj-group><subject>Full Paper</subject></subj-group></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Effect of fuzapladib sodium hydrate on adhesion molecule expression in canine
endothelial cells and neutrophils</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>DARAWIROJ</surname><given-names initials="K">Kanittha</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>SUNAGA</surname><given-names initials="T">Takafumi</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>OWAKI</surname><given-names initials="R">Ryo</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>HANDONDO</surname><given-names initials="NM">Nomsa Mulenga</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>OKUMURA</surname><given-names initials="M">Masahiro</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp">
<sup>*</sup>
</xref></contrib><aff id="aff1"><label>1)</label>Laboratory of Veterinary Surgery, Department of Veterinary
Clinical Sciences, Graduate School of Veterinary Medicine, Hokkaido University, Hokkaido,
Japan</aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="cor1"><label>*</label>Correspondence to: Okumura M: <email xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="okumuram@vetmed.hokudai.ac.jp">okumuram@vetmed.hokudai.ac.jp</email>,
Laboratory of Veterinary Surgery, Department of Veterinary Clinical Sciences, Graduate
School of Veterinary Medicine, Hokkaido University, Sapporo, Hokkaido 060-0818,
Japan</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>31</day><month>12</month><year>2025</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="ppub"><month>3</month><year>2026</year></pub-date><volume>88</volume><issue>3</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">509813</issue-id><fpage>471</fpage><lpage>481</lpage><history><date date-type="received"><day>29</day><month>10</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>16</day><month>12</month><year>2025</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>31</day><month>12</month><year>2025</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>20</day><month>03</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2026-03-20 00:25:12.663"><day>20</day><month>03</month><year>2026</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>©2026 The Japanese Society of Veterinary Science</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2026</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative
Commons Attribution Non-Commercial No Derivatives (by-nc-nd) License. (CC-BY-NC-ND 4.0:
<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">
https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ext-link>)</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="jvms-88-3-471.pdf"/><abstract><p>Neutrophil recruitment to inflamed tissue is mediated by adhesion molecules and chemokine
signaling. Fuzapladib sodium hydrate (FZP) has been reported to reduce neutrophil
infiltration, but its broader effect on adhesion molecules in dogs remains unclear. This
study investigated the influence of FZP on canine aortic endothelial cells (CnAOEC) and
primary neutrophils under cytokine stimulation. CnAOEC were treated with recombinant
canine tumor necrosis factor alpha (rh-cTNFα) or lipopolysaccharide together with FZP,
while neutrophils isolated from healthy dogs were preincubated with FZP before rh-cTNFα
stimulation for gene and protein expression analyses. Expression of endothelial
<italic toggle="yes">E-selectin</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">P-selectin</italic>, and <italic toggle="yes">intercellular
adhesion molecule-1</italic> (<italic toggle="yes">ICAM-1</italic>) was quantified by qPCR.
Neutrophil <italic toggle="yes">C-X-C motif chemokine receptor 2</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">P-selectin
glycoprotein ligand-1</italic> (<italic toggle="yes">PSGL-1</italic>), and
<italic toggle="yes">L-selectin</italic> were also analyzed using qPCR. In addition, C-X-C motif
chemokine ligand 1 and leukocyte function-associated antigen-1 (LFA-1) were determined
using ELISA and flow cytometry, respectively. Neutrophil adhesion to FZP-treated
endothelial monolayers was evaluated under static conditions. FZP significantly
downregulated endothelial <italic toggle="yes">P-selectin</italic> at the highest dose, whereas
<italic toggle="yes">ICAM-1</italic> was upregulated. In neutrophils, FZP decreased
<italic toggle="yes">L-selectin</italic> and <italic toggle="yes">PSGL-1</italic> expression at the highest
concentration. These findings suggest that FZP selectively modulates early adhesion
through suppression of <italic toggle="yes">P-selectin</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">L-selectin</italic>, and
<italic toggle="yes">PSGL-1</italic>, which may weaken rolling and tethering interactions between
cells. Although functional adhesion effects were limited, these molecular responses
provide further insight into the anti-inflammatory effect of FZP.</p></abstract><kwd-group><kwd>C-X-C motif chemokine ligand 1</kwd><kwd>fuzapladib</kwd><kwd>L-selectin</kwd><kwd>P-selectin</kwd><kwd>P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-ND</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec sec-type="intro" id="s1"><title>INTRODUCTION</title><p>Inflammation is a fundamental defense mechanism triggered by harmful stimuli, including
pathogens, damaged cells, toxins, and irritants, and is characterized by increased vascular
permeability, neutrophil recruitment, and the release of pro-inflammatory mediators.
Collectively, these characteristics contribute to the major clinical signs of inflammation,
including redness, swelling, heat, pain, and impaired tissue function [<xref rid="r5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>]. A key component of inflammation is the interaction between adhesion
molecules on leukocytes and endothelial cells, which facilitates leukocyte extravasation
into inflamed tissue. This interaction is mediated by selectins, integrins, and members of
the immunoglobulin superfamily, regulating neutrophil rolling, firm adhesion, and
transendothelial migration [<xref rid="r8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>].</p><p>Neutrophils, as the primary responders in the early phase of acute inflammation, are
rapidly recruited from the circulation to inflamed tissues, where they contribute to
pathogen clearance and modulation of the immune response. However, under certain
pathological conditions, neutrophils may undergo reverse migration. This phenomenon has been
associated with systemic inflammation and the development of complications such as acute
lung injury, renal injury, encephalomyelitis, colitis, and endotoxemia [<xref rid="r10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>].</p><p>Neutrophil recruitment and transmigration are regulated through a sequence of adhesive
interactions. The process begins with selectin-mediated tethering and rolling along
activated endothelial cells. Neutrophils express P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1 (PSGL-1),
which binds to E- and P-selectins on the inflamed endothelium, initiating contact.
Subsequent firm adhesion is achieved through the binding of β2-integrins, specifically
leukocyte function-associated antigen-1 (LFA-1) or CD11a/CD18, to intercellular adhesion
molecule-1 (ICAM-1), regulated by bidirectional signaling. Neutrophils then continue along
the endothelial surface, guided by LFA-1-ICAM-1 interactions, before crossing the
endothelium through paracellular or transcellular pathways [<xref rid="r23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>]. Effective removal of neutrophils from inflamed tissue is essential for
inflammation resolution and protecting tissue integrity. Therefore, understanding the course
of migrated neutrophils is crucial to differentiating between self-limiting and chronic
inflammation, as well as advancing focused therapeutic strategies [<xref rid="r9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>].</p><p>Targeting adhesion molecules has become a promising approach for regulating
neutrophil-mediated inflammation. Fuzapladib sodium hydrate (FZP), a leukocyte
function-associated antigen-1 (LFA-1) inhibitor, prevents neutrophil extravasation by
interfering with LFA-1-mediated adhesion. It is currently approved for the treatment of
canine pancreatitis in the United States of America and Japan [<xref rid="r11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>]. Preclinical investigations in rat and canine models have shown that
FZP reduced the severity of pancreatic injury by decreasing neutrophil infiltration [<xref rid="r12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>, <xref rid="r13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>].
Furthermore, <italic toggle="yes">in vitro</italic> studies using human umbilical vein endothelial cells
(HUVEC) and HL-60 cells revealed reduced neutrophil-endothelial adhesion after
lipopolysaccharide (LPS) stimulation and FZP treatment, explained by reduced LFA-1
expression [<xref rid="r25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]. However, the effect of FZP on the
broader range of adhesion molecule expression has yet to be researched, particularly in
canine endothelial cells and neutrophils. Moreover, the information available on the
dose-dependent effect is limited. This study aims to investigate the effect of FZP on the
expression of key adhesion molecules involved in neutrophil-endothelial interactions in a
canine cell-based <italic toggle="yes">in vitro</italic> model, emphasizing potential dose-dependent
responses.</p></sec><sec sec-type="materials|methods" id="s2"><title>MATERIALS AND METHODS</title><sec><title>Cell culture</title><p>Canine aortic endothelial cells (CnAOEC; Cell Applications, Inc., San Diego, CA, USA;
Cat. No Cn304-05) were obtained as a cryopreserved vial at passage 2. In this study,
CnAOEC from passage 4 to passage 9 were used. The cells were cultured in the Canine EC
Growth Medium (Cell Applications, Cat. No. Cn211K-500) according to the manufacturer’s
instructions with a minor modification. Briefly, CnAOEC were seeded at a density of 1 ×
10<sup>4</sup> cells/cm<sup>2</sup> onto 100 mm culture dishes (Corning, Lowell, MA,
USA) coated with Attachment Factor Solution (AFS; Cell Applications, Cat. No. 123). Fresh
medium, pre-warmed to 37°C, was replaced every other day. When cultures reached 80–90%
confluence, cells were washed three times with Hanks’ Balanced Salt Solution (HBSS; Thermo
Fisher Scientific, Waltham, MA, USA; Cat. No. 14025092) and detached using Acutase
solution (Sigma-Aldrich, St. Louis, MO, USA). The cell suspension was then centrifuged at
400 × <italic toggle="yes">g</italic> for 5 min at 4°C without braking, and the cell pellet was
resuspended in Canine EC growth medium. Cell number and viability were assessed using the
trypan blue exclusion method (Wako Pure Chemical Industries, Osaka, Japan). Following this
assessment, cells were expanded and sub-cultured under identical conditions for subsequent
experiments.</p></sec><sec><title>Canine neutrophil isolation</title><p>Ten milliliters of fresh whole blood were obtained from the cephalic vein of three
healthy female beagles, with the approval of the Ethics Committee of Hokkaido University
(Approval No. 230104). This followed the institutional guidelines for the care and use of
experimental animals. Neutrophils were isolated from 10 mL of fresh, anticoagulated
K<sub>2</sub>EDTA (Dojindo Laboratories, Kumamoto, Japan) using Polymorphprep (Serumwerk
Bernburg, Bernburg, Germany) through density gradient centrifugation, following the
manufacturer’s protocol for human neutrophil isolation (500 × <italic toggle="yes">g</italic> for 30
min at 20°C). Residual erythrocytes were eliminated by the addition of 1 mL of 1× RBC
lysis buffer (Thermo Fisher Scientific) for 8 min at room temperature. This was
immediately followed by an addition of HBSS and centrifugation at 400 × <italic toggle="yes">g</italic>
for 10 min. The residual neutrophils were resuspended and calibrated to 4 × 10<sup>6</sup>
cells/mL in the Roswell Park Memorial Institute 1640 medium (RPMI-1640; Thermo Fisher
Scientific), supplemented with 10% fetal bovine serum (FBS; Sigma-Aldrich) and 1%
penicillin-streptomycin solution (Wako Pure Chemical Industries). The isolated neutrophils
were immediately used for the subsequent experiment.</p></sec><sec><title>RNA extraction, reverse transcription, and quantitative real-time polymerase chain
reaction (qPCR)</title><p>CnAOEC were cultured at a density of 2 × 10<sup>5</sup> cells per well in 6-well plates
(Corning), with the Canine EC Growth Medium replaced every other day until it became
confluent. The cells were subsequently treated in Canine EC Basal Medium (Cell
Applications, Inc., Cat. No. Cn210-500) with either recombinant canine tumor necrosis
factor alpha (rh-cTNFα; Kingfisher Biotech, Saint Paul, MN, USA) at 30 ng/mL or LPS (100
ng/mL; Wako Pure Chemical Industries, Cat. No. 127-05141), each administered alone or in
combination with Fuzapladib sodium hydrate (1, 10, or 100 µM; BRENDA; Ishihara Sangyo
Kaisha, Ltd., Osaka, Japan), abbreviated as FZP. Treatments were applied for 6 hr in a
humidified incubator at 37°C with 5% CO<sub>2</sub>. Following incubation, the cells were
washed three times with HBSS to remove residual medium, and total RNA was subsequently
isolated.</p><p>Freshly isolated neutrophils, at a concentration of 1 × 10<sup>6</sup> cells/mL, were
pre-incubated with or without FZP at concentrations of 1, 10, or 100 µM in a humidified
incubator with 5% CO<sub>2</sub> at 37°C for 24 hr. The cells were then stimulated with
rh-cTNFα at 20 ng/mL for 1 hr. RPMI-1640 supplemented with 10% FBS and 1%
penicillin-streptomycin served as the negative control, while rh-cTNFα treatment alone was
used as the positive control. Following treatment, neutrophils were washed once with
phosphate-buffered saline (PBS; Thermo Fisher Scientific, Cat. No. 10010023).
Subsequently, the cells were lysed and stored at −70°C until all samples were collected,
after which RNA was extracted. Neutrophil viability under these incubation conditions was
evaluated in parallel experiments using 7-Aminoactinomycin D (7-AAD; BD Biosciences, San
Diego, CA, USA) staining.</p><p>Total RNA was isolated utilizing the NucleoSpin RNA Purification Kit (Macherey-Nagel,
Dürren, Germany). The concentration of RNA was determined using a NanoEX Lite
spectrophotometer (Optima Inc., Tokyo, Japan) at a wavelength of 260 nm. Subsequently, 500
ng of total RNA from CnAOEC and 50 ng from canine neutrophils were reverse-transcribed
into cDNA using the M-MLV RT Kit (Invitrogen, Carlsbad, CA, USA), following the
manufacturer’s guidelines. A two-step qPCR was conducted with the KAPA SYBR FAST qPCR Kit
(KAPA Biosystems, Woburn, MA, USA). The relative expression levels of target genes were
determined using the 2<sup>-ΔΔCt</sup> method, with <italic toggle="yes">glyceraldehyde-3-phosphate
dehydrogenase </italic>(<italic toggle="yes">GAPDH</italic>) serving as the housekeeping gene for
normalization. The expression levels of adhesion-related genes, which include
<italic toggle="yes">E-selectin</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">ICAM-1</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">P-selectin</italic>,
<italic toggle="yes">C-X-C motif chemokine receptor 2</italic> (<italic toggle="yes">CXCR2</italic>),
<italic toggle="yes">PSGL-1</italic>, and <italic toggle="yes">L-selectin</italic>, were evaluated to determine
the impact of FZP on endothelial and neutrophil adhesion molecules. Primer sequences are
listed in <xref rid="tbl_001" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref><table-wrap position="float" id="tbl_001" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1.</label><caption><title>Primer sequences for quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Primer</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Primer sequence</th><th align="center" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Reference</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="2" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">CXCR2</italic></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Forward: 5′ AGCTGCCTTAATCCCCTCAT 3′</td><td align="center" valign="top" rowspan="2" colspan="1">[<xref rid="r18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Reverse: 5′ CTGAACCTGCTGGGAAACTC 3′</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="2" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">E-selectin</italic></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Forward: 5′ GAAATTCTTGGCCCGTCCATC 3′</td><td align="center" valign="top" rowspan="2" colspan="1">[<xref rid="r22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Reverse: 5′ ATGCAGCCAGCACTTAATCTGAAAC 3′</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="2" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">GAPDH</italic></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Forward: 5′ TGTCCCCACCCCCAATGTATC 3′</td><td align="center" valign="top" rowspan="2" colspan="1">[<xref rid="r22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Reverse: 5′ CTCCGATGCCTGCTTCACTACCTT 3′</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="2" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">ICAM-1</italic></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Forward: 5′ CAGGGTTGCCAGGTACAGTT 3′</td><td align="center" valign="top" rowspan="2" colspan="1">[<xref rid="r22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Reverse: 5′ AGTATGGGCTCAGTGGGTTG 3′</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="2" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">L-selectin</italic></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Forward: 5′ GATTTCAACAGGACCAGCAGCA 3′</td><td align="center" valign="top" rowspan="2" colspan="1">[<xref rid="r22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Reverse: 5′ CCGCAGGGTCCACAAGTAAGA 3′</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="2" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">PSGL-1</italic></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Forward: 5′ TTCTGGCTGAGATGGCGATG 3′</td><td align="center" valign="top" rowspan="2" colspan="1">[<xref rid="r22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Reverse: 5′ AGAGTGGCTGGCTCTGGAGTTC 3′</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="2" colspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P-selectin</italic></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Forward: 5′ TACAACACCAGCTGTCGCTTCC 3′</td><td align="center" valign="top" rowspan="2" colspan="1">[<xref rid="r22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Reverse: 5′ GTGCTGTCCACTGTCCCAAGTC 3′</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p><italic toggle="yes">CXCR2</italic>: C-X-C motif chemokine receptor 2; <italic toggle="yes">GAPDH</italic>:
glyceraldehyde-3 phosphate dehydrogenase; <italic toggle="yes">ICAM-1</italic>: intercellular
adhesion molecule-1; <italic toggle="yes">PSGL-1</italic>: P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1.</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap> [<xref rid="r18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>, <xref rid="r22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]. The qPCR assays consisted of three biological replicates for each
endothelial cell sample. Moreover, each sample comprised two technical replicates. For
neutrophils, the process was as follows. Blood was drawn from a dog on three separate
occasions. Each sample was used for two technical replicates. This process was repeated
for a total of three dogs.</p></sec><sec><title>Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA)</title><p>In an independent experiment, CnAOEC were inoculated onto 96-well plates (Corning) coated
with AFS at a density of 1 × 10<sup>5</sup> cells per well in 200 μL of the Canine EC
Growth Medium and incubated for 24 hr to allow cell attachment. Following incubation, the
culture medium was replaced with one of the following treatments: rh-cTNFα at 30 ng/mL,
either alone or combined with FZP at concentrations of 1, 10, or 100 μM, or with LPS at
100 ng/mL, either alone or in combination with FZP (1, 10, or 100 μM). The Canine EC Basal
Medium without stimulants or FZP served as the negative control. All procedures were
conducted in a humidified incubator at 37°C with 5% CO<sub>2</sub>. After 24 hr of
stimulation, the concentration of secreted C-X-C motif chemokine ligand 1 (CXCL1) protein
in the culture medium was quantified using the Canine CXCL1 ELISA kit (RayBiotech, Inc.,
Norcross, GA, USA) according to the manufacturer’s instructions.</p></sec><sec><title>Flow cytometry</title><p>Neutrophils were isolated from three dogs. For each dog, the experiment was conducted in
three separate runs. Fresh isolated neutrophils were subjected to the same pre-incubation
and stimulation protocol as described above for the qPCR assay. Following this protocol,
the cells were washed once with PBS. Subsequently, 3 × 10<sup>5</sup> cells were
resuspended in PBS containing 10% goat serum (Thermo Fisher Scientific) and incubated at
room temperature for 20 min to reduce nonspecific antibody binding. The cells were then
stained with PE-conjugated mouse anti-human CD11a monoclonal antibody (clone HI111, mouse
IgG1; BD Biosciences) or PE-conjugated mouse IgG1, κ isotype control (clone MOPC-21; BD
Biosciences) for 10 min under light-protected conditions. After staining, the cells were
washed twice with PBS containing 10% goat serum. Two microliters of 7-AAD was then added
to the stained cell suspension in 200 µL of PBS containing 10% goat serum and subsequently
incubated for 10 min. Flow cytometric analysis was performed using a BD
FACSLyric<sup>™</sup> Flow Cytometer (BD Biosciences). Viability was quantified as the
percentage of 7-AAD-negative (viable) cells within the singlet neutrophil gate. The gating
strategy, including neutrophil identification, singlet selection, exclusion of non-viable
events, and definition of CD11a-low and CD11a-high subsets using an isotype control, is
shown in <xref rid="pdf_001" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplementary Fig.
2</xref>.</p></sec><sec><title>Static adhesion assay</title><p>A static adhesion assay, modified from a prior human investigation [<xref rid="r33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>], was conducted to assess the impact of FZP on neutrophil adherence
to endothelial cells. Within this experiment, CnAOEC were seeded at a density of 1 ×
10<sup>4</sup> cells per well in 96-well plates. The Canine EC Growth Medium was
replaced every other day until the cells reached 100% confluence. Once confluent, the
cells were pre-incubated for 3 hr with FZP at doses of 1, 10, or 100 μM, or the Canine EC
Basal Medium as a control. Following pretreatment, the cells were exposed to rh-cTNFα at a
final concentration of 30 ng/mL and incubated for 4 hr. Freshly isolated neutrophils were
labeled with Calcein-AM (Dojindo Laboratories). The labeled neutrophils, at a
concentration of 1 × 10<sup>5</sup> cells per well, were then coincubated with treated
CnAOEC for 20 min. All incubations were performed at 37°C in a humidified incubator with
5% CO<sub>2</sub>. Fluorescence intensity (FI) at an excitation wavelength of 485 nm and
an emission wavelength of 520 nm was measured using a GloMax Discover microplate reader
(Promega, Madison, WI, USA). This measurement was performed before the washing step to
determine the total cell count. The cells were then gently washed twice with HBSS to
remove non-adherent neutrophils. Subsequently, 100 µL of RPMI-1640 solution was added to
each well, and fluorescence was re-evaluated. Neutrophil adhesion was calculated as the
relative adherence by examining the FI before and after washing using the following
equation:</p><p>
<inline-formula>
<mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" id="M1" display="inline" overflow="scroll"><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mfrac><mml:mrow><mml:mo stretchy="false">(</mml:mo><mml:mi>P</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>w</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mi>h</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>F</mml:mi><mml:mi>I</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>f</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>m</mml:mi><mml:mi>p</mml:mi><mml:mi>l</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mo>−</mml:mo><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>P</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>w</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mi>h</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>F</mml:mi><mml:mi>I</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>f</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>b</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>c</mml:mi><mml:mi>k</mml:mi><mml:mi>g</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>u</mml:mi><mml:mi>n</mml:mi><mml:mi>d</mml:mi><mml:mo stretchy="false">)</mml:mo><mml:mo> </mml:mo></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mo stretchy="false">(</mml:mo><mml:mi>P</mml:mi><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mi>w</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mi>h</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>F</mml:mi><mml:mi>I</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>f</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>m</mml:mi><mml:mi>p</mml:mi><mml:mi>l</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mo>−</mml:mo><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>P</mml:mi><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mi>w</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mi>h</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>F</mml:mi><mml:mi>I</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>f</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>b</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>c</mml:mi><mml:mi>k</mml:mi><mml:mi>g</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>u</mml:mi><mml:mi>n</mml:mi><mml:mi>d</mml:mi><mml:mo stretchy="false">)</mml:mo></mml:mrow></mml:mfrac><mml:mo>×</mml:mo><mml:mn>100</mml:mn><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:mi>%</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>d</mml:mi><mml:mi>h</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>n</mml:mi><mml:mi>c</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math>
</inline-formula>
</p><p>
<inline-formula>
<mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" id="M2" display="inline" overflow="scroll"><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mfrac><mml:mrow><mml:mi>%</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>d</mml:mi><mml:mi>h</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>n</mml:mi><mml:mi>c</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>f</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mi>m</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>n</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi></mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>v</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>g</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>%</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>d</mml:mi><mml:mi>h</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>n</mml:mi><mml:mi>c</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>f</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>p</mml:mi><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>s</mml:mi><mml:mi>i</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mi>i</mml:mi><mml:mi>v</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>c</mml:mi><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>n</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>o</mml:mi><mml:mi>l</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mfrac><mml:mo>=</mml:mo><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>l</mml:mi><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>t</mml:mi><mml:mi>i</mml:mi><mml:mi>v</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mo> </mml:mo><mml:mi>a</mml:mi><mml:mi>d</mml:mi><mml:mi>h</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>r</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi><mml:mi>n</mml:mi><mml:mi>c</mml:mi><mml:mi>e</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math>
</inline-formula>
</p><p>Similar to the previous experiment, neutrophils were isolated from three healthy dogs,
and the experiment was independently repeated three times for each dog. Each repeat
included five treatment conditions, with six technical replicates per condition.</p></sec><sec><title>Statistical analysis</title><p>All data are presented as mean ± standard deviation (SD). Statistical analyses were
conducted using GraphPad Prism 10.0 software (GraphPad Software, San Diego, CA, USA), and
a <italic toggle="yes">P-</italic>value &lt;0.05 was considered statistically significant for all
tests. The assumption of a normal distribution was assessed using the Shapiro-Wilk test.
The repeated-measures (RM) one-way ANOVA followed by Tukey’s multiple comparison test was
used to analyze the normally distributed data. In case the assumption of normality was
violated, the Friedman test in combination with Dunn’s test was employed instead.</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="results" id="s3"><title>RESULTS</title><sec><title>Effect of fuzapladib sodium hydrate on adhesion molecule gene expression in
cytokine-induced CnAOEC</title><p>To confirm that the observed changes in gene expression were not caused by cytotoxicity,
cell viability was evaluated using the Cell Counting Kit-8 assay (CCK-8; Dojindo
Laboratories). CnAOEC were treated with FZP (1, 10, and 100 μM) for 24 hr. The results
showed that FZP did not cause significant cytotoxicity at any tested concentration. Cell
viability at 100 μM FZP remained above 90% compared to the control and showed no
statistical difference (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&gt;0.05). In contrast, the positive control
(10% DMSO) significantly decreased cell viability (<xref rid="pdf_001" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplementary Fig. 1</xref>).</p><p>Following viability confirmation, qPCR was conducted to assess the effect of FZP on the
expression of endothelial adhesion molecules, specifically: <italic toggle="yes">E-selectin</italic>,
<italic toggle="yes">ICAM-1</italic>, and <italic toggle="yes">P-selectin</italic> in CnAOEC stimulated with
rh-cTNFα or LPS. All expression levels were compared to those of the corresponding
positive control. The results indicated that stimulation with both LPS and rh-cTNFα
increased the mRNA levels of all target genes compared to the negative control (<xref rid="pdf_001" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplementary Table 1</xref>).</p><p>Across both stimuli on the CnAOEC for 6 hr, the result revealed that FZP did not reduce
<italic toggle="yes">E-selectin</italic> transcription level relative to the stimulus control. Under
LPS stimuli, the mean fold was set at 1.00, while the treatment groups showed mean values
of 0.79, 0.85, and 1.40 for FZP at 1, 10, and 100 μM, respectively, as shown in <xref rid="fig_001" ref-type="fig">Fig. 1A.</xref><fig position="float" fig-type="figure" id="fig_001" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 1.</label><caption><p>Effects of fuzapladib sodium hydrate (FZP) on adhesion molecule expression in
lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-treated canine aortic endothelial cells (CnAOEC). CnAOEC
were stimulated with LPS (100 ng/mL) alone for 6 hr or in combination with FZP (1,
10, or 100 μM). The mRNA expression of (A) <italic toggle="yes">E-selectin</italic>, (B)
<italic toggle="yes">intercellular adhesion molecule-1</italic> (<italic toggle="yes">ICAM-1</italic>), and
(C) <italic toggle="yes">P-selectin</italic> was analyzed by qPCR and normalized to the LPS
control set to 1.0. The data represent the mean ± SD from three independent
experiments. Statistical significance was assessed using RM one-way ANOVA with
Tukey’s <italic toggle="yes">post hoc</italic> test, or the Friedman test with Dunn’s correction
when normality was not met. *<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&lt;0.05 versus the indicated
groups.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="jvms-88-3-471-g001.jpg"/></fig> Neither of the doses was statistically significant compared to the LPS control
group (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>≥0.347). Among the treatments, the 100 μM group values increased
compared to the 1 μM group (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>=0.027), yet other pairs were not
significant. In the rh-cTNFα-stimulated group (see <xref rid="fig_002" ref-type="fig">Fig.
2A</xref><fig position="float" fig-type="figure" id="fig_002" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 2.</label><caption><p>Effects of fuzapladib sodium hydrate (FZP) on adhesion molecule expression in
recombinant canine tumor necrosis factor alpha (rh-cTNFα)-stimulated canine aortic
endothelial cells <bold>(</bold>CnAOEC). CnAOEC were challenged with rh-cTNFα (30
ng/mL) alone for 6 hr or combined with FZP (1, 10, or 100 μM). The mRNA expression
of (A) <italic toggle="yes">E-selectin</italic>, (B) <italic toggle="yes">intercellular adhesion
molecule-1</italic> (<italic toggle="yes">ICAM-1</italic>), and (C) <italic toggle="yes">P-selectin</italic>
was quantified by qPCR and normalized to the rh-cTNFα control (set to 1.0). Data are
presented as mean ± SD from three independent experiments. Statistical significance
was assessed using RM one-way ANOVA followed by Tukey’s multiple comparison test.
*<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&lt;0.05, **<italic toggle="yes"> P</italic>&lt;0.01 versus the indicated
groups.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="jvms-88-3-471-g002.jpg"/></fig>), the statistics showed no difference between treatment groups versus the positive
control (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>≥0.395) and no difference between the treatments
(<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>≥0.534). The mean folds were 1.00, 0.82, and 0.95 for 1, 10, and 100
μM of FZP, respectively.</p><p><italic toggle="yes">ICAM-1</italic> gene expression relative to the positive control exhibits a
similar pattern in the LPS-exposed group as <italic toggle="yes">E-selectin</italic>, illustrated in
<xref rid="fig_001" ref-type="fig">Fig. 1B.</xref> The mean fold was 1.00, 0.95, 0.86,
and 1.56 for LPS and FZP concentrations of 1, 10, and 100 μM, respectively. The
statistical analysis showed no significant effect of the <italic toggle="yes">ICAM-1</italic> gene
expression after being challenged with all treatments compared to the LPS treatment alone
(<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>≥0.347). However, <italic toggle="yes">ICAM-1</italic> was significantly
upregulated in the 100 μM group compared to the 10 μM group (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>=0.027).
Other pairwise comparisons were not significant. For the rh-cTNFα treatment groups, the
mean fold versus rh-cTNFα alone was 0.99, 0.81, and 1.39 at 1, 10, and 100 μM of FZP,
respectively, as shown in <xref rid="fig_002" ref-type="fig">Fig. 2B.</xref> These results
revealed that FZP at 100 μM concentration significantly increased <italic toggle="yes">ICAM-1</italic>
gene expression level compared to both the positive control (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>=0.007) and
the FZP 1 μM treatment group (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>=0.039). There are no significant
differences between other pairwise comparisons (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>≥0.359).</p><p><italic toggle="yes">P-selectin</italic> mRNA expression level was highlighted across both stimuli, as
it illustrates an inverse-dose response. The results of the LPS-challenged group indicate
that the mean fold against the isolated LPS treatment was 1.09 (1 μM), 1.21 (10 μM), and
0.84 (100 μM), visible in <xref rid="fig_001" ref-type="fig">Fig. 1C.</xref> The
statistical calculations showed that 100 μM concentration had a significant effect in
reducing <italic toggle="yes">P-selectin</italic> expression levels compared to the 10 μM group
(<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>=0.024). However, other pairwise comparisons were not statistically
significant (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>≥0.052). For the rh-cTNFα treatment groups, the mean fold
change compared to the positive control was 1.07, 0.90, and 0.69 for FZP at 1, 10, and 100
μM, respectively, in a dose-dependent pattern. <xref rid="fig_002" ref-type="fig">Figure
2C</xref> visualizes this pattern. The statistical results indicate that
<italic toggle="yes">P-selectin</italic> was downregulated after incubation with FZP 100 μM compared
to both incubations with rh-cTNFα alone (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>=0.009) and FZP 1 μM
(<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>=0.046). However, all remaining pairwise comparisons were
non-significant (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>≥0.157).</p></sec><sec><title>Effect of fuzapladib sodium hydrate on CXCL1 protein expression in cytokine-induced
CnAOEC</title><p>The concentration of CXCL1 protein was quantified using the Canine CXCL1 ELISA kit to
determine the effect of FZP on cytokine-induced CnAOEC. As expected, stimulation with both
LPS and rh-cTNFα markedly increased CXCL1 levels compared with the negative control (<xref rid="pdf_001" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplementary Table 3</xref>). The
conducted ANOVA test showed no significant effect of treatment on CXCL1 expression in
LPS-stimulated samples (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>=0.286), illustrated in <xref rid="fig_003" ref-type="fig">Fig. 3A.</xref><fig position="float" fig-type="figure" id="fig_003" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 3.</label><caption><p>Effects of fuzapladib sodium hydrate (FZP) on C-X-C motif chemokine ligand 1
(CXCL1) protein expression in cytokine-induced canine aortic endothelial cells
(CnAOEC). CnAOEC were stimulated with (A) lipopolysaccharide (LPS; 100 ng/mL) or (B)
recombinant canine tumor necrosis factor alpha (rh-cTNFα; 30 ng/mL), either in
isolation or combined with FZP (1, 10, or 100 μM) for 24 hr. CXCL1 levels in culture
supernatants were measured using a Canine CXCL1 ELISA kit. Data represent mean ± SD
from three independent experiments. Statistical significance was determined by RM
one-way ANOVA with Tukey’s multiple comparison test
(<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&gt;0.05).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="jvms-88-3-471-g003.jpg"/></fig> In contrast, the overall effect of treatment was statistically significant in the
rh-cTNFα-challenged group (<italic toggle="yes">F</italic>(1.16, 2.32)=20.14,
<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>=0.035), as shown in <xref rid="fig_003" ref-type="fig">Fig. 3B.</xref>
However, Tukey’s <italic toggle="yes">post hoc</italic> test did not identify significant pairwise
differences (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>≥0.054), indicating that the reduction represents a
downward trend rather than a statistically significant suppression. The partial
eta-squared <inline-formula>
<mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" id="M3" display="inline" overflow="scroll"><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:msubsup><mml:mi>η</mml:mi><mml:mi>ρ</mml:mi><mml:mn>2</mml:mn></mml:msubsup></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math>
</inline-formula> was 0.91, consistent with a very large effect size despite the
non-significant pairwise comparisons.</p></sec><sec><title>Effect of fuzapladib sodium hydrate on adhesion molecule gene expression in
cytokine-induced canine neutrophils</title><p>The effect of FZP on neutrophil adhesion molecule gene expression, including
<italic toggle="yes">CXCR2</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">PSGL-1</italic>, and <italic toggle="yes">L-selectin</italic>, was
evaluated using neutrophils isolated from three healthy dogs. For each dog, experiments
were independently repeated three times. Expression values were normalized within the dogs
to the rh-cTNFα–stimulated condition. Subsequently, the gene expression data were averaged
for each dog before statistical analysis. Baseline comparisons showed no significant
difference in <italic toggle="yes">CXCR2</italic> or <italic toggle="yes">L-selectin</italic> expression between
non-stimulated and cTNFα–stimulated neutrophils, but <italic toggle="yes">PSGL-1</italic> expression
was significantly decreased following stimulation (<xref rid="pdf_001" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplementary Table 2</xref>).</p><p>To verify cell survival under the incubation conditions used for gene expression
analysis, neutrophil viability was assessed by evaluating membrane integrity using 7-AAD
staining in parallel flow cytometry experiments performed under identical conditions.
Viability remained high across all treatments (90.6–91.8%) with no significant differences
across all groups (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>≥0.078), confirming that the observed gene expression
changes were not due to cytotoxicity.</p><p>The results of this analysis are shown in <xref rid="fig_004" ref-type="fig">Fig.
4A–C</xref><fig position="float" fig-type="figure" id="fig_004" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 4.</label><caption><p>Effects of fuzapladib sodium hydrate (FZP) on adhesion molecule gene expression in
recombinant canine tumor necrosis factor alpha (rh-cTNFα)-induced canine
neutrophils. Neutrophils from three dogs were pre-incubated with FZP (1, 10, or 100
μM) for 24 hr and then stimulated with rh-cTNFα (20 ng/mL) for 1 hr. Gene expression
of (A) <italic toggle="yes">C-X-C motif chemokine receptor 2</italic> (<italic toggle="yes">CXCR2</italic>),
(B) <italic toggle="yes">P-selectin glycoprotein ligand-1</italic> (<italic toggle="yes">PSGL-1</italic>), and
(C) <italic toggle="yes">L-selectin</italic> was quantified by qPCR and normalized to
rh-cTNFα-stimulated controls. Data represent mean ± SD, averaged per dog.
Statistical analysis was performed using RM one-way ANOVA with Tukey’s test
(*<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&lt;0.05, **<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&lt;0.01).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="jvms-88-3-471-g004.jpg"/></fig>. They highlight that FZP did not significantly affect <italic toggle="yes">CXCR2</italic> gene
expression across 1, 10, and 100 μM, with relative fold changes of 0.92, 0.80, and 0.88,
respectively (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>≥0.368). This is illustrated by <xref rid="fig_004" ref-type="fig">Fig. 4A.</xref> For <italic toggle="yes">PSGL-1</italic>, expression increased at 1 μM
(1.40-fold) and declined at 10 and 100 μM (0.94- and 0.53-fold, respectively), visible in
<xref rid="fig_004" ref-type="fig">Fig. 4B.</xref> When comparing each result with
rh-cTNFα, there was no statistical significance (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>≥0.064). However, 100
μM was significantly lower than 10 μM (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>=0.037).
<italic toggle="yes">L-selectin</italic> revealed a similar pattern, showing relative fold changes of
1.81, 0.88, and 0.54 (1, 10, and 100 μM, respectively). Importantly, expression at 100 μM
was significantly lower than that of the rh-cTNFα-stimulated control
(<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>=0.005), as visualized in <xref rid="fig_004" ref-type="fig">Fig.
4C.</xref></p></sec><sec><title>Effect of fuzapladib sodium hydrate on LFA-1 on rh-cTNFα-induced canine
neutrophils</title><p>This study evaluated whether FZP modulates the expression of LFA-1 (CD11a) in canine
neutrophils under rh-cTNFα-stimulated conditions. Neutrophils were isolated from three
dogs, and three independent experiments were performed for each animal. The mean value
from each dog was used for statistical analysis. The results indicated that stimulation
with rh-cTNFα did not significantly alter CD11a expression compared to the negative
control (<xref rid="pdf_001" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplementary Table
4</xref>).</p><p>The effect of FZP on the mean fluorescence intensity (MFI) of CD11a is shown in <xref rid="fig_005" ref-type="fig">Fig. 5A.</xref><fig position="float" fig-type="figure" id="fig_005" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 5.</label><caption><p>Effects of fuzapladib sodium hydrate (FZP) on leukocyte function-associated
antigen-1 (LFA-1; CD11a subunit) expression in recombinant canine tumor necrosis
factor alpha (rh-cTNFα)-stimulated canine neutrophils. Neutrophils were
pre-incubated with FZP (1, 10, or 100 μM) for 24 hr and stimulated with rh-cTNFα (20
ng/mL) for 1 hr. (A) Mean fluorescence intensity (MFI) of CD11a expression. (B)
Representative flow-cytometric plots showing distinct CD11a-low and CD11a-high
subpopulations. (C and D) Quantitative analysis of low- and high-expression
populations, respectively. Each dog was tested in triplicate, using the mean per
dog. Data are mean ± SD (n=3). Statistical significance was assessed using RM
one-way ANOVA with Tukey’s test, or the Friedman test with Dunn’s correction. No
significant differences were detected (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&gt;0.05).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="jvms-88-3-471-g005.jpg"/></fig> The mean MFI of the rh-cTNFα control group was 2,818; meanwhile, the FZP-treated
groups were 2,892, 2,685, and 2,250 at FZP 1, 10, and 100 μM, respectively. The statistics
indicated that there was no significant difference in overall treatment effect
(<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>=0.727). In addition, the flow cytometric analysis also revealed two
distinct populations of CD11a-positive cells, characterized by either low or high CD11a
expression (<xref rid="fig_005" ref-type="fig">Fig. 5B</xref>). Consequently, the effect
of FZP on the CD11a expression population was determined. The mean percentage of live
cells with low CD11a expression was 49.59% in the rh-cTNFα-stimulated group and 49.15%,
53.83%, and 66.70% following FZP treatment at 1, 10, and 100 μM, respectively (<xref rid="fig_005" ref-type="fig">Fig. 5C</xref>). Conversely, the proportion of live cells
showing high CD11a expression was 37.59%, 47.30%, 42.23%, and 41.41% for the rh-cTNFα
control, FZP at 1, 10, and 100 μM groups, respectively, as exhibited in <xref rid="fig_005" ref-type="fig">Fig. 5D.</xref> The results revealed no statistical
significance in both the low (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>=0.253) and high-expression
(<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>=0.608) populations between any pairs of comparisons.</p></sec><sec><title>Effect of fuzapladib sodium hydrate on static neutrophil adherence to
rh-cTNFα-induced CnAOEC</title><p>Given the observed downregulation of <italic toggle="yes">P-selectin</italic> on endothelial cells
following treatment with FZP, the potential effect on neutrophil adhesion to
rh-cTNFα-stimulated CnAOEC under static adhesion conditions was further investigated.
CnAOEC at passages 4–9 were used for this experiment. Calcein-AM–labeled neutrophils,
isolated from three healthy beagles, were applied to the endothelial cell monolayer
following treatment. Three independent experiments were performed for each dog, and the
mean per dog was used for statistical analysis.</p><p>Stimulation with rh-cTNFα induced a marked increase in neutrophil adhesion to CnAOEC
compared to the negative control (<xref rid="pdf_001" ref-type="supplementary-material">Supplementary Table 5</xref>). The effect of different concentrations of FZP on
neutrophil adhesion was evaluated, as shown in <xref rid="fig_006" ref-type="fig">Fig.
6.</xref><fig position="float" fig-type="figure" id="fig_006" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 6.</label><caption><p>Effect of fuzapladib sodium hydrate (FZP) on static neutrophil adhesion to
recombinant canine tumor necrosis factor alpha (rh-cTNFα)-stimulated canine aortic
endothelial cells <bold>(</bold>CnAOEC). CnAOEC were pre-incubated with FZP (1, 10,
or 100 μM) for 3 hr and subsequently stimulated with rh-cTNFα (30 ng/mL) for 4 hr.
Calcein-AM-labeled neutrophils (1 × 10<sup>5</sup> cells/well) were added and
allowed to adhere for 20 min. Neutrophil adhesion was quantified as relative
fluorescence intensity before and after washing. Data represent mean ± SD from three
dogs, each tested in three independent experiments. The mean per dog was used for
statistical analysis using the Friedman test with Dunn’s <italic toggle="yes">post hoc</italic>
correction, observing no significant effect (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>&gt;0.05).</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="jvms-88-3-471-g006.jpg"/></fig> Overall, there was no statistically significant difference in adhesion among the
treatment groups (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>=0.446). Subsequent pairwise comparisons confirmed the
lack of significance between any of the groups (<italic toggle="yes">P</italic>≥0.683).</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="discussion" id="s4"><title>DISCUSSION</title><p>This study investigated the effects of FZP on adhesion molecules in CnAOEC and canine
neutrophils, focusing on <italic toggle="yes">E-selectin</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">ICAM-1</italic>,
<italic toggle="yes">P-selectin</italic>, CXCL1, <italic toggle="yes">CXCR2</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">PSGL-1</italic>,
<italic toggle="yes">L-selectin</italic>, and LFA-1. Across both stimuli, low concentrations of FZP (1
and 10 μM) showed no significant effect on <italic toggle="yes">E-selectin</italic> and
<italic toggle="yes">ICAM-1</italic> gene expression compared to the stimulation controls, yet 100 μM
resulted in a significant increase in expression levels. These findings are consistent with
earlier observations in HUVEC, where pretreatment with 1 μM FZP did not reduce ICAM-1
protein expression after LPS stimulation [<xref rid="r25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]. In
contrast, <italic toggle="yes">P-selectin</italic> expression illustrated a dose-response profile:
rh-cTNFα-stimulated CnAOEC showed a significant reduction at 100 μM, and LPS-stimulated
cells demonstrated a similar downward trend, though not significant. A notable aspect of the
endothelial response was the divergent behavior of <italic toggle="yes">P-selectin</italic> and
<italic toggle="yes">ICAM-1</italic> at 100 μM. This difference indicates a specific modulation of
signaling pathways rather than overall cytotoxicity, which would usually inhibit global
protein synthesis. One possible explanation is a functional compensatory mechanism that
responds with an increase in <italic toggle="yes">ICAM-1</italic> expression in response to selectin
suppression to maintain adhesive quality [<xref rid="r4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>].</p><p>In addition to adhesion molecules, this study examined the CXCL1-CXCR2 axis, a key pathway
in neutrophil recruitment and survival [<xref rid="r16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>].
Dysregulated CXCL1 expression contributes to inflammation and chronic injury in multiple
organs [<xref rid="r34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>]. In this study, both LPS and rh-cTNFα
strongly induced CXCL1 secretion from CnAOEC, confirming the expected pro-inflammatory
activation. FZP did not change CXCL1 levels under LPS stimulation. In rh-cTNFα-stimulated
conditions, the overall treatment effect was statistically significant, but <italic toggle="yes">post
hoc</italic> comparisons were not. The reduction at 100 μM should therefore be interpreted
as a non-significant downward trend rather than confirmed suppression. Notably, the effect
size was very large <inline-formula>
<mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" id="M4" display="inline" overflow="scroll"><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:msubsup><mml:mi>η</mml:mi><mml:mi>ρ</mml:mi><mml:mn>2</mml:mn></mml:msubsup></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math>
</inline-formula> , indicating that FZP accounted for substantial variance in CXCL1 level
despite the limited statistical power. This observation is consistent with a previous report
showing reduced cytokine-induced neutrophil chemoattractant (CINC), the rodent homolog of
CXCL1, following FZP treatment in an inflammatory model [<xref rid="r35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>]. Given the established role of the CXCL1-CXCR2 axis in neutrophil-mediated
tissue injury, including severe lung conditions [<xref rid="r24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]
and acute pancreatitis, in which fibroblast-derived CXCL1 contributes to inflammation [<xref rid="r32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>], even a partial reduction of CXCL1 has been reported
to influence neutrophil infiltration and inflammatory pathology. Related preclinical
findings, such as reduced macrophage infiltration [<xref rid="r15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>] and improved clinical outcome in canine acute pancreatitis [<xref rid="r6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>], further support the possibility that FZP influences
this cytokine pathway, though confirmation will require studies with larger sample
sizes.</p><p>TNFα is a well-known proinflammatory cytokine that activates neutrophils. The
transcriptional responses observed in rh-cTNFα-stimulated neutrophils were consistent with
established models of leukocyte activation. <italic toggle="yes">PSGL-1</italic> was significantly
downregulated, whereas <italic toggle="yes">CXCR2</italic> and <italic toggle="yes">L-selectin</italic> remained
comparable to non-stimulated controls. These patterns are compatible with the predominance
of rapid ectodomain shedding from the surface rather than transcriptional modulation [<xref rid="r2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>, <xref rid="r14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>, <xref rid="r20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]. Interestingly, high concentrations of FZP further
decreased <italic toggle="yes">L-selectin</italic> and <italic toggle="yes">PSGL-1</italic> mRNA expression. Because
L-selectin mediates leukocyte rolling and secondary tethering between leukocytes [<xref rid="r1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>, <xref rid="r3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>, <xref rid="r17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>, <xref rid="r26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>], and
PSGL-1 cooperates with L-selectin to initiate LFA-1 activation [<xref rid="r27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>], the observed reductions in <italic toggle="yes">L-selectin</italic> and
<italic toggle="yes">PSGL-1</italic> suggest that FZP may interfere with early steps of neutrophil
recruitment. This interpretation is consistent with the established role of L-selectin in
directing lymphocyte migration through high endothelial venules [<xref rid="r31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>].</p><p>In addition to transcriptional responses, the effect of FZP on neutrophil surface
expression of LFA-1 (CD11a) was examined. rh-cTNFα stimulation did not increase CD11a
surface expression compared with control conditions. This is consistent with the established
biology of LFA-1, in which cytokines typically regulate integrin affinity rather than total
surface levels [<xref rid="r30" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>]. Accordingly, MFI analysis was
used to determine whether FZP altered CD11a expression on rh-cTNFα-stimulated neutrophils.
Total LFA-1 (CD11a) expression remained similar across all treatment groups. Although a
numerical increase in the proportion of cells in the low-expression subset was observed at
100 μM FZP, this redistribution did not reach statistical significance. Consequently, it is
suggested that FZP does not primarily affect surface expression or population distributions
under these conditions. This pattern is consistent with the previous report indicating that
FZP and related inhibitors can reduce integrin activation, such as LFA-1 and MAC-1, in
inflammatory models, limiting their conformational activation and adhesive function [<xref rid="r25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>].</p><p>The functional relevance of these molecular changes was examined using a static neutrophil
adhesion assay. As expected, rh-cTNFα stimulation significantly increased neutrophil
adhesion to CnAOEC. Pretreatment of endothelial cells with FZP did not affect adhesion
across all treatment groups, indicating that suppression of <italic toggle="yes">P-selectin</italic>
transcription alone is insufficient to affect static adhesion <italic toggle="yes">in vitro.</italic>
This is consistent with previous studies showing that P-selectin is essential for the
initial tethering of polymorphonuclear leukocytes. However, by itself, it cannot support
firm adhesion without additional activating signals, such as platelet-activating factors
[<xref rid="r19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]. P-selectin has also been involved in several
inflammatory pathologies, including dermatitis, lung injury, ischemia, myocardial damage,
and arterial thrombosis [<xref rid="r7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>, <xref rid="r21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>, <xref rid="r28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>]. Thus, although no
significant effects were detected in this static adhesion assay, which primarily relies on
integrin-mediated firm adhesion, the observed <italic toggle="yes">P-selectin</italic> suppression
remains biologically significant for the earlier stages of the adhesion cascade. Because
P-selectin mediates initial tethering and rolling under physiological flow conditions, its
downregulation by FZP suggests a potential to attenuate the recruitment phase of
inflammation. Furthermore, only endothelial cells were exposed to FZP in this assay, and
neutrophil integrin activation was therefore unlikely to be affected, which may further
explain the absence of changes in firm adhesion in this study.</p><p>Taken together, these results suggest that FZP modulates several adhesion molecules in
endothelial cells and neutrophils in a dose-dependent manner. In CnAOEC, the most consistent
effect was suppression of <italic toggle="yes">P-selectin</italic> and a potential reduction of CXCL1
secretion. Yet, in neutrophils, decreases in <italic toggle="yes">L-selectin</italic> and
<italic toggle="yes">PSGL-1</italic> were observed. Although statistical significance was not achieved
across multiple assays, the overall downward trends in both cell types support the
possibility that FZP influences the early steps of neutrophil recruitment, particularly the
rolling and tethering phases. It should be noted that most of the notable effects occurred
at 100 μM, which exceeds the expected peak plasma concentration (C<sub>max</sub>) observed
in dogs treated with the clinical dose at 0.4 mg/kg [<xref rid="r29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>]. Consequently, these findings should be interpreted as <italic toggle="yes">in
vitro</italic> mechanistic observations demonstrating the potential effect rather than a
direct reflection of therapeutic plasma concentration.</p><p>However, this study has several limitations. The experiments were performed under static
<italic toggle="yes">in vitro</italic> conditions, which do not replicate physiological shear stress or
dynamic interactions that occur <italic toggle="yes">in vivo</italic>. The number of donor dogs and the
range of FZP concentrations were also limited, which may influence the statistical power.
Most observations were derived from gene expression analyses, with restricted confirmation
at the protein level. In the present static adhesion assay, FZP treatment was restricted to
endothelial cells to specifically isolate the endothelial contribution to neutrophil
recruitment. Consequently, the direct effects of FZP on the neutrophil side were not
evaluated in this functional assay. Future studies should employ flow-based adhesion assays,
which more accurately replicate physiological conditions, and co-incubation assays under
cytokine-induced conditions to clarify downstream consequences. Additional experiments with
larger sample sizes and protein-level analyses, as well as further investigation of the
underlying mechanisms, would help confirm the biological relevance of FZP. Overall, the
present findings provide experimental support that FZP has anti-inflammatory effects by
modulating adhesion molecules and neutrophil trafficking.</p></sec><sec sec-type="COI-statement" id="s5"><title>CONFLICT OF INTEREST</title><p>The authors declare that they have no competing financial interests or personal
relationships that could have influenced the work reported in this study.</p></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Material</title><supplementary-material id="pdf_001" position="float" content-type="local-data" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="jvms-88-3-471-s001.pdf" id="d67e1356" position="anchor" orientation="portrait"/></supplementary-material></sec></body><back><ack><p>The authors would like to thank the staff of the Laboratory of Veterinary Surgery,
Department of Veterinary Clinical Science, Hokkaido University, for their valuable technical
assistance and continuous support throughout this study. We are also grateful to the animal
care staff for their assistance with sample collection and to our colleagues for
constructive discussions.</p></ack><ref-list><title>REFERENCES</title><ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Alon</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fuhlbrigge</surname><given-names>RC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Finger</surname><given-names>EB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Springer</surname><given-names>TA</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>1996</year>. <article-title>Interactions through L-selectin between
leukocytes and adherent leukocytes nucleate rolling adhesions on selectins and VCAM-1 in
shear flow</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">J Cell
Biol</italic></source><volume>135</volume>: <fpage>849</fpage>–<lpage>865</lpage>. doi:
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1083/jcb.135.3.849</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8909556</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2121073</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Asagoe</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Takahashi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Suzuki</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Maeda</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nohgawa</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Harakawa</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Takano</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mukaida</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Matsushima</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Okuma</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sasada</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>1998</year>. <article-title>Down-regulation of CXCR2 expression on
human polymorphonuclear leukocytes by TNF-alpha</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">J
Immunol</italic></source><volume>160</volume>:
<fpage>4518</fpage>–<lpage>4525</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.160.9.4518</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9574558</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Bargatze</surname><given-names>RF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kurk</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Butcher</surname><given-names>EC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jutila</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>1994</year>. <article-title>Neutrophils roll on adherent
neutrophils bound to cytokine-induced endothelial cells via L-selectin on the rolling
cells</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">J Exp Med</italic></source><volume>180</volume>:
<fpage>1785</fpage>–<lpage>1792</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1084/jem.180.5.1785</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7525838</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2191733</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Bullard</surname><given-names>DC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kunkel</surname><given-names>EJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kubo</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hicks</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lorenzo</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Doyle</surname><given-names>NA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Doerschuk</surname><given-names>CM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ley</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Beaudet</surname><given-names>AL</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>1996</year>. <article-title>Infectious susceptibility and severe
deficiency of leukocyte rolling and recruitment in E-selectin and P-selectin double
mutant mice</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">J Exp
Med</italic></source><volume>183</volume>: <fpage>2329</fpage>–<lpage>2336</lpage>. doi:
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1084/jem.183.5.2329</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8642341</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2192541</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Deng</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cui</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zuo</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Deng</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2017</year>. <article-title>Inflammatory responses and
inflammation-associated diseases in organs</article-title>.
<source><italic toggle="yes">Oncotarget</italic></source><volume>9</volume>:
<fpage>7204</fpage>–<lpage>7218</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.18632/oncotarget.23208</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29467962</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5805548</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Cridge</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lim</surname><given-names>SY</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Algül</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Steiner</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2022</year>. <article-title>New insights into the etiology, risk
factors, and pathogenesis of pancreatitis in dogs: Potential impacts on clinical
practice</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">J Vet Intern
Med</italic></source><volume>36</volume>: <fpage>847</fpage>–<lpage>864</lpage>. doi:
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jvim.16437</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35546513</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9151489</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Doré</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sirois</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>1996</year>. <article-title>Regulation of P-selectin expression by
inflammatory mediators in canine jugular endothelial cells</article-title>.
<source><italic toggle="yes">Vet Pathol</italic></source><volume>33</volume>:
<fpage>662</fpage>–<lpage>671</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/030098589603300605</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8952025</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Doré</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Simon</surname><given-names>SI</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hughes</surname><given-names>BJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Entman</surname><given-names>ML</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>CW</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>1995</year>. <article-title>P-selectin- and CD18-mediated
recruitment of canine neutrophils under conditions of shear stress</article-title>.
<source><italic toggle="yes">Vet Pathol</italic></source><volume>32</volume>:
<fpage>258</fpage>–<lpage>268</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/030098589503200307</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7541590</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Filep</surname><given-names>JG</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2022</year>. <article-title>Targeting Neutrophils for Promoting the
Resolution of Inflammation</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Front
Immunol</italic></source><volume>13</volume>: <fpage>866747</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2022.866747</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35371088</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8966391</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Habtezion</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2015</year>. <article-title>Inflammation in acute and chronic
pancreatitis</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Curr Opin
Gastroenterol</italic></source><volume>31</volume>:
<fpage>395</fpage>–<lpage>399</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/MOG.0000000000000195</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26107390</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4618697</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Hines</surname><given-names>OJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pandol</surname><given-names>SJ</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2019</year>. <article-title>Management of severe acute
pancreatitis</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">BMJ</italic></source><volume>367</volume>:
<fpage>l6227</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/bmj.l6227</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31791953</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r12"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Imamura</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Niikawa</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kitamura</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Takahashi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ikegami</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yoshida</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mitamura</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2003</year>. <article-title>Effect of IS-741 on ethionine-induced
acute pancreatitis in rats: relation to pancreatic acinar cell
regeneration</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">J
Gastroenterol</italic></source><volume>38</volume>:
<fpage>260</fpage>–<lpage>267</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s005350300045</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12673449</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r13"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Isaji</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hayashi</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Higashiguchi</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yokoi</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ogura</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Noguchi</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kawarada</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>1999</year>. <article-title>Effect of IS-741 (a new synthetic
antiinflammatory agent) on acute necrotizing pancreatitis in dogs. Significance of its
inhibitory effect on cytosolic phospholipase A2</article-title>.
<source><italic toggle="yes">Digestion</italic></source><volume>60</volume>
<issue>Suppl 1</issue>: <fpage>47</fpage>–<lpage>51</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1159/000051453</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10026431</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r14"><label>14</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Ivetic</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hoskins Green</surname><given-names>HL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hart</surname><given-names>SJ</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2019</year>. <article-title>L-selectin: a major regulator of
leukocyte adhesion, migration and signaling</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Front
Immunol</italic></source><volume>10</volume>: <fpage>1068</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2019.01068</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31139190</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6527602</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r15"><label>15</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaji</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Iwaoka</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tsukamoto</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2023</year>. <article-title>Fuzapladib reduces postsurgical
inflammation in the intestinal muscularis externa</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">J Vet
Med Sci</italic></source><volume>85</volume>: <fpage>1151</fpage>–<lpage>1156</lpage>.
doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1292/jvms.23-0257</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37730381</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10686772</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r16"><label>16</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Korbecki</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gąssowska-Dobrowolska</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wójcik</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Szatkowska</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Barczak</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chlubek</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Baranowska-Bosiacka</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2022</year>. <article-title>The importance of CXCL1 in physiology
and noncancerous diseases of bone, bone marrow, muscle and the nervous
system</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Int J Mol
Sci</italic></source><volume>23</volume>: <fpage>4205</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/ijms23084205</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35457023</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9024980</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r17"><label>17</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Kunkel</surname><given-names>EJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chomas</surname><given-names>JE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ley</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>1998</year>. <article-title>Role of primary and secondary capture
for leukocyte accumulation <italic toggle="yes">in vivo</italic></article-title>.
<source><italic toggle="yes">Circ Res</italic></source><volume>82</volume>:
<fpage>30</fpage>–<lpage>38</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1161/01.RES.82.1.30</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9440702</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r18"><label>18</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Imaizumi</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Matsumiya</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Seya</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kawaguchi</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ding</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ohkuma</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2020</year>. <article-title>Polyinosinic-polycytidylic acid induces
CXCL1 expression in cultured hCMEC/D3 human cerebral microvascular endothelial
cells</article-title>.
<source><italic toggle="yes">Neuroimmunomodulation</italic></source><volume>27</volume>:
<fpage>38</fpage>–<lpage>47</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1159/000506482</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32294654</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r19"><label>19</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Lorant</surname><given-names>DE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Topham</surname><given-names>MK</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Whatley</surname><given-names>RE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>McEver</surname><given-names>RP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>McIntyre</surname><given-names>TM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Prescott</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zimmerman</surname><given-names>GA</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>1993</year>. <article-title>Inflammatory roles of
P-selectin</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">J Clin
Invest</italic></source><volume>92</volume>: <fpage>559</fpage>–<lpage>570</lpage>. doi:
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1172/JCI116623</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">7688760</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC294887</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r20"><label>20</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Marsik</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mayr</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cardona</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schaller</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wagner</surname><given-names>OF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jilma</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2004</year>. <article-title>Endotoxin down-modulates P-selectin
glycoprotein ligand-1 (PSGL-1, CD162) on neutrophils in humans</article-title>.
<source><italic toggle="yes">J Clin Immunol</italic></source><volume>24</volume>:
<fpage>62</fpage>–<lpage>65</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1023/B:JOCI.0000018064.13793.83</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14997035</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r21"><label>21</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Minamino</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kitakaze</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Asanuma</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tomiyama</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shiraga</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sato</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ueda</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Funaya</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kuzuya</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Matsuzawa</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hori</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>1998</year>. <article-title>Endogenous adenosine inhibits
P-selectin-dependent formation of coronary thromboemboli during hypoperfusion in
dogs</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">J Clin
Invest</italic></source><volume>101</volume>: <fpage>1643</fpage>–<lpage>1653</lpage>.
doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1172/JCI635</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">9541494</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC508745</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r22"><label>22</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Okanishi</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kagawa</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Watari</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2014</year>. <article-title>Expression of selectins and P-selectin
glycoprotein ligand-1 in dogs with lymphocytic-plasmacytic enteritis</article-title>.
<source><italic toggle="yes">Vet Immunol Immunopathol</italic></source><volume>161</volume>:
<fpage>42</fpage>–<lpage>48</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.vetimm.2014.06.005</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25063223</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r23"><label>23</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Park</surname><given-names>SA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hyun</surname><given-names>YM</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2016</year>. <article-title>Neutrophil extravasation cascade: what
can we learn from two-photon intravital imaging?</article-title><source><italic toggle="yes">Immune
Netw</italic></source><volume>16</volume>: <fpage>317</fpage>–<lpage>321</lpage>. doi:
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4110/in.2016.16.6.317</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28035206</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5195840</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r24"><label>24</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Sawant</surname><given-names>KV</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cox</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hawkins</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sbrana</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kolli</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Garofalo</surname><given-names>RP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rajarathnam</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2015</year>. <article-title>Chemokine CXCL1-mediated neutrophil
trafficking in the lung: role of CXCR2 activation</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">J
Innate Immun</italic></source><volume>7</volume>:
<fpage>647</fpage>–<lpage>658</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1159/000430914</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26138727</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4618178</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r25"><label>25</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Shikama</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yotsuya</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Satake</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sugi</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kato</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>1999</year>. <article-title>Effect of IS-741 on cell adhesion
between human umbilical vein endothelial cells and HL-60 cells</article-title>.
<source><italic toggle="yes">Biol Pharm Bull</italic></source><volume>22</volume>:
<fpage>127</fpage>–<lpage>131</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1248/bpb.22.127</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10077429</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r26"><label>26</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Spertini</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Luscinskas</surname><given-names>FW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kansas</surname><given-names>GS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Munro</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Griffin</surname><given-names>JD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gimbrone</surname><given-names>MA</given-names><suffix>Jr.</suffix></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tedder</surname><given-names>TF</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>1991</year>. <article-title>Leukocyte adhesion molecule-1 (LAM-1,
L-selectin) interacts with an inducible endothelial cell ligand to support leukocyte
adhesion</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">J
Immunol</italic></source><volume>147</volume>: <fpage>2565</fpage>–<lpage>2573</lpage>.
doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.147.8.2565</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1717567</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r27"><label>27</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Stadtmann</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Germena</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Block</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Boras</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rossaint</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sundd</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lefort</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fisher</surname><given-names>CI</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Buscher</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gelschefarth</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Urzainqui</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gerke</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ley</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zarbock</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2013</year>. <article-title>The PSGL-1-L-selectin signaling complex
regulates neutrophil adhesion under flow</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">J Exp
Med</italic></source><volume>210</volume>: <fpage>2171</fpage>–<lpage>2180</lpage>.
doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1084/jem.20130664</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24127491</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3804951</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r28"><label>28</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Tremblay</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Paradis</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Doré</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2001</year>. <article-title>Expression of E- and P-selectin in
tumor necrosis factor-induced dermatitis in dogs</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Vet
Pathol</italic></source><volume>38</volume>: <fpage>261</fpage>–<lpage>268</lpage>.
doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1354/vp.38-3-261</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11355655</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r29"><label>29</label><mixed-citation publication-type="eref">U.S. Food and Drug
Administration. <year>2022</year>. Freedom of Information Summary, Conditional Approval
NADA 141–567, PANOQUELL<sup>®</sup>-CA1 (fuzapladib sodium for injection). <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://animaldrugsatfda.fda.gov/adafda/app/search/public/document/downloadFoi/13134" ext-link-type="uri">https://animaldrugsatfda.fda.gov/adafda/app/search/public/document/downloadFoi/13134</ext-link>
[accessed on November 29, 2025].</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r30"><label>30</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>van Kooyk</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Figdor</surname><given-names>CG</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2000</year>. <article-title>Avidity regulation of integrins: the
driving force in leukocyte adhesion</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Curr Opin Cell
Biol</italic></source><volume>12</volume>: <fpage>542</fpage>–<lpage>547</lpage>. doi:
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0955-0674(00)00129-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10978887</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r31"><label>31</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>von Andrian</surname><given-names>UH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mempel</surname><given-names>TR</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2003</year>. <article-title>Homing and cellular traffic in lymph
nodes</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Nat Rev
Immunol</italic></source><volume>3</volume>: <fpage>867</fpage>–<lpage>878</lpage>. doi:
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nri1222</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14668803</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r32"><label>32</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Han</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lv</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zheng</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>X</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Du</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Xue</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2025</year>. <article-title>Immunodynamic axis of fibroblast-driven
neutrophil infiltration in acute pancreatitis: NF-κB-HIF-1α-CXCL1</article-title>.
<source><italic toggle="yes">Cell Mol Biol Lett</italic></source><volume>30</volume>:
<fpage>57</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s11658-025-00734-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40335899</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12060353</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r33"><label>33</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Wilhelmsen</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Farrar</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hellman</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2013</year>. <article-title>Quantitative <italic toggle="yes">in vitro</italic>
assay to measure neutrophil adhesion to activated primary human microvascular
endothelial cells under static conditions</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">J Vis
Exp</italic></source><volume>78</volume>: <fpage>e50677</fpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23995778</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3791/50677</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3856291</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r34"><label>34</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>CL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yin</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>SN</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ying</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>2021</year>. <article-title>A review of CXCL1 in cardiac
fibrosis</article-title>. <source><italic toggle="yes">Front Cardiovasc
Med</italic></source><volume>8</volume>: <fpage>674498</fpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2021.674498</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33996954</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8113392</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r35"><label>35</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group><name name-style="western"><surname>Yamaguchi</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Okabe</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Matsumura</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Akizuki</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Matsuda</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ohshiro</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nakano</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ishihara</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ogawa</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group>. <year>1999</year>. <article-title>The novel carboxamide derivative IS-741
reduces neutrophil chemoattractant production by bronchoalveolar macrophages in rats
with cerulein-induced pancreatitis complicated by sepsis</article-title>.
<source><italic toggle="yes">Digestion</italic></source><volume>60</volume>
<issue>Suppl 1</issue>: <fpage>52</fpage>–<lpage>56</lpage>. doi: <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1159/000051454</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">10026432</pub-id>
</mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>