<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article article-type="research-article" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Acta Neuropathol Commun</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Acta Neuropathol Commun</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2200</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">actaneurocomm</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Acta Neuropathologica Communications</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2051-5960</issn><publisher><publisher-name>BMC</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC13041443</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC13041443.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">13041443</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">13041443</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">41742307</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s40478-026-02264-4</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">2264</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Research</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title><italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic> R213 knock-in mice reveal variant- and region-specific mechanisms underlying self-limited familial neonatal-infantile epilepsy and early infantile developmental and epileptic encephalopathy</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" equal-contrib="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Nishijo</surname><given-names initials="T">Takuma</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff4">4</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" equal-contrib="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hamada</surname><given-names initials="N">Nanako</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Suliman-Lavie</surname><given-names initials="R">Reut</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tabata</surname><given-names initials="H">Hidenori</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ito</surname><given-names initials="H">Hidenori</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Iwamoto</surname><given-names initials="I">Ikuko</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Shifman</surname><given-names initials="S">Sagiv</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Nagata</surname><given-names initials="KI">Koh-ichi</given-names></name><address><email>knagata@inst-hsc.jp</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/05w4mbn40</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.440395.f</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1773 8175</institution-id><institution>Department of Molecular Neurobiology, Institute for Developmental Research, </institution><institution>Aichi Developmental Disability Center, </institution></institution-wrap>713-8 Kamiya, Kasugai, Aichi 480-0392 Japan </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/03qxff017</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.9619.7</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1937 0538</institution-id><institution>Department of Genetics, </institution><institution>The Alexander Silberman Institute of Life Sciences The Hebrew University of Jerusalem, </institution></institution-wrap>91904 Jerusalem, Israel </aff><aff id="Aff3"><label>3</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/04chrp450</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.27476.30</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0001 0943 978X</institution-id><institution>Department of Neurochemistry, </institution><institution>Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, </institution></institution-wrap>65 Tsurumai-Cho, Showa-Ku, Nagoya, Aichi 466-8550 Japan </aff><aff id="Aff4"><label>4</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/01gaw2478</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.264706.1</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0000 9239 9995</institution-id><institution>Present Address: Laboratory of Physical Chemistry, Faculty of Pharmaceutical Sciences, </institution><institution>Teikyo University, </institution></institution-wrap>Itabashi-ku, Tokyo, 173-8605 Japan </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>25</day><month>2</month><year>2026</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2026</year></pub-date><volume>14</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">503820</issue-id><elocation-id>76</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>4</day><month>7</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>16</day><month>2</month><year>2026</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>25</day><month>02</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>02</day><month>04</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2026-04-02 10:25:13.330"><day>02</day><month>04</month><year>2026</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>© The Author(s) 2026</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2026</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License, which permits use, sharing, adaptation, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons licence, and indicate if changes were made. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article’s Creative Commons licence, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article’s Creative Commons licence and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this licence, visit <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="40478_2026_Article_2264.pdf"/><abstract id="Abs1" abstract-type="unstructured"><p id="Par1"><italic toggle="yes">KCNQ2</italic> variants cause a spectrum of neonatal epilepsies, ranging from self-limited familial neonatal-infantile epilepsy (SeLFNIE) to early infantile developmental and epileptic encephalopathy (EIDEE). Two distinct missense variants at the same residue, p.R213W and p.R213Q, are associated with SeLFNIE and EIDEE, respectively. This study aimed to elucidate the in vivo effects of these variants on brain development and neuronal excitability using two knock-in mouse models, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup>. We assessed survival, seizure susceptibility, histological and molecular phenotypes, and electrophysiological properties in cortical and hippocampal neurons, and conducted RNA sequencing analyses of cortical tissue to identify transcriptional alterations. <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice exhibited tonic–clonic seizures, shortened lifespan, delayed cortical neuron migration, abnormal elongation of the axon initial segment in cortical neurons, and dentate gyrus-specific gliosis. In contrast, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> mice showed a milder phenotype with transient seizures and largely preserved cortical function. RNA sequencing analyses revealed that p.R213Q selectively upregulated genes involved in endoplasmic reticulum stress and synaptic regulation, together with compensatory upregulation of potassium channel subunits. These findings demonstrate that the two <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic> variants lead to distinct neurodevelopmental phenotypes, attributable not only to differential impairment of the M-current but also to aberrant cortical development and stress response pathways. In particular, p.R213Q induces sustained cortical hyperexcitability and axon initial segment abnormalities, whereas p.R213W results in the milder phenotype. The established knock-in models provide powerful tools for elucidating disease mechanisms of EIDEE and SeLFNIE, and developing targeted therapies for <italic toggle="yes">KCNQ2</italic>-related epilepsies.</p><sec><title>Supplementary Information</title><p>The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s40478-026-02264-4.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group xml:lang="en"><title>Keywords</title><kwd>KCNQ2</kwd><kwd>Self-limited familial neonatal-infantile epilepsy</kwd><kwd>Early infantile developmental epileptic encephalopathy</kwd><kwd>Pathogenic variants</kwd><kwd>Knock-in mice</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="FundRef">https://doi.org/10.13039/501100001691</institution-id><institution>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</institution></institution-wrap></funding-source><award-id>JP23K14997</award-id><award-id>JP22H03049, JP22K19498</award-id></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>© BioMed Central Ltd., part of Springer Nature 2026</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par2"><italic toggle="yes">KCNQ2</italic> encodes the Kv7.2 subunit of the voltage-gated potassium channel, which pairs with Kv7.3 (encoded by <italic toggle="yes">KCNQ3</italic>) to form heterotetrameric channels generating the M-current (I<sub>M</sub>). This non-inactivating K<sup>+</sup> current stabilizes the neuronal membrane potential and regulates action potential generation by controlling its threshold [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>]. Kv7.2 plays a crucial role in regulating neuronal excitability, and its importance in brain development is highlighted by neonatal-onset epilepsy caused by <italic toggle="yes">KCNQ2</italic> variants, spanning a clinical spectrum from benign self-limited familial neonatal-infantile epilepsy (SeLFNIE) to severe early infantile developmental and epileptic encephalopathy (EIDEE), which is characterized by severe seizures and neurocognitive delay [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>].</p><p id="Par3">Haploinsufficiency caused by the loss-of-function of a single <italic toggle="yes">KCNQ2</italic> allele, typically due to nonsense, splice-site, or frameshift variants, is the most common genetic mechanism underlying SeLFNIE, accounting for over 90% of molecularly confirmed cases [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>]. In contrast, de novo missense variants are frequently associated with EIDEE, a more severe epileptic phenotype [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>]. Variants causing complete loss of function or exerting dominant-negative effects tend to result in EIDEE, whereas milder functional reductions are linked to SeLFNIE [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>]. Notably, missense variants associated with both SeLFNIE and EIDEE are distributed broadly across the Kv7.2 protein – including the voltage-sensing domain (VSD), pore region, and cytoplasmic domains – without a clear correlation to clinical severity [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>]. This suggests that a variant’s functional and phenotypic outcome is not determined solely by its location in the protein. Rather, the biochemical nature of the amino acid substitution and its effect on channel gating or assembly (perhaps in a development- or cell-specific context) likely drive the clinical severity. Although accumulating evidence shows that many pathogenic variants reduce I<sub>M</sub> and thereby increase neuronal excitability, the precise pathophysiological significance of <italic toggle="yes">KCNQ2</italic> variants in SeLFNIE and EIDEE, as well as the molecular mechanisms underlying their functional defects, remain to be fully elucidated.</p><p id="Par4">It is noteworthy that two distinct de novo heterozygous missense variants at residue R213 of Kv7.2, a positively charged site within the S4 transmembrane segment of the VSD, have been identified in children with divergent clinical outcomes. The variant (c.637C &gt; T, p.R213W) is associated with SeLFNIE [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>], while the variant (c.638G &gt; A, p.R213Q) is linked to EIDEE [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>]. In vitro electrophysiological studies suggest that the significant phenotypic differences between these two variants are related to the degree of functional impairment: both variants reduce channel voltage sensitivity, but p.R213Q produces more severe impairment, potentially underlying its drastic clinical presentation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>]. In silico structural analyses further suggest that substitution with tryptophan (p.R213W), but not glutamine (p.R213Q), stabilizes the VSD through a unique aromatic interaction [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>], implying that different amino acid substitutions at R213 exert distinct effects on Kv7.2 function. Nevertheless, it remains unclear whether the substantial clinical divergence can be fully explained by differences in I<sub>M</sub> impairment. Other, yet unidentified mechanisms may also contribute to the severe phenotype observed with the p.R213Q variant. Supporting this, a pathological analysis of a post-mortem brain from a patient with EIDEE carrying the p.G215R variant revealed cortical malformations, including the presence of heterotopic neurons in deep white matter, when compared to an age-matched control [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>]. These findings emphasize the critical role of Kv7.2 in cortical development. However, both the pathophysiological significance of these variants and the precise molecular mechanisms by which they influence cortical architecture remain to be elucidated.</p><p id="Par5">In this study, we generated two knock-in (KI) mouse models, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> for SeLFNIE and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> for EIDEE. Analyses of these models revealed structural and functional neuronal changes associated with each variant, indicating region- and variant-specific effects on neuronal excitability. These findings provide new insights into the mechanisms driving the contrasting phenotypes of benign and severe <italic toggle="yes">KCNQ2</italic>-related epilepsies.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2"><title>Material and methods</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>Plasmids</title><p id="Par6">Mouse <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic> cDNA was kindly provided by Prof. Naoto Hoshi (University of California, Irvine), and subcloned into the pCAG-Myc vector (Addgene Inc., Cambridge, MA). Using pCAG-Myc-<italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic> as a template, two variants, c.637C &gt; T (p.R213W) and c.638G &gt; A (p.R213Q), were introduced using KOD-Plus Mutagenesis kit (Toyobo, Osaka, Japan). All constructs were verified by DNA sequencing. pCAG-EGFP were from Addgene Inc (Cat#11,150).</p><sec id="Sec4"><title>Primary antibodies</title><p id="Par7">Polyclonal rabbit anti-Myc was produced as described previously [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>]. The following rabbit polyclonal antibodies were used: anti-Cux1 (Gene Tex, Cat# GTX56275, 1:300), anti-GFP (Medical &amp; Biological Laboratories, Cat# 598, 1:1000), anti-Iba1 (FUJIFILM, Cat# 019–19741, 1:1000), anti-NeuN (Abcam, Cat# ab177487, 1:3000), and anti-Kv7.2 (KCNQ2; Synaptic Systems, Cat# 368 103, 1:1000). Polyclonal guinea pig anti-Ankyrin G was from Synaptic Systems (Cat# 368 005, 1:500). Mouse monoclonal anti-GFAP (Sigma, Cat# G3893, 1:300), and anti-β-actin (Cell Signaling, Cat# 3700, 1:5000), as well as rat monoclonal anti-Ctip2 antibody (Abcam, Cat# ab18465, 1:500), were also used. Alexa Fluor 488-, 568-, and 647-labeled IgG (Abcam, Cat# ab150077, ab175471, and ab150075, respectively) were used as secondary antibodies at a 1:1000 dilution. 4’, 6-diamidino-2-phenylindole (DAPI) (Sigma-Aldrich, Cat# D9542, 0.2 μg/ml) was used to stain DNA.</p></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Structural analysis</title><p id="Par8">To determine the protein structure of the human Kv7.2, we consulted with the AlphaFold Protein Structure Database (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://alphafold.ebi.ac.uk/">https://alphafold.ebi.ac.uk/</ext-link>), and performed a structural analysis using PyMol software (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.pymol.org/pymol/">http://www.pymol.org/pymol/</ext-link>).</p></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Generation of KI mice, <bold><italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic></bold><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <bold><italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic></bold><sup>R213Q/+</sup>, carrying the c.637C &gt; T, p.R213W and c.638G &gt; A, p.R213Q variants, respectively</title><p id="Par9">The KI mouse models, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup>, with Slc:ICR background were generated using the <underline>i</underline>mproved<underline>-g</underline>enome editing via <underline>o</underline>viductal <underline>n</underline>ucleic <underline>a</underline>cids <underline>d</underline>elivery (i-GONAD) technique [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>]. For <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup>, crRNA 5′- GGATGATCCGTATGGACCGG-3′ was chosen to target exon 4 (Supplementary Fig. 1A). ssODN (5′-TTGCGGTTCTTGCAAATCTTGCGGATGATCCGTATGGACTGGAGGGGTGGCACCTGGAAGCTCTTGG -3′ for R213W and 5′-TTGCGGTTCTTGCAAATCTTGCGGATGATCCGTATGGACCAGAGGGGTGGCACCTGGAAGCTCTTGG -3′ for R213Q, respectively), Cas9 (cat# 1,081,060), and tracrRNA (cat# 1,072,534) were obtained from Integrated DNA Technologies Inc. For the i-GONAD procedure, Cas9, crRNAs, and tracrRNA were dissolved in Opti-MEM and injected into the oviducts of Slc:ICR pregnant mice 0.5 day post conception. The electroporation parameters were as follows: poring pulse (voltage, 50 V; pulse length, 5 ms; pulse interval, 50 ms; number of pulses, 3; decay rate, 10%; polarity switch, +), and transfer pulse (voltage, 10 V; pulse length, 50 ms; pulse interval, 10 ms; number of pulses, 3; decay rate, 40%; polarity switch, ±). Genotyping for R213W was performed by digesting PCR products with PstI for R213W, and PvuII for R213Q, using genomic DNA extracted from the mice (R213W: forward primer, 5′-GGGCAATGTCTTTGCCACATCTGC-3′; reverse primer, 5′-GAGCTTCCAGGTGCCACCCCTGC-3′, R213Q: forward primer, 5′-GGGCAATGTCTTTGCCACATCTGC-3′; reverse primer, 5′-CCAAGAGCTTCCAGGTGCCACCCAGC-3′).</p><p id="Par10"><italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice were independently generated and each backcrossed for at least five generations to C57BL/6 J. Thus, the lines are not strictly congenic, and their genetic backgrounds are not completely identical. For all analyses in this study, wild-type littermates from both lines were pooled and used as common controls.</p></sec><sec id="Sec7"><title>Immunohistochemistry</title><p id="Par11">Mice were deeply anesthetized with isoflurane inhalation, followed by perfusion with phosphate-buffered saline (PBS) and subsequently with 4% paraformaldehyde (PFA) in PBS.</p><p id="Par12">After perfusion, the embryonic and adult brains were dissected and fixed in 4% PFA for at least.</p><p id="Par13">16 h. Brains were then coronally sectioned at either 100 μm or 12 μm thickness. For immunostaining, embryonic brain sections were mounted on MAS-coated slides and treated with HistoVT One (Nacalai Tesque Inc., Cat#06380–05) at 70 °C for 20 min. After washing with PBS containing 0.05% Tween-20 (PBST), sections were blocked with 1% bovine serum alubmin in PBST. Primary antibodies were applied overnight at 4 °C in PBST. The following day, secondary antibody incubation and nuclear staining with DAPI (0.2 μg/ml) were carried out in PBST for 1 h. Stained sections were mounted using anti-fading mounting medium (PERMAFLUOR, Thermo Scientific, Cat# TA-030-FM). Fluorescence images were acquired using an LSM880 confocal laser microscope (Carl Zeiss), and bright field images were captured using a BZ-9000 microscope (Keyence).</p></sec><sec id="Sec8"><title>Golgi–Cox staining and spine analysis</title><p id="Par14">Golgi-Cox staining was performed using the FD Rapid GolgiStain Kit (FD NeuroTechnologies, Cat# PK401A) following the manufacturer’s protocol with slight modifications. One month-old male mice were deeply anesthetized with isoflurane and decapitated. Their brains were rapidly removed and placed in FD Solution AB (1:1 mixture) for two weeks at room temperature in the dark. After this incubation, the brains were transferred to FD Solution C or a tissue-protectant solution (20% sucrose, 15% glycerol in distilled water) and kept at 4 °C in the dark for 72 h before being coronally sectioned at 100 μm thickness. Sections were mounted and stained according to the manufacturer’s instructions. After dehydration, slides were mounted with Permount (Fisher Scientific, Cat# SP15-100). Z-stack images (20–30 stacks with 1 μm intervals for dendrites, 0.1 μm intervals for spines) were captured using 20x (dendrites) and 100x (spines) objectives on a BZ-9000 microscope. The number and length of basal dendritic branches were analyzed using the NeuronJ plugin in Fiji. Spine density on dendrites located within 50–100 μm of the cell body was quantified using the Dendritic Spine Counter plugin, also in Fiji.</p></sec><sec id="Sec9"><title>In utero electroporation</title><p id="Par15">In utero electroporation was conducted following a previously described protocol [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>]. In brief, pregnant mice were deeply anesthetized with a mixture of butorphanol (5 mg/kg), medetomidine (0.75 mg/kg), and midazolam (4 mg/kg) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>]. The specified plasmid was injected into the lateral ventricles of the embryos, followed by electroporation using the NEPA21 electroporator (NEPA Gene). Electroporation parameters consisted of five 50 ms pulses at 35 V with 450 ms intervals. This method ensured plasmid introduction into the somatosensory cortex, located within the parietal lobe. After electroporation, brains were collected at the indicated embryonic or postnatal stages, fixed, sectioned, and subjected to analysis. All procedures were performed during daylight hours. No animals were excluded or harmed during the course of the experiments.</p></sec><sec id="Sec10"><title>Electrophysiological analyses</title><p id="Par16">The analyses were performed as described previously [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>]. Briefly, coronal cortical slices (300 μm-thickness) from postnatal day (P) 12—19 mice were prepared in ice-cold cutting Krebs solution using a microslicer (PRO7, Dosaka, Kyoto, Japan)<sub>.</sub> The slices were transferred to a holding chamber containing standard Krebs solution and incubated at room temperature. For recording, a slice was superfused with standard Krebs solution at a rate of 3–4 ml/min. To record synaptic currents, patch pipettes made from borosilicate glass capillaries were filled with CsCl-based internal solution. For I<sub>M</sub> and current-clamp recordings, patch pipettes were filled with K-gluconate based internal solution. Whole-cell recordings were conducted on pyramidal neurons in the cortical layer II/III and granule cells in dentate gyrus of the hippocampus using a patch-clamp amplifier (Axopatch 200B, Molecular Devices, Foster City, CA) and pCLAMP8 software (Molecular Devices). Miniature excitatory postsynaptic currents were recorded at a holding potential of -60 mV in the presence of bicuculline (10 μM, abcam, Cat# ab120110), strychnine (0.5 μM, Tokyo Chemical Industry, Cat# S0257) and tetrodotoxin (TTX) (0.5 μM, Wako, Cat# 206–11071). Miniature inhibitory postsynaptic currents were recorded at a holding potential of -60 mV in the presence of 6,7-Dinitroquinoxaline-2,3-dione (DNQX) (5 μM, Cayman Chemical Company, Cat# 14,583), D-AP5 (25 μM, Cayman Chemical Company, Cat# 14,539), strychnine (0.5 μM) and TTX (0.5 μM). To record the I<sub>M</sub>, the currents were held at -20 mV and hyperpolarizing steps during 3 s were applied from -20 to -60 mV in 10 mv-increments.</p></sec><sec id="Sec11"><title>Gene expression analysis</title><p id="Par17">Primary and secondary somatosensory areas from adult mice (P60) were dissected, and RNA was extracted using Sepasol®-RNA I Super (Nacalai Tesque Inc., Cat# G09379-97). The sample size was three males and three females per genotype (R213Q, R213W, and wild-type [WT]). mRNA libraries for sequencing were prepared using the MGIEasy RNA Directional Library Prep Set kit (MGI, Cat# 1,000,006,385), and sequencing was performed with the DNBSEQ-T7RS High-throughput Sequencing Kit (FCL PE150) V3.0 (MGI, Cat# 940–000266-00). RNA-seq reads were aligned to the mouse genome using the STAR aligner (v2.7.11), and gene-level read counts were obtained. Genes with low counts were filtered using the filterByExpr function. Normalization was performed using the trimmed mean of M-values (TMM), and differential expression analysis was conducted using a quasi-likelihood negative binomial generalized log-linear model (glmQLFit), with a model controlling for the animal sex. Genes with a false discovery rate (FDR) &lt; 0.05 were considered significantly differentially expressed. Gene ontology (GO) enrichment analysis for differentially expressed genes (DEGs), including cellular components and biological process terms, was performed using ShinyGO (v0.82).</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec12"><title>Statistical analyses</title><p id="Par18">For all imaging experiments, cell counting and morphological analyses were performed by an investigator blinded to the experimental conditions. Statistical analysis was carried out using GraphPad Prism 10 software (GraphPad Software Inc.). Data are presented as mean ± SD. For comparisons between two groups, Welch’s t-test was employed. For comparisons involving more than three groups, one-way analysis of variance (ANOVA) was performed, followed by a Tukey–Kramer least significant difference (LSD) test for post hoc analysis of multiple comparisons. A p-value of &lt; 0.05 was considered statistically significant. Normality of data distribution was not assessed in this study. Box and whisker plots display the median (horizontal bars), the interquartile range (25th to 75th percentiles as box edges), and whiskers extending to the smallest and largest non-outlier values. The mean is indicated by the cross within the boxes.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec13"><title>Results</title><sec id="Sec14"><title>Generation of <bold><italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic></bold><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <bold><italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic></bold><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice</title><p id="Par19">Because the overall amino acid sequences of human and mouse Kv7.2 (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="pmc:entrez-protein" xlink:href="NP_742105.1">NP_742105.1</ext-link> and <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="pmc:entrez-protein" xlink:href="NP_034741.2">NP_034741.2</ext-link>, respectively) share 94.7% identity, and the region surrounding exon 4, where R213 is located is completely conserved (100% identity; Supplementary Fig. 1B), this high conservation provides a strong rationale for analyzing KI mice harboring mutations at this residue. Structural modeling further revealed that residue R213 forms hydrogen bonds with E86 and E140, and that substitution of R213 with W or Q disrupts these interactions (Supplementary Fig. 1C). Disruption of hydrogen bonding in membrane proteins is known to influence protein folding, assembly, and function [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>]. Thus, the microstructural alterations caused by these substitutions may underlie functional changes in Kv7.2.</p><p id="Par20">To investigate the impact of the p.R213W and p.R213Q variants of <italic toggle="yes">KCNQ2</italic> on brain function, we generated KI mouse models, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q</sup> (Supplementary Fig. 1A and D). Both lines were born at Mendelian ratios (data not shown). Exploratory behavior in the home cage and circadian activity patterns were comparable to those of WT littermates. Kaplan–Meier survival curves revealed a significant reduction in lifespan for <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice compared with both WT and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> mice. <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice displayed progressive mortality, with 60% dying before 250 days of age (Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>A). While WT mice exhibited high survival rates, approximately 20% of <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> mice died between P40 and P100, with no substantial increase in mortality thereafter. Notably, deceased <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> mice commonly exhibited a rigid posture with extended limbs and a severely curved spine—features highly indicative of epileptic seizures.<fig id="Fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 1</label><caption><p>Characterization of <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice. <bold>A</bold> Reduced survival in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice. Kaplan–Meier survival curves of 131 WT, 74 <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and 118 <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice from P0 to P250. <bold>B</bold> Seizures in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice. Representative images of seizure episodes at P16 (<italic toggle="yes">upper</italic> panel) and in adulthood (<italic toggle="yes">lower</italic> panel). The red arrow indicates a seizure captured at P16. See Supplementary video 1 for additional seizure events. <bold>C</bold> Normal brain morphology in the model mice. Bright field images of representative coronal sections from WT, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup>, and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice at 7 months of age. <bold>D</bold> Quantification of corpus callosum size in WT and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice at P21. The area enclosed by the red line was measured. <italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 10 and 6 for WT and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup>, respectively. Scale bars, 1 mm</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO1" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="40478_2026_2264_Fig1_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec15"><title>Both <bold><italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic></bold><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <bold><italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic></bold><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice exhibited tonic–clonic seizures</title><p id="Par21">Seizures were observed in both <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice. In <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice, the earliest seizure was visually observed at P8, and video-documented seizures were recorded from P16 (Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>B; Supplementary video 1), indicating that the p.R213Q variant may disrupt neuronal excitability, leading to epileptic phenotypes in vivo. Seizure events were most frequently triggered by handling during home cage changes and were classified as generalized tonic–clonic seizures, consisting of distinct tonic and clonic phases (Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>B; Supplementary video 2). Notably, death during seizures was frequently observed in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice (Supplementary video 3). Although <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> mice also exhibited generalized tonic–clonic seizures resembling those observed in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup>, the seizure frequency was markedly lower. While some individuals in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mouse group exhibited recurrent seizures, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> mice were observed to have a single seizure at the time of death. Moreover, no seizures were observed during early developmental stages, and seizure incidence decreased further after P100 in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> mice (Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>A; Supplementary video 4). Taken together, these findings indicate that the p.R213Q variant leads to a severe epilepsy phenotype characterized by high seizure frequency and reduced survival, whereas the p.R213W variant results in a milder phenotype with only a modest effect on lifespan.</p></sec><sec id="Sec16"><title>Effects of the p.R213W and p.R213Q variants on the Kv7.2 expression and gross brain morphology</title><p id="Par22">To determine whether these epileptogenic <italic toggle="yes">KCNQ2</italic> variants affect protein expression levels, we performed western blot analysis using cortical lysates. Endogenous Kv7.2 expression is developmentally regulated in the mouse brain, with relatively low levels at E17 and P0, followed by a progressive increase from P3 to P60 (Supplementary Fig. 2A). To assess whether the p.R213W and p.R213Q variants affect protein stability, we expressed Myc-tagged WT and variant proteins in COS7 cells and found both variants to be as stable as WT (Supplementary Fig. 2B). We then compared endogenous Kv7.2 levels in the cortex of WT, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup>, and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice. Western blotting revealed no significant differences in Kv7.2 abundance among the three genotypes, indicating that the severe epileptic phenotype observed in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice appears not to be due to altered protein expression levels (Supplementary Fig. 2C).</p><p id="Par23">Subsequently, we performed histological analysis to assess whether the p.R213W and p.R213Q variants lead to anatomical abnormalities. Representative coronal brain sections from WT, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup>, and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice at 7 months of age revealed no apparent differences in overall brain structure, including cortical lamination and hippocampal organization (Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>C; Supplementary Fig. 3A). The area of the corpus callosum was comparable between WT and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice (Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>D), suggesting that axon extension into the contralateral cortex is minimally affected by the mutation.</p><p id="Par24">Taken together, despite the increased seizure susceptibility, severe epileptic phenotype, and reduced survival observed in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice, no significant anatomical abnormalities were detected in the brain.</p></sec><sec id="Sec17"><title>Analyses of inflammatory changes in the hippocampus and cerebral cortex</title><p id="Par25">Since no overt structural abnormalities were detected in cortical or hippocampal architecture, we next assessed potential neuroinflammatory changes associated with epilepsy. To this end, we evaluated glial responses to seizure activity by examining astrocytic and microglial activation using immunostaining for GFAP and Iba1, respectively. Brain sections from <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice aged 6–7 months were used, as four seizure episodes had been confirmed at this age. Notably, although the first seizure sometimes occurred earlier, subsequent seizures were infrequent, and many mice died after the second or third episode.</p><p id="Par26">The results revealed that GFAP-positive astrocytes were markedly increased in the dentate gyrus of <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice (Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>A and B), indicating astrocytic activation in response to chronic seizures. Similarly, expression of Iba1, a marker of activated microglia, was elevated in the same region (Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>A and C), suggesting an inflammatory response associated with persistent seizure burden. In contrast, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> mice exhibited no elevation in GFAP or Iba1 expression (Supplementary Fig. 3B). These findings suggest that seizure activity in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice—defined in this study as seizures most frequently triggered by routine handling procedures such as cage changes or feeding— induces astrocytic and microglial activation, contributing to neuroinflammation in the hippocampus. Notably, these neuroinflammatory changes in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice were largely restricted to the hippocampus, as similar increases in GFAP expression were not observed in the cerebral cortex (Supplementary Fig. 3C). This region-specific gliosis suggests that the dentate gyrus is particularly vulnerable to seizure-induced neuroinflammation in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice. Together, these findings indicate that the chronic seizures observed in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice are associated with localized neuroinflammatory responses, including astrocyte and microglial activation, which may contribute to disease progression and neuronal dysfunction.<fig id="Fig2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 2</label><caption><p>Immunohistochemical and morphological analysis of <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice. <bold>A</bold> Increased gliosis in the dentate gyrus of <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice. Representative immunofluorescence images of the dentate gyrus from WT and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice at 6–7 months of age. Sections were stained with DAPI (blue), GFAP (red), and Iba1 (green). Boxes in the DAPI panels indicate the areas magnified in the adjacent GFAP and Iba1 panels. Scale bars, 200 μm (left) and 50 μm (right). <bold>B</bold>, <bold>C</bold> Quantification of gliosis shown in (A). Bar graphs represent the immunofluorescence (IF) intensity of GFAP (B) and Iba1 <bold>C</bold> in the dentate gyrus of WT and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice. Sample size: i = 8 per group. **<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.01. <bold>D</bold> AnkyrinG localization at the AIS of cortical neurons. Representative immunofluorescence images showing AnkyrinG (red) and NeuN (green) in the cortex of WT, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup>, and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice at P30. Merged images are also shown. Scale bar, 10 μm. <bold>E</bold> Quantification of AIS length in <bold>D</bold>. Scatter plot showing AnkyrinG-positive AIS length in cortical neurons from each genotype. Sample size: <italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 3 animals per genotype; 319, 295, and 261 cells for WT, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup>, and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup>, respectively. *<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05; ***<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001. <bold>F</bold> Cortical neuron migration. Neurons were labeled by in utero electroporation at E14, and brains were analyzed at P0. Representative images of GFP-labeled neurons in the cortex of WT, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup>, and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice. Cortical layers are indicated on the left. IZ, intermediate zone. Scale bar, 100 μm. <bold>G</bold> Quantification of (F). Graphs show the fluorescence intensity distribution of GFP-positive neurons across cortical bins (I–III). Sample size: <italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 8, 6 and 8 for WT, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice, respectively. ****<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.0001; ***<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001; **<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.01. (H) Representative images of cortical neuron migration of WT and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice at P7. W.M., while matter. Scale bar, 100 μm</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO2" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="40478_2026_2264_Fig2_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="Sec18"><title>Morphological analysis of the axon initial segment (AIS) in the mouse models</title><p id="Par27">Given that Kv7.2 is highly enriched in the AIS of neurons, we examined its morphology by immunostaining for AnkyrinG, a structural marker of the AIS, in cortical neurons at P30. This analysis revealed that AnkyrinG-positive AIS structures were significantly elongated in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice compared to WT and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> mice (Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>D and E). In contrast, AIS morphology in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> mice appeared similar to that of WT, consistent with the relatively milder phenotype observed in these mice (Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>D and E).</p><p id="Par28">Given the observed structural alterations in the AIS, we hypothesized that cortical neurons in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice might also exhibit morphological abnormalities at the cellular level, potentially affecting the formation and maintenance of synaptic networks. To test this, we analyzed the morphology of dendrites and synapses in Golgi-Cox-stained pyramidal neurons located in layer II/III of the somatosensory cortex at P60. Quantitative analysis revealed that both the number of branches and the total length of basal dendrites in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice were comparable to those in control littermates (Supplementary Fig. 4A–C). Furthermore, spine densities in cortical pyramidal neurons, as well as in hippocampal neurons within the CA2 and CA3 regions, did not differ significantly between <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice and controls (Supplementary Fig. 4D–G).</p></sec><sec id="Sec19"><title>Effects of the p.R213W and p.R213Q variants on cortical neuron migration during corticogenesis</title><p id="Par29">To assess whether the p.R213W and p.R213Q variants affect cortical neuron migration, we performed in utero electroporation at E14 and analyzed their positioning at P0. Fluorescence imaging revealed a significant migration delay in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice compared to WT and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> mice (Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>F). While the majority of GFP-labeled neurons in WT and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> mice had reached the upper cortical layers (layers II/III), many neurons in Kcnq2<sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice remained in the deeper layers, indicating migration impairment (Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>F and G). Notably, by P7, most GFP-labeled neurons in Kcnq2<sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice had reached their appropriate laminar positions (Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>H), suggesting that the migration defect is transient rather than permanent. Consistent with this, the laminar distribution of Cux1- and Ctip2-expressing neurons at P40 did not differ significantly among WT, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup>, and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice (Supplementary Fig. 3A), indicating that overall cortical layer organization is ultimately preserved.</p></sec><sec id="Sec20"><title>Dysfunction of Kv7.2 channels and increased neuronal excitability in dentate gyrus granule cells of the mouse models</title><p id="Par30">To evaluate the functional impact of the p.R213W and p.R213Q variants on neuronal excitability, we performed whole-cell patch-clamp recordings from granule cells in the dentate gyrus of hippocampal slices obtained from WT, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup>, and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice at P12-19. We first examined the I<sub>M</sub>, a subthreshold potassium current mediated by Kv7.2 channels, which plays a key role in stabilizing membrane potential and limiting neuronal excitability. Representative current traces revealed voltage-dependent activation of I<sub>M</sub> in WT as well as in both mutant neurons (Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>A). However, quantitative analysis showed a significant reduction in I<sub>M</sub> amplitudes in both <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> neurons compared to WT, with the reduction being more pronounced in the latter (Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>A and B). We next measured the resting membrane potential (RMP). Both <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> granule cells exhibited significantly depolarized RMPs relative to WT neurons, with Kcnq2<sup>R213Q/+</sup> neurons showing a greater degree of depolarization (Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>C and D). Together, these results indicate that both the p.R213W and p.R213Q variants impair Kv7.2 channel function, with the p.R213Q variant exerting a more severe effect, leading to elevated neuronal excitability. We next examined the excitability of granule cells by analyzing their firing rates. Action potentials were evoked by injecting a 120 pA current pulse for 800 ms. Both <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> neurons exhibited significantly higher firing rates compared to WT neurons, with the increase being more pronounced in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q</sup> neurons (Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>E and F).<fig id="Fig3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 3</label><caption><p>Impaired Kv7.2 channel function and increased neuronal excitability in granule cells of the hippocampal dentate gyrus from <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice. <bold>A</bold> Representative traces of I<sub>M</sub> recorded from granule cells in WT, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup>, and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice. The voltage-clamp protocol was described previously, and the current traces show hyperpolarizing steps to  −40 mV from a holding potential of  −20 mV. <bold>B</bold> Quantification of <bold>A</bold>. Recordings were obtained from 7 WT neurons and 7 <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> neurons (3 slices from 2 mice per genotype), and 8 <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> neurons (4 slices from 3 mice). <bold>C</bold> Representative recordings of RMP in granule cells from each genotype. <bold>D</bold> Quantification of <bold>C</bold>. Eight neurons were analyzed per genotype (4 slices from 3 mice per genotype). <bold>E</bold> Representative traces of action potentials evoked by a 120 pA current injection for 800 ms in granule cells from WT, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup>, and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice. <bold>F</bold> Quantification of <bold>E</bold>. Recordings were obtained from 9 neurons per genotype (4 slices from 3 mice). The number of mice represents the biological replicates, whereas the number of slices and neurons represents technical replicates. Box plots show the median (horizontal line), interquartile range (box), and full range (whiskers). In the dot plots, different point shapes indicate the individual mice: red circles for mouse #1, green squares for mouse #2, and purple triangles for mouse #3. See “Materials and methods” for details. *<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.05; ***<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001 (Tukey–Kramer LSD test)</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO3" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="40478_2026_2264_Fig3_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p><p id="Par31">To determine whether synaptic transmission was altered, we recorded miniature excitatory postsynaptic currents (mEPSCs) and miniature inhibitory postsynaptic currents (mIPSCs) using voltage-clamp recordings. The frequency and amplitude of mEPSCs in both <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> neurons were comparable to those in WT (Supplementary Fig. 5A and B). Similarly, no significant differences in the frequency or amplitude of mIPSCs were observed between WT and either mutant (Supplementary Fig. 5C and D). These findings indicate that the p.R213W and p.R213Q variants do not appreciably affect excitatory or inhibitory synaptic transmission, although previous work reported that Kv7.2 play a regulatory role in neurotransmitter release from rat hippocampal nerve ending [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>].</p><p id="Par32">In summary, both <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq</italic>2 variants result in marked neuronal hyperexcitability, likely driven by impaired I<sub>M</sub> and depolarized RMP. The p.R213Q variant, however, causes a more severe dysfunction, which may underlie the epilepsy phenotypes observed in this model.</p></sec><sec id="Sec21"><title>Kv7.2 channel dysfunction and increased firing rate in cortical pyramidal neurons of <bold><italic toggle="yes">Kcnq</italic></bold>2<sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice</title><p id="Par33">To assess the impact of the p.R213W and p.R213Q variants on cortical excitability, we performed whole-cell patch-clamp recordings from layer II/III pyramidal neurons at P12-19. The amplitude of the I<sub>M</sub> was significantly reduced in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> neurons compared to WT, whereas I<sub>M</sub> in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> neurons was comparable to WT (Fig. <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>A and B). These results indicate that the p.R213Q variant markedly impairs Kv7.2 channel function in pyramidal neurons, while the p.R213W variant has little effect under the conditions tested. We next assessed RMP in the same neuronal population. Pyramidal neurons from <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice exhibited a significantly depolarized RMP compared to both WT and Kcnq2<sup>R213W/+</sup> neurons, whereas <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> neurons did not differ significantly from WT (Fig. <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>C and D). This indicates that only the p.R213Q variant substantially alters RMP in cortical neurons. Collectively, these findings demonstrate that the p.R213Q variant causes notable deficits in Kv7.2 channel function and neuronal excitability in the cortex, whereas the p.R213W variant exerts minimal functional effects in this brain region.<fig id="Fig4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 4</label><caption><p>Dysfunction of Kv7.2 channels and increased firing rate in cortical neurons from <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice. <bold>A</bold> Representative traces of I<sub>M</sub> recorded from layer II/III pyramidal neurons in WT, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup>, and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice. The voltage-clamp protocol was described previously, and the current traces show hyperpolarizing steps to  −40 mV from a holding potential of -20 mV. <bold>B</bold> Quantification of <bold>A</bold>. Recordings were obtained from 7 WT neurons (3 slices from 2 mice) and 9 neurons each for <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> genotypes (3 slices from 3 mice each). <bold>C</bold> Representative traces of RMPs recorded from cortical neurons in each genotype. <bold>D</bold> Quantification of <bold>C</bold>. Nine neurons were analyzed per genotype (3 slices from 3 mice each). <bold>E</bold> Representative traces of action potentials evoked by a 120 pA current injection (800 ms) in layer II/III pyramidal neurons from WT, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup>, and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice. <bold>F</bold> Quantification of <bold>E</bold>. Recordings were obtained from 9 neurons per genotype (3 slices from 3 mice). The number of mice represents the biological replicates, whereas the number of slices and neurons represents technical replicates. Box plots show the median (horizontal line), interquartile range (box), and full range (whiskers). In the dot plots, different point shapes indicate the individual mice: red circles for mouse #1, green squares for mouse #2, and purple triangles for mouse #3. See “Materials and methods” for details. *<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.05; ***<italic toggle="yes">P</italic> &lt; 0.001 (Tukey–Kramer LSD test)</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO4" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="40478_2026_2264_Fig4_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p><p id="Par34">To further investigate intrinsic excitability, we examined action potential firing properties by injecting depolarizing current pulses. <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq</italic>2<sup>R213Q/+</sup> neurons showed a significantly higher firing rate than both WT and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> neurons, while <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> neurons were comparable to WT (Fig. <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>E and F). These results demonstrate that increased excitability is specific to the p.R213Q variant. These findings indicate that the p.R213Q variant enhances intrinsic neuronal excitability, likely due to impaired Kv7.2 channel function and depolarized RMP, whereas the p.R213W variant exerts minimal effects. Then, to assess whether synaptic transmission was altered, we recorded mEPSCs and mIPSCs using voltage-clamp recordings. Both the frequency and amplitude of mEPSCs and mIPSCs in neurons from <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice were not significantly different from those in WT neurons (Supplementary Fig. 6A—D), indicating that excitatory and inhibitory synaptic inputs onto cortical neurons remain largely unaffected by either variant. Thus, neither the p.R213W nor p.R213Q variant alters baseline synaptic transmission in this region.</p><p id="Par35">Collectively, these results demonstrate that the p.R213Q variant leads to marked neuronal hyperexcitability in the cortex, likely resulting from impaired I<sub>M</sub> and RMP depolarization, without affecting synaptic transmission. In contrast, the p.R213W variant has little impact on either intrinsic excitability or synaptic function, consistent with its association with a milder, benign epilepsy phenotype.</p></sec><sec id="Sec22"><title>Gene expression analysis</title><p id="Par36">To investigate transcriptomic differences between the genotypes, we performed DEGs analysis comparing WT, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup>, and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> mice, while accounting for sex as a covariate, using a quasi-likelihood generalized linear model across the three genotypes. This analysis identified 107 DEGs with a false discovery rate (FDR) &lt; 0.05 (Supplementary Table S1). Hierarchical clustering of these DEGs revealed that the expression differences were primarily driven by the contrast between <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> mice (Fig. <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>A). Consistent with this, no genes met the significance threshold in pairwise comparisons between WT and either mutant when adjusted for multiple testing, suggesting a high degree of overlap at the global level. However, a direct comparison between <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> revealed 267 DEGs (FDR &lt; 0.05), including 159 genes upregulated in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> and 108 genes upregulated in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> (Fig. <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>B, Supplementary Table S2). We confirmed the upregulation of <italic toggle="yes">Prss41</italic> and <italic toggle="yes">Mettl27</italic> in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> mice, respectively, using quantitative RT-PCR (Supplementary Fig. 7A and B).<fig id="Fig5" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 5</label><caption><p>Differential gene expression analysis reveals transcriptomic differences between <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup><italic toggle="yes">R213W/</italic>+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup><italic toggle="yes">R213Q/</italic>+</sup> mice. <bold>A</bold> Heatmap of the top 50 most significant DEGs across WT, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup><italic toggle="yes">R213W/</italic>+</sup>, and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup><italic toggle="yes">R213Q/</italic>+</sup> mice. Gene expression values are log2-transformed CPM (counts per million), scaled, and clustered by genes. <bold>B</bold> Volcano plot of gene expression differences between <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice. DEGs (FDR &lt; 0.05) are colored according to direction of change: genes upregulated in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W</sup> are shown in red, genes upregulated in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> in blue, and non-significant genes in gray. Selected top 5 genes upregulated in each group (based on p-value) are labeled. Fold-change is shown on the x-axis (log₂ scale) and significance on the y-axis as -log₁₀ (p-value). (<bold>C</bold>, <bold>D</bold>) GO enrichment analysis for genes upregulated in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> relative to <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup>. Enrichment of top 15 cellular component terms <bold>C</bold>, and top 15 biological process terms <bold>D</bold>. <bold>E</bold> Expression of voltage-gated potassium channel subunits. Each point represents the log-transformed CPM values for an individual sample, colored by genotype. The empty point represents the mean and the error bars are ± standard error of the mean (SEM)</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="MO5" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="40478_2026_2264_Fig5_HTML.jpg"/></fig></p><p id="Par37">GO enrichment analysis identified significantly enriched terms (FDR &lt; 0.05) exclusively among genes upregulated in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> relative to <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup>. These enriched terms were mainly associated with endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress response (evidenced by upregulation of <italic toggle="yes">Calr</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">Hspa5</italic>, and <italic toggle="yes">Xbp1</italic>, etc.) and synaptic regulation pathways (Fig. <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>C and D, Supplementary Table S3). In addition, there was enrichment for genes coding for subunits of voltage-gated potassium channels (i.e., <italic toggle="yes">Kcns1</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnb1</italic>, <italic toggle="yes">Kcng1</italic>, and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic>). Notably, both <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcng1</italic> were significantly upregulated in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice compared to <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and WT (Fig. <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>E). Furthermore, <italic toggle="yes">Slc5a3</italic>, which encodes the Na<sup>+</sup>/myo-inositol cotransporter known to associate with the Kv7.2/Kv7.3 channel and alter ion selectivity [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR26">26</xref>], was also upregulated (Fig. <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>E). Quantitative RT-PCR further confirmed the upregulation and downregulation of genes involved in synaptic regulation (<italic toggle="yes">Erg3</italic> and <italic toggle="yes">Homer1</italic>), the ER stress response (<italic toggle="yes">Sdf2l1</italic>), and potassium channel function (<italic toggle="yes">Slc5a3</italic> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcng1</italic>) (Supplementary Fig. 7C- H).</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec23"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par38">We generated <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic> KI mice carrying the p.R213Q or p.R213W variant to examine their respective contributions to EIDEE and SeLFNIE. Although both <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice showed normal gross brain morphology, cortical lamination, and hippocampal formation, gliosis was specifically observed in the dentate gyrus of <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice (Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>A–C), suggesting that hippocampal neurons may be more vulnerable to the p.R213Q variant, whereas cortical neurons are intrinsically more resilient. We next focused on the AIS, a site of Kv7.2 enrichment essential for action potential initiation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR27">27</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR28">28</xref>]. In <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice, but not in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> mice, the AIS was abnormally elongated (Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>D and E), which may account for their aberrant electrophysiological properties. The p.R213Q variant is likely to impair AIS-dependent excitability in cortical neurons, contributing to the pathogenesis of EIDEE. Alternatively, altered neuronal activity could secondarily induce AIS elongation, consistent with AIS plasticity [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR29">29</xref>].</p><p id="Par39">Although the cortical layer structure of <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice appeared grossly normal in adulthood, we found that functional defects in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice led to delayed neuronal migration during corticogenesis, suggesting that Kv7.2 plays a crucial role in the establishment of cortical architecture in the embryonic stage. Given its predominant expression during early developmental stages [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>], Kv7.2 is presumed to function as homotetramers at this time. Thus, a specific subunit composition (Kv7.2: Kv7.2-R213Q = 2:2) may dysregulate not only channel properties but also cytoskeletal dynamics, thereby impairing the migration of excitatory neurons during cortical development.</p><p id="Par40">Consistent with these findings, microscopic cortical malformations have been reported in a patient with intractable neonatal seizures carrying the p.G215R variant, which is located in close proximity to R213 [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>]. Histopathological examination of the patient’s autopsy samples revealed abnormal clustering of cortical neurons in layers V and VI of the frontal lobes, despite the preservation of macroscopic brain structures such as the neocortical gyral pattern [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>]. In addition, the interface between the cortex and underlying white matter appeared diffusely blurred due to the presence of numerous heterotopic neurons, accompanied by marked reactive gliosis in the affected regions [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>]. These histopathological features resemble the aberrant neuronal migration and glial activation observed in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice, further supporting the face validity of this KI model for studying <italic toggle="yes">KCNQ2</italic>-related cortical malformations. Another EIDEE model, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>T274M/+</sup> mice, exhibited phenotypes similar to those of <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup>, including increased early mortality and the absence of gross morphological abnormalities, although electrophysiological analyses were not performed [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR30">30</xref>]. Notably, cortical pyramidal neuron–specific <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic> cKO mice also showed cortical hyperexcitability and early death [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR31">31</xref>], while heterozygous loss of <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic> alters social, repetitive, and exploratory behaviors [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR32">32</xref>]. These findings underscore the indispensable function of Kv7.2, the activity of which is under strict regulation.</p><p id="Par41">Electrophysiological analyses in heterologous systems, such as CHO cells and <italic toggle="yes">Xenopus</italic> oocytes, have shown that the p.R213Q variant induces more severe functional impairment than p.R213W, disrupting channel gating and increasing neuronal excitability, findings consistent with the clinical phenotype associated with p.R213Q [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>]. Computational modeling further revealed enhanced firing frequency of hippocampal neurons carrying p.R213Q [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>], while <italic toggle="yes">Xenopus</italic> studies demonstrated a depolarizing shift in activation and reduced current amplitudes despite proper surface expression of Kv7.2-R213Q [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>]. Although some discrepancies exist across assay systems, the p.R213Q variant is likely to substantially impair channel opening and exert dominant-negative effects on Kv7.2/Kv7.3 subunits, particularly at subthreshold voltages, underpinning the severe clinical phenotypes.</p><p id="Par42">Our KI mouse models provide in vivo validation of the mechanisms by which the p.R213W and p.R213Q variants disrupt neuronal excitability. Both variants exhibited reduced I<sub>M</sub> amplitude, depolarized RMP, and increased action potential firing in dentate granule cells, with more pronounced effects in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice (Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>). In contrast, cortical pyramidal neurons were affected only by p.R213Q (Fig. <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>), which also exhibited abnormal AIS elongation (Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>D). Given the little effects on the frequency and amplitude of spontaneous synaptic events (Supplementary Figs. 5 and 6), the enhanced excitability in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> neurons may be attributable intrinsic membrane properties (impaired I<sub>M</sub> and depolarized RMP).</p><p id="Par43">These region- and variant-specific alterations not only align with previous in vitro findings but also extend them, demonstrating how p.R213Q uniquely disrupts neuronal function in vivo. Considering that SeLFNIE typically resolves within the first six months of life, cortical neuronal function may remain largely preserved in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> mice. In contrast, sustained hyperexcitability in cortical neurons—as observed with p.R213Q and another EIDEE-associated variant, p.I205V [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR33">33</xref>]—likely represents a key pathogenic mechanism in EIDEE. Furthermore, the hippocampus-specific gliosis in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice supports the notion that regional vulnerability contributes to the phenotypic spectrum from SeLFNIE to EIDEE.</p><p id="Par44">RNA-seq analysis identified differentially expressed genes that primarily reflected differences between <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> mice (Fig. <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>A). Despite the presence of dysregulated neuronal activity observed in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice, GO analysis revealed that the most significantly upregulated pathways were related to the ER stress response and synaptic regulation (Fig. <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>B). While EIDEE-associated <italic toggle="yes">KCNQ2</italic> variants may trigger cellular stress responses, the upregulation of synapse-related genes may represent compensatory mechanisms aimed at preserving synaptic integrity under pathological conditions. These transcriptomic findings provide novel insights into how pathogenic <italic toggle="yes">KCNQ2</italic> variants may influence neurodevelopment, not only by affecting neuronal excitability, but also by engaging stress-responsive and synaptic regulatory pathways. Notably, <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcng1</italic> were significantly upregulated in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice (Fig. <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref>C). It remains to be elucidated whether the p.R213Q variant alters the gating properties of Kv6.1-containing channels and reduces potassium conductance. On the other hand, since the Kv7.2 protein level was comparable to WT in <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice (Supplementary Fig. 2B and C), pathophysiological meaning of <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic> upregulation is unknown.</p><p id="Par45">In conclusion, p.R213W and p.R213Q differentially perturb neuronal excitability in a region-dependent manner: both induce hyperexcitability in dentate granule cells, whereas p.R213Q alone causes cortical hyperexcitability accompanied by AIS elongation and ER stress signatures. These findings explain the SeLFNIE–EIDEE divergence and provide a platform for targeted interventions. <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213W/+</sup> and <italic toggle="yes">Kcnq2</italic><sup>R213Q/+</sup> mice recapitulate key aspects of human disease and serve as valuable models for dissecting <italic toggle="yes">KCNQ2</italic> pathophysiology. Continued investigation using these models may ultimately facilitate the development of precision therapies tailored to specific <italic toggle="yes">KCNQ2</italic> variant profiles.</p></sec><sec id="Sec24" sec-type="supplementary-material"><title>Supplementary Information</title><p>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="40478_2026_2264_MOESM1_ESM.pdf" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Additional file1 (PDF 156 KB). Supplementary Fig. 1 Strategy for generating Kcnq2R213W/+ and Kcnq2R213Q/+ mice using i-GONAD. (A) Targeted mutations were introduced into exon 4 of the Kcnq2 gene. Guide RNA sequence and corresponding proto-spacer adjacent motif (PAM) are shown. (B) Alignment of the amino acid sequences of human (NP_742105.1; upper row) and mouse (NP_034741.2; lower row) Kv7.2, illustrating the conservation of the region surrounding exon 4, where the KI mutations were introduced. Numbers indicate amino acid positions. (C) Structural models of wild-type human Kv7.2 (p.R213) and its variants p.R213W and p.R213Q. The structures, obtained from the AlphaFold Protein Structure Database (AF-O43526-F1-v4), were visualized using PyMOL software. Nitrogen atoms are shown in blue, oxygen atoms in red, and hydrogen bonds between amino acids are depicted as yellow dashed lines. (D) Direct sequencing results of the p.R213W (left) and p.R213Q (right). Corresponding amino acid sequences are shown for each.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="40478_2026_2264_MOESM2_ESM.pdf" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Additional file2 (PDF 364 KB). Supplementary Fig. 2. Expression analysis of Kv7.2 and the p.R213W and p.R213Q variants. (A) Developmental expression profile of endogenous Kv7.2 in the mouse cerebral cortex. Western blot analysis (7.5 % gel) was performed using cortical lysates collected at various developmental stages (E17 to P60). GFAP and β-actin were used as an astrocyte marker and loading control, respectively. (B) Expression of Myc-tagged Kcnq2 constructs in COS7 cells. Cells were transfected with pCAG-Myc-Kcnq2 (WT), -Kcnq2-R213W, or -Kcnq2-R213Q (1 μg each). After 48h of incubation, cell lysates were collected and immunoblotted with anti-Myc. (C) Kv7.2 protein levels in Kcnq2R213W/+ and Kcnq2R213Q/+ mice at P34. Western blot analysis with anti-KCNQ2 (10% gel) of cortical lysates from WT, Kcnq2R213W/+, and Kcnq2R213Q/+ mice. β-actin was used to confirm equal protein loading.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="40478_2026_2264_MOESM3_ESM.pptx" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Additional file3 (PPTX 1851 KB). Supplementary Fig. 3. Morphological analyses of the cerebral cortex and hippocampus. (A) Cortical layer organization at P40. Immunostaining was performed using Cux1 (upper-layer marker) and Ctip2 (deep-layer marker), showing normal laminar structure in Kcnq2R213W/+ and Kcnq2R213Q/+ mice. (B) Representative immunofluorescence images of the dentate gyrus from WT and Kcnq2R213W/+ mice at 6–7 months of age. Sections were stained as in Fig. 2A. Boxes in the DAPI panels indicate the areas magnified in the adjacent GFAP and Iba1 panels. Scale bars, 200 μm (left) and 50 μm (right). (C) Distribution of GFAP-positive astrocytes in the cerebral cortex of a 7-month-old Kcnq2R213Q/+ mouse that experienced four seizure episodes. Scale bar, 100 μm.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="40478_2026_2264_MOESM4_ESM.pdf" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Additional file4 (PDF 206 KB). Supplementary Fig. 4. Morphological analyses of cortical and hippocampal neurons in Kcnq2R213Q/+ mice. (A) Dendritic morphology of cortical neurons. Representative images of Golgi-stained cortical neurons from WT and Kcnq2R213Q/+ mice (upper panel) at P30. Digitally reconstructed dendritic structures are shown in the lower panels. (B, C) Quantification of (A). Violin plots showing the number of dendritic branches (B) and the total basal dendritic length (C) in WT and Kcnq2R213Q/+ mice. n = 4 animals per genotype; 36 and 30 cells for WT and Kcnq2R213Q/+, respectively. No significant differences (ns) were observed. (D) Dendritic spine density in cortical neurons. Representative images of dendritic spines in cortical neurons from WT and Kcnq2R213Q/+ mice. (E) Quantification of (D). Violin plots showing dendritic spine densities (spines per 10 μm) in cortical neurons. n = 4 animals per genotype; 41 and 34 cells for WT and Kcnq2R213Q/+, respectively. No significant differences were detected. (F) Dendritic spine density in hippocampal CA2 (left) and CA3 (right) neurons. Representative images of dendritic spines in neurons from WT and Kcnq2R213Q/+ mice were shown. (G) Quantification of (F). Violin plots showing dendritic spine densities (spine number per 10 μm) in hippocampal CA2 neurons (n = 4 animals per genotype; 30 and 28 cells for WT and Kcnq2R213Q/+, respectively) and CA3 neurons (n = 4 animals per genotype; 27 and 30 cells for WT and Kcnq2R213Q/+, respectively). No significant differences were observed. Scale bar, 50μm (A) and 5μm (D and F).</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM5" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="40478_2026_2264_MOESM5_ESM.pdf" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Additional file5 (PDF 354 KB). Supplementary Fig. 5. Synaptic transmission in granule cells of the hippocampal dentate gyrus from Kcnq2R213W/+ and Kcnq2R213Q/+ mice. (A) Representative traces of mEPSCs recorded under the pharmacological conditions described in the “Materials and methods” section. (B) Quantification of mEPSC frequency and amplitude in (A). Recordings were obtained from 6 neurons per genotype (3 slices from 2 mice). (C) Representative traces of mIPSCs recorded under the conditions indicated in “Materials and methods” section. (D) Quantification of mIPSC frequency and amplitude in (C). Recordings were obtained from 6 neurons per genotype (2 slices from 2 mice). The number of mice represents the biological replicates, whereas the number of slices and neurons represents technical replicates. Box plots show the median (horizontal line), interquartile range (box), and full range (whiskers). In the dot plots, different point shapes indicate the individual mice: red circles for mouse #1, squares for mouse #2, and triangles for mouse #3. See “Materials and methods” for details. *P &lt; 0.05; ***P &lt; 0.001 (Tukey-Kramer LSD test).</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM6" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="40478_2026_2264_MOESM6_ESM.pdf" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Additional file6 (PDF 220 KB). Supplementary Fig. 6. Synaptic transmission in cortical neurons from Kcnq2R213W/+ and Kcnq2R213Q/+ mice. (A) Representative traces of mEPSCs recorded under the pharmacological conditions described in the “Materials and methods” section. (B) Quantification of mEPSC frequency and amplitude in (A). Recordings were obtained from 6 neurons per genotype (3 slices from 2 mice). (C) Representative traces of mIPSCs recorded under the pharmacological conditions described in the “Materials and methods” section. (D) Quantification of mIPSC frequency and amplitude in (C). Recordings were obtained from 6 neurons per genotype (3 slices from 2 mice). The number of mice represents the biological replicates, whereas the number of slices and neurons represents technical replicates. Box plots show the median (horizontal line), interquartile range (box), and full range (whiskers). In the dot plots, different point shapes indicate the individual mice: circles for mouse #1, squares for mouse #2, and triangles for mouse #3. See “Materials and methods” for details. *P &lt; 0.05; ***P &lt; 0.001 (Tukey-Kramer LSD test).</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM7" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="40478_2026_2264_MOESM7_ESM.pdf" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Additional file7 (PDF 218 KB). Supplementary Fig. 7. Quantitative RT-PCR analysis of the differentially expressed genes identified by RNAseq. Relative expression levels of Press41 (A), Mettl27 (B), Egr3 (C), Homer1 (D), Sdf2l1 (E), Hspa5 (F), Slc5a3 (G), and Kcng1 (H) were examined. cDNA was synthesized from total brain RNA using ReverTra Ace reagent (Toyobo, Cat#FSQ-301, Osaka, Japan). qPCR was performed with Thunderbird SYBR qPCR mix (Toyobo, Cat#QPS-201) on a CFX real-time PCR system (Bio-Rad Laboratories, GmbH, Germany) under the following conditions: 95°C for 1 min, followed by 40 cycles of 95°C for 15 s and 60°C for 45 s. Primer sequences were as follows: Press41 (forward: 5’-CTTGAAGAAGTCCCACCGCT-3’, reverse: 5’-GGACGGTCCACTTTTCTGGA-3’), Mettl27 (forward: 5’-GGAACCTCCCACGGTATCAC-3’, reverse: 5’-GTGGGGCTCGGTACTTCAAA-3’), Egr3 (forward: 5’-GATGGCTACAGAGAATGTGATGGA-3’, reverse: 5’- AGTCGAAAGCGAACTTTCCCA-3’), Homer1 (forward: 5’-AGTTTGGCCAATGGGCTGAT-3’, reverse: 5’- GCGACTTCTCCTTTGCAAGC-3’), Sdf2l1 (forward: 5’-CCTCTGTGTTCCTGTCGGTC-3’, reverse: 5’- CCATTGCCTTCCACGTGTTG-3’), Hspa5 (forward: 5’-CGGCTTCCGATAATCAGCCA-3’, reverse: 5’- TCAATCTGGGGAACTCCACG-3’), Slc5a3 (forward: 5’-TGCAGCGAGAATAGCGAAGT-3’, reverse: 5’- ATGACCCATGGAAGCCACTG-3’), Kcng1 (forward: 5’-CCTGGATGAGTTCCCACTGAC-3’, reverse: 5’- GGATGGTGCCAAAAGCTCCG-3’), and GAPDH (forward: 5’-TGATGGGTGTGAACCACGAGAA-3’, reverse: 5’-GGCATGGACTGTGGTCATGAG-3’). Relative expression levels (fold change), normalized to GAPDH and expressed relative to WT, were calculated using the ∆∆Ct method. Differences between R213Q and R213W were assessed by two-tailed unpaired t-test (Prism 10). Press41 (RQ&gt;RW, ***p=0.0001), Mettl27 (RQ&lt;RW, **p=0.0057), Egr3 (RQ&gt;RW, *p=0.0318), Homer1 (RQ&gt;RW, **p=0.0045), Sdf2l1 (RQ&gt;RW, *p=0.0201), Hspa5 (ns, p=0.2126), Slc5a3 (RQ&gt;RW, **p=0.0074), and Kcng1 (RQ&gt;RW, **p=0.0037).</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM8" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="40478_2026_2264_MOESM8_ESM.avi" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Additional file8 (AVI 9887 KB). Supplementary video 1 Seizures in Kcnq2R213Q/+ mice at P16.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM9" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="40478_2026_2264_MOESM9_ESM.csv" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Additional file9 (CSV 1857 KB)</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM10" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="40478_2026_2264_MOESM10_ESM.csv" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Additional file10 (CSV 1109 KB)</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM11" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="40478_2026_2264_MOESM11_ESM.xlsx" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Additional file11 (XLSX 53 KB)</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM12" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="40478_2026_2264_MOESM12_ESM.avi" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Additional file12 (AVI 21583 KB). Supplementary video 2. Seizures in Kcnq2R213Q/+ mice in adult age.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM13" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="40478_2026_2264_MOESM13_ESM.avi" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Additional file13 (AVI 13749 KB). Supplementary video 3. Seizures in Kcnq2R213Q/+ mice in adult age.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
<supplementary-material content-type="local-data" id="MOESM14" position="float" orientation="portrait"><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="40478_2026_2264_MOESM14_ESM.avi" position="float" orientation="portrait"><caption><p>Additional file14 (AVI 23039 KB). Supplementary video 4. Seizures in Kcnq2R213W/+ mice in adult age.</p></caption></media></supplementary-material>
</p></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher's Note</bold></p><p>Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn><fn><p>Takuma Nishijo and Nanako Hamada have contributed equally to this work.</p></fn></fn-group><ack><title>Acknowledgements</title><p>We thank Prof. Naoto Hoshi and Prof. Anastasios Tzingounis for helpful discussion. We thank Hiroko Kosuge and Ikuko Iwamoto for technical assistance.</p></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Author contributions</title><p>T.N. performed electrophysiological analyses. N.H. designed and made knock-in mice. N.H. and I.I. performed immunohistochemical and biochemical analyses. R.S., H.I., and S.S. performed gene expression analyses. H.T. conducted qPCR analysis. K.N. conceived and designed the experiment, and drafted the manuscript. All authors read and approved the final manuscript.</p></notes><notes notes-type="funding-information"><title>Funding</title><p>This work was supported in part by Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS) KAKENHI Grant-in-Aid for Scientific Research (B) (Grant Number JP22H03049), Grant-in-Aid for Challenging Exploratory Research (JP22K19498), and Grant-in-Aid for Early-Career Scientists (Grant Number JP23K14997).</p></notes><notes notes-type="data-availability"><title>Data availability</title><p>The datasets used and/or analysed during the current study available from the corresponding author on reasonable request.</p></notes><notes><title>Declarations</title><notes id="FPar1"><title>Ethics approval and consent to participate</title><p id="Par46">This study does not involve human participants, human data or human tissue. As to the animal experiments, we followed the fundamental guidelines for proper conduct of animal experiments and related activity in academic research institution under the jurisdiction of the Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology, Japan. All the protocols for animal handling and treatment were reviewed and approved by the animal care and use committee of Institute for Developmental Research, Aichi Developmental Disability Center (approval number: 2019–013). All experiments were conducted in compliance with the ARRIVE (Animal Research: Reporting of In Vivo Experiments) guidelines. All methods, data presentation and statistical analyses were carried out in accordance with the TOP (Transparency and Openness Promotion) guidelines.</p></notes><notes id="FPar2"><title>Consent for publication</title><p id="Par47">Not applicable.</p></notes><notes id="FPar3" notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing interests</title><p id="Par48">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR1" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Dirkx</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Miceli</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Taglialatela</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Weckhuysen</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The role of Kv7.2 in neurodevelopment: insights and gaps in our understanding</article-title><source>Front Physiol</source><year>2020</year><volume>11</volume><fpage>570588</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fphys.2020.570588</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33192566</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7657400</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR1" publication-type="journal">Dirkx N, Miceli F, Taglialatela M, Weckhuysen S (2020) The role of Kv7.2 in neurodevelopment: insights and gaps in our understanding. Front Physiol 11:570588<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33192566</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fphys.2020.570588</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7657400</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR2" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cornet</surname><given-names>MC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sands</surname><given-names>TT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cilio</surname><given-names>MR</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Neonatal epilepsies: clinical management</article-title><source>Semin Fetal Neonatal Med</source><year>2018</year><volume>23</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>204</fpage><lpage>212</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.siny.2018.01.004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29426806</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR2" publication-type="journal">Cornet MC, Sands TT, Cilio MR (2018) Neonatal epilepsies: clinical management. Semin Fetal Neonatal Med 23(3):204–212<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29426806</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.siny.2018.01.004</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR3" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lin</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wen</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Potassium channels and epilepsy</article-title><source>Acta Neurol Scand</source><year>2022</year><volume>146</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>699</fpage><lpage>707</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/ane.13695</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36225112</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR3" publication-type="journal">Gao K, Lin Z, Wen S, Jiang Y (2022) Potassium channels and epilepsy. Acta Neurol Scand 146(6):699–707<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36225112</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/ane.13695</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR4" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Innes</surname><given-names>EA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Marne</surname><given-names>FAL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Macintosh</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nevin</surname><given-names>SM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Briggs</surname><given-names>NE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vivekanandarajah</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Webster</surname><given-names>RI</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sachdev</surname><given-names>RK</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bye</surname><given-names>AME</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Neurodevelopmental outcomes in a cohort of Australian families with self-limited familial epilepsy of neonatal/infantile onset</article-title><source>Seizure</source><year>2024</year><volume>115</volume><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>13</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2023.12.013</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38160512</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR4" publication-type="journal">Innes EA, Marne FAL, Macintosh R, Nevin SM, Briggs NE, Vivekanandarajah S, Webster RI, Sachdev RK, Bye AME (2024) Neurodevelopmental outcomes in a cohort of Australian families with self-limited familial epilepsy of neonatal/infantile onset. Seizure 115:1–13<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38160512</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.seizure.2023.12.013</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR5" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Miceli</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Soldovieri</surname><given-names>MV</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ambrosino</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Barrese</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Migliore</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cilio</surname><given-names>MR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Taglialatela</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Genotype-phenotype correlations in neonatal epilepsies caused by mutations in the voltage sensor of K(v)7.2 potassium channel subunits</article-title><source>Proc Natl Acad Sci USA</source><year>2013</year><volume>110</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>4386</fpage><lpage>91</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1073/pnas.1216867110</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23440208</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3600471</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR5" publication-type="journal">Miceli F, Soldovieri MV, Ambrosino P, Barrese V, Migliore M, Cilio MR, Taglialatela M (2013) Genotype-phenotype correlations in neonatal epilepsies caused by mutations in the voltage sensor of K(v)7.2 potassium channel subunits. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 110(11):4386–91<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23440208</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1073/pnas.1216867110</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3600471</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR6" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Orhan</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bock</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schepers</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ilina</surname><given-names>EI</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Reichel</surname><given-names>SN</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Löffler</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jezutkovic</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Weckhuysen</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Dominant-negative effects of KCNQ2 mutations are associated with epileptic encephalopathy</article-title><source>Ann Neurol</source><year>2014</year><volume>75</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>382</fpage><lpage>394</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/ana.24080</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24318194</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR6" publication-type="journal">Orhan G, Bock M, Schepers D, Ilina EI, Reichel SN, Löffler H, Jezutkovic N, Weckhuysen S et al (2014) Dominant-negative effects of KCNQ2 mutations are associated with epileptic encephalopathy. Ann Neurol 75(3):382–394<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24318194</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/ana.24080</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR7" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Millichap</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Park</surname><given-names>KL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tsuchida</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ben-Zeev</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Carmant</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Flamini</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Joshi</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Levisohn</surname><given-names>PM</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>KCNQ2 encephalopathy: features, mutational hot spots, and ezogabine treatment of 11 patients</article-title><source>Neurol Genet</source><year>2016</year><volume>2</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>e96</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1212/NXG.0000000000000096</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27602407</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4995058</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR7" publication-type="journal">Millichap JJ, Park KL, Tsuchida T, Ben-Zeev B, Carmant L, Flamini R, Joshi N, Levisohn PM et al (2016) KCNQ2 encephalopathy: features, mutational hot spots, and ezogabine treatment of 11 patients. Neurol Genet 2(5):e96<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27602407</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1212/NXG.0000000000000096</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4995058</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR8" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ye</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tang</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Miao</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gong</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shu</surname><given-names>Q</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Feng</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Clinical analysis and functional characterization of KCNQ2-related developmental and epileptic encephalopathy</article-title><source>Front Mol Neurosci</source><year>2023</year><volume>16</volume><fpage>1205265</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fnmol.2023.1205265</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37497102</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10366601</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR8" publication-type="journal">Ye J, Tang S, Miao P, Gong Z, Shu Q, Feng J, Li Y (2023) Clinical analysis and functional characterization of KCNQ2-related developmental and epileptic encephalopathy. Front Mol Neurosci 16:1205265<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37497102</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fnmol.2023.1205265</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10366601</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR9" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>YJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>TS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>XM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yu</surname><given-names>LF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>LM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>YF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhou</surname><given-names>SZ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Biallelic variants of KCNQ2 in early infantile developmental and epileptic encephalopathy</article-title><source>Seizure</source><year>2024</year><volume>116</volume><fpage>159</fpage><lpage>161</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2023.03.007</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36934001</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR9" publication-type="journal">Zhang YJ, Wang TS, Zhu XM, Yu LF, Zhang LM, Zhou YF, Wang Y, Zhou SZ (2024) Biallelic variants of KCNQ2 in early infantile developmental and epileptic encephalopathy. Seizure 116:159–161<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36934001</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.seizure.2023.03.007</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR10" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chi</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jiann-Jou</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shuan-Yow</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>KCNQ2-associated epilepsy: a review of variable phenotypes and neurodevelopmental outcomes</article-title><source>Neuropsychiatry</source><year>2018</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>318</fpage><lpage>323</lpage></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR10" publication-type="journal">Chi L, Jiann-Jou Y, Shuan-Yow L (2018) KCNQ2-associated epilepsy: a review of variable phenotypes and neurodevelopmental outcomes. Neuropsychiatry 8:318–323</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR11" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>IC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yang</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liou</surname><given-names>YM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wong</surname><given-names>SH</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>KCNQ2 selectivity filter mutations cause Kv7.2 M-current dysfunction and configuration changes manifesting as epileptic encephalopathies and autistic spectrum disorders</article-title><source>Cells.</source><year>2022</year><volume>11</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>894</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/cells11050894</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35269516</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8909571</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR11" publication-type="journal">Lee IC, Yang JJ, Liou YM, Wong SH (2022) KCNQ2 selectivity filter mutations cause Kv7.2 M-current dysfunction and configuration changes manifesting as epileptic encephalopathies and autistic spectrum disorders. Cells. 11(5):894<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35269516</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/cells11050894</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8909571</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR12" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sadewa</surname><given-names>AH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sasongko</surname><given-names>TH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Daikoku</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yamamoto</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Yamasaki</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tanaka</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Matsuo</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nishio</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Germ-line mutation of KCNQ2, p.R213W, in a Japanese family with benign familial neonatal convulsion</article-title><source>Pediatr Int.</source><year>2008</year><volume>50</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>167</fpage><lpage>71</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/j.1442-200X.2008.02539.x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18353052</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR12" publication-type="journal">Sadewa AH, Sasongko TH, Lee MJ, Daikoku K, Yamamoto A, Yamasaki T, Tanaka S, Matsuo M, Nishio H (2008) Germ-line mutation of KCNQ2, p.R213W, in a Japanese family with benign familial neonatal convulsion. Pediatr Int. 50(2):167–71<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18353052</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/j.1442-200X.2008.02539.x</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR13" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Weckhuysen</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mandelstam</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Suls</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Audenaert</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Deconinck</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Claes</surname><given-names>LR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Deprez</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Smets</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>KCNQ2 encephalopathy: emerging phenotype of a neonatal epileptic encephalopathy</article-title><source>Ann Neurol</source><year>2012</year><volume>71</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>15</fpage><lpage>25</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/ana.22644</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22275249</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR13" publication-type="journal">Weckhuysen S, Mandelstam S, Suls A, Audenaert D, Deconinck T, Claes LR, Deprez L, Smets K et al (2012) KCNQ2 encephalopathy: emerging phenotype of a neonatal epileptic encephalopathy. Ann Neurol 71(1):15–25<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22275249</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/ana.22644</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR14" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Milh</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lacoste</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cacciagli</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Abidi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sutera-Sardo</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tzelepis</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Colin</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Badens</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Variable clinical expression in patients with mosaicism for KCNQ2 mutations</article-title><source>Am J Med Genet A</source><year>2015</year><volume>167A</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2314</fpage><lpage>2318</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/ajmg.a.37152</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25959266</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR14" publication-type="journal">Milh M, Lacoste C, Cacciagli P, Abidi A, Sutera-Sardo J, Tzelepis I, Colin E, Badens C et al (2015) Variable clinical expression in patients with mosaicism for KCNQ2 mutations. Am J Med Genet A 167A(10):2314–2318<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25959266</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1002/ajmg.a.37152</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR15" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Trump</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>McTague</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Brittain</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Papandreou</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Meyer</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ngoh</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Palmer</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Morrogh</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Improving diagnosis and broadening the phenotypes in early-onset seizure and severe developmental delay disorders through gene panel analysis</article-title><source>J Med Genet</source><year>2016</year><volume>53</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>310</fpage><lpage>317</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/jmedgenet-2015-103263</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26993267</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4862068</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR15" publication-type="journal">Trump N, McTague A, Brittain H, Papandreou A, Meyer E, Ngoh A, Palmer R, Morrogh D et al (2016) Improving diagnosis and broadening the phenotypes in early-onset seizure and severe developmental delay disorders through gene panel analysis. J Med Genet 53(5):310–317<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26993267</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/jmedgenet-2015-103263</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4862068</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR16" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>van der Dalen Meurs- Schoor</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>van Weissenbruch</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>van Kempen</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bugiani</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Aronica</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ronner</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Vermeulen</surname><given-names>RJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Severe neonatal epileptic encephalopathy and KCNQ2 mutation: neuropathological substrate?</article-title><source>Front Pediatr</source><year>2014</year><volume>2</volume><fpage>136</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25566516</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fped.2014.00136</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4271583</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR16" publication-type="journal">van der Dalen Meurs- Schoor C, van Weissenbruch M, van Kempen M, Bugiani M, Aronica E, Ronner H, Vermeulen RJ (2014) Severe neonatal epileptic encephalopathy and KCNQ2 mutation: neuropathological substrate? Front Pediatr 2:136<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25566516</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fped.2014.00136</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4271583</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR17" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mizutani</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ito</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Iwamoto</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Morishita</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kanoh</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Seishima</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nagata</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Possible role of a septin, SEPT1, in spreading in squamous cell carcinoma DJM-1 cells</article-title><source>Biol Chem</source><year>2013</year><volume>394</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>281</fpage><lpage>290</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1515/hsz-2012-0258</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23087102</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR17" publication-type="journal">Mizutani Y, Ito H, Iwamoto I, Morishita R, Kanoh H, Seishima M, Nagata K (2013) Possible role of a septin, SEPT1, in spreading in squamous cell carcinoma DJM-1 cells. Biol Chem 394(2):281–290<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23087102</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1515/hsz-2012-0258</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR18" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gurumurthy</surname><given-names>CB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sato</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nakamura</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Inui</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kawano</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Islam</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ogiwara</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Takabayashi</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Creation of CRISPR-based germline-genome-engineered mice without ex vivo handling of zygotes by i-GONAD</article-title><source>Nat Protoc</source><year>2019</year><volume>14</volume><issue>8</issue><fpage>2452</fpage><lpage>2482</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41596-019-0187-x</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31341289</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR18" publication-type="journal">Gurumurthy CB, Sato M, Nakamura A, Inui M, Kawano N, Islam MA, Ogiwara S, Takabayashi S et al (2019) Creation of CRISPR-based germline-genome-engineered mice without ex vivo handling of zygotes by i-GONAD. Nat Protoc 14(8):2452–2482<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31341289</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1038/s41596-019-0187-x</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR19" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hamada</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Iwamoto</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nagata</surname><given-names>KI</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>MED13L and its disease-associated variants influence the dendritic development of cerebral cortical neurons in the mammalian brain</article-title><source>J Neurochem</source><year>2023</year><volume>165</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>334</fpage><lpage>347</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/jnc.15783</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36798993</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR19" publication-type="journal">Hamada N, Iwamoto I, Nagata KI (2023) MED13L and its disease-associated variants influence the dendritic development of cerebral cortical neurons in the mammalian brain. J Neurochem 165(3):334–347<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36798993</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/jnc.15783</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR20" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kawai</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Takagi</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kaneko</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kurosawa</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effect of three types of mixed anesthetic agents alternate to ketamine in mice</article-title><source>Exp Anim</source><year>2011</year><volume>60</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>481</fpage><lpage>487</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1538/expanim.60.481</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22041285</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR20" publication-type="journal">Kawai S, Takagi Y, Kaneko S, Kurosawa T (2011) Effect of three types of mixed anesthetic agents alternate to ketamine in mice. Exp Anim 60(5):481–487<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22041285</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1538/expanim.60.481</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR21" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hamada</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nishijo</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Iwamoto</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shifman</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nagata</surname><given-names>KI</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Analyses of conditional knockout mice for Pogz, a gene responsible for neurodevelopmental disorders in excitatory and inhibitory neurons in the brain</article-title><source>Cells</source><year>2024</year><volume>13</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>540</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/cells13060540</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38534384</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10969489</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR21" publication-type="journal">Hamada N, Nishijo T, Iwamoto I, Shifman S, Nagata KI (2024) Analyses of conditional knockout mice for Pogz, a gene responsible for neurodevelopmental disorders in excitatory and inhibitory neurons in the brain. Cells 13(6):540<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38534384</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/cells13060540</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10969489</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR22" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>White</surname><given-names>SH</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>How hydrogen bonds shape membrane protein structure</article-title><source>Adv Protein Chem</source><year>2005</year><volume>72</volume><fpage>157</fpage><lpage>172</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0065-3233(05)72006-4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16581376</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR22" publication-type="journal">White SH (2005) How hydrogen bonds shape membrane protein structure. Adv Protein Chem 72:157–172<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16581376</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/S0065-3233(05)72006-4</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR23" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bowie</surname><given-names>JU</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Membrane protein folding: how important are hydrogen bonds?</article-title><source>Curr Opin Struct Biol</source><year>2011</year><volume>21</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>42</fpage><lpage>49</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.sbi.2010.10.003</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21075614</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3073540</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR23" publication-type="journal">Bowie JU (2011) Membrane protein folding: how important are hydrogen bonds? Curr Opin Struct Biol 21(1):42–49<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21075614</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.sbi.2010.10.003</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3073540</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR24" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bondar</surname><given-names>AN</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>White</surname><given-names>SH</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Hydrogen bond dynamics in membrane protein function</article-title><source>Biochim Biophys Acta</source><year>2012</year><volume>1818</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>942</fpage><lpage>950</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.bbamem.2011.11.035</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22178866</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3288666</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR24" publication-type="journal">Bondar AN, White SH (2012) Hydrogen bond dynamics in membrane protein function. Biochim Biophys Acta 1818(4):942–950<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22178866</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.bbamem.2011.11.035</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3288666</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR25" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Martire</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Castaldo</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>D'Amico</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Preziosi</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Annunziato</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Taglialatela</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>M channels containing KCNQ2 subunits modulate norepinephrine, aspartate, and GABA release from hippocampal nerve terminals</article-title><source>J Neurosci</source><year>2004</year><volume>24</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>592</fpage><lpage>597</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3143-03.2004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14736843</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6729253</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR25" publication-type="journal">Martire M, Castaldo P, D’Amico M, Preziosi P, Annunziato L, Taglialatela M (2004) M channels containing KCNQ2 subunits modulate norepinephrine, aspartate, and GABA release from hippocampal nerve terminals. J Neurosci 24(3):592–597<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">14736843</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3143-03.2004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6729253</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR26"><label>26.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR26" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Manville</surname><given-names>RW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Neverisky</surname><given-names>DL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Abbott</surname><given-names>GW</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>SMIT1 modifies KCNQ channel function and pharmacology by physical interaction with the pore</article-title><source>Biophys J</source><year>2017</year><volume>113</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>613</fpage><lpage>626</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.bpj.2017.06.055</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28793216</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5550323</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR26" publication-type="journal">Manville RW, Neverisky DL, Abbott GW (2017) SMIT1 modifies KCNQ channel function and pharmacology by physical interaction with the pore. Biophys J 113(3):613–626<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28793216</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.bpj.2017.06.055</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5550323</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR27"><label>27.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR27" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Pan</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kao</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Horvath</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lemos</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sul</surname><given-names>JY</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cranstoun</surname><given-names>SD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bennett</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Scherer</surname><given-names>SS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cooper</surname><given-names>EC</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>A common ankyrin-G-based mechanism retains KCNQ and NaV channels at electrically active domains of the axon</article-title><source>J Neurosci</source><year>2006</year><volume>26</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>2599</fpage><lpage>2613</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4314-05.2006</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16525039</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6675151</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR27" publication-type="journal">Pan Z, Kao T, Horvath Z, Lemos J, Sul JY, Cranstoun SD, Bennett V, Scherer SS, Cooper EC (2006) A common ankyrin-G-based mechanism retains KCNQ and NaV channels at electrically active domains of the axon. J Neurosci 26(10):2599–2613<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16525039</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4314-05.2006</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6675151</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR28"><label>28.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR28" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Battefeld</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tran</surname><given-names>BT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gavrilis</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cooper</surname><given-names>EC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kole</surname><given-names>MH</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Heteromeric Kv7.2/7.3 channels differentially regulate action potential initiation and conduction in neocortical myelinated axons</article-title><source>J Neurosci.</source><year>2014</year><volume>34</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>3719</fpage><lpage>32</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4206-13.2014</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24599470</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3942587</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR28" publication-type="journal">Battefeld A, Tran BT, Gavrilis J, Cooper EC, Kole MH (2014) Heteromeric Kv7.2/7.3 channels differentially regulate action potential initiation and conduction in neocortical myelinated axons. J Neurosci. 34(10):3719–32<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24599470</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4206-13.2014</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3942587</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR29"><label>29.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR29" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Yoshimura</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rasband</surname><given-names>MN</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Axon initial segments: diverse and dynamic neuronal compartments</article-title><source>Curr Opin Neurobiol</source><year>2014</year><volume>27</volume><fpage>96</fpage><lpage>102</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.conb.2014.03.004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24705243</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4122623</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR29" publication-type="journal">Yoshimura T, Rasband MN (2014) Axon initial segments: diverse and dynamic neuronal compartments. Curr Opin Neurobiol 27:96–102<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24705243</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.conb.2014.03.004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4122623</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR30"><label>30.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR30" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Milh</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Roubertoux</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Biba</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chavany</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Spiga Ghata</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fulachier</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Collins</surname><given-names>SC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wagner</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>A knock-in mouse model for KCNQ2-related epileptic encephalopathy displays spontaneous generalized seizures and cognitive impairment</article-title><source>Epilepsia</source><year>2020</year><volume>61</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>868</fpage><lpage>878</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/epi.16494</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32239694</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7317210</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR30" publication-type="journal">Milh M, Roubertoux P, Biba N, Chavany J, Spiga Ghata A, Fulachier C, Collins SC, Wagner C et al (2020) A knock-in mouse model for KCNQ2-related epileptic encephalopathy displays spontaneous generalized seizures and cognitive impairment. Epilepsia 61(5):868–878<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32239694</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/epi.16494</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7317210</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR31"><label>31.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR31" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Soh</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pant</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>LoTurco</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tzingounis</surname><given-names>AV</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Conditional deletions of epilepsy-associated KCNQ2 and KCNQ3 channels from cerebral cortex cause differential effects on neuronal excitability</article-title><source>J Neurosci</source><year>2014</year><volume>34</volume><issue>15</issue><fpage>5311</fpage><lpage>5321</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3919-13.2014</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24719109</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3983807</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR31" publication-type="journal">Soh H, Pant R, LoTurco JJ, Tzingounis AV (2014) Conditional deletions of epilepsy-associated KCNQ2 and KCNQ3 channels from cerebral cortex cause differential effects on neuronal excitability. J Neurosci 34(15):5311–5321<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24719109</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3919-13.2014</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3983807</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR32"><label>32.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR32" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>EC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Soh</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rhodes</surname><given-names>JS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tzingounis</surname><given-names>AV</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>HJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Heterozygous loss of epilepsy gene KCNQ2 alters social, repetitive and exploratory behaviors</article-title><source>Genes Brain Behav</source><year>2020</year><volume>19</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>e12599</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/gbb.12599</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31283873</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7050516</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR32" publication-type="journal">Kim EC, Patel J, Zhang J, Soh H, Rhodes JS, Tzingounis AV, Chung HJ (2020) Heterozygous loss of epilepsy gene KCNQ2 alters social, repetitive and exploratory behaviors. Genes Brain Behav 19(1):e12599<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31283873</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1111/gbb.12599</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7050516</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR33"><label>33.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR33" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Niday</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hawkins</surname><given-names>VE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Soh</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mulkey</surname><given-names>DK</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tzingounis</surname><given-names>AV</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Epilepsy-associated KCNQ2 channels regulate multiple intrinsic properties of layer 2/3 pyramidal neurons</article-title><source>J Neurosci</source><year>2017</year><volume>37</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>576</fpage><lpage>586</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1425-16.2016</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28100740</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5242407</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR33" publication-type="journal">Niday Z, Hawkins VE, Soh H, Mulkey DK, Tzingounis AV (2017) Epilepsy-associated KCNQ2 channels regulate multiple intrinsic properties of layer 2/3 pyramidal neurons. J Neurosci 37(3):576–586<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28100740</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1425-16.2016</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5242407</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>