<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40286097</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1420-3049</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Molecules (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Molecules</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Preparation and Properties of Low-Exothermic Polyurethanes Doped with Modified Hydrated Salt Phase Change Materials.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1508</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/molecules30071508</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In this study, fumed silica (FS) was used as a support material and infused with the hydrated salt sodium hydrogen phosphate dodecahydrate (DHPD) to create shape-stabilized constant phase change materials (CPCMs). These CPCMs were integrated into a polyurethane matrix as a functional filler, resulting in low-exothermic polyurethane composite foams (CPCM-RPUFs) that demonstrate thermoregulation and flame-retardant properties. Recent findings show that CPCM-RPUF excels in thermal stability compared to pure polyurethane, with a melt phase transition enthalpy of 115.8 J/g. The use of fumed silica allows for the encapsulation of hydrated salts up to 87%, ensuring the structural integrity of the vesicles. As FS content in CPCMs increased, the internal temperature of the composite foam significantly decreased, showing excellent thermal regulation. Thermogravimetric analysis showed that the synergistic effect of DHPD and FS improved the thermal stability and flame retardancy of the composites. By monitoring the internal and surface temperature changes in the foam, it was verified that CPCMs can effectively alleviate heat accumulation during the curing process and reduce the core temperature (56.9 &#xb0;C) and surface warming rate, thus realizing the thermal buffering effect. With the increase in FS content in CPCMs, the compressive strength of CPCM-RPUF can be maintained or even enhanced. This study provides a theoretical basis and technical support for the development of polyurethane composite foams with integrated thermal regulation and flame-retardant properties, which can have broad application prospects in the fields of building energy conservation, energy storage equipment, and thermal mine insulation.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xin</LastName><ForeName>Song</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Transportation, Shandong University of Science and Technology, Qingdao 266590, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Mengya</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Safety and Environmental Engineering, Shandong University of Science and Technology, Qingdao 266590, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Shangxiao</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Safety and Environmental Engineering, Shandong University of Science and Technology, Qingdao 266590, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Safety and Environmental Engineering, Shandong University of Science and Technology, Qingdao 266590, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Han</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Transportation, Shandong University of Science and Technology, Qingdao 266590, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Molecules</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100964009</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1420-3049</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Na2HPO4-12H2O</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">flame retardant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oligothermic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polyurethane</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pyrogenic silica</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40286097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11990646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules30071508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">molecules30071508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yang C.G., Xu L., Chen N. Thermal expansion of polyurethane foam at low temperature. Energy Convers. Manag. 2007;48:481&#x2013;485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu W., Zeng Z., He Z., Liang Y., Sun Y., Song S., Wang L., Liu R. A highly efficient melamine/red phosphorus flame retardant for polyurethane-based foams. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 2023;140:e53546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu D., Wang Z., Ma W. Fabrication and characterization of a novel polyurethane microencapsulated phase change material for thermal energy storage. Prog. Org. Coat. 2021;151:106006. doi: 10.1016/j.porgcoat.2020.106006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.porgcoat.2020.106006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C., Chang Y., Zhang L., Wang B., Tian X. Effect of NCO content on properties of latent curing one-component polyurethane. J. Shandong Univ. Sci. Technol. (Nat. Sci.) 2023;42:85&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B., Wang B., Zhong Y., Wang S., Li X., Wang L. Experimental Study on Reducing the Heat of Curing Reaction of Polyurethane Polymer Grouting Material. Adv. Polym. Technol. 2021;2021:9954498. doi: 10.1155/2021/9954498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/9954498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amundarain I., Miguel-Fernandez R., Asueta A. Synthesis of Rigid Polyurethane Foams Incorporating Polyols from Chemical Recycling of Post-Industrial Waste Polyurethane Foams. Polymers. 2022;14:1157. doi: 10.3390/polym14061157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym14061157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8950580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35335488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S., Wang W., Xin S. Preparation and characterization of oligomeric thermal phase change polyurethane foam. J. Energy Storage. 2023;72:108703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin C.R., Lu W., Li J.Y. Analysis of the cooling mechanism of cooling polyurethane/nano fly ash grouting material. J. China Coal Soc. 2019;44:178&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung Y.-j., Kim Y., Kim S. Flame retardant properties of polyurethane produced by the addition of phosphorous containing polyurethane oligomers (II) Ind. Eng. Chem. 2009;15:888&#x2013;893. doi: 10.1016/j.jiec.2009.09.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jiec.2009.09.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Li X. Mechanical Properties and Flame Retardancy of Rigid Polyurethane Foams Containing SiO2 Nanospheres/Graphene Oxide Hybrid and Dimethyl Methylphosphonate. Polym. Plast. Technol. Eng. 2018;57:884&#x2013;892.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao W.-H., Liao W., Wang H. Flame-retardant and smoke-suppressant flexible polyurethane foams based on reactive phosphorus-containing polyol and expandable graphite. J. Hazard. Mater. 2018;360:651&#x2013;660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30153630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu N., Wang T., Xu C.-X. In-situ packing self-intumescent aerogel particles in rigid polyurethane foam towards thermal insulation, flame retardance and smoke suppression. Chem. Eng. J. 2025;503:158514. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.158514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.158514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efimova A., Pinnau S., Mischke M., Breitkopf C., Ruck M., Schmidt P. Development of salt hydrate eutectics as latent heat storage for air conditioning and cooling. Thermochim. Acta. 2014;575:276&#x2013;278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarier N., Onder E. Organic phase change materials and their textile applications: An overview. Thermochim. Acta. 2012;540:7&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1016/j.tca.2012.04.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tca.2012.04.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao Z., Zhang G., Xu T., Hong K. Experimental study on a novel form-stable phase change materials based on diatomite for solar energy storage. Sol. Energy Mater. Sol. Cells. 2018;182:52&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1016/j.solmat.2018.03.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solmat.2018.03.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y., Alva G., Fang G. Review on thermal performances and applications of thermal energy storage systems with inorganic phase change materials. Energy. 2018;165:685&#x2013;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahir M.H., Mohamed S.A., Saidur R., Al-Sulaiman F.A. Supercooling of phase-change materials and the techniques used to mitigate the phenomenon. Appl. Energy. 2019;240:793&#x2013;817. doi: 10.1016/j.apenergy.2019.02.045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2019.02.045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Yang Y. Preparation and thermal properties of Na2CO3&#xb7;10H2O-Na2HPO4&#xb7;12H2O eutectic hydrate salt as a novel phase change material for energy storage. Appl. Therm. Eng. 2017;112:606&#x2013;609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y., Jia Y., Alva G., Fang G. Review on thermal conductivity enhancement, thermal properties and applications of phase change materials in thermal energy storage. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2018;82:2730&#x2013;2742.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Yang Y. Form-stable phase change material based on Na2CO3&#xb7;10H2O-Na2HPO4&#xb7;12H2O eutectic hydrated salt/expanded graphite oxide composite: The influence of chemical structures of expanded graphite oxide. Renew. Energy. 2018;115:734&#x2013;740.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong S.-G., Jeon J., Cha J., Kim J., Kim S. Preparation and evaluation of thermal enhanced silica fume by incorporating organic PCM, for application to concrete. Energy Build. 2013;62:190&#x2013;195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canbazo&#x11f;lu S., &#x15e;ahinaslan A., Ekmekyapar A. Enhancement of solar thermal energy storage performance using sodium thiosulfate pentahydrate of a conventional solar water-heating system. Energy Build. 2005;37:235&#x2013;242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamaru M., Suzuki H., Hidema R. Fabrication of hard-shell microcapsules containing inorganic materials. Int. J. Refrig. Revue Int. Du Froid. 2017;82:97&#x2013;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan X.Z., Tan Z.-C., Shi Q. A novel gelling method for stabilization of phase change material Na2HPO4&#xb7;12H2O with sodium alginate grafted sodium acrylate. Thermochim. Acta. 2007;463:18&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng J., Mo W., Ma S., Wang Y., Yang J., Su X., Wang G., Lin M. Thermal shrinkage inhibition mechanism of fumed silica based thermal insulating composite. Appl. Therm. Eng. 2017;113:749&#x2013;755.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang Y., Jeong S.-G., Wi S., Kim S. Energy efficient Bio-based PCM with silica fume composites to apply in concrete for energy saving in buildings. Sol. Energy Mater. Sol. Cells. 2015;143:430&#x2013;434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng S., Huang J., Wang T. Effect of fumed silica additive on supercooling, thermal reliability and thermal stability of Na2HPO4&#xb7;12H2O as inorganic PCM. Thermochim. Acta. 2019;675:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du X., Qiu J., Deng S. Flame-retardant and solid-solid phase change composites based on dopamine-decorated BP nanosheets/Polyurethane for efficient solar-to-thermal energy storage. Renew. Energy. 2021;164:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morishige K., Kataoka T. Origin of melting point depression for rare gas solids confined in carbon pores. J. Chem. Phys. 2015;143:034707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26203042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nomura T., Zhu C., Sheng N. Shape-stabilized phase change composite by impregnation of octadecane into mesoporous SiO2. Sol. Energy Mater. Sol. Cells. 2015;143:424&#x2013;429.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu X., Xu G., Wang C., Gao Y., Zhao P. Preparation of mullite whisker ceramic membrane and its oil-water separation performance. J. Shandong Univ. Sci. Technol. (Nat. Sci.) 2023;42:70&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi A., Barikani M., Barmar M. Synthesis and investigation of thermal and mechanical properties of in situ prepared biocompatible Fe3O4/polyurethane elastomer nanocomposites. Polym. Bull. 2015;72:219&#x2013;234. doi: 10.1007/s00289-014-1268-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00289-014-1268-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin X., Guo N., You Z., Tan Y. Design and Performance of Polyurethane Elastomers Composed with Different Soft Segments. Materials. 2020;13:4991. doi: 10.3390/ma13214991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma13214991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7664240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33167575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao N., Tang T., Xiang H. Preparation and structure-properties of crosslinking organic montmorillonite/polyurethane as solid-solid phase change materials for thermal energy storage. Sol. Energy Mater. Sol. Cells. 2022;244:111831. doi: 10.1016/j.solmat.2022.111831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solmat.2022.111831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao L., Xiao H., Wang Q., Sun J. Thermal degradation characteristics of rigid polyurethane foam and the volatile products analysis with TG-FTIR-MS. Polym. Degrad. Stab. 2013;98:2687&#x2013;2696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zygmunt-Kowalska B., Pielichowska K., Trestka P. The Effect of Ash Silanization on the Selected Properties of Rigid Polyurethane Foam/Coal Fly Ash Composites. Energy. 2022;15:9725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue B.-L., Wen J.-L., Sun R.-C. Producing lignin-based polyols through microwave-assisted liquefaction for rigid polyurethane foam production. Materials. 2015;8:586&#x2013;599. doi: 10.3390/ma8020586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma8020586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5455266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28787959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q., Lin X., Chen W., Zhang H., Han D. Modification of Rigid Polyurethane Foams with the Addition of Nano-SiO2 or Lignocellulosic Biomass. Polymers. 2020;12:107. doi: 10.3390/polym12010107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym12010107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7022631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31948014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>