<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40881899</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2307-8960</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>27</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of clinical cases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Clin Cases</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Euglycemic diabetic ketoacidosis associated with etogliflozin in post-pancreatitis diabetes: A case report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>108550</StartPage><MedlinePgn>108550</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">108550</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12998/wjcc.v13.i27.108550</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 (SGLT-2) inhibitors improve cardiovascular and renal outcomes in diabetes but may induce euglycemic diabetic ketoacidosis (euDKA) <i>via</i> insulin-independent mechanisms. Post-pancreatitis diabetes mellitus (PPDM) patients with impaired &#x3b2;-cell function face undefined risks with these agents.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CASE SUMMARY" NlmCategory="METHODS">A 29-year-old man with PPDM developed euDKA 1 week after initiating etogliflozin (5 mg/day). On admission, laboratory tests revealed blood ketones &gt; 4.5 mmol/L, pH 7.1, and glucose 10.78 mmol/L. Discontinuation of SGLT-2 inhibitor, insulin pump therapy (basal 12 U/day, premeal bolus 4 U), aggressive hydration (6000 mL first 2 days), and nutritional support normalized ketosis and acidosis within 24 hours.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Caution is warranted with SGLT-2 inhibitors in PPDM. Insulin therapy is preferred to prevent euDKA.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2025. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chai</LastName><ForeName>Jiang-Tao</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology, 960th Hospital of PLA, Jinan 250014, Shandong Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xin-Hui</ForeName><Initials>XH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology, 960th Hospital of PLA, Jinan 250014, Shandong Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Zhao-Shun</ForeName><Initials>ZS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology, 960th Hospital of PLA, Jinan 250014, Shandong Province, China. jzs012@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Clin Cases</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101618806</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2307-8960</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acute pancreatitis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Case report</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Etogliflozin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Euglycemic diabetic ketoacidosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-pancreatitis diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sodium-glucose cotransporter-2</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest related to this report.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40881899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12362423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12998/wjcc.v13.i27.108550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Umpierrez GE, Davis GM, ElSayed NA, Fadini GP, Galindo RJ, Hirsch IB, Klonoff DC, McCoy RG, Misra S, Gabbay RA, Bannuru RR, Dhatariya KK. Hyperglycaemic crises in adults with diabetes: a consensus report. Diabetologia. 2024;67:1455&#x2013;1479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11343900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38907161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benoit SR, Zhang Y, Geiss LS, Gregg EW, Albright A. Trends in Diabetic Ketoacidosis Hospitalizations and In-Hospital Mortality - United States, 2000-2014. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2018;67:362&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5877353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29596400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Reilly JE, Jeyam A, Caparrotta TM, Mellor J, Hohn A, McKeigue PM, McGurnaghan SJ, Blackbourn LAK, McCrimmon R, Wild SH, Petrie JR, McKnight JA, Kennon B, Chalmers J, Phillip S, Leese G, Lindsay RS, Sattar N, Gibb FW, Colhoun HM Scottish Diabetes Research Network Epidemiology Group. Rising Rates and Widening Socioeconomic Disparities in Diabetic Ketoacidosis in Type 1 Diabetes in Scotland: A Nationwide Retrospective Cohort Observational Study. Diabetes Care. 2021;44:2010&#x2013;2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34244330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen CJ, Xu C. [Analysis of related factors for mortality in diabetic ketoacidosis] Zhonghua Neifenmi Waike Zazhi. 2017;11:467&#x2013;470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters AL, Buschur EO, Buse JB, Cohan P, Diner JC, Hirsch IB. Euglycemic Diabetic Ketoacidosis: A Potential Complication of Treatment With Sodium-Glucose Cotransporter 2 Inhibition. Diabetes Care. 2015;38:1687&#x2013;1693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4542270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26078479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCoy RG, Herrin J, Galindo RJ, Sindhu Swarna K, Umpierrez GE, Hill Golden S, O'Connor PJ. All-cause mortality after hypoglycemic and hyperglycemic emergencies among U.S. adults with diabetes, 2011-2020. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2023;197:110263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10023431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36693542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaka H, Wani F, El-Amir Z, Dahiya DS, Singh J, Edigin E, Eseaton P, Kichloo A. Comparing patient characteristics and outcomes in type 1 versus type 2 diabetes with diabetic ketoacidosis: a review and a propensity-matched nationwide analysis. J Investig Med. 2021;69:1196&#x2013;1200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33972382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharmal SH, Cho J, Alarcon Ramos GC, Ko J, Stuart CE, Modesto AE, Singh RG, Petrov MS. Trajectories of glycaemia following acute pancreatitis: a prospective longitudinal cohort study with 24 months follow-up. J Gastroenterol. 2020;55:775&#x2013;788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32494905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;hr JM, Dominguez-Munoz E, Rosendahl J, Besselink M, Mayerle J, Lerch MM, Haas S, Akisik F, Kartalis N, Iglesias-Garcia J, Keller J, Boermeester M, Werner J, Dumonceau JM, Fockens P, Drewes A, Ceyhan G, Lindkvist B, Drenth J, Ewald N, Hardt P, de Madaria E, Witt H, Schneider A, Manfredi R, Br&#xf8;ndum FJ, Rudolf S, Bollen T, Bruno M HaPanEU/UEG Working Group. United European Gastroenterology evidence-based guidelines for the diagnosis and therapy of chronic pancreatitis (HaPanEU) United European Gastroenterol J. 2017;5:153&#x2013;199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5349368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28344786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhi M, Zhu X, Lugea A, Waldron RT, Pandol SJ, Li L. Incidence of New Onset Diabetes Mellitus Secondary to Acute Pancreatitis: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Front Physiol. 2019;10:637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6558372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31231233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins R, Young KG, Thomas NJ, Jones AG, Hattersley AT, Shields BM, Dennis JM, McGovern AP MASTERMIND consortium. Treatment outcomes with oral anti-hyperglycaemic therapies in people with diabetes secondary to a pancreatic condition (type 3c diabetes): A population-based cohort study. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2025;27:1544&#x2013;1553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11802396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39762966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart PA, Bradley D, Conwell DL, Dungan K, Krishna SG, Wyne K, Bellin MD, Yadav D, Andersen DK, Serrano J, Papachristou GI. Diabetes following acute pancreatitis. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;6:668&#x2013;675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8277724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34089654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahara T, Takamura T, Otoda T, Ishikura K, Matsushita E. Transient anti-GAD antibody positivity and acute pancreatitis with pancreas tail swelling in a patient with susceptible haplotype for type 1 diabetes mellitus. Intern Med. 2009;48:1897&#x2013;1899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19881242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purcell AW, Sechi S, DiLorenzo TP. The Evolving Landscape of Autoantigen Discovery and Characterization in Type 1 Diabetes. Diabetes. 2019;68:879&#x2013;886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6477901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31010879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szentesi A, P&#xe1;rniczky A, Vincze &#xc1;, Bajor J, G&#xf3;di S, Sarl&#xf3;s P, Gede N, Izb&#xe9;ki F, Hal&#xe1;sz A, M&#xe1;rta K, Dobszai D, T&#xf6;r&#xf6;k I, Farkas H, Papp M, Varga M, Hamvas J, Nov&#xe1;k J, Mickevicius A, Maldonado ER, Sallinen V, Ill&#xe9;s D, Kui B, Er&#x151;ss B, Czak&#xf3; L, Tak&#xe1;cs T, Hegyi P. Multiple Hits in Acute Pancreatitis: Components of Metabolic Syndrome Synergize Each Other's Deteriorating Effects. Front Physiol. 2019;10:1202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6763590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31620021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang AL, McNabb-Baltar J. Hypertriglyceridemia and acute pancreatitis. Pancreatology. 2020;20:795&#x2013;800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32571534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Feng X, Li Q, Wang Y, Li Q, Hua M. Adiponectin, TNF-&#x3b1; and inflammatory cytokines and risk of type 2 diabetes: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Cytokine. 2016;86:100&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27498215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart PA, Bellin MD, Andersen DK, Bradley D, Cruz-Monserrate Z, Forsmark CE, Goodarzi MO, Habtezion A, Korc M, Kudva YC, Pandol SJ, Yadav D, Chari ST Consortium for the Study of Chronic Pancreatitis, Diabetes, and Pancreatic Cancer(CPDPC) Type 3c (pancreatogenic) diabetes mellitus secondary to chronic pancreatitis and pancreatic cancer. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2016;1:226&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5495015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28404095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenstock J, Ferrannini E. Euglycemic Diabetic Ketoacidosis: A Predictable, Detectable, and Preventable Safety Concern With SGLT2 Inhibitors. Diabetes Care. 2015;38:1638&#x2013;1642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26294774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogawa W, Sakaguchi K. Euglycemic diabetic ketoacidosis induced by SGLT2 inhibitors: possible mechanism and contributing factors. J Diabetes Investig. 2016;7:135&#x2013;138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4773669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27042263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lapolla A, Amaro F, Bruttomesso D, Di Bartolo P, Grassi G, Maffeis C, Purrello F, Tumini S. Diabetic ketoacidosis: A consensus statement of the Italian Association of Medical Diabetologists (AMD), Italian Society of Diabetology (SID), Italian Society of Endocrinology and Pediatric Diabetoloy (SIEDP) Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2020;30:1633&#x2013;1644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32771260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright EM. Glucose transport families SLC5 and SLC50. Mol Aspects Med. 2013;34:183&#x2013;196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23506865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>