<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40135029</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Tumor Lysis Syndrome Following Endoscopic Retrograde Cholangiopancreatography With Stent Placement in a Patient With Cholangiocarcinoma: A Case Report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e79476</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e79476</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e79476</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.79476</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Tumor lysis syndrome (TLS) is an oncological emergency commonly associated with hematologic malignancies and aggressive chemotherapy. Its occurrence following endoscopic retrograde cholangiopancreatography (ERCP) with stent placement in patients with cholangiocarcinoma is exceedingly rare, with only a handful of cases reported in the literature. This report discusses a unique case of TLS occurring after ERCP in a patient with cholangiocarcinoma, highlighting the clinical challenges and the need for heightened awareness among clinicians. Herein, we present the case of a 58-year-old female patient with a diagnosis of cholangiocarcinoma who developed TLS following ERCP with stent placement. The patient initially underwent the procedure to relieve biliary obstruction, a common palliative intervention in cholangiocarcinoma cases. Within 24 hours post-procedure, the patient exhibited signs of acute renal failure, hyperkalemia, hyperphosphatemia, and hypocalcemia, consistent with TLS. Prompt recognition and aggressive management, including hydration, electrolyte correction, and renal support, were crucial in stabilizing the patient. Despite prompt recognition and aggressive management, including hydration, electrolyte correction, and renal support, the patient unfortunately passed away 24 hours later. This tragic outcome underscores the critical importance of early recognition and intervention, as well as the need for awareness of this rare but possible complication. This case highlights the rare but serious risk of TLS following ERCP in patients with cholangiocarcinoma. Clinicians should be aware of this potential complication, especially in patients with a high tumor burden or those undergoing palliative procedures. Early recognition and intervention are paramount in improving patient outcomes. Further studies are needed to better understand the mechanisms and predisposing factors for TLS in this context.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Boutari et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boutari</LastName><ForeName>Rim A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Al Zahraa Hospital University Medical Center, Beirut, LBN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hallal</LastName><ForeName>Mahmoud M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Al Zahraa Hospital University Medical Center, Beirut, LBN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mallah</LastName><ForeName>Fatmeh I</ForeName><Initials>FI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radiology, Faculty of Medicine, Lebanese University, Beirut, LBN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biliary stent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">case report</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cholangiocarcinoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ercp</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oncological emergencies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tumor lysis syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40135029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11932962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.79476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tumor lysis syndrome. Barbar T, Jaffer Sathick I. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35190110/ Adv Chronic Kidney Dis. 2021;28:438&#x2013;446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35190110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tumor lysis syndrome. Durfee EM. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35640898/ Crit Care Nurse. 2022;42:19&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35640898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Advances in the management of cholangiocarcinoma. Zori AG, Yang D, Draganov PV, Cabrera R. http://Zori AG, Yang D, Draganov PV, Cabrera R: Advances in the management of cholangiocarcinoma. World J Hepatol. 2021;13:1003&#x2013;1018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8473501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34630871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term results of ERCP- or PTCS-directed photodynamic therapy for unresectable hilar cholangiocarcinoma. Li Z, Jiang X, Xiao H, et al.  https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/33104917/ Surg Endosc. 2021;35:5655&#x2013;5664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8437910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33104917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spontaneous tumor lysis syndrome in patients with solid tumors: a scoping review of the literature. Papapanou M, Athanasopoulos AE, Georgiadi E, et al. Med Oncol. 2023;40:233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10335952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37432468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tumour lysis syndrome: new therapeutic strategies and classification. Cairo MS, Bishop M. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2141.2004.05094.x. Br J Haematol. 2004;127:3&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15384972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tumor lysis syndrome in patients with solid tumors: a systematic review of reported cases. Alqurashi RM, Tamim HH, Alsubhi ZD, Alzahrani AA, Tashkandi E. Cureus. 2022;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9685209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36439565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbapenem-resistant Enterobacterales sepsis following endoscopic retrograde cholangiopancreatography: risk factors for 30-day all-cause mortality and the development of a nomogram based on a retrospective cohort. Zhang H, Wang Y, Zhang X, et al. Antimicrob Resist Infect Control. 2024;13:84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11304701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39113089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The tumor lysis syndrome. Howard SC, Jones DP, Pui CH. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMra0904569. N Engl J Med. 2011;364:1844&#x2013;1854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3437249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21561350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preventing and monitoring for tumor lysis syndrome and other toxicities of venetoclax during treatment of chronic lymphocytic leukemia. Fischer K, Al-Sawaf O, Hallek M. https://doi.org/10.1182/hematology.2020000120. Hematology Am Soc Hematol Educ Program. 2020;2020:357&#x2013;362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7727567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33275717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>