<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41502215</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1750-3841</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>91</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of food science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Food Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Development of Cold Plasma-Treated Soy-Pea Protein Meat Analogues Incorporating Mango Peel Powder as a Texturant by Low-Moisture Extrusion: Evaluation of Rehydration Kinetics and Textural Properties.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e70801</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e70801</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1750-3841.70801</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Growing concerns about health, nutrition, and environmental sustainability have accelerated global interest in plant-based meat analogues as viable alternatives to animal-derived products. Low-moisture extrusion (LME) remains one of the most effective structuring technologies for achieving meat-like texture from plant proteins. In this study, soy protein isolate (SPI) and pea protein isolate (PPI) blends in varying ratios (S10/P60, S20/P50, S30/P40, S40/P30, S50/P20, and S60/P10) were incorporated with mango peel powder as a texturant and pretreated using cold plasma before extrusion. Mango peel powder (MPP) was selected due to its dietary fiber and functional bioactive properties as well as its ability to enhance hydration, binding, and structural development within extruded matrices. Key quality parameters assessed included piece and true density, expansion ratio, water absorption index, rehydration behavior, cooking duration, solid loss, in vitro digestibility, and texture profile analysis. Rehydration kinetics fitted both the Peleg and exponential models; however, the Peleg model exhibited superior predictive performance. Incorporation of MPP contributed to improved structural integrity and reduced solid loss (&lt;10%) during cooking, while enhancing water uptake and textural consistency. Color attributes (L*, a*, b*) varied significantly with the SPI:PPI ratio, with higher SPI levels yielding lighter products. Among all formulations, S40/P30 demonstrated the most desirable physicochemical properties, rehydration performance, and faster digestion rate, suggesting that a balanced SPI-PPI matrix combined with MPP as a texturant can produce a nutritionally enriched, structurally stable, and high-quality plant-based meat analogue. PRACTICAL APPLICATIONS: Meat analogues were developed via low-moisture extrusion by blending CP-treated soy and pea protein isolates. PPI substituted SPI as an expansion or texture modifier in producing SPI and PPI-based meat analogues. Sample S40/P30 showed optimal textural properties and the fastest in vitro digestion rate among all formulations. The Peleg model was best fitted for the rehydration kinetics of the meat analogues.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Institute of Food Technologists.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rout</LastName><ForeName>Srutee</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1712-1576</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Agricultural and Food Engineering, Indian Institute of Technology Kharagpur, Kharagpur, West Bengal, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Srivastav</LastName><ForeName>Prem Prakash</ForeName><Initials>PP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Agricultural and Food Engineering, Indian Institute of Technology Kharagpur, Kharagpur, West Bengal, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Food Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0014052</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-1147</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D030262">Soybean Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000078724">Pea Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011208">Powders</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D031022" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mangifera</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D030262" MajorTopicYN="Y">Soybean Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000078724" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pea Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011208" MajorTopicYN="N">Powders</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005511" MajorTopicYN="Y">Food Handling</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007700" MajorTopicYN="N">Kinetics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="N">Water</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005638" MajorTopicYN="N">Fruit</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003296" MajorTopicYN="N">Cooking</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008461" MajorTopicYN="Y">Meat Products</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cold plasma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">low moisture extrusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meat alternatives</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peleg model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehydration kinetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">soy and pea protein isolate</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41502215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1750-3841.70801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Annapure, U. S., S. Rout, and P. P. Srivastav. 2023. &#x201c;Applications of Enzymes in Food Industries as Additives.&#x201d; In Microbes for Natural Food Additives, 13&#x2013;26. Springer Nature Singapore.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baig, M. A., F. F. Ajayi, M. Hamdi, et&#xa0;al. 2025. &#x201c;Recent Research Advances in Meat Analogues: A Comprehensive Review on Production, Protein Sources, Quality Attributes, Analytical Techniques Used, and Consumer Perception.&#x201d; Food Reviews International 41, no. 1: 236&#x2013;267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bulgaru, V., N. Netreba, and A. Ghendov&#x2010;Mosanu. 2025. &#x201c;Pre&#x2010;Treatment of Vegetable Raw Materials (Sorghum Oryzoidum) for Use in Meat Analog Manufacture.&#x201d; Applied Sciences 15, no. 1: 349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimina, L., D. R&#xe9;mond, J.&#x2010;F. Huneau, and F. Mariotti. 2022. &#x201c;Combining Plant Proteins to Achieve Amino Acid Profiles Adapted to Various Nutritional Objectives&#x2014;An Exploratory Analysis Using Linear Programming.&#x201d; Frontiers in Nutrition 8: 809685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinali, M., R. Liyanage, M. Silva, et&#xa0;al. 2024. &#x201c;Fibrous Structure in Plant&#x2010;Based Meat: High&#x2010;Moisture Extrusion Factors and Sensory Attributes in Production and Storage.&#x201d; Food Reviews International 40, no. 9: 2940&#x2013;2968.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flory, J., and S. Alavi. 2024. &#x201c;Use of Hydration Properties of Proteins to Understand Their Functionality and Tailor Texture of Extruded Plant&#x2010;Based Meat Analogues.&#x201d; Journal of Food Science 89, no. 1: 245&#x2013;258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu, J., Z. Zhan, Q. Duan, et&#xa0;al. 2025. &#x201c;Application of Soybean Protein Isolates&#x2010;Polysaccharides Hybrid Emulsion Gels as Alternative Fats in Fabricating Plant&#x2010;Based Meats With Two&#x2010;Phase.&#x201d; LWT 218: 117524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu, J., Y. Zheng, Y. Gao, Y. Zhang, C. Sun, and Y. Fang. 2023. &#x201c;Effect of Different Polysaccharides on the Texture and Fibrous Structure of High&#x2010;Moisture Extruded Pea Protein Isolate.&#x201d; Food Biophysics 18, no. 4: 606&#x2013;618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong, W., X.&#x2010;l. Guo, H.&#x2010;B. Huang, X. Li, Y. Xu, and J.&#x2010;N. Hu. 2021. &#x201c;Structural Characterization of Modified Whey Protein Isolates Using Cold Plasma Treatment and Its Applications in Emulsion Oleogels.&#x201d; Food Chemistry 356: 129703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, R., B. Sun, Y. Zhu, et&#xa0;al. 2024. &#x201c;Low&#x2010;Moisture Extruded Mung Bean Protein Isolate and Wheat Gluten: Structure, Techno&#x2010;Functional Characteristics and Establishment of Rehydration Kinetics of the Products.&#x201d; LWT 210: 116844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyony, V., F. Fayolle, and V. Jury. 2023. &#x201c;High Moisture Extrusion of Vegetable Proteins for Making Fibrous Meat Analogs: A Review.&#x201d; Food Reviews International 39, no. 7: 4262&#x2013;4287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, Z., Y. Wang, Z. Ma, et&#xa0;al. 2023. &#x201c;Impacts of Industrial Modification on the Structure and Gel Features of Soy Protein Isolate and Its Composite Gel With Myofibrillar Protein.&#x201d; Foods 12, no. 10: 1982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, Z., Y. Liu, H. An, et&#xa0;al. 2024. &#x201c;Utilizing Haematococcus Pluvialis to Simulate Animal Meat Color in High&#x2010;Moisture Meat Analogues: Texture Quality and Color Stability.&#x201d; Food Research International 175: 113685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung, T. I., Y.&#x2010;J. Hsieh, W.&#x2010;L. Lu, K.&#x2010;P. Wu, and C. A. Chang. 2023. &#x201c;What Strengthens Protein&#x2010;protein Interactions: Analysis and Applications of Residue Correlation Networks.&#x201d; Journal of Molecular Biology 435, no. 24: 168337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji, H., F. Han, S. Peng, et&#xa0;al. 2019. &#x201c;Behavioral Solubilization of Peanut Protein Isolate by Atmospheric Pressure Cold Plasma (ACP) Treatment.&#x201d; Food and Bioprocess Technology 12, no. 12: 2018&#x2013;2027.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi, S., I. Khan, A. Soni, et&#xa0;al. 2025. &#x201c;Meat Products With Soy.&#x201d; In Healthier Meat Products, 291&#x2013;311. Springer Nature Switzerland .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, J.&#x2010;S., I. Choi, and J. Han. 2022. &#x201c;Construction of Rice Protein&#x2010;Based Meat Analogues by Extruding Process: Effect of Substitution of Soy Protein With Rice Protein on Dynamic Energy, Appearance, Physicochemical, and Textural Properties of Meat Analogues.&#x201d; Food Research International 161: 111840.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, J.&#x2010;S., S. Kim, Y. J. Jeong, I. Choi, and J. Han. 2023. &#x201c;Impact of Interactions Between Soy and Pea Proteins on Quality Characteristics of High&#x2010;Moisture Meat Analogues Prepared via Extrusion Cooking Process.&#x201d; Food Hydrocolloids 139: 108567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, J.&#x2010;S., H. Oh, I. Choi, C. S. Yoon, and J. Han. 2022. &#x201c;Physico&#x2010;chemical Characteristics of Rice Protein&#x2010;Based Novel Textured Vegetable Proteins as Meat Analogues Produced by Low&#x2010;Moisture Extrusion Cooking Technology.&#x201d; LWT 157: 113056.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, G., Y. Wen, W. Chen, et&#xa0;al. 2024. &#x201c;Enhancing Soy Protein Isolate Gels: Combined Control of pH and Surface Charge for Improved Structural Integrity and Gel Strength.&#x201d; Food Bioscience 59: 103934.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malila, Y., I. O. Owolabi, T. Chotanaphuti, et&#xa0;al. 2024. &#x201c;Current Challenges of Alternative Proteins as Future Foods.&#x201d; NPJ Science of Food 8, no. 1: 53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mini&#x107;, S., N. Gligorijevi&#x107;, L. Veli&#x10d;kovi&#x107;, and M. Nikoli&#x107;. 2024. &#x201c;Narrative Review of the Current and Future Perspectives of Phycobiliproteins' Applications in the Food Industry: From Natural Colors to Alternative Proteins.&#x201d; International Journal of Molecular Sciences 25, no. 13: 7187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olatunde, O. O., A. Hewage, T. Dissanayake, et&#xa0;al. 2023. &#x201c;Cold Atmospheric Plasma&#x2010;Induced Protein Modification: Novel Nonthermal Processing Technology to Improve Protein Quality, Functionality, and Allergenicity Reduction.&#x201d; Comprehensive Reviews in Food Science and Food Safety 22, no. 3: 2197&#x2013;2234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ommat Mohammadi, E., S. Yeganehzad, M. A. Hesarinejad, et&#xa0;al. 2024. &#x201c;Adsorption Layer Properties and Foam Behavior of Aqueous Solutions of Whey Protein Isolate (WPI) Modified by Vacuum Cold Plasma (VCP).&#x201d; Colloids and Interfaces 8, no. 2: 25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oyinloye, T. M., H. Jung, and W. B. Yoon. 2023. &#x201c;Developing a Novel Method to Measure Texture Changes of Semi&#x2010;Solid Food During a Continuous Compressive Motion With High Deformation Using Repeatable Dual Extrusion Cell (RDEC).&#x201d; Food Research International 165: 112571.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peleg, M. 1988. &#x201c;An Empirical Model for the Description of Moisture Sorption Curves.&#x201d; Journal of Food Science 53, no. 4: 1216&#x2013;1217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelloux, C., P. Pibarot, and C. J. E. Schmitt. 2023. U.S. Patent Application No. 17/758,146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, J., L. Lu, K.&#x2010;X. Zhu, X.&#x2010;N. Guo, Y. Chen, and H.&#x2010;M. Zhou. 2022. &#x201c;Effect of Rehydration on Textural Properties, Oral Behavior, Kinetics and Water state of Textured Wheat Gluten.&#x201d; Food Chemistry 376: 131934.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu, Z., G. Chen, J. Wang, X. Xie, and Y. Chen. 2023. &#x201c;Preparation, Structure Evaluation, and Improvement in Foaming Characteristics of Fibrotic Pea Protein Isolate by Cold Plasma Synergistic Organic Acid Treatment.&#x201d; Food Hydrocolloids 134: 108057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman, M. M., and B. P. Lamsal. 2023. &#x201c;Effects of Atmospheric Cold Plasma and High&#x2010;Power Sonication on Rheological and Gelling Properties of Mung Bean Protein Dispersions.&#x201d; Food Research International 163: 112265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravindran, N., S. K. Singh, and P. Singha. 2024. &#x201c;A Comprehensive Review on the Recent Trends in Extractions, Pretreatments and Modifications of Plant&#x2010;Based Proteins.&#x201d; Food Research International 190: 114575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rout, S., P. Dash, P. K. Panda, P.&#x2010;C. Yang, and P. P. Srivastav. 2024. &#x201c;Interaction of Dairy and Plant Proteins for Improving the Emulsifying and Gelation Properties in Food Matrices: a Review.&#x201d; Food Science and Biotechnology 33, no. 14: 3199&#x2013;3212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rout, S., R. S. Sowmya, and P. P. Srivastav. 2024. &#x201c;A Review on Development of Plant&#x2010;Based Meat Analogues as Future Sustainable Food.&#x201d; International Journal of Food Science and Technology 59, no. 1: 481&#x2013;487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rout, S., and P. P. Srivastav. 2023. &#x201c;A Concise Review on the Thermal and Non&#x2010;Thermal Extraction Methods of Dietary Fiber and Their Implications on Human Health.&#x201d; Food Chemistry Advances 3: 100466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rout, S., and P. P. Srivastav. 2023. &#x201c;Effect of Cold Plasma on the Technological and Functional Modification of Plant Proteins and Enzymes.&#x201d; Innovative Food Science &amp; Emerging Technologies 88: 103447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rout, S., and P. P. Srivastav. 2024. &#x201c;Modification of Soy Protein Isolate and Pea Protein Isolate by High Voltage Dielectric Barrier Discharge (DBD) Atmospheric Cold Plasma: Comparative Study on Structural, Rheological and Techno&#x2010;Functional Characteristics.&#x201d; Food Chemistry 447: 138914.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rout, S., and P. P. Srivastav. Early view. &#x201c;Impact of Cold&#x2010;Plasma on the Nutritional, Textural and Structural Properties of Soy and Pea Protein Isolate for the Development of Plant&#x2010;Based Noodles.&#x201d; Journal of Food Science and Technology 1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rout, S., S. Tripathy, S. Ranjan, and P. P. Srivastav. 2025a. &#x201c;Synergistic Effect of Pre&#x2010;Treatment and Microwave Drying on the Physicochemical and Functional Properties of Chausa Mango Peel: Process Optimization and HPLC Analysis to Identify Mangiferin.&#x201d; Sustainable Chemistry for the Environment 10: 100235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rout, S., S. Tripathy, and P. P. Srivastav. 2024. &#x201c;Effect of Cold Plasma for Modulating Macromolecules and Bioactive Composition of Food: Unveiling Mechanisms and Synergies With Other Emerging Techniques.&#x201d; Food Bioscience 61: 104545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rout, S., S. Tripathy, and P. P. Srivastav. 2025b. &#x201c;Valorization of Mango Peels Toward Sustainability and Circular Economy by Combining Pretreatment and Drying With Ultrasound Assisted Extraction: Mathematical Modeling, Functional Properties, and Identification of Mangiferin by HPLC.&#x201d; Journal of Food Process Engineering 48, no. 3: e70079.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souppez, J.&#x2010;B. R. G., B. A. S. Dages, G. S. Pavar, J. Fabian, J. M. Thomas, and E. Theodosiou. 2025. &#x201c;Mechanical Properties and Texture Profile Analysis of Beef Burgers and Plant&#x2010;Based Analogues.&#x201d; Journal of Food Engineering 385: 112259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sousa, R., R. Portmann, S. Dubois, I. Recio, and L. Egger. 2020. &#x201c;Protein Digestion of Different Protein Sources Using the INFOGEST Static Digestion Model.&#x201d; Food Research International 130: 108996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speranza, B., A. Bevilacqua, M. Mastromatteo, M. Sinigaglia, and M. R. Corbo. 2010. &#x201c;Modelling the Interactions Between Pseudomonas Putida and Escherichia coli O157: H7 in Fish&#x2010;Burgers: Use of the Lag&#x2010;Exponential Model and of a Combined Interaction Index.&#x201d; Journal of Applied Microbiology 109, no. 2: 667&#x2013;678.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, D., B. Zhang, C. Zhou, W. Ren, and M. Wu. 2023. &#x201c;Effect of High&#x2010;Moisture Extrusion Process on Quality Attribute and Fibrous Formation Mechanism of Pea Protein: Insight Into Dynamic Changes of Textural Protein.&#x201d; Innovative Food Science &amp; Emerging Technologies 89: 103486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, L., X. Ye, S. Liu, et&#xa0;al. 2025. &#x201c;Study on the Mechanism of Protein&#x2010;polysaccharide Complex High Viscosity Gel and Its Adhesion in Plant Meat Substitute.&#x201d; International Journal of Biological Macromolecules 143547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, L., X. Hua, L. Yin, X. Jia, and H. Liu. 2024. &#x201c;Effect of Corona Discharge Cold Plasma on the Structure and Emulsification Properties of Soybean Protein Isolate.&#x201d; Food Hydrocolloids 156: 110337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian, T., K. Ren, X. Cao, et&#xa0;al. 2023. &#x201c;High Moisture Extrusion of Soybean&#x2010;Wheat Co&#x2010;Precipitation Protein: Mechanism of Fibrosis Based on Different Extrusion Energy Regulation.&#x201d; Food Hydrocolloids 144: 108950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Berg, L. A., J. J. Mes, M. Mensink, and A. J. Wanders. 2022. &#x201c;Protein Quality of Soy and the Effect of Processing: A Quantitative Review.&#x201d; Frontiers in Nutrition 9: 1004754.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen, Y., H. W. Kim, and H. J. Park. 2022. &#x201c;Effects of Transglutaminase and Cooking Method on the Physicochemical Characteristics of 3D&#x2010;Printable Meat Analogs.&#x201d; Innovative Food Science &amp; Emerging Technologies 81: 103114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, X., G. Wang, F. Xie, et&#xa0;al. 2025. &#x201c;Fermentation of Plant&#x2010;Based Yogurt and Its Effects on Phytochemicals: A Review.&#x201d; Food Reviews International 1&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Y., Y. Bai, C. Dai, H. Lv, X. Zhou, and Q. Xu. 2022. &#x201c;Effects of Non&#x2010;Thermal Atmospheric Plasma on Protein.&#x201d; Journal of Clinical Biochemistry and Nutrition 71, no. 3: 173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, L., T. Zhang, H. Li, T. Chen, and X. Liu. 2023. &#x201c;Control of Beany Flavor From Soybean Protein Raw Material in Plant&#x2010;Based Meat Analog Processing.&#x201d; Foods 12, no. 5: 923.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, L., X. Ma, J. Liu, X. Hu, Z. Wu, and C. Shi. 2022. &#x201c;Improving the Effectiveness of Internal Curing Through Engineering the Pore Structure of Lightweight Aggregates.&#x201d; Cement and Concrete Composites 134: 104773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Q., Z. Cheng, J. Zhang, M. Muhammad Nasiru, Y. Wang, and L. Fu. 2021. &#x201c;Atmospheric Cold Plasma Treatment of Soybean Protein Isolate: Insights Into the Structural, Physicochemical, and Allergenic Characteristics.&#x201d; Journal of Food Science 86, no. 1: 68&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, H., Y. Hu, Y. Tan, Z. Zhang, and D. J. McClements. 2021. &#x201c;Digestibility and Gastrointestinal Fate of Meat versus Plant&#x2010;Based Meat Analogs: An in Vitro Comparison.&#x201d; Food Chemistry 364: 130439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, H., G. Vu, X. Gong, and D. J. McClements. 2022. &#x201c;Comparison of the Cooking Behaviors of Meat and Plant&#x2010;Based Meat Analogues: Appearance, Texture, and Fluid Holding Properties.&#x201d; ACS Food Science &amp; Technology 2, no. 5: 844&#x2013;851.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>