<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40020050</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2375-2548</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Science advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Approaching infinite selectivity in membrane-based aqueous lithium extraction via solid-state ion transport.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>eadq9823</StartPage><MedlinePgn>eadq9823</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">eadq9823</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1126/sciadv.adq9823</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>As the gap between lithium supply and demand continues to widen, the need to develop ion-selective technologies, which can efficiently extract lithium from unconventional water sources, grows increasingly crucial. In this study, we investigated the fundamentals of applying a solid-state electrolyte (SSE), typically used in battery technologies, as a membrane material for aqueous lithium extraction. We find that the anhydrous hopping of lithium ions through the ordered and confined SSE lattice is highly distinct from ion migration through the hydrated free volumes of conventional nanoporous membranes, thus culminating in unique membrane transport properties. Notably, we reveal that the SSE provides unparalleled performance with respect to ion-ion selectivity, consistently demonstrating lithium ion selectivity values that are immeasurable by even the part-per-billion detection limit of mass spectrometry. Such exceptional selectivity is shown to be the result of the characteristic size and charge exclusion mechanisms of solid-state ion transport, which may be leveraged in the design of next-generation membranes for resource recovery.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patel</LastName><ForeName>Sohum K</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5228-9449</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical and Environmental Engineering, Yale University, New Haven, CT 06520-8286, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iddya</LastName><ForeName>Arpita</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9811-1096</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical and Environmental Engineering, Yale University, New Haven, CT 06520-8286, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pan</LastName><ForeName>Weiyi</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6587-1040</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical and Environmental Engineering, Yale University, New Haven, CT 06520-8286, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qian</LastName><ForeName>Jianhao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0508-7494</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical and Environmental Engineering, Yale University, New Haven, CT 06520-8286, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elimelech</LastName><ForeName>Menachem</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4186-1563</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical and Environmental Engineering, Yale University, New Haven, CT 06520-8286, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101653440</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2375-2548</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40020050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11870030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.adq9823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Castelvecchi D., Electric cars and batteries: How will the world produce enough? Nature 596, 336&#x2013;339 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34404944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C., Dai Q., Gaines L., Hu M., Tukker A., Steubing B., Future material demand for automotive lithium-based batteries. Commun. Mater. 1, 99 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziegler M. S., Trancik J. E., Re-examining rates of lithium-ion battery technology improvement and cost decline. Energy Environ. Sci. 14, 1635&#x2013;1651 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greim P., Solomon A. A., Breyer C., Assessment of lithium criticality in the global energy transition and addressing policy gaps in transportation. Nat. Commun. 11, 4570 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7486911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32917866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A., Fukuda H., Hatton T. A., Lienhard V. J. H., Lithium recovery from oil and gas produced water: A need for a growing energy industry. ACS Energy Lett. 4, 1471&#x2013;1474 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sener S. E. C., Thomas V. M., Hogan D. E., Maier R. M., Carbajales-Dale M., Barton M. D., Karanfil T., Crittenden J. C., Amy G. L., Recovery of critical metals from aqueous sources. ACS Sustainable Chem. Eng. 9, 11616&#x2013;11634 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8580379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34777924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DuChanois R. M., Cooper N. J., Lee B., Patel S. K., Mazurowski L., Graedel T. E., Elimelech M., Prospects of metal recovery from wastewater and brine. Nat. Water 1, 37&#x2013;46 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dugamin E. J. M., Richard A., Cathelineau M., Boiron M.-C., Despinois F., Brisset A., Groundwater in sedimentary basins as potential lithium resource: A global prospective study. Sci. Rep. 11, 21091 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8548349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34702944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choubey P. K., Kim M. S., Srivastava R. R., Lee J. C., Lee J. Y., Advance review on the exploitation of the prominent energy-storage element: Lithium. Part I: From mineral and brine resources. Miner. Eng. 89, 119&#x2013;137 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalil A., Mohammed S., Hashaikeh R., Hilal N., Lithium recovery from brine: Recent developments and challenges. Desalination 528, 115611 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vera M. L., Torres W. R., Galli C. I., Chagnes A., Flexer V., Environmental impact of direct lithium extraction from brines. Nat. Rev. Earth Environ. 4, 149&#x2013;165 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Li Y., Lin D., Hsu P.-C., Liu B., Yan G., Wu T., Cui Y., Chu S., Lithium extraction from seawater through pulsed electrochemical intercalation. Joule 4, 1459&#x2013;1469 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Z. Y., Ji Z. Y., Wang J., Guo X. F., Liang J. S., Electrochemical lithium extraction based on &#x201c;rocking-chair&#x201d; electrode system with high energy-efficient: The driving mode of constant current-constant voltage. Desalination 533, 115767 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tr&#xf3;coli R., Battistel A., La Mantia F., 
Selectivity of a lithium-recovery process based on LiFePO<sub>4</sub>. Chem. Eur. J.
20, 
9888&#x2013;9891 (2014).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25043970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu L., Zhang C., Kim S., Hatton T. A., Mo H., Waite T. D., Lithium recovery using electrochemical technologies: Advances and challenges. Water Res. 221, 118822 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35834973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng Q., Wang R., Zhao Z., Lin S., Liu Y., Dong D., Wang Z., He Y., Zhu Y., Jin J., Jiang L., Extreme Li-Mg selectivity via precise ion size differentiation of polyamide membrane. Nat. Commun. 15, 2505 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10954764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38509082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razmjou A., Asadnia M., Hosseini E., Korayem A. H., Chen V., Design principles of ion selective nanostructured membranes for the extraction of lithium ions. Nat. Commun. 10, 5793 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6923379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31857585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y., Ying Y., Mao Y., Peng X., Chen B., Polystyrene sulfonate threaded through a metal-organic framework membrane for fast and selective lithium-ion separation. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. Engl. 55, 15120&#x2013;15124 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27805300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu J., Zhang H., Hou J., Li X., Hu X., Hu Y., Easton C. D., Li Q., Sun C., Thornton A. W., Hill M. R., Zhang X., Jiang G., Liu J. Z., Hill A. J., Freeman B. D., Jiang L., Wang H., Efficient metal ion sieving in rectifying subnanochannels enabled by metal-organic frameworks. Nat. Mater. 19, 767&#x2013;774 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32152561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Hou J., Hu Y., Wang P., Ou R., Jiang L., Liu J. Z., Freeman B. D., Hill A. J., Wang H., Ultrafast selective transport of alkali metal ions in metal organic frameworks with subnanometer pores. Sci. Adv. 4, eaaq0066 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5817922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29487910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo R. J., Chen S., Huang L. Q., Ding X. L., Rafique S., Xia X. H., Li Z. Q., Regulating ion affinity and dehydration of metal-organic framework sub-nanochannels for high-precision ion separation. Nat. Commun. 15, 2145 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10924084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38459053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou L., Xian W., Bing S., Song Y., Sun Q., Zhang L., Ma S., Understanding the ion transport behavior across nanofluidic membranes in response to the charge variations. Adv. Funct. Mater. 31, 2009970 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C., Mu Y., Zhang W., Zhao S., Wang Y., 
PVC-based hybrid membranes containing metal-organic frameworks for Li<sup>+</sup> /Mg<sup>2+</sup> separation. J. Memb. Sci.
596, 
117724 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eden N. T., Scalzo M. T., Hou R., Ghasemiestahbanati E., Konstas K., Hill M. R., Sulfonated metal&#x2013;organic framework mixed-matrix membrane toward direct lithium extraction. ACS Appl. Eng. Mater. 1, 2336&#x2013;2346 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Famprikis T., Canepa P., Dawson J. A., Islam M. S., Masquelier C., Fundamentals of inorganic solid-state electrolytes for batteries. Nat. Mater. 18, 1278&#x2013;1291 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31427742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bachman J. C., Muy S., Grimaud A., Chang H. H., Pour N., Lux S. F., Paschos O., Maglia F., Lupart S., Lamp P., Giordano L., Shao-Horn Y., Inorganic solid-state electrolytes for lithium batteries: Mechanisms and properties governing ion conduction. Chem. Rev. 116, 140&#x2013;162 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26713396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B., Tan R., Yang L., Zheng J., Zhang K., Mo S., Lin Z., Pan F., Mechanisms and properties of ion-transport in inorganic solid electrolytes. Energy Storage Mater. 10, 139&#x2013;159 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S., Zhang F., Ding H., He P., Zhou H., Lithium metal extraction from seawater. Joule 2, 1648&#x2013;1651 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoshino T., Innovative lithium recovery technique from seawater by using world-first dialysis with a lithium ionic superconductor. Desalination 359, 59&#x2013;63 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Li C., Liu X., Cao L., Li P., Wei R., Li X., Guo D., Huang K.-W., Lai Z., Continuous electrical pumping membrane process for seawater lithium mining. Energy Environ. Sci. 14, 3152&#x2013;3159 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akkinepally B., Reddy I. N., Ko T. J., Yoo K., Shim J., 
Dopant effect on Li<sup>+</sup> ion transport in NASICON-type solid electrolyte: Insights from molecular dynamics simulations and experiments. Ceram. Int.
48, 
12142&#x2013;12151 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai F., Kakimoto K., Shang X., Mori D., Taminato S., Matsumoto M., Takeda Y., Yamamoto O., Izumi H., Minami H., Imanishi N., 
Water-stable high lithium-ion conducting solid electrolyte of Li<sub>1 4</sub>Al<sub>0 4</sub>Ge<sub>0 2</sub>Ti<sub>1 4</sub>.(PO<sub>4</sub>)<sub>3</sub>-LiCl for aqueous lithium-air batteries. Front. Energy Res.
8, 
187 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dlugolecki P., Ogonowski P., Metz S. J., Saakes M., Nijmeijer K., Wessling M., On the resistances of membrane, diffusion boundary layer and double layer in ion exchange membrane transport. J. Memb. Sci. 349, 369&#x2013;379 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamcev J., Sujanani R., Jang E.-S., Yan N., Moe N., Paul D. R., Freeman B. D., Salt concentration dependence of ionic conductivity in ion exchange membranes. J. Memb. Sci. 547, 123&#x2013;133 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan H., Yip N. Y., Elucidating conductivity-permselectivity tradeoffs in electrodialysis and reverse electrodialysis by structure-property analysis of ion-exchange membranes. J. Memb. Sci. 573, 668&#x2013;681 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkisov L., Bueno-Perez R., Sutharson M., Fairen-Jimenez D., Materials Informatics with PoreBlazer v4.0 and the CSD MOF Database. Chem. Mater. 32, 9849&#x2013;9867 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Mehrer, <i>Diffusion in Solids: Fundamentals, Methods, Materials, Diffusion-Controlled Processes</i> (Springer Science &amp; Business Media, 2007), vol. 155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kononenko N., Nikonenko V., Grande D., Larchet C., Dammak L., Fomenko M., Volfkovich Y., Porous structure of ion exchange membranes investigated by various techniques. Adv. Colloid Interface Sci. 246, 196&#x2013;216 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28511788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamcev J., Paul D. R., Manning G. S., Freeman B. D., Ion diffusion coefficients in ion exchange membranes: Significance of counterion condensation. Macromolecules 51, 5519&#x2013;5529 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasuda H., Lamaze C. E., Ikenberry L. D., Permeability of solutes through hydrated polymer membranes. I. Diffusion of sodium chloride. Makromol. Chem. 118, 19&#x2013;35 (1968).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shefer I., Lopez K., Straub A. P., Epsztein R., Applying transition-state theory to explore transport and selectivity in salt-rejecting membranes: A critical review. Environ. Sci. Technol. 56, 7467&#x2013;7483 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35549171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zwolinski B. J., Eyring H., Reese C. E., Diffusion and membrane permeability. J. Phys. Colloid Chem. 53, 1426&#x2013;1453 (1949).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritt C. L., Liu M., Pham T. A., Epsztein R., Kulik H. J., Elimelech M., Machine learning reveals key ion selectivity mechanisms in polymeric membranes with subnanometer pores. Sci. Adv. 8, eabl5771 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8759746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35030018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X., Wang Z., Epsztein R., Zhan C., Li W., Fortner J. D., Pham T. A., Kim J.-H., Elimelech M., Intrapore energy barriers govern ion transport and selectivity of desalination membranes. Sci. Adv. 6, eabd9045 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7688318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason P. E., Ansell S., Neilson G. W., Rempe S. B., Neutron scattering studies of the hydration structure of Li. J. Phys. Chem. B 119, 2003&#x2013;2009 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25559086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loeffler H. H., Rode B. M., The hydration structure of the lithium ion. J. Chem. Phys. 117, 110&#x2013;117 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varma S., Rempe S. B., Coordination numbers of alkali metal ions in aqueous solutions. Biophys. Chem. 124, 192&#x2013;199 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16875774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang B., Ziebarth B., Els&#xe4;sser C., 
Lithium ion conduction in LiTi<sub>2</sub>(PO<sub>4</sub>)<sub>3</sub> and related compounds based on the NASICON structure: A first-principles study. Chem. Mater.
27, 
5040&#x2013;5048 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xed;az J. C., Park J., Shapiro A., Patel H., Santiago-Pag&#xe1;n L., Kitto D., Kamcev J., Understanding monovalent cation diffusion in negatively charged membranes and the role of membrane water content. Macromolecules 57, 2468&#x2013;2481 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan H., Huang Y., Billinge I. H., Bannon S. M., Geise G. M., Yip N. Y., Counterion mobility in ion-exchange membranes: Spatial effect and valency-dependent electrostatic interaction. ACS Est. Eng. 2, 1274&#x2013;1286 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R., Lin S., Membrane design principles for ion-selective electrodialysis: An analysis for Li/Mg separation. Environ. Sci. Technol. 58, 3552&#x2013;3563 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10882969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38324772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Juarez A., Pecharroman C., Iglesias J. E., Rojo J. M., 
Relationship between activation energy and bottleneck size for Li<sup>+</sup> ion conduction in NASICON materials of composition LiMM&#x2032;(PO<sub>4</sub>)<sub>3</sub>; M, M&#x2032; = Ge, Ti, Sn, Hf. J. Phys. Chem. B
102, 
372&#x2013;375 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L., Wang Y., Chen J., Li W., Wang T., Wu J., Han S., Xia Y., Wu Y., Wu M., Wang F., Zheng Y., Peng L., Liu J., Chen L., Tang W., Enhancing ionic conductivity in solid electrolyte by relocating diffusion ions to under-coordination sites. Sci. Adv. 8, eabj7698 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8932667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35302845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou Z., Ma N., Wang A., Ran Y., Song T., He B., Ye A., Mi P., Zhang L., Zhou H., Jiao Y., Liu J., Wang D., Li Y., Avdeev M., Shi S., Identifying migration channels and bottlenecks in monoclinic NASICON-type solid electrolytes with hierarchical ion-transport algorithms. Adv. Funct. Mater. 31, 2107747 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DuChanois R. M., Heiranian M., Yang J., Porter C. J., Li Q., Zhang X., Verduzco R., Elimelech M., Designing polymeric membranes with coordination chemistry for high-precision ion separations. Sci. Adv. 8, eabm9436 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8896795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35245114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shannon R. D., Revised effective ionic-radii and systematic studies of interatomic distances in halides and chalcogenides. Acta Crystallogr. 32, 751&#x2013;767 (1976).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M., Pan H., Wang Y., Yang J., Dong H., He P., Zhou H., 
Research on Li<sup>+</sup>/Na<sup>+</sup> selectivity of NASICON-type solid-state ion conductors by first-principles calculations. Energy Fuel
37, 
10663&#x2013;10672 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DuChanois R. M., Mazurowski L., Fan H., Verduzco R., Nir O., Elimelech M., Precise cation separations with composite cation-exchange membranes: Role of base layer properties. Environ. Sci. Technol. 57, 6331&#x2013;6341 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37023347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ul Afsar N., Shehzad M. A., Irfan M., Emmanuel K., Sheng F., Xu T., Ren X., Ge L., Xu T., Cation exchange membrane integrated with cationic and anionic layers for selective ion separation via electrodialysis. Desalination 458, 25&#x2013;33 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu T., Shehzad M. A., Yu D., Li Q., Wu B., Ren X., Ge L., Xu T., Highly cation permselective metal-organic framework membranes with leaf-like morphology. ChemSusChem 12, 2593&#x2013;2597 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31020804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao H., Chai M., Hosseini A., Korayem A. H., Abdollahzadeh M., Ahmadi H., Chen V., Gore D. B., Asadnia M., Razmjou A., 
UiO-66-(COONa)<sub>2</sub> membrane with programmable ionic channels for lithium ion-selective transport. J. Memb. Sci.
670, 
121312 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammad M., Lisiecki M., Liang K., Razmjou A., Chen V., Metal-Phenolic network and metal-organic framework composite membrane for lithium ion extraction. Appl. Mater. Today 21, 100884 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng F., Wu B., Li X., Xu T., Shehzad M. A., Wang X., Ge L., Wang H., Xu T., Efficient ion sieving in covalent organic framework membranes with sub-2-nanometer channels. Adv. Mater. 33, 2104404 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34480387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choubey P. K., Chung K. S., Kim M. S., Lee J. C., Srivastava R. R., Advance review on the exploitation of the prominent energy-storage element lithium. Part II: From sea water and spent lithium ion batteries (LIBs). Miner. Eng. 110, 104&#x2013;121 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ooi K., Sonoda A., Makita Y., Chitrakar R., Tasaki-Handa Y., Nakazato T., Recovery of lithium from salt-brine eluates by direct crystallization as lithium sulfate. Hydrometallurgy 174, 123&#x2013;130 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Tran, V. T. Luong, in <i>Lithium Process Chemistry</i>, A. Chagnes, J. &#x15a;wiatowska, Eds. (Elsevier, 2015), pp. 81&#x2013;124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Hu Y., Wang L., Sun W., Systematic review of lithium extraction from salt-lake brines via precipitation approaches. Miner. Eng. 139, 105868 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He R., Dong C., Xu S., Liu C., Zhao S., He T., 
Unprecedented Mg<sup>2+</sup>/Li<sup>+</sup> separation using layer-by-layer based nanofiltration hollow fiber membranes. Desalination
525, 
115492 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel S. K., Qin M., Walker W. S., Elimelech M., Energy efficiency of electro-driven brackish water desalination: Electrodialysis significantly outperforms membrane capacitive deionization. Environ. Sci. Technol. 54, 3663&#x2013;3677 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32084313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Momma K., Izumi F., 
<i>VESTA 3</i> for three-dimensional visualization of crystal, volumetric and morphology data. J. Appl. Cryst.
44, 
1272&#x2013;1276 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Z., Mishra T. P., Mahayoni E., Ma Q., Tieu A. J. K., Guillon O., Chotard J.-N., Seznec V., Cheetham A. K., Masquelier C., Gautam G. S., Canepa P., Fundamental investigations on the sodium-ion transport properties of mixed polyanion solid-state battery electrolytes. Nat. Commun. 13, 4470 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9345873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35918385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maf&#xe9; S., Manzanares J. A., Ramirez P., Modeling of surface bulk ionic conductivity in fixed charge membranes. Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 5, 376&#x2013;383 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dlugolecki P., Nymeijer K., Metz S., Wessling M., Current status of ion exchange membranes for power generation from salinity gradients. J. Memb. Sci. 319, 214&#x2013;222 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nightingale E. R. Jr., Phenomenological theory of ion solvation. Effective Radii of hydrated ions. J. Phys. Chem. 63, 1381&#x2013;1387 (1959).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcus Y., Thermodynamics of solvation of ions. Part 5.&#x2014;Gibbs free energy of hydration at 298.15 K. J. Chem. Soc. Faraday Trans. 87, 2995&#x2013;2999 (1991).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Rehman D., Sun P.-F., Deshmukh A., Zhang L., Han Q., Yang Z., Wang Z., Park H.-D., Lienhard J. H., Tang C. Y., Novel positively charged metal-coordinated nanofiltration membrane for lithium recovery. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 13, 16906&#x2013;16915 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33798334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>