<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41809287</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exertional Rhabdomyolysis, Hyposthenuria, and Acute Kidney Injury: The Non-benign Side of Sickle Cell Trait.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e103115</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e103115</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e103115</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.103115</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sickle cell trait (SCT) is largely understood to be a clinically silent disease that typically does not require intensive clinical monitoring or counseling of patients. In fact, many patients with SCT are unaware that they have this genetic condition. However, emerging studies, case reports, and reviews increasingly demonstrate&#xa0;that severe clinical pathology can be associated with SCT, showcasing the need for improved counseling and education. We present the case of a&#xa0;healthy young male patient who was admitted to the hospital with rhabdomyolysis, acute liver injury, extreme electrolyte disturbances, and acute renal failure necessitating emergent hemodialysis. Given that this was an otherwise healthy young athlete with no known&#xa0;risk factors, the gravity of his clinical condition led our team to question why he had such a severe presentation. Further evaluation revealed the diagnosis of SCT. SCT has been linked to an increased risk of exertional rhabdomyolysis, which causes muscle damage via microvascular occlusion as well as tissue ischemia, caused by endothelial damage. These processes predispose&#xa0;to a decreased ability to concentrate urine, increasing&#xa0;risk for dehydration, and more serious clinical presentations. The potential links between SCT and exertional rhabdomyolysis support the hypothesis that SCT is not a clinically silent condition.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Vincent et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vincent</LastName><ForeName>Ashley C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, University of Colorado Anschutz, Aurora, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swiostek</LastName><ForeName>Irmina</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Rush University Medical Center, Chicago, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaffie</LastName><ForeName>Rehaan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital Medicine, Denver Health, Denver, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dehydration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hyperkalemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hyposthenuria</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">renal failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rhabdomyolysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sickle cell trait</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41809287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12968087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.103115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Clinical outcomes associated with sickle cell trait: a systematic review. Naik RP, Smith-Whitley K, Hassell KL, et al. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169:619&#x2013;627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6487193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30383109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sickle cell trait, rhabdomyolysis, and mortality among U.S. army soldiers. Nelson DA, Deuster PA, Carter R 3rd, Hill OT, Wolcott VL, Kurina LM. N Engl J Med. 2016;375:435&#x2013;442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5026312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27518662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The carrier state for sickle cell disease is not completely harmless. Xu JZ, Thein SL. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31097635/ Haematologica. 2019;104:1106&#x2013;1111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6545856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31097635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Management of the sickle cell trait: an opinion by expert panel members. Pinto VM, De Franceschi L, Gianesin B, et al. J Clin Med. 2023;12:3441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10219090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37240547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sickle cell trait: a benign state? Kotila TR. Acta Haematol. 2016;136:147&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27423233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acute kidney injury among black patients with sickle cell trait and sickle cell disease. Olaniran KO, Allegretti AS, Zhao SH, Nigwekar SU, Kalim S. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2021;16:348&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8011026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33648973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhabdomyolysis and acute renal failure in a sickle cell trait athlete: a case study. Shelmadine BD, Baltensperger A, Wilson RL, Bowden RG. Clin J Sport Med. 2013;23:235&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22894971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sickle cell trait and fatal rhabdomyolysis in football training: a case study. Anzalone ML, Green VS, Buja M, Sanchez LA, Harrykissoon RI, Eichner ER. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42:3&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20010136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exertional rhabdomyolysis and renal failure in patients with sickle cell trait: is it time to change our approach? Makaryus JN, Catanzaro JN, Katona KC. Hematology. 2007;12:349&#x2013;352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17654064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exertion-induced rhabdomyolysis with acute renal failure and disseminated intravascular coagulation in sickle cell trait. Koppes GM, Daly JJ, Coltman CA Jr, Butkus DE. Am J Med. 1977;63:313&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">888852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acute exertional rhabdomyolysis and its relationship to sickle cell trait. Harrelson GL, Fincher AL, Robinson JB. http://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16558353/ J Athl Train. 1995;30:309&#x2013;312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1317999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16558353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Consensus Statement: Sickle Cell Trait and the Athlete. Consensus Statement: Sickle Cell Trait and the Athlete.  [
Oct;
2025 
]. 2007. https://www.charlydmiller.com/LIB09/2007JuneNatAthleticTrainersSickleCellTrait.pdf https://www.charlydmiller.com/LIB09/2007JuneNatAthleticTrainersSickleCellTrait.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashorobi D, Ramsey A, Killeen RB, Bhatt R. StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2024. Sickle cell trait.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhabdomyolysis. Cabral BM, Edding SN, Portocarrero JP, Lerma EV. Dis Mon. 2020;66:101015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32532456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhai S, Dimachkie MM. UpToDate. Netherlands: Wolters Kluwer; 2025. Rhabdomyolysis: epidemiology and etiology.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhai S, Dimachkie MM. UpToDate. Netherlands: Wolters Kluwer; 2024. Rhabdomyolysis: clinical manifestations and diagnosis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical practice guidelines for exertional rhabdomyolysis: a military medicine perspective. Nye NS, Kasper K, Madsen CM, et al. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2021;20:169&#x2013;178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33655999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vichinsky EP. UpToDate. Netherlands: Wolters Kluwer; 2025. Sickle cell trait.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll RG. Elsevier's Integrated Physiology. Philadelphia, PA: Mosby Elsevier; 2007. Renal system and urinary tract; pp. 117&#x2013;137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creatine kinase, coenzyme Q10, race, and risk of rhabdomyolysis. Prince LK, Abbott KC, Lee JJ, Oliver DK, Olson SW. Am J Kidney Dis. 2015;66:541&#x2013;542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26060183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>