<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41886148</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1614-7499</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Environmental science and pollution research international</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Environ Sci Pollut Res Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Modifying alkali-activated materials with reactive MgO: A comprehensive overview of mechanisms and performance.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11356-026-37506-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Alkali-activated materials (AAMs) are promising low-carbon alternatives to Portland cement, but their wider application is limited by poor volumetric stability, high shrinkage, and slow reaction kinetics, particularly in near-neutral salt-activated systems. Reactive magnesium oxide (MgO) has emerged as a multifunctional component that can address these limitations by acting as a partial precursor replacement, a composite activator, or a primary activator. This review provides a comprehensive overview of MgO's role in AAMs, focusing on hydration mechanisms, fresh properties, mechanical performance, volumetric stability, and durability. MgO influences AAM behavior through several mechanisms. Its hydration produces expansive brucite, which compensates for shrinkage, while in near-neutral systems MgO increases pore solution alkalinity, accelerating precursor dissolution and reaction kinetics. The formation of secondary phases, such as hydrotalcite-like compounds and hydrated magnesium carbonates, further refines pore structure, enhances durability, and contributes to self-healing. The impact of MgO is highly system-dependent. MgO generally reduces workability and accelerates setting, but significantly mitigates autogenous and drying shrinkage. Optimal dosages vary with activator type: approximately 4-7.5% is effective in sodium silicate-activated slag, whereas higher dosages (~&#x2009;5-10%) are typically required in Na<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub>-activated systems. Strength development is non-monotonic and activator-specific, with moderate dosages enhancing strength in Na<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub>-activated systems but potentially reducing strength in NaOH-activated slag due to excessive expansion. When optimally dosed, MgO improves durability by enhancing chloride binding and carbonation resistance. Overall, MgO performance depends on its reactivity, particle size, activator chemistry, and precursor composition. This review synthesizes these interactions to guide the design of durable, high-performance, and sustainable AAM binders.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rashad</LastName><ForeName>Alaa M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5138-5452</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Building Materials Research and Quality Control Institute, Housing and Building National Research Center (HBRC), Cairo, Egypt. alaarashad@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Civil Engineering Department, College of Engineering, Shaqra University, Al-Dawadmi, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia. alaarashad@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Environ Sci Pollut Res Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9441769</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0944-1344</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alkali-activated materials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Durability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fresh properties</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hardened properties</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MgO</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval: This is not applicable. Consent to participate: This is not applicable. Consent to publish: This is not applicable. Competing interests: The author declares no competing interests. Mandatory if your study involves humans and/or animals: This is not applicable.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41886148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-026-37506-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11356-026-37506-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aligizaki KK (2005) Pore structure of cement-based materials: testing, interpretation and requirements. Crc Press</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1201/9781482271959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai Y-H, Yu S, Chen W (2019) Experimental study of carbonation resistance of alkali-activated slag concrete. ACI Mater J 116</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blotevogel S, Doussang L, Poirier M, Andr&#xe9; L, Canizar&#xe8;s A, Simon P, Montouillout V, Kaknics J, Patapy C, Cyr M (2024) The influence of Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>, CaO, MgO and TiO<sub>2</sub> content on the early-age reactivity of GGBS in blended cements, alkali-activated materials and supersulfated cements. Cem Concr Res 178:107439</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2024.107439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Ye H (2022) Influence of metakaolin and limestone on chloride binding of slag activated by mixed magnesium oxide and sodium hydroxide. Cem Concr Compos 127:104397</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2021.104397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Ye H (2022) The role of CaO and MgO incorporation in chloride resistance of sodium carbonate-activated slag. Cem Concr Compos 132:104625</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P, Chen Q, Fang Y, Wang C, Wang X, Li J, Wang Y (2023) Preparation of shrinkage-free alkali-activated slag material using MgO as both the activator and the expansive agent. Mater Construcc 73:e306-e306</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HX, Xue QP, Feng SJ, Zheng QT, Lv DJ (2024) Durability of geopolymer cutoff wall backfill incorporating reactive MgO particles under dry-wet cycles. Cem Concr Compos 146:105406</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2023.105406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng J, Qin Y, Luo L, Liang R (2025) Mixing ratio optimization of alkali-activated pastes containing reactive MgO composite activators using response surface methodology. Constr Build Mater 458:139667</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.139667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dung N, Hooper T, Unluer C (2019) Accelerating the reaction kinetics and improving the performance of Na<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub>-activated GGBS mixes. Cem Concr Res 126:105927</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng S, Zhu J, Wang R, Qu Z, Song L, Wang H (2022) The influence of CaO and MgO on the mechanical properties of alkali-activated blast furnace slag powder. Materials 15:6128</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15176128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gholami S, Kim Y-R, Little D, Kwon S, Jung JS (2024) Carbonation of one-part alkali-activated materials incorporated by MgO: phase characteristics and micromechanical properties. Constr Build Mater 441:137400</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu K, Jin F, Al-Tabbaa A, Shi B, Liu J (2014) Mechanical and hydration properties of ground granulated blastfurnace slag pastes activated with MgO&#x2013;CaO mixtures. Constr Build Mater 69:101&#x2013;108</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.07.032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haha MB, Lothenbach B, Le Saout G, Winnefeld F (2011) Influence of slag chemistry on the hydration of alkali-activated blast-furnace slag&#x2014;part I: effect of MgO. Cem Concr Res 41:955&#x2013;963</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2011.05.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J, Zheng W, Bai W, Hu T, He J, Song X (2021) Effect of reactive MgO on hydration and properties of alkali-activated slag pastes with different activators. Constr Build Mater 271:121608</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y, Jin Z, Pang B, Huang Y, Sun H, Du Z (2025) Effect of high-activity MgO on drying shrinkage and microstructure of geopolymer coatings. J Build Eng 111972</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Z, Zhang Z, Shi C, Zhu Y, Zhou Z, Jia X, Ren Q, Jiang Z (2025) Early hydration and microstructure formation of ultra-rapid hardening alkali-activated slag cement (URHA) at presence of MgO. Cem Concr Compos 160:106057</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2025.106057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang C-L, Vo D-H, Tran V-A, Yehualaw MD (2018) Effect of high MgO content on the performance of alkali-activated fine slag under water and air curing conditions. Constr Build Mater 186:503&#x2013;513</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.07.129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin F, Al-Tabbaa A (2013) Thermogravimetric study on the hydration of reactive magnesia and silica mixture at room temperature. Thermochim Acta 566:162&#x2013;168</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tca.2013.05.036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin F, Al-Tabbaa A (2015) Strength and drying shrinkage of slag paste activated by sodium carbonate and reactive MgO. Constr Build Mater 81:58&#x2013;65</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.01.082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin F, Gu K, Al-Tabbaa A (2014) Strength and drying shrinkage of reactive MgO modified alkali-activated slag paste. Constr Build Mater 51:395&#x2013;404</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2013.10.081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin F, Gu K, Al-Tabbaa A (2015) Strength and hydration properties of reactive MgO-activated ground granulated blastfurnace slag paste. Cem Concr Compos 57:8&#x2013;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2014.10.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaya M, Koksal F, Gencel O, Munir MJ, Kazmi SMS (2022) Influence of micro Fe2O3 and MgO on the physical and mechanical properties of the zeolite and kaolin based geopolymer mortar. J Build Eng 52:104443</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee NK, Koh KT, Kim MO, An GH, Ryu GS (2017) Physicochemical changes caused by reactive MgO in alkali-activated fly ash/slag blends under accelerated carbonation. Ceram Int 43:12490&#x2013;12496</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceramint.2017.06.119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma H, Li X, Zheng X, Niu X, Fang Y (2022) Effect of active MgO on the hydration kinetics characteristics and microstructures of alkali-activated fly ash-slag materials. Constr Build Mater 361:129677</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashad AM (2013) A comprehensive overview about the influence of different additives on the properties of alkali-activated slag&#x2013;a guide for civil engineer. Constr Build Mater 47:29&#x2013;55</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2013.04.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashad AM (2013) Alkali-activated metakaolin: a short guide for civil engineer&#x2013;an overview. Constr Build Mater 41:751&#x2013;765</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2012.12.030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashad AM (2014a) Metakaolin effect on geopolymers&#x2019; properties. SpringerBriefs in Applied Science and Technology. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-45151-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashad AM (2014) A comprehensive overview about the influence of different admixtures and additives on the properties of alkali-activated fly ash. Mater des 53:1005&#x2013;1025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2013.07.074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashad AM (2023) Silica fume in geopolymers: a comprehensive review of its effects on properties, Springer. Briefs in Applied Science and Technology, 2023. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-33219-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vo D-H, Hwang C-L, Yehualaw MD, Liao M-C (2021) The influence of MgO addition on the performance of alkali-activated materials with slag&#x2212; rice husk ash blending. J Build Eng 33:101605</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Park S, Khalid HR, Lee H (2021) Hydration properties of alkali-activated fly ash/slag binders modified by MgO with different reactivity. J Build Eng 44:103252</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu R, Kong F, Yang R, Wang H, Hong T (2024) Drying shrinkage mitigation of alkali-activated blast furnace slag-copper slag by polyether-based shrinkage reducing admixture and MgO-based expansion agent. Constr Build Mater 416:135172</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue C, Zhang W, Zhao Q (2024) The role of Al2O3, MgO and CaO in promoting Cl-uptake by hydrotalcite-like phases in alkali-activated binders with MSWI FA. Constr Build Mater 439:137259</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon HN, Park SM, Lee H-K (2018) Effect of MgO on chloride penetration resistance of alkali-activated binder. Constr Build Mater 178:584&#x2013;592</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.05.156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng W, He J, Tong Y, He J, Song X, Sang G (2022) Investigation of effects of reactive MgO on autogenous and drying shrinkage of near-neutral salt activated slag cement. Ceram Int 48:5518&#x2013;5526</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceramint.2021.11.096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>