<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40245026</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mechanical properties research of unconsolidated hydrate-bearing sediments under the effect of clay minerals.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0319772</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0319772</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0319772</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0319772</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The shallow hydrate reservoir in the Shenhu Sea area is mainly composed of clayey silt. Clay mineral has an important impact on the mechanical properties, and the hydrate decomposition aggravates this impact. Therefore, the composition and geological conditions of shallow clay hydrate-bearing sediment in Shenhu sea area are fully considered, hydrate-bearing sediment samples with similar physical properties are synthesized in situ. Then, indoor triaxial mechanical experiments are carried out, and the effect of clay minerals on the mechanical property is analyzed. The results show that the clay content and clay type have an important impact on the mechanical properties of unconsolidated hydrate-bearing sediment. With the increase of clay content, the strain hardening characteristics are prominent, the yield stage is longer, and the plasticity is enhanced. Hydrate-bearing sediment with different clay content shows similar mechanical laws under the influence of hydrate saturation and effective confining pressure. The peak strength, elastic modulus and Poisson's ratio all show a downward trend, but the peak strength and elastic modulus change more obviously. The peak strength changes linearly with hydrate saturation, while nonlinearly with effective confining pressure, especially 0-3&#x2009;MPa. This is the comprehesive result of clay particle's movement and fragmentation, clay hydration and expansion, affecting hydrate formation and sediment cementation. When the content ratio of montmorillonite/illite decreases, the peak strength and elastic modulus show an increasing trend. Because the frictional resistance and connection strength of illite crystal layer are larger with bigger particle size, weaker hydration and thinner water film. The research can provide reference for drilling and production engineering of natural gas hydrate (NGH) reservoir in the Shenhu sea area.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Sun et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Yuanwei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4159-3346</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Petroleum Engineering, China University of Petroleum (East China), Qingdao, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Petroleum Engineering, Shandong Institute of Petroleum and Chemical Technology, Dongying, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Yuanfang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Petroleum Engineering, China University of Petroleum (East China), Qingdao, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Cui</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Petroleum Engineering, Shandong Institute of Petroleum and Chemical Technology, Dongying, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Liqiang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Petroleum Engineering, Shandong Institute of Petroleum and Chemical Technology, Dongying, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dai</LastName><ForeName>Xiaodong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Petroleum Engineering, Shandong Institute of Petroleum and Chemical Technology, Dongying, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Chuanliang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Petroleum Engineering, China University of Petroleum (East China), Qingdao, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>T1FAD4SS2M</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000077215">Clay</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008903">Minerals</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000538">Aluminum Silicates</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077215" MajorTopicYN="Y">Clay</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019015" MajorTopicYN="Y">Geologic Sediments</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008903" MajorTopicYN="Y">Minerals</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000538" MajorTopicYN="Y">Aluminum Silicates</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="Y">Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40245026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12005542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0319772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-24-35292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chen H, Guan F, Xiao Q, et al. Experimental study on incremental synthesis of gas hydrate based on temperature oscillation. Oil Drill Prod Technol. 2019;41(3):399&#x2013;404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei L, Santamarina J. Laboratory strategies for hydrate formation in fine-grained sediments. J Geophys Res Solid Earth. 2018;123(4):2583&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu TB. Experimental study on sand production characteristics and micro mechanism of hydrate mining. Dalian Univ Technol. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo P, Liu S, Du J, et al. Development of gas hydrate reservoir. Beijing: Petr Ind Press; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grace J, Collett T, Colwell F, et al. Energy from gas hydrates assessing the opportunities and challenges for Canada. Rep Expert Panel Gas Hydrates. 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang HT, Zhang HQ, Zhu YH. Status quo and progress of natural gas hydrate investigation and research in China. Geol China. 2007;34(6):953&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia YL. Multi scale joint study on dynamic evolution characteristics of reservoir seepage parameters during hydrate decomposition. Jilin Univ. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YL, Hu GW, Wu NY, Liu C, Chen Q, Li C. Undrained shear strength evaluation for hydrate-bearing sediment overlying strata in the Shenhu area, northern South China Sea. Acta Oceanol Sin. 2019;38(3):114&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1007/s13131-019-1404-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13131-019-1404-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin XW, Lu C, Wang PK et al. Hydrate phase transition and percolation mechanism of natural gas hydrate recovery reservoirs in the South China Sea: Review and prospect. China Geol. 2022;49(03):749&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei X, Yao YB, Qin XW et al. Pore structure changes induced by hydrate dissociation: An example of the unconsolidated clayey-silty hydrate bearing sediment reservoir in the South China Sea. Marine Geology. 2022;443:106689. doi: 10.1016/j.margeo.2022.106689</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.margeo.2022.106689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang MJ, Xiao Y, Zhu FY. Discrete element numerical simulation analysis of macro mechanical properties of deep sea energy soil. J Geotech Eng. 2013;35(1):157&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong L, Li Y, Liao H, et al. Strength estimation for hydrate-bearing sediments based on triaxial shearing tests. J Pet Sci Eng. 2020;184:1064&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YL, Liu CL, Liu LL, Sun J, Liu H, Meng Q. Experimental study on evolution behaviors of triaxial-shearing parameters for hydrate-bearing intermediate fine sediment. Adv Geo-Energy Res. 2018;2(1):43&#x2013;52. doi: 10.26804/ager.2018.01.04</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26804/ager.2018.01.04</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang XJ, Jin JP, Guo YQ et al. The characteristics of gas hydrate accumulation and quantitative estimation in the North slope of South China Sea. Earth Sci. 2021;46(3):1038&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui W, Xiao JQ. Application of numerical simulation to study the first trial production data of hydrate in Shenhu Sea Area. Geosci. 2022;47(05):1890&#x2013;900.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu HL, Shang SL, Cheng XJ, et al. Research progress and development direction of numerical simulator for natural gas hydrate development. Acta Pet Sin. 2021;42(11):1516&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin XW, Lu JA, Lu HL, et al. Coexistence of natural gas hydrate, free gas and water in the gas hydrate system in the Shenhu Area, South China Sea. Chin Geol. 2020;3(2):210&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai JC, Xia YX, Xu S, et al. Advances in multiphase seepage characteristics of natural gas hydrate-bearing sediments. Chin J Theor Appl Mech. 2020;52(1):208&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bian H, Xia Y, Lu C, et al. Pore structure fractal characterization and permeability simulation of natural gas hydrate reservoir based on CT images. Geofluids. 2020;36:6934691.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng LT, Cai J, Lu C, et al. Phase equilibria of natural gas hydrates in bulk brine and marine sediments from the South China Sea. J Chem Eng Data. 2021;66:4064&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi RR, Qin XW, Lu C, et al. Experimental study on the isothermal adsorption of methane gas in natural gas hydrate argillaceous silt reservoir. Adv Geoenerg Res. 2022;6(2):143&#x2013;156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu T, Zhang ZB, Li SD, Li X, Lu C. Numerical evaluation of gas hydrate production performance of the depressurization and backfilling with an in situ supplemental heat method. ACS Omega. 2021;6(18):12274&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.1c01143</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.1c01143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8154132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34056380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong L, Li YL, Liu CL, et al. Mechanical properties of methane hydrate-bearing interlayered sediments. J Ocean Univ China. 2019;18(6):1344&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1007/s11802-019-3929-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11802-019-3929-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang P, Li YH, Wang L, et al. Hydrate-bearing sediment of the South China Sea: Microstructure and mechanical characteristics. Eng Geol. 2022;307:106782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu P, Li YH, Yu T, et al. Microstructure evolution and dynamic permeability anisotropy during hydrate dissociation in sediment under stress state. Energy. 2023;263:126126. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2022.126126</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2022.126126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winters WJ, Waite WF, Mason DH, et al. Methane gas hydrate effect on sediment acoustic and strength properties. J Pet Sci Eng. 2007;56(1):127&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan JA, Lu JS, Liang DQ, et al. Preliminary triaxial mechanical properties test of submarine sedimentary strata in South China Sea Shenhu hydrate region under high pressure. New Energ Prog. 2017;5(01):40&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YH, Wang L, Xie Y, et al. Deformation characteristics of methane hydrate-bearing clayey and sandy sediments during depressurization dissociation. Energy. 2023;275:127527. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2023.127527</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2023.127527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YH, Li JY, You ZC, et al. A particle-scale investigation of mechanical behavior of cemented hydrate-bearing sediment using Discrete Element Method. Geomech Energy Environ. 2023;33:100436. doi: 10.1016/j.gete.2023.100436</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gete.2023.100436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu GW, Li YL, Wu NY, et al. Undrained shear strength estimation of the cover layer of hydrate at Site W18/19 of Shenhu area. Mar Geol Quat Geol. 2017;37(5):151&#x2013;158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y, Liu CL, Liu LL, et al. Triaxial shear test and strain analysis of unconsolidated hydrate-bearing sediments. Nat Gas Geosci. 2017;28(3):383&#x2013;390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masui A, Haneda H, Ogata Y, et al. Effects of methane hydrate formation on shear strength of synthetic methane hydrate-bearing sediments. Int Soc Offsh Pol Engrs. 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masui A, Miyazaki K, Haneda H, et al. Mechanical properties of natural gas hydrate bearing sediments retrieved from eastern Nankai trough. Proc SPE Conf. 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyodo M, Nakata Y, Yoshimoto N, et al. Shear behavior of methane hydrate bearing sand. The Seventeenth International Offshore and Polar Engineering Conference. Int Soc Offsh Pol Engrs. 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan C, Ren X, Cheng Y, Song B, Li Y, Tian W. Geomechanical issues in the exploitation of natural gas hydrate. Gondwana Res. 2020;81:403&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1016/j.gr.2019.11.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gr.2019.11.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang XH, Wang SY, Li QP, et al. Experimental study on mechanical properties of natural gas hydrate-bearing sediments. Geotech Mech. 2010;31(10):3069&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez M, Gai X, Santamarina JC. A constitutive mechanical model for gas hydrate bearing sediments incorporating inelastic mechanisms. Comput Geotech. 2017;84:28&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1016/j.compgeo.2016.11.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compgeo.2016.11.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CL, Meng QG, Li CF, et al. Characterization of natural gas hydrate and its deposits recovered from the northern slope of South China Sea. Earth Sci Front. 2016;24(4):41&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang M, Shan HX, Liu LL, et al. Triaxial test of unconsolidated hydrate-bearing sediment containing methane. J Xi&#x2019;an Shiyou Univ (Nat Sci Ed). 2017;32(1):31&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z. Study on static and dynamic behavior and law of hydrate bearing sediments. China Univ Geosci. 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu GW, Ye YG, Zhang J, et al. Experimental study on formation, decomposition process and acoustic characteristics of natural gas hydrate in loose sediments. Mod Geol. 2008;22(3):465&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q, Lu JS, Li DL, et al. Study on mechanical properties of hydrate bearing sediments during depressurization mining. Geotech Mech. 2018;39(12):4508&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan YZ, Wu NY, Hu GW, et al. Reservoir stability in the process of natural gas hydrate production by depressurization in the Shenhu area of the South China Sea. Nat Gas Ind. 2018;38(4):117&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y. Study on strength and deformation characteristics of natural gas hydrate-bearing sediments. Dalian: Dalian University of Technology; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li YH, Song YC, Yu F, et al. Effect of confining pressure on mechanical properties of hydrate bearing sediments. Petrol Explor Dev. 2011;38(5):637&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang YQ, Yang P, Jiang WY, et al. Study on triaxial strength and constitutive model of silty clay frozen soil. J Civ Eng. 2019;52(S1):8&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun XJ. Experimental study on physical and mechanical properties of gas hydrate formation. Dongying: China Univ Petrol Press; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Li S, Hao Y, et al. Theory and technology of gas hydrate exploitation. Dongying: China Univ Petrol Press; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye JL, Qin XW, Xie WW, et al. Main progress of the second gas hydrate trial production in the South China Sea. Geol China. 2020;47(3):557&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>