<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41828237</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Study on the Performance Evolution Law and Microscopic Mechanism of Cement-Sodium Silicate Grout Prepared by Seawater.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">971</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma19050971</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>During the construction of underwater shield tunnels (excavated using a slurry pressure balance shield machine), whether seawater (Sw) can be used to replace freshwater (Fw) in the preparation of cement-sodium silicate grout (CSG) has become a major concern in the engineering community. CSG is formed by mixing components A and B, where component A is a liquid prepared by mixing bentonite, cement, and water, and component B is a sodium silicate solution. In this paper, the CSG was prepared using Sw instead of part of Fw. The properties, including bleeding rate, initial and final setting time, gel time, compressive strength, and microscopic characteristics, were tested to investigate the influence of Sw on the performance of CSG and explore its impact mechanism. The results showed that when expanding bentonite with Sw, the bleeding rate of Component A exceeded 50%, failing to meet the engineering requirement of 10%. However, expanding bentonite with Fw, the seawater replacement ratio has almost no effect on Component A, with all values remaining below 10%. As the seawater replacement ratio increases, the setting time of CSG is significantly shortened. Although the inclusion of seawater results in a marginally lower 1-day strength for CSG, it notably boosts the strength at later ages. Specifically, at a 45% seawater replacement ratio, the 28-day strength showed a marked increase of 52% relative to the CSG without seawater. In the later stage of hydration, the positive effect of Cl<sup>-</sup> in seawater, promoting the hydrolysis of C<sub>3</sub>S and C<sub>2</sub>S on strength, is significantly higher than the negative effect of sulfate ion erosion in seawater on strength. Therefore, seawater significantly increases the 28-day compressive strength of CSG. This study can provide reference and guidance for the application of seawater in the preparation of two-component grout for submarine shield tunnels.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Dengfeng</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Precision Blasting, Hohai University, Nanjing 210024, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil and Transportation Engineering, Hohai University, Nanjing 210024, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zhen</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil and Transportation Engineering, Hohai University, Nanjing 210024, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GD Power Shandong New Energy Development Co., Ltd., Yantai 264100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qi</LastName><ForeName>Yujie</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Precision Blasting, Hohai University, Nanjing 210024, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil and Transportation Engineering, Hohai University, Nanjing 210024, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Daiwei</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-5938-9692</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CCCC Tunnel Engineering Co., Ltd., Beijing 100102, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Xiaopeng</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CCCC Tunnel Engineering Co., Ltd., Beijing 100102, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jianfeng</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1686-9010</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Mechanics and Materials, Hohai University, Nanjing 211100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Min</LastName><ForeName>Fanlu</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Precision Blasting, Hohai University, Nanjing 210024, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil and Transportation Engineering, Hohai University, Nanjing 210024, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>52378394</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>B230201037</GrantID><Agency>Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">backfilling grout</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cement&#x2013;sodium silicate grout</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">resource utilization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">seawater</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">submarine tunnel</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Author Zhen Li is currently employed by GD Power Shandong New Energy Development Co. Ltd., while contributing to this manuscript. His contributions to this work and manuscript were made independently without any requirement, guidance, or input by his employer. He received no financial compensation from any source for the contributions he made to the scientific work and manuscript. Authors Daiwei Wei and Xiaopeng Zhao are currently employed by CCCC Tunnel Engineerng Co. Ltd., while contributing to this manuscript. His contributions to this work and manuscript were made independently without any requirement, guidance, or input by his employer. He received no financial compensation from any source for the contributions he made to the scientific work and manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41828237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12986188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma19050971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma19050971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Feng K., He C., Qiu Y., Zhang L., Wang W., Xie H., Zhang Y., Cao S. Full-scale tests on bending behavior of segmental joints for large underwater shield tunnels. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2018;75:100&#x2013;116. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2018.02.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2018.02.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y. Investigation into the Characteristics and Strength Simulation Test of the Complex Two-Component in Synchronous Grouting of Shield Tunneling. Beijing Jiaotong University; Beijing, China: 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D., Min F., Li Z. Investigation into the properties of two-component backfilling grouts prepared by substituting bentonite with slurry from slurry shield tunnelling treated by a hydrocyclone. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2024;154:106142. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2024.106142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2024.106142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todaro C., Carigi A., Martinelli D., Peila D. Study of the shear strength evolution over time of two-component backfilling grout in shield tunnelling. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2021;15:00689. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharghi M., Chakeri H., Ozcelik Y. Investigation into the effects of two component grout properties on surface settlements. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2017;63:205&#x2013;216. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2017.01.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2017.01.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., He C., Nie L., Zhang G. Study on the long-term performance of cement-sodium silicate grout and its impact on segment lining structure in synchronous backfill grouting of shield tunnels. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2019;92:103015. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2019.103015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2019.103015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah R., A. Lavasan A., Peila D., Todaro C., Luciani A., Schanz T. Numerical study on backfilling the tail void using a two-component grout. J. Mater. Civil. Eng. 2018;30:04018003. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0002175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0002175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen F., Huang P., Ba M., Bao X. Experimental study on dual-fluid-grout composite materials with slag steel modified portland cement and sodium silicate. Acta Mater. Compos. Sin. 2013;30:139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dou H. Investigation on the Performance and Microscopic Characteristics of Complex Cementitious-Sodium Silicate Two-Shot Grouting Materials. China University of Geosciences; Wuhan, China: 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharghi M., Chakeri H., Afshin H., Ozcelik Y. An experimental study of the performance of two-component backfilling grout used behind the segmental lining of a tunnel-boring machine. J. Test. Eval. 2018;46:2083&#x2013;2099. doi: 10.1520/JTE20160617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1520/JTE20160617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peila D., Chieregato A., Martinelli D., Onate Salazar C.G., Shah R., Boscaro A., Dal Negro E., Picchio A. Long term behavior of two component back-fill grout mix used in full face mechanized tunneling. Geoing. Ambient. 2015;144:57&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He X., Ma S., Chen J., Li M., Yu L., He J. Field test on construction influence on large-diameter shield tail segment floating of tunnel. Tunnel. Constr. 2023;43:136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y., Ruan J., Lin S. Floating Analysis and Control of Subsea Shield Tunnel Segment. Chin. J. Undergr. Space Eng. 2022;18:1665&#x2013;1677.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dal E., Boscaro A., Plescia E. Two-component backfill grout system in TBM. The experience of the tunnel &#x201c;Sparvo&#x201d; in Italy; Proceedings of the Tunnelling in a Resource Driven World Conference; TAC, Vancouver, BC, Canada. 26&#x2013;28 October 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todaro C., Saltarin S., Cardu M. Bentonite in two-component grout applications. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2022;16:00901. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e00901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e00901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youn B., Shulte-Schrep C., Breitenbucher R. Properties and Requirements of Two-Component Grouts in Mechanized Tunneling; Proceedings of the ITA WTC World Tunnel Congress 2016; San Francisco, CA, USA. 22&#x2013;28 April 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia Y., Li F., Wu D., Wang Y. Experimental Study on Mix Proportions of Synchronous Two-component Grouting for Shield Tunnels. Cogent Eng. 2019;56:143&#x2013;151,157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesboua N., Benyounes K., Benmounah A. Study of the impact of bentonite on the physico-mechanical and flow properties of cement grout. Cogent Eng. 2018;5:1446252. doi: 10.1080/23311916.2018.1446252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23311916.2018.1446252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todaro C., Zanti D., Carigi A., Peila D. The role of bentonite in two-component grout: A comparative study. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2023;142:105412. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2023.105412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2023.105412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todaro C., Pace F. Elastic properties of two-component grouts at short curing times: The role of bentonite. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2022;130:104756. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2022.104756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2022.104756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao W., Wu P., Huang J., Chen G., Lin J., Guo Y., Chen R. Cost-Effective Engineered Cementitious Composites with Hybrid PVA and Basalt/PP Fiber: A Study on Compressive, Tensile and Impact Performance. Materials. 2023;16:5172. doi: 10.3390/ma16145172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16145172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10383972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37512446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi J., Wang L., Ma L., Zhang Q., Zhang J., Chi J. Experimental Study on Basic Mechanical Properties of PVA Fiber-Reinforced Coral Cement-Based Composites. Materials. 2023;16:2914. doi: 10.3390/ma16072914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16072914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10096063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37049210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song W., Zhu Z., Pu S., Wan Y., Huo W., Peng Y. Preparation and engineering properties of alkali-activated filling grouts for shield tunnel. Constr. Build. Mater. 2022;314:125620. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.125620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.125620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulte-Schrep C., Ov D., Breitenb&#xfc;cher R. 3rd International Conference on the Application of Superabsorbent Polymers (SAP) and Other New Admixtures Towards Smart Concrete. Volume 3. Springer International Publishing; Cham, Switzerland: 2020. Solidification of two-component grouts by the use of superabsorbent polymers as activator; pp. 230&#x2013;238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Z., Li X., Liu Q., Tang Q., Lin X., Fan X., Huang X., Gan M., Chen X., Ji Z. Recent Advances in Alkali-Activated Materials with Seawater and Sea Sand. Materials. 2023;16:3571. doi: 10.3390/ma16093571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16093571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10179923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37176453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao J., Qiang C., Nanni A., Zhang K. Use of sea-sand and seawater in concrete construction: Current status and future opportunities. Constr. Build. Mater. 2017;155:1101&#x2013;1111. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.08.130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.08.130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge L., Feng Z., Sayed U., Li H. Research on the performance of seawater sea-sand concrete: A review. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;409:133921. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J., Jia J., Zhu M. Development of admixtures on seawater sea sand concrete: A critical review on Concrete hardening, chloride ion penetration and steel corrosion. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;411:134219. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi D., Yao Y., Ye J., Zhang W. Effects of seawater on mechanical properties, mineralogy and microstructure of calcium silicate slag-based alkali-activated materials. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;212:569&#x2013;577. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.03.288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.03.288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lao J., Huang B., Xu L., Khan M., Fang Y., Dai J. Seawater sea-sand Engineered Geopolymer Composites (EGC) with high strength and high ductility. Cement Concrete Comp. 2023;138:104998. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2023.104998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2023.104998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Y.Z., Guo L.P., Xue X.L. Effects of sodium chloride and sodium sulfate on hydration process. J. Southeast Univ. (Nat. Sci. Ed.) 2019;49:1001-0505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sikora P., Cendrowski K., Abd Elrahman M., Chung S.Y., Mijowska E., Stephan D. The effects of seawater on the hydration, microstructure and strength development of Portland cement pastes incorporating colloidal silica. Appl. Nanosci. 2020;10:2627&#x2013;2638. doi: 10.1007/s13204-019-00993-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13204-019-00993-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Younis A., Ebead U., Suraneni P., Nanni A. Fresh and hardened properties of seawater-mixed concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;190:276&#x2013;286. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.09.126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.09.126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao S., Zhang M., Zou D., Liu T., Zhou A., Li Y. Influence of seawater and sea sand on the performance of Anti-washout underwater concrete: The overlooked significance of Mg2+ Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;374:130932. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.130932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.130932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Shi C., He F., Yuan Q., Wang D., Huang Y., Li Q. Chloride binding and its effects on microstructure of cement-based materials. J. Chin. Ceram. Soc. 2013;41:187&#x2013;198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Weerdt K., Colombo A., Coppola L., Justnes H., Geiker M.R. Impact of the associated cation on chloride binding of Portland cement paste. Cement Concrete Res. 2015;68:196&#x2013;202. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2014.01.027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2014.01.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talero R., Trusilewicz L., Delgado A., Pedrajas C., Lannegrand R., Rahhal V., Mej&#xed;a R., Delvasto S., Ram&#xed;rez F. Comparative and semi-quantitative XRD analysis of Friedel&#x2019;s salt originating from pozzolan and Portland cement. Constr. Build. Mater. 2011;25:2370&#x2013;2380. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2010.11.037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2010.11.037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo M., Hu B., Xing F., Zhou X., Sun M., Sui L., Zhou Y. Characterization of the mechanical properties of eco-friendly concrete made with untreated sea sand and seawater based on statistical analysis. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;234:117339. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaseen S., Yiseen G., Poon C., Li Z. Influence of seawater on the morphological evolution and the microchemistry of hydration products of tricalcium silicates (C3S) ACS Sustain. Chem. Eng. 2020;8:15875&#x2013;15887. doi: 10.1021/acssuschemeng.0c04440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acssuschemeng.0c04440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukmak P., De Silva P., Horpibulsuk S., Chindaprasirt P. Sulfate resistance of clay-portland cement and clay high-calcium fly ash geopolymer. J. Mater. Civil. Eng. 2015;27:04014158. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0001112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0001112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ting M., Yi Y. Durability of cementitious materials in seawater environment: A review on chemical interactions, hardened-state properties and environmental factors. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;367:130224. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.130224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.130224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Society for Testing and Materials . Standard Practice for the Preparation of Substitute Ocean Water. ASTM International; West Conshohocken, PA, USA: 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Technical Specification for Simultaneous Grouting Material in Shield Projects. China Building Materials Press; Beijing, China: 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Technical Specifications for Construction of Highway Bridges and Culverts. China Building Materials Press; Beijing, China: 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Guan X., Li H., Liu X. Performance and hydration study of ultra-fine sulfoaluminate cement-based double liquid grouting material. Constr. Build. Mater. 2017;132:262&#x2013;270. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.11.135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.11.135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C., Yang J., Fu J., Ou X., Xie Y., Liang X. Performance evaluation of modified cement-sodium silicate grouting material for prereinforcing loose deposit tunnels. J. Mater. Civil. Eng. 2019;31:06019003. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0002747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0002747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z., Yang L., Zhou S., Gong Q., Zhu H. Durability of cement-sodium silicate grouts with a high water to binder ratio in marine environments. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;189:550&#x2013;559. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.09.040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.09.040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Test Method of Cement Mortar Strength (ISO Method) China Standards Press; Beijing, China: 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Au P., Pillai P., Leong Y. Ageing and collapse of bentonite gels&#x2014;Effects of Mg (II), Ca (II) and Ba (II) ions. Appl. Clay Sci. 2015;114:141&#x2013;150. doi: 10.1016/j.clay.2015.05.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clay.2015.05.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorakhki M., Bareither C. Salinity effects on sedimentation behavior of kaolin, bentonite, and soda ash mine tailings. Appl. Clay Sci. 2015;114:593&#x2013;602. doi: 10.1016/j.clay.2015.07.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clay.2015.07.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganesalingam D., Sivakugan N., Ameratunga J. Influence of settling behavior of soil particles on the consolidation properties of dredged clay sediment. J. Waterw. Port. Coast. 2013;139:295&#x2013;303. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)WW.1943-5460.0000183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)WW.1943-5460.0000183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min F., Du J., Zhang N., Chen X., Lv H., Liu L., Yu C. Experimental study of property change of slurry and filter cake of slurry shield under seawater intrusion. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2019;88:290&#x2013;299. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2019.03.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2019.03.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D., Min F., Zhou X., Liu L., Li B., Wang X., Du J., Zhang J. Influence of cation on properties of slurry and filter cake used in submarine shield tunnelling. Mar. Georesour. Geotechnol. 2025;43:1732&#x2013;1740. doi: 10.1080/1064119X.2024.2431995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1064119X.2024.2431995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sha F., Liu R., Li S., Lin C., Li Z., Liu B., Bai J. Application on different types of cementitious grouts for water-leakage operational tunnels. J. Cent. South. Univ. Sci. Technol. 2016;47:4163&#x2013;4172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song B., Min F., Zhang J., Li M., Zhang Y., Fang Z., Zhang L., Zhao X. Influence of Triethanolamine and Rapid Hardening Sulfoaluminate Cement on Performance of Backfill Grouting in Shield Engineering. J. Chin. Ceram. Soc. 2022;50:2886&#x2013;2896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chindaprasirt P., De Silva P., Sagoe-Crentsil K., Hanjitsuwan S. Effect of SiO2 and Al2O3 on the setting and hardening of high calcium fly ash-based geopolymer systems. J. Mater. Sci. 2012;47:4876&#x2013;4883. doi: 10.1007/s10853-012-6353-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10853-012-6353-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen R., Lai H., Cui D., Zhu Y. Alkali-activated mortar for tunnel-lining structure repair. J. Mater. Civil. Eng. 2019;31:04019217. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0002857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0002857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Y., Xuan D., Hou P., Shi J., Poon C.S. Effect of seawater as mixing water on the hydration behaviour of tricalcium aluminate. Cement Concrete Res. 2021;149:106565. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2021.106565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2021.106565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas J., Allen A., Jennings H. Density and water content of nanoscale solid C&#x2013;S&#x2013;H formed in alkali-activated slag (AAS) paste and implications for chemical shrinkage. Cement Concrete Res. 2012;42:377&#x2013;383. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2011.11.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2011.11.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y., Xu J., Luo X., Zhu J., Nie L. Experiment research on mix design and early mechanical performance of alkali-activated slag using response surface methodology (RSM) Ceram. Int. 2016;42:11666&#x2013;11673. doi: 10.1016/j.ceramint.2016.04.076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceramint.2016.04.076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan D., Yaseen S., Chen K., Niu D., Leung C., Li Z. Study of the influence of seawater and sea sand on the mechanical and microstructural properties of concrete. J. Build. Eng. 2021;42:103006. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andr&#xe9; L., Bacqui&#xe9; C., Comin G., Ploton R., Achard D., Frouin L. Cyr Martin Improvement of two-component grouts by the use of ground granulated blast furnace slag. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2022;122:104369. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2022.104369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2022.104369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y., Tan Z., Zhang W., Liu X., Song J., Shang H. Incorporating supplementary cementitious materials into ultra-high-performance seawater sea-sand concrete (UHPSSC): Hydration, microstructure, and mechanical performance. Constr. Build. Mater. 2025;472:140824. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.140824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.140824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., Ding D., Sun J., Guo F., Feng H., Ma H., Hong S., Dong B., Hou D. Novel insights on the setting process, hardened properties, and durability of sustainable ultra-high-performance seawater sea sand concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;447:138092. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.138092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.138092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>