<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39287510</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1944-8252</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>39</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Appl Mater Interfaces</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Interfacial Stabilization of Organic Electrochemical Transistors Conferred Using Polythiophene-Based Conjugated Block Copolymers with a Hydrophobic Coil Design.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>52753</StartPage><EndPage>52765</EndPage><MedlinePgn>52753-52765</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsami.4c13197</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The recent interest in developing low-cost, biocompatible, and lightweight bioelectronic devices has focused on organic electrochemical transistors (OECTs), which have the potential to fulfill these requirements. In this study, three types of poly(3-hexylthiophene) (P3HT)-based block copolymers (BCPs) incorporating different insulating blocks (poly(<sup><i>n</i></sup>butyl acrylate) (PBA), polystyrene, and poly(ethylene oxide) (PEO)) were synthesized for application in OECTs. The morphological, crystallographic, and electrochemical properties of these BCPs are systematically investigated. Accordingly, P3HT-<i>b</i>-PBA demonstrates superior performance in the KCl-based aqueous electrolyte, with a higher product of mobility and capacitance (&#x3bc;<i>C</i>*) at 170 F s<sup>-1</sup> cm<sup>-1</sup> V<sup>-1</sup> than that of the P3HT homopolymer at 58 F s<sup>-1</sup> cm<sup>-1</sup> V<sup>-1</sup>. P3HT-<i>b</i>-PBA exhibits better stability over 50 ON/OFF switching cycles than do other BCPs and P3HT homopolymers. With regard to the performance in the KPF<sub>6</sub>-based aqueous electrolyte, P3HT-<i>b</i>-PBA outperforms with a higher &#x3bc;<i>C</i>* of 9.2 F s<sup>-1</sup> cm<sup>-1</sup> V<sup>-1</sup> than that of 8.6 F s<sup>-1</sup> cm<sup>-1</sup> V<sup>-1</sup> observed from P3HT. Notably, both polymers exhibited almost no decay in device performance over 110 ON/OFF switching cycles. The strongly different performance of polymers in these two electrolytes is due to the side chain's hydrophobicity and interdigitated lamellar structures, thereby retarding the doping kinetics of the highly hydrated Cl<sup>-</sup> ions compared with the slightly hydrated PF<sub>6</sub><sup>-</sup> ions. Concerning the improved performance of P3HT-<i>b</i>-PBA, this is attributed to its soft and hydrophobic backbone. Our morphological and crystallographic analyses reveal that P3HT-<i>b</i>-PBA experiences minimal structural disorder when swelled by the electrolyte, maintaining its original structure better than the P3HT homopolymer and the hydrophilic BCP of P3HT-<i>b</i>-PEO. The hydrophobic nature of P3HT-<i>b</i>-PBA contributes to the stability of its backbone structure, ensuring enhanced capacitance during the operation of the OECT operation. These findings provide reassurance about the stability and performance of P3HT-<i>b</i>-PBA in the field of OECT applications. In summary, this study represents the first exploration of P3HT-based BCPs for OECT applications and investigates their structure-performance relationships in mixed ionic-electronic conductors.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Chia-Ying</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Engineering, National Cheng Kung University, Tainan 70101, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Guo-Hao</ForeName><Initials>GH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Engineering, National Cheng Kung University, Tainan 70101, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Higashihara</LastName><ForeName>Tomoya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2115-1281</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Organic Materials Science, Graduate School of Organic Materials Science, Yamagata University, 4-3-16 Jonan, Yonezawa, Yamagata 992-8510, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Yan-Cheng</ForeName><Initials>YC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2914-6762</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Engineering, National Cheng Kung University, Tainan 70101, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Research Center for Green Materials Science and Technology, National Taiwan University, Taipei 10617, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Appl Mater Interfaces</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101504991</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1944-8244</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">device stability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electrochemical transistors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">poly(3-hexylthiophene)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">poly(ethylene oxide)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">poly(nbutyl acrylate)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors
declare no competing financial interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39287510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11450721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.4c13197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rivnay J.; Inal S.; Salleo A.; Owens R. M.; Berggren M.; Malliaras G. G. Organic Electrochemical Transistors. Nat. Rev. Mater. 2018, 3 (2), 17086 10.1038/natrevmats.2017.86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/natrevmats.2017.86</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang N.; Yang A.; Fu Y.; Li Y.; Yan F. Functionalized Organic Thin Film Transistors for Biosensing. Acc. Chem. Res. 2019, 52 (2), 277&#x2013;287. 10.1021/acs.accounts.8b00448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.accounts.8b00448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30620566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeglio E.; Ingan&#xe4;s O. Active Materials for Organic Electrochemical Transistors. Adv. Mater. 2018, 30 (44), 1800941 10.1002/adma.201800941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.201800941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30022545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao C.; Zhang M.; Yao M. Y.; Hua T.; Li L.; Yan F. Flexible Organic Electronics in Biology: Materials and Devices. Adv. Mater. 2015, 27 (46), 7493&#x2013;7527. 10.1002/adma.201402625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.201402625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25393596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs I. E.; Lin Y.; Huang Y.; Ren X.; Simatos D.; Chen C.; Tjhe D.; Statz M.; Lai L.; Finn P. A.; Neal W. G.; D&#x2019;Avino G.; Lemaur V.; Fratini S.; Beljonne D.; Strzalka J.; Nielsen C. B.; Barlow S.; Marder S. R.; McCulloch I.; Sirringhaus H. High-Efficiency Ion-Exchange Doping of Conducting Polymers. Adv. Mater. 2022, 34 (22), 2102988 10.1002/adma.202102988.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202102988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34418878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S.; Surendran A.; Wu X.; Lee S. Y.; Stephen M.; Leong W. L. Recent Technological Advances in Fabrication and Application of Organic Electrochemical Transistors. Adv. Mater. Technol. 2020, 5 (12), 2000523 10.1002/admt.202000523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/admt.202000523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y.; Zeglio E.; Wang L.; Cong S.; Zhu G.; Liao H.; Duan J.; Zhou Y.; Li Z.; Mawad D.; Herland A.; Yue W.; McCulloch I. Green Synthesis of Lactone-Based Conjugated Polymers for N-Type Organic Electrochemical Transistors. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2022, 32 (16), 2111439 10.1002/adfm.202111439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202111439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qing X.; Wang Y.; Zhang Y.; Ding X.; Zhong W.; Wang D.; Wang W.; Liu Q.; Liu K.; Li M.; Lu Z. Wearable Fiber-Based Organic Electrochemical Transistors as a Platform for Highly Sensitive Dopamine Monitoring. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2019, 11 (14), 13105&#x2013;13113. 10.1021/acsami.9b00115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.9b00115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30896142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Y.; Feng J. Y.; Shi X.; Yang Y. Q.; Wang J. J.; Sun X.; Li W. J.; Sun X. M.; Peng H. S. Coaxial Fiber Organic Electrochemical Transistor with High Transconductance. Nano Res. 2023, 16 (9), 11885&#x2013;11892. 10.1007/s12274-023-5722-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12274-023-5722-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parlak O.; Keene S. T.; Marais A.; Curto V. F.; Salleo A. Molecularly Selective Nanoporous Membrane-based Wearable Organic Electrochemical Device for Noninvasive Cortisol Sensing. Sci. Adv. 2018, 4 (7), eaar2904 10.1126/sciadv.aar2904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.aar2904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6054510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30035216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khodagholy D.; Doublet T.; Quilichini P.; Gurfinkel M.; Leleux P.; Ghestem A.; Ismailova E.; Herv&#xe9; T.; Sanaur S.; Bernard C.; Malliaras G. G. In Vivo Recordings of Brain Activity Using Organic Transistors. Nat. Commun. 2013, 4 (1), 1575. 10.1038/ncomms2573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms2573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3615373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23481383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H.; Lee S.; Lee W.; Yokota T.; Fukuda K.; Someya T. Ultrathin Organic Electrochemical Transistor with Nonvolatile and Thin Gel Electrolyte for Long-Term Electrophysiological Monitoring. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2019, 29 (48), 1906982 10.1002/adfm.201906982.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.201906982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X.; Tam T. L. D.; Chen S.; Salim T.; Zhao X.; Zhou Z.; Lin M.; Xu J.; Loo Y.-L.; Leong W. L. All-Polymer Bulk-Heterojunction Organic Electrochemical Transistors with Balanced Ionic and Electronic Transport. Adv. Mater. 2022, 34 (42), 2206118 10.1002/adma.202206118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202206118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36008368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin P.; Luo X.; Hsing I. M.; Yan F. Organic Electrochemical Transistors Integrated in Flexible Microfluidic Systems and Used for Label-Free DNA Sensing. Adv. Mater. 2011, 23 (35), 4035&#x2013;4040. 10.1002/adma.201102017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.201102017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21793055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai Y.; Dai S.; Li N.; Li Y.; Moser M.; Strzalka J.; Prominski A.; Liu Y.; Zhang Q.; Li S.; Hu H.; Liu W.; Chatterji S.; Cheng P.; Tian B.; McCulloch I.; Xu J.; Wang S. Stretchable Redox-Active Semiconducting Polymers for High-Performance Organic Electrochemical Transistors. Adv. Mater. 2022, 34 (23), 2201178 10.1002/adma.202201178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202201178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35448913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erhardt A.; Hochgesang A.; McNeill C. R.; Thelakkat M. A Competitive n-Type OECT Material via Copolymerization of Electron Deficient Building Blocks. Adv. Electron. Mater. 2023, 9 (7), 2300026 10.1002/aelm.202300026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aelm.202300026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keene S. T.; Laulainen J. E. M.; Pandya R.; Moser M.; Schnedermann C.; Midgley P. A.; McCulloch I.; Rao A.; Malliaras G. G. Hole-limited electrochemical doping in conjugated polymers. Nat. Mater. 2023, 22 (9), 1121&#x2013;1127. 10.1038/s41563-023-01601-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41563-023-01601-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10465356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37414944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flagg L. Q.; Giridharagopal R.; Guo J.; Ginger D. S. Anion-Dependent Doping and Charge Transport in Organic Electrochemical Transistors. Chem. Mater. 2018, 30 (15), 5380&#x2013;5389. 10.1021/acs.chemmater.8b02220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.chemmater.8b02220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng X.; Sun J.; Jiang J.; Ke S.; Li J.; Lou Z.; Hou Y.; Hu Y.; Teng F. Ion Effects on Salt-in-water Electrolyte Gated Polymer Electrochemical Transistors. Org. Electron. 2023, 120, 106859 10.1016/j.orgel.2023.106859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.orgel.2023.106859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giovannitti A.; Rashid R. B.; Thiburce Q.; Paulsen B. D.; Cendra C.; Thorley K.; Moia D.; Mefford J. T.; Hanifi D.; Weiyuan D.; Moser M.; Salleo A.; Nelson J.; McCulloch I.; Rivnay J. Energetic Control of Redox-Active Polymers toward Safe Organic Bioelectronic Materials. Adv. Mater. 2020, 32 (16), 1908047 10.1002/adma.201908047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.201908047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32125736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giovannitti A.; Nielsen C. B.; Sbircea D.-T.; Inal S.; Donahue M.; Niazi M. R.; Hanifi D. A.; Amassian A.; Malliaras G. G.; Rivnay J.; Moser M.; Salleo A.; Nelson J.; McCulloch I.; Rivnay J. N-type Organic Electrochemical Transistors with Stability in Water. Nat. Commun. 2016, 7 (1), 13066 10.1038/ncomms13066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms13066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5059848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27713414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schafer E. A.; Wu R.; Meli D.; Tropp J.; Moser M.; McCulloch I.; Paulsen B. D.; Rivnay J. Sources and Mechanism of Degradation in P-Type Thiophene-Based Organic Electrochemical Transistors. ACS Appl. Electron. Mater. 2022, 4 (4), 1391&#x2013;1404. 10.1021/acsaelm.1c01171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsaelm.1c01171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moser M.; Hidalgo T. C.; Surgailis J.; Gladisch J.; Ghosh S.; Sheelamanthula R.; Thiburce Q.; Giovannitti A.; Salleo A.; Gasparini N.; Wadsworth A.; Zozoulenko I.; Berggren M.; Stavrinidou E.; Inal S.; McCulloch I. Side Chain Redistribution as a Strategy to Boost Organic Electrochemical Transistor Performance and Stability. Adv. Mater. 2020, 32 (37), 2002748 10.1002/adma.202002748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202002748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32754923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bard A. J.; Faulkner L. R. Fundamentals and Applications. Electrochem. Methods 2001, 2 (482), 580&#x2013;632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y.; Koklu A.; Zhong Y.; Chang T.; Guo K.; Zhao C.; Castillo T. C. H.; Bu Z.; Xiao C.; Yue W.; Ma W.; Inal S. Acceptor Functionalization via Green Chemistry Enables High-Performance N-Type Organic Electrochemical Transistors for Biosensing, Memory Applications. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 34 (15), 2304103 10.1002/adfm.202304103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202304103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flagg L. Q.; Bischak C. G.; Onorato J. W.; Rashid R. B.; Luscombe C. K.; Ginger D. S. Polymer Crystallinity Controls Water Uptake in Glycol Side-Chain Polymer Organic Electrochemical Transistors. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2019, 141 (10), 4345&#x2013;4354. 10.1021/jacs.8b12640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.8b12640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30779568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L.; Wang Z.; Chen J.; Wang B.; Chen Y.; Huang W.; Chi L.; Marks T. J.; Facchetti A. Porous Semiconducting Polymers Enable High-Performance Electrochemical Transistors. Adv. Mater. 2021, 33 (14), 2007041 10.1002/adma.202007041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202007041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33655643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Z.; Khau B.; Dong H.; Takacs C. J.; Yuan S.; Sun M.; Mosevitzky Lis B.; Nguyen D.; Reichmanis E. Carboxyl-Alkyl Functionalized Conjugated Polyelectrolytes for High Performance Organic Electrochemical Transistors. Chem. Mater. 2023, 35 (21), 9299&#x2013;9312. 10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c02103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c02103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10653087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38027548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S.; Ding P.; Ruoko T.-P.; Wu R.; Stoeckel M.-A.; Massetti M.; Liu T.; Vagin M.; Meli D.; Kroon R.; Rivnay J.; Fabiano S. Toward Stable p-Type Thiophene-Based Organic Electrochemical Transistors. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2023, 33 (40), 2302249 10.1002/adfm.202302249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202302249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohayon D.; Flagg L. Q.; Giugni A.; Wustoni S.; Li R.; Hidalgo Castillo T. C.; Emwas A.-H.; Sheelamanthula R.; McCulloch I.; Richter L. J.; Sheelamanthula R.; McCulloch I.; Richter L. J.; Inal S. Salts as Additives: A Route to Improve Performance and Stability of n-Type Organic Electrochemical Transistors. ACS Mater. Au 2023, 3 (3), 242&#x2013;254. 10.1021/acsmaterialsau.2c00072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsmaterialsau.2c00072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10176614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38089129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J.-T.; Takshima S.; Wu H.-C.; Shih C.-C.; Isono T.; Kakuchi T.; Satoh T.; Chen W.-C. Stretchable Conjugated Rod&#x2013;Coil Poly(3-hexylthiophene)-block-poly(butyl acrylate) Thin Films for Field Effect Transistor Applications. Macromolecules 2017, 50 (4), 1442&#x2013;1452. 10.1021/acs.macromol.6b02722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.macromol.6b02722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang W.-C.; Lin Y.-C.; Inagaki S.; Shimizu H.; Ercan E.; Hsu L.-C.; Chueh C.-C.; Higashihara T.; Chen W.-C. Low-Energy-Consumption and Electret-Free Photosynaptic Transistor Utilizing Poly(3-hexylthiophene)-Based Conjugated Block Copolymers. Adv. Sci. 2022, 9 (8), 2105190 10.1002/advs.202105190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/advs.202105190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8922097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35064648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang A.-C.; Mulia T.; Wu Y.-S.; Weng Y.-H.; Lin Y.-C.; Chen W.-C. Recent Developments of Block Copolymers in Nonvolatile Memory and Artificial Synapses. J. Polym. Sci. 2023, 61 (21), 2633&#x2013;2654. 10.1002/pol.20230207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pol.20230207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamps A. C.; Fryd M.; Park S.-J. Hierarchical Self-Assembly of Amphiphilic Semiconducting Polymers into Isolated, Bundled, and Branched Nanofibers. ACS Nano 2012, 6 (3), 2844&#x2013;2852. 10.1021/nn300385p.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/nn300385p</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22381129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H.; Xia H.; Wang G.; Peng J.; Qiu F. Insights into Poly(3-hexylthiophene)-b-poly(ethylene oxide) Block Copolymer: Synthesis and Solvent-induced Structure Formation in Thin Films. J. Polym. Sci., Part A: Polym. Chem. 2012, 50 (24), 5060&#x2013;5067. 10.1002/pola.26353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pola.26353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie W.; Frisbie C. D.
Organic Electrical Double Layer Transistors Based onRubrene
Single Crystals: Examining Transport at High SurfaceCharge Densities
above 1013 cm<sup>&#x2013;2</sup>. J. Phys.
Chem. C
2011, 115 (29), 14360&#x2013;14368. 10.1021/jp204152y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp204152y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulsen B. D.; Frisbie C. D. Dependence of Conductivity on Charge Density and ElectrochemicalPotential in Polymer Semiconductors Gated with Ionic Liquids. J. Phys. Chem. C 2012, 116 (4), 3132&#x2013;3141. 10.1021/jp2093934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp2093934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas E. M.; Brady M. A.; Nakayama H.; Popere B. C.; Segalman R. A.; Chabinyc M. L. X-Ray Scattering Reveals Ion-Induced Microstructural Changes During Electrochemical Gating of Poly(3-Hexylthiophene). Adv. Funct. Mater. 2018, 28 (44), 1803687 10.1002/adfm.201803687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.201803687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterson A. F.; Faber H.; Savva A.; Nikiforidis G.; Gedda M.; Hidalgo T. C.; Chen X.; McCulloch I.; Anthopoulos T. D.; Inal S. On the Role of Contact Resistance and Electrode Modification in Organic Electrochemical Transistors. Adv. Mater. 2019, 31 (37), 1902291 10.1002/adma.201902291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.201902291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31343087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colaneri N.; Nowak M.; Spiegel D.; Hotta S.; Heeger A. J. Bipolarons in Poly(3-methylthiophene): Spectroscopic, Nagnetic, and Electrochemical Measurements. Phys. Rev. B 1987, 36 (15), 7964&#x2013;7968. 10.1103/PhysRevB.36.7964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.36.7964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9942594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guimard N. K.; Gomez N.; Schmidt C. E. Conducting Polymers in Biomedical Engineering. Prog. Polym. Sci. 2007, 32 (8), 876&#x2013;921. 10.1016/j.progpolymsci.2007.05.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.progpolymsci.2007.05.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahi M.; Le V. N.; Alarcon Espejo P.; Alsufyani M.; Kousseff C. J.; McCulloch I.; Paterson A. F. The Organic Electrochemical Transistor Conundrum When Reporting a Mixed Ionic&#x2013;Electronic Transport Figure of Merit. Nat. Mater. 2024, 23 (1), 2&#x2013;8. 10.1038/s41563-023-01672-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41563-023-01672-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37880535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernards D. A.; Malliaras G. G. Steady-State and Transient Behavior of Organic Electrochemical Transistors. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2007, 17 (17), 3538&#x2013;3544. 10.1002/adfm.200601239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.200601239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmood A.; Wang J.-L. A Review of Grazing Incidence Small- and Wide-Angle X-Ray Scattering Techniques for Exploring the Film Morphology of Organic Solar Cells. Sol. RRL 2020, 4 (10), 2000337 10.1002/solr.202000337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/solr.202000337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan J.; Zhu G.; Lan L.; Chen J.; Zhu X.; Chen C.; Yu Y.; Liao H.; Li Z.; McCulloch I.; Yue W. Electron-Deficient Polycyclic Molecules via Ring Fusion for n-Type Organic Electrochemical Transistors. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2023, 62 (1), e202213737 10.1002/anie.202213737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202213737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36349830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boudouris B. W.; Ho V.; Jimison L. H.; Toney M. F.; Salleo A.; Segalman R. A. Real-Time Observation of Poly(3-alkylthiophene) Crystallization and Correlation with Transient Optoelectronic Properties. Macromolecules 2011, 44 (17), 6653&#x2013;6658. 10.1021/ma201316a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ma201316a</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das P.; Zayat B.; Wei Q.; Salamat C. Z.; Magd&#x103;u I.-B.; Elizalde-Segovia R.; Rawlings D.; Lee D.; Pace G.; Irshad A.; Ye L.; Schmitt A.; Segalman R. A.; Miller T. F. III; Tolbert S. H.; Dunn B. S.; Narayan S. R.; Thompson B. C. Dihexyl-Substituted Poly(3,4-Propylenedioxythiophene) as a Dual Ionic and Electronic Conductive Cathode Binder for Lithium-Ion Batteries. Chem. Mater. 2020, 32 (21), 9176&#x2013;9189. 10.1021/acs.chemmater.0c02601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.chemmater.0c02601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>