<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40787357</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-1343</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>30</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS omega</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Omega</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Performance Evaluation and Mechanism Study of a Fluid Loss Additive in a Cement Slurry.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>33008</StartPage><EndPage>33021</EndPage><MedlinePgn>33008-33021</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsomega.5c02208</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>For cementing operations in oil and gas wells to maintain the cement sheath integrity, effective fluid loss management is essential. In order to improve fluid loss management in cement slurries, this study examines the mechanism of action of a new copolymer fluid loss additive (FLA) made of sodium styrenesulfonate (SSS), <i>N</i>-methacrylamide (HAM), and itaconic acid (IA). The performance evaluation results indicate that under conditions of 180 &#xb0;C and saturated brine, the water loss can still be controlled within 70 mL, and the cement exhibits excellent settling stability. After additives were added, the compressive strength of the cement samples in freshwater, semi-saturated brine, and saturated brine systems decreased by 15.9%, 25.3%, and 20.6%, respectively, compared to the control samples. Although there is a certain degree of reduction, these values still meet industry standards and do not affect on-site construction. The mechanism of action of the SSS/HAM/IA copolymer is elucidated through comprehensive testing, including total organic carbon test, zeta potential, environmental scanning electron microscopy test, mercury intrusion porosimetry, and X-ray diffraction analysis. The copolymer's adsorption onto cement particles dynamically alters the zeta potential of the cement slurry system, with the extent of adsorption directly correlating with fluid loss reduction. As the hydration reaction progresses, the copolymer's adsorption on cement particles increases, enhancing the system's stability without altering the composition of the cement hydration products. This study contributes to the development of an advanced FLA, paving the way for more efficient and reliable cementing operations in the oil and gas industry.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Changqing Cementing Company, CNPC Chuanqing Drilling Engineering Co., Ltd., Xian 610051, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">420228</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Qiang</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Changqing Cementing Company, CNPC Chuanqing Drilling Engineering Co., Ltd., Xian 610051, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">420228</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pu</LastName><ForeName>Jian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Changqing Cementing Company, CNPC Chuanqing Drilling Engineering Co., Ltd., Xian 610051, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">420228</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fu</LastName><ForeName>Xiongtao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Changqing Cementing Company, CNPC Chuanqing Drilling Engineering Co., Ltd., Xian 610051, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">420228</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xie</LastName><ForeName>Dongbai</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of New Energy and Materials, Southwest Petroleum University, Chengdu 610500, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">74602</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiao</LastName><ForeName>Weiyuan</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of New Energy and Materials, Southwest Petroleum University, Chengdu 610500, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">74602</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Simeng</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of New Energy and Materials, Southwest Petroleum University, Chengdu 610500, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">74602</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Ming</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3908-3336</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of New Energy and Materials, Southwest Petroleum University, Chengdu 610500, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">74602</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Omega</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101691658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-1343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40787357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12332649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.5c02208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Davoodi S., Al-Shargabi M., Wood D. A., Rukavishnikov V. S., Minaev K. M.. Thermally Stable and Salt-Resistant Synthetic Polymers as Drilling Fluid Additives for Deployment in Harsh Sub-Surface Conditions: A Review. J. Mol. Liq. 2023;371:121117. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2022.121117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2022.121117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Yin H., Zhou S., Liu H., Zhao J., Zhang H.. The Development of Anti-Salt Fluid Loss Additive for Cement-Metakaolin Slurry with Semi-Saturated/Saturated Saline Water: The Application of Maleic Anhydride. Processes. 2024;12(2):360. doi: 10.3390/pr12020360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pr12020360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiaolan L., Zhijun Z., Peng G.. Synthesis and Performance of High Temperature Filter Loss Reducer ZFA-1 for Oil Well Cement Slurries. Drill. Fluid Completion Fluid. 2020;37(2):209&#x2013;213. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1001-5620.2020.02.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1001-5620.2020.02.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M., Xiao W., Zhang H., Yu Y., Liu Z., Xie D.. An Effective Salt-Tolerant Fluid Loss Additive-Suitable for High Temperature Oil Well Cement. J. Dispers. Sci. Technol. 2021;42(5):730&#x2013;741. doi: 10.1080/01932691.2019.1709494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01932691.2019.1709494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y., Zhang H., Xia X., Li P., Jin J., Hu M., Guo J.. Synthesis and Study of an Ultra-High Temperature Filtrate Reducer for Cement Slurries. Drill. Fluid Completion Fluid. 2022;39(3):352&#x2013;358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekizkardes B., Su E., Okay O.. Mechanically Strong Superabsorbent Terpolymer Hydrogels Based on AMPS via Hydrogen-Bonding Interactions. ACS Appl. Polym. Mater. 2023;5(3):2043&#x2013;2050. doi: 10.1021/acsapm.2c02085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsapm.2c02085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Zhang Y., Wang H.. Zwitterionic copolymers as high-temperature fluid loss additives for oil well cementing. J. Pet. Sci. Eng. 2020;185:106634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., Chen J., Liu Y.. Synthesis and performance evaluation of a novel terpolymer fluid loss additive for oil well cementing. Polym. Eng. Sci. 2021;61(3):789&#x2013;798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Li Z., Zhang Q.. Electrostatic interactions between fluid loss additives and cement particles in oil well cementing. Cem. Concr. Res. 2019;120:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Zhang W., Li M.. Impact of fluid loss additives on the microstructure and mechanical properties of oil well cement. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;280:122512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li P., Xu Y., Hu M., Chen D., Yu Y., Zhang H., Xia X., Guo J.. Influence of Carboxyl Group on Filtration Property of Oil Well Cement Paste at Different Temperatures Investigated Using Molecular Dynamics Simulation. J. Mol. Liq. 2020;306:112943. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2020.112943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2020.112943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plank J., Brandl A., Lummer N. R.. Effect of different anchor groups on adsorption behavior and effectiveness of poly&#xad;(N,N-dimethylacrylamide-co-Ca 2-acrylamido-2-methylpropanesulfonate) as cement fluid loss additive in presence of acetone-formaldehyde-sulfite dispersant. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 2007;106:3889&#x2013;3894. doi: 10.1002/app.26897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/app.26897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plank J., Brandl A., Lummer N. R.. Effect of Different Anchor Groups on Adsorption Behavior and Effectiveness of Poly&#xad;(N,N-dimethylacrylamide-co-Ca 2-acrylamido-2- methylpropanesulfonate) as Cement Fluid Loss Additive in Presence of Acetone&#x2013;Formaldehyde&#x2013;Sulfite Dispersant. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 2007;106:3889&#x2013;3894. doi: 10.1002/app.26897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/app.26897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plank J., Dugonji&#x107;-Bili&#x107; F., Lummer N. R.. Modification of the Molar Anionic Charge Density of Acetone&#x2013;Formaldehyde&#x2013;Sulfite Dispersant to Improve Adsorption Behavior and Effectiveness in the Presence of CaAMPS&#xae;-co-NNDMA Cement Fluid Loss Polymer. J. Of Applied Polymer Sci. 2009;111:2018&#x2013;2024. doi: 10.1002/app.29261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/app.29261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li P., Lu H., Hu M., Yu Y., Liu M., Xia X., Cao J., Cheng Y., Guo J.. Performance Comparison and Adsorption Mechanism Analysis of Polyanionic and Zwitterionic Copolymer Fluid Loss Additives for Oil-Well Cement Paste: An Experimental and Computational Study. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;415:134955. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.134955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.134955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou P., Li M., Zhang C., Xia X., Yu Y., Qi F., Wu Y.. Ultra-High Temperature Suspending Stabilizer and Cement Slurry Interface Interaction Law and Mechanism Study for Ultra-Deep Well Cementing. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;409:133979. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Jiang G., Shen X., Li G.. Application of Tea Polyphenols as a Biodegradable Fluid Loss Additive and Study of the Filtration Mechanism. ACS Omega. 2020;5(7):3453&#x2013;3461. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.9b03712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.9b03712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7045546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32118159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J., Pang S., Zhang Z., Xia B., An Y.. Experimental Study on the Polymer/Graphene Oxide Composite as a Fluid Loss Agent for Water-Based Drilling Fluids. ACS Omega. 2021;6(14):9750&#x2013;9763. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.1c00374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.1c00374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8047695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33869955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu W., Zheng X.. Effective Modified Xanthan Gum Fluid Loss Agent for High-Temperature Water-Based Drilling Fluid and the Filtration Control Mechanism. ACS Omega. 2021;6(37):23788&#x2013;23801. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.1c02617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.1c02617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8459350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34568659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong Y., Wang P., Liu S., Gao Z., Rao M.. Effect of microwave curing on the hydration properties of cement-based material containing glass powder. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;158:563&#x2013;573. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.10.058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.10.058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong B., Liu C., Shumuye E., Zhang Y., Zhong H., Fang G.. Effect of nano-silica on mechanical properties and microstructure of engineered geopolymer composites. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2025;156:105849. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2024.105849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2024.105849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Shen N., Zhang M., Fu F., Qian K.. Bond performance of Steel-CFRP bar reinforced coral concrete beams. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;245:118456. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purswani P., Karpyn Z. T., Enab K., Xue Y., Huang X.. Evaluation of image segmentation techniques for image-based rock property estimation. J. Pet. Sci. Eng. 2020;195:107890. doi: 10.1016/j.petrol.2020.107890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2020.107890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Gamal S. M. A., Hashem F. S., Amin M. S.. Influence of carbon nanotubes, nanosilica and nanometakaolin on some morphological-mechanical properties of oil well cement pastes subjected to elevated water curing temperature and regular room air curing temperature. Constr. Build. Mater. 2017;146:531&#x2013;546. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.04.124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.04.124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Y., Li X., Shao Y., Du M.. Application of Hybrid Polymer Containing POSS as High-Temperature- and High-Salt-Resistant Fluid Loss Additive in Water-Based Drilling Fluids. Energy Fuels. 2024;38(11):10019&#x2013;10031. doi: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tripathi B.. Effects of Polymers on Cement Hydration and Properties of Concrete: A Review. ACS Omega. 2024;9(2):2014&#x2013;2021. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.3c05914.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.3c05914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10795056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38250407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B., Gong S., Shi C., Hao P., Cheng Y., Li B., Li D.. Study on Preparation and Mechanism of High Temperature and High Salt Resistance Fluid Loss Reducer. ACS Omega. 2025;10(7):7172&#x2013;7180. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.4c10623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.4c10623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11866008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40028118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>