<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39729107</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-1041</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>81</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European journal of clinical pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Clin Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors and contrast-induced nephropathy risk: a meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>337</StartPage><EndPage>345</EndPage><MedlinePgn>337-345</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00228-024-03799-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Contrast-induced nephropathy (CIN) is an adverse renal event that occurs following the administration of contrast media for diagnostic procedures or therapeutic angiographic intervention. Nevertheless, there is currently no efficacious and safe agents for the treatment of CIN, except for hydration. We aimed to conduct a meta-analysis to verify the potential nephroprotective role of sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors (SGLT2is) in the prevention of CIN.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The PubMed, Web of Science, and China National Knowledge Infrastructure (CNKI) databases were searched from their respective inception dates up until 26 August 2024. The "Meta" package of R and Stata software was used for data analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 12 studies were included in the analysis, comprising 11 single-center retrospective studies and one prospective cohort study. Our meta-analysis determined that SGLT2is significantly decrease CIN (odds ratio (OR) 0.39, 95% confidence interval (CI) (0.31, 0.48), P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.0001, I<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0%) and mortality (OR 0.45, 95% CI (0.26, 0.77), P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.0039, I<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;48%). No notable discrepancy was discerned in continuous renal replacement therapy (CRRT) (OR 0.53, 95% CI (0.15, 1.91), I<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0%) or contrast volume (MD&#x2009;-&#x2009;9.68, 95% CI (-&#x2009;19.38, 0.03), I<sup>2</sup>&#x2009;=&#x2009;71%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The present study demonstrated that SGLT2is markedly reduce the incidence of contrast-induced nephropathy in diabetic patients. It is recommended that future large-scale randomized controlled trials (RCTs) are required to confirm these findings and to elucidate further the outcomes in patients without diabetes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Gang</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology Department of Xianyang Central Hospital, Xianyang, Shaanxi Province, 712000, People's Republic of China. nfgcardiology@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shaanxi University of Chinese Medicine, Xianyang, Shaanxi Province, 712046, People's Republic of China. nfgcardiology@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Hospital of the Second Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University, Xi'an, Shaanxi Province, 710016, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zuo</LastName><ForeName>Hong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology Department of Xianyang Central Hospital, Xianyang, Shaanxi Province, 712000, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Rui</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology Department of Beijing Luhe Hospital of Capital Medical University, Beijing, 101149, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Chao</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology Department of Yangling Demonstration District Hospital, Xianyang, Shaanxi Province, 712100, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Eur J Clin Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>1256165</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0031-6970</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003287">Contrast Media</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000077203">Sodium-Glucose Transporter 2 Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003287" MajorTopicYN="Y">Contrast Media</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077203" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sodium-Glucose Transporter 2 Inhibitors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058186" MajorTopicYN="Y">Acute Kidney Injury</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000139" MajorTopicYN="N">chemically induced</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007674" MajorTopicYN="Y">Kidney Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000139" MajorTopicYN="N">chemically induced</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Contrast-induced nephropathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Renal function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39729107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00228-024-03799-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00228-024-03799-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Martin SS, Aday AW, Almarzooq ZI, Anderson CAM, Arora P, Avery CL et al (2024) 2024 heart disease and stroke statistics: a report of US and global data from the American Heart Association. Circulation 149:e347&#x2013;e913</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000001209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38264914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mensah GA, Fuster V, Murray CJL, Roth GA, Global Burden of Cardiovascular D, Risks C (2023) Global burden of cardiovascular diseases and risks, 1990&#x2013;2022. J Am Coll Cardiol 82:2350&#x2013;473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faro DC, Laudani C, Agnello FG, Ammirabile N, Finocchiaro S, Legnazzi M et al (2023) Complete percutaneous coronary revascularization in acute coronary syndromes with multivessel coronary disease: a systematic review. JACC Cardiovasc Interv 16:2347&#x2013;2364</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcin.2023.07.043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37821180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kusirisin P, Chattipakorn SC, Chattipakorn N (2020) Contrast-induced nephropathy and oxidative stress: mechanistic insights for better interventional approaches. J Transl Med 18:400</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-020-02574-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33081797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7576747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Writing Committee M, Lawton JS, Tamis-Holland JE, Bangalore S, Bates ER, Beckie TM et al (2022) 2021 ACC/AHA/SCAI guideline for coronary artery revascularization: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines. J Am Coll Cardiol 79:e21&#x2013;e129</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2021.09.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zannad F, Ferreira JP, Pocock SJ, Anker SD, Butler J, Filippatos G et al (2020) SGLT2 inhibitors in patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction: a meta-analysis of the EMPEROR-Reduced and DAPA-HF trials. Lancet 396:819&#x2013;829</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31824-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32877652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho PEP, Veiga TMA, Simoes ESAC, Gewehr DM, Dagostin CS, Fernandes A et al (2023) Cardiovascular and renal effects of SGLT2 inhibitor initiation in acute heart failure: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Clin Res Cardiol 112:1044&#x2013;1055</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00392-022-02148-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36592186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao H, Liu T, Wang L, Ji Q (2022) Comparative efficacy of novel antidiabetic drugs on cardiovascular and renal outcomes in patients with diabetic kidney disease: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Diabetes Obes Metab 24:1448&#x2013;1457</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dom.14702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35665989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9541855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricco AC, Lillie E, Zarin W, O&#x2019;Brien KK, Colquhoun H, Levac D et al (2018) PRISMA Extension for Scoping Reviews (PRISMA-ScR): checklist and explanation. Ann Intern Med 169:467&#x2013;473</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M18-0850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stang A (2010) Critical evaluation of the Newcastle-Ottawa scale for the assessment of the quality of nonrandomized studies in meta-analyses. Eur J Epidemiol 25:603&#x2013;605</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10654-010-9491-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20652370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feitosa MPM, Lima EG, Abizaid AAC, Mehran R, Lopes NHM, De Assis Fischer Ramos T et al (2023) The safety of SGLT-2 inhibitors in diabetic patients submitted to elective percutaneous coronary intervention regarding kidney function: SAFE-PCI pilot study. Diabetol Metab Syndr 15:138</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13098-023-01107-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37365618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10291785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Shicheng ZP, Cong Hongliang Fu, Naikuan, (2024) Impact of dapagliflozin on incidence of contrast-induced nephropathy and cardiovascular prognosis in elderly T2DM patients after PCI. Chin J Geriatr Heart Brain Vessel Di 26:5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Can BL, Yang X (2023) Effect of dapagliflozin on renal function and contrast-induced nephropathy in patients with coronary heart disease complicated with type 2 diabetes mellitus after PCI. Pract J Cardiac Cereb Pneum Vasc Dis 31:4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dingguo RLZ (2023) The prevention of contrast-induced nephropathy in coronary heart disease complicated by type-2 diabetes mellitus by dapagliflozin following interventional therapy. J Med Res Combat Trauma Care 36:5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua R, Ding N, Guo H, Wu Y, Yuan Z, Li T (2022) Contrast-induced acute kidney injury in patients on SGLT2 inhibitors undergoing percutaneous coronary interventions: a propensity-matched analysis. Front Cardiovasc Med 9:918167</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2022.918167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35795364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9251334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nardi G, Marchi E, Allinovi M, Lugli G, Biagiotti L, Di Muro FM et al (2024) Contrast-induced acute kidney injury in patients with heart failure on sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitors undergoing radiocontrast agent invasive procedures: a propensity-matched analysis. J Clin Med 13(7):2041</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm13072041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38610806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11012317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paolisso P, Bergamaschi L, Gragnano F, Gallinoro E, Cesaro A, Sardu C et al (2023) Outcomes in diabetic patients treated with SGLT2-Inhibitors with acute myocardial infarction undergoing PCI: the SGLT2-I AMI PROTECT Registry. Pharmacol Res 187:106597</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phrs.2022.106597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36470546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabuk G, Hazir KE (2024) Do sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors decrease the risk of contrast-associated acute kidney injury in patients with type II diabetes mellitus? Anatol J Cardiol 28:222&#x2013;228</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14744/AnatolJCardiol.2024.3980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38506315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11059220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kultursay B, Yilmaz C, Guven B, Mutlu D, Karagoz A (2024) Potential renoprotective effect of SGLT2 inhibitors against contrast-induced AKI in diabetic STEMI patients undergoing primary PCI. Kardiol Pol 82:29&#x2013;36</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33963/v.kp.98260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38230461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozkan U, Gurdogan M (2023) The effect of SGLT2 inhibitors on the development of contrast-induced nephropathy in diabetic patients with non-ST segment elevation myocardial infarction. Medicina (Kaunas) 59:3&#x2013;505</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos-Gallego CG, Palamara G, Requena-Ibanez JA, Vargas AP, Mohebi R, Abascal V, Moreno P, Badimon JJ (2020) Pretreatment with Sglt2 inhibitors ameliorates contrast-induced nephropathy. J Am College Cardiol 75:11&#x2013;1405</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0735-1097(20)32032-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T, Jian X, Li L, Chu S, Fan Z (2023) The association between dapagliflozin use and the risk of post-contrast acute kidney injury in patients with type 2 diabetes and chronic kidney disease: a propensity-matched analysis. Kidney Blood Press Res 48:752&#x2013;760</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000535208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37980899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catala-Lopez F, Macias Saint-Gerons D, Gonzalez-Bermejo D, Rosano GM, Davis BR, Ridao M et al (2016) Cardiovascular and renal outcomes of renin-angiotensin system blockade in adult patients with diabetes mellitus: a systematic review with network meta-analyses. PLoS Med 13:e1001971</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1001971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26954482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4783064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang H, Chen H, Li Z, Xu S, Yan G, Tang C et al (2022) Association between uric acid level and contrast-induced acute kidney injury in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus after coronary angiography: a retrospective cohort study. BMC Nephrol 23:399</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12882-022-03030-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36510177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9746209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X, Guo X, Yan G, Zhang Y, Yao Y, Qiao Y et al (2022) Dapagliflozin attenuates contrast-induced acute kidney injury by regulating the HIF-1alpha/HE4/NF-kappaB pathway. J Cardiovasc Pharmacol 79:904&#x2013;913</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/FJC.0000000000001268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35383661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9162274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyata KN, Lo CS, Zhao S, Zhao XP, Chenier I, Yamashita M et al (2021) Deletion of heterogeneous nuclear ribonucleoprotein F in renal tubules downregulates SGLT2 expression and attenuates hyperfiltration and kidney injury in a mouse model of diabetes. Diabetologia 64:2589&#x2013;2601</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-021-05538-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34370045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8992778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuo M, Paik JM, Wexler DJ, Bonventre JV, Kim SC, Patorno E (2022) SGLT2 inhibitors and the risk of acute kidney injury in older adults with type 2 diabetes. Am J Kidney Dis 79:858&#x2013;67 e1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2021.09.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34762974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuen BL, Young T, Heerspink HJL, Neal B, Perkovic V, Billot L et al (2019) SGLT2 inhibitors for the prevention of kidney failure in patients with type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol 7:845&#x2013;854</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-8587(19)30256-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31495651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernardini FNA, Giannone S, Mangiacapra F, Melfi R, Ricottini E,&#xa0;Ussia GP,&#xa0;Grigioni F (2022) Role of new antidiabetic drugs in the prevention of contrast induced nephropathy in diabetic patients undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention. Eur Heart J Suppl 24:k179</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee HC, Sheu SH, Yen HW, Lai WT, Chang JG (2010) JNK/ATF2 pathway is involved in iodinated contrast media-induced apoptosis. Am J Nephrol 31:125&#x2013;133</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000259899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19923798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu GL, Lei R, Duan SB, Tang MM, Luo M, Xu Q (2017) Atorvastatin alleviates iodinated contrast media-induced cytotoxicity in human proximal renal tubular epithelial cells. Exp Ther Med 14:3309&#x2013;3313</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/etm.2017.4859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28912882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5585761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Tai S, Zhang N, Fu L, Wang Y (2023) Dapagliflozin prevents oxidative stress-induced endothelial dysfunction via sirtuin 1 activation. Biomed Pharmacother 165:115213</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2023.115213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37517289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopaschuk GD, Verma S (2020) Mechanisms of cardiovascular benefits of sodium glucose co-transporter 2 (SGLT2) inhibitors: a state-of-the-art review. JACC Basic Transl Sci 5:632&#x2013;644</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacbts.2020.02.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32613148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7315190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dabravolski SA, Zhuravlev AD, Kartuesov AG, Borisov EE, Sukhorukov VN, Orekhov AN (2022) Mitochondria-mediated cardiovascular benefits of sodium-glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitors. Int J Mol Sci. 23(10):5371</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23105371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35628174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9140946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>