<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">40839199</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1434-9949</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>44</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical rheumatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Rheumatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Questionnaire on willingness and preference for biological treatment of knee osteoarthritis: a single-center cross-sectional survey.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4301</StartPage><EndPage>4314</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4301-4314</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10067-025-07630-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Understand the willingness and preference of patients with knee osteoarthritis for biological treatment, and the current status of knee osteoarthritis treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">KOA patients with grades 1-4 Kellgren-Ray (K-L) in the knee of our imaging department from November 1, 2022, solstice May 1, 2023, were included in this single-center cross-sectional survey. The questionnaire was designed through the online questionnaire platform, and 502 questionnaires were completed, of which 393 were eligible for this study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">(1) Basic information: 66.67% (262/393), female, male 33.33% (131/393), male: 1:2; patients aged 45-69&#xa0;years 89.06% (350/393); 28.50% (112/393); first degree relatives' osteoarthritis 6.87% (27/393); hyperlipidemia 10.94% (43/393); hypertension 30.79% (121/393); diabetes 9.16% (36/393). (2) Disease assessment: the patients had a significant negative relationship between Lysholm score and WOMAC score, with a correlation coefficient of&#x2009;-&#x2009;0.632, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01. Using the Kruskal-Wallis test statistic, the Lysholm score showed different K-L grade samples for the WOMAC score (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01). (3) Classical treatment: 84.99% of the subjects had no attempted basic treatment for osteoarthritis. 94.40% had not tried 4 exercise therapies for osteoarthritis. 96.95% had not attempted physical therapy for osteoarthritis. 98.73% did not try exercise aids for osteoarthritis. 67.94% had not tried TCM treatment for osteoarthritis, accounting for 18.58%, two accounted for 10.69%, three accounted for 2.04%, and four accounted for 0.76%. 77.35% did not try nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs for osteoarthritis, 16.03%, 6.36%, and six 0.25%. 87.02% had not tried non-class NSAIDs analgesic drugs for osteoarthritis, using weak opioid analgesics 10.69% and strong opioid analgesics 2.29%. 95.93% denied previous use of glucocorticoids for osteoarthritis, 16 but not consistently. 85.75% had not tried using slow-acting drugs (SYSADOAs) to relieve OA symptoms, 11.45% and 2.80%, respectively. 99.24% denied taking antidepressant anxiety medication for osteoarthritis. 92.37% denied attempted knee cavity injection (sodium hyaluronate, glucocorticoids), 25 had sodium hyaluronate injection in the joint cavity, 6.36%, and 5 had glucocorticoid injection, 1.27%. (4) Biological therapy situation: 96.44% did not know the biological therapy of the knee cavity for osteoarthritis. 96.69% were not recommended for knee cavity biological treatment, 13 people were recommended, accounting for 3.31%, of which 11 were recommended by doctors, accounting for 84.62% (11/13), and relatives recommended for 15.38% (11/13). In the Likert5 scoring method of joint cavity biological treatment, 10 people in this study were very reluctant, accounting for 2.54%; 37 preferred unwilling, accounting for 9.41%; 264, average, accounting for 67.18%; 40 preferred, accounting for 10.18%; 42, very willing, accounting for 10.69%. The stepwise regression analysis of the factors affecting the willingness to treat joint cavity biotherapy, the previous treatment with sodium hyaluronate or corticosteroid knee cavity injection, WOMAC score will have a significant positive effect on the willingness score of joint cavity biotherapy. In addition, age had a significant negative effect on the willingness to treat the joint cavity. (5) The analysis was performed by MaxDiff: efficacy, course of treatment, side effects, medical expenses, and administration pathways (oral, external use, and intra-articular injection), subject preference for choosing a joint cavity biotherapy. The preferred shares are, respectively. Efficacy&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;side effect&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;medical expenses&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;course of treatment&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;administration pathways, 69.42%&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;15.85%&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;6.39%&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;4.93%&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;3.41%.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In this study, KOA subjects, most had not received osteoarthritis-related standard treatment, and the proportion of TCM treatment was relatively high.&#xa0;The low&#xa0;awareness rate of knee biological therapy, the joint cavity injection treatment, high&#xa0;WOMAC score, and age have an impact on the treatment intention of biologics.&#xa0;Efficacy is the most important factor in patient preference for KOA treatment. Key Points &#x2022; The low awareness rate of knee biological therapy, the joint cavity injection treatment, high WOMAC score, and age have an impact on the treatment intention of biologics. &#x2022; Efficacy is the most important factor in patient preference for KOA treatment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to International League of Associations for Rheumatology (ILAR).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Feng</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2821-1171</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatology and Immunology Department, Heping Hospital Affiliated to Changzhi Medical College, Shanxi Province, No. 110, Yan'an Nan Lu, Changzhi City, 046000, China. wangfengwf10@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Rheumatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8211469</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0770-3198</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001688">Biological Products</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020370" MajorTopicYN="Y">Osteoarthritis, Knee</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057240" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patient Preference</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010342" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patient Acceptance of Health Care</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001688" MajorTopicYN="Y">Biological Products</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-sectional</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Knee osteoarthritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MaxDiff</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patient preference</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Questionnaire</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment willingness</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical approval for this study was obtained from the Affiliated Peace Hospital of Changzhi Medical College (No. (2023) 009). Consent for publication: Not applicable. Disclosures: None. Conflict of interest: The authors report no conflicts of interest in this work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40839199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10067-025-07630-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10067-025-07630-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Li W, Xiao Z, Liu J, Feng J, Zhu D, Liao J, Yu W, Qian B, Chen X, Fang Y, Li S (2023) Deep learning-assisted knee osteoarthritis automatic grading on plain radiographs: the value of multiview X-ray images and prior knowledge. Quant Imaging Med Surg 13(6):3587&#x2013;3601</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/qims-22-1250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37284121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10239991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang G, Wang J, Liu Y, Lu H, He L, Ma C, Zhao Z (2023) Burden of knee osteoarthritis in 204 countries and territories, 1990&#x2013;2019: results from the global burden of disease study 2019. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). https://doi.org/10.1002/acr.25158</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.25158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37849415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Migliorini F, Maffulli N, Pipino G, Jeyaraman M, Ramasubramanian S, Jeyaraman N (2025) Intra-articular injections of hyaluronic acid versus plasma rich in growth factors (PRGF) for knee osteoarthritis: a meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials: a meta-analysis. Intraartikul&#xe4;re Injektionen von Hyalurons&#xe4;ure im Vergleich zu plasmareichen Wachstumsfaktoren (PRGF) bei Kniearthrose: eine Metaanalyse von randomisierten kontrollierten Studien: Eine Metaanalyse. Orthopadie (Heidelb). 54(3):218&#x2013;226</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A, Maffulli N (2025) Undenatured type II collagen for knee osteoarthritis. Ann Med 57(1):2493306</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07853890.2025.2493306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40253594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12010644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stothers Rosenberg S, Ng X, Mansfield C et al (2023) Adaptation of the WOMAC for use in a patient preference study. Ther Innov Regul Sci 57(4):702&#x2013;711</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43441-023-00510-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37061632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chahla J, Mandelbaum BR (2018) Biological treatment for osteoarthritis of the knee: moving from bench to bedside-current practical concepts. Arthroscopy 34(5):1719&#x2013;1729</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arthro.2018.01.048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29628381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang S, Lee K, Ju JH (2021) Recent updates of diagnosis, pathophysiology, and treatment on osteoarthritis of the knee. Int J Mol Sci 22(5):2619</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms22052619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33807695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7961389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saraf A, Hussain A, Bishnoi S, Habib H, Garg A (2023) Serial intraarticular injections of growth factor concentrate in knee osteoarthritis: a placebo controlled randomized study. J Orthop 37:46&#x2013;52</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jor.2023.02.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36974096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10039117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Y, Lei G (2023) Annual progress in biotherapy of osteoarthritis 2022. Chinese Med J 103(16):1247&#x2013;1252</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joint Surgery Group, Bone Science Branch of Chinese Medical Association (2018) Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of osteoarthritis (2018 edition). Chinese Journal of Orthopaedics 38(12):705&#x2013;715</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou G, Zhao M, Wang X, Geng X, Tian H (2023) Demographic and radiographic factors for knee symptoms and range of motion in patients with knee osteoarthritis: a cross-sectional study in Beijing, China. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 24(1):378</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-023-06432-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37173724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10176682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The SPSSAU project (2023) SPSSAU. (Version 23.0) [Online Application Software]. Retrieved from https://www.spssau.com . Accessed 13 Jun 2023</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hauke J, Kossowski T (2011) Comparison of values of Pearson&#x2019;s and Spearman&#x2019;s correlation coefficients on the same sets of data. Quaest Geogr 30(2):87&#x2013;93</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arndt S, Turvey C, Andreasen NC (1999) Correlating and predicting psychiatric symptom ratings: spearmans r versus kendalls tau correlation. J Psychiatr Res 33(2):97&#x2013;104</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-3956(98)90046-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10221741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Xu J (2009) Modern psychology and educational statistics. Beijing: Beijing Normal University Press p 506</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voshaar MJH, Vriezekolk JE, van Dulmen AM, van den Bemt BJF, van de Laar MAFJ (2021) Ranking facilitators and barriers of medication adherence by patients with inflammatory arthritis: a maximum difference scaling exercise. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 22(1):21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-020-03874-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33407344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7786955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verhoef LM, Selten EMH, Vriezekolk JE, de Jong AJL, van den Hoogen FHJ, den Broeder AA, Hulscher ME (2018) The patient perspective on biologic DMARD dose reduction in rheumatoid arthritis: a mixed methods study. Rheumatology (Oxford) 57(11):1947&#x2013;1955</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/key205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30010899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theodorssonnorheim E (1986) Kruskal-wallis test: BASIC computer program to perform nonparametric one-way analysis of variance and multiple comparisons on ranks of several independent samples. Comput Methods Programs Biomed 23(1):57&#x2013;62</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0169-2607(86)90081-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3638187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dao-de S (2000) Selection of the linear regression model according to the parameter estimation. Wuhan Univ J Nat Sci 5(4):400&#x2013;405</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02850764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cameron AC, Trivedi PK (2005) Microeconometrics: methods and applications[M]. Cambridge University Press</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green WH (1998) Econometric analysis. China Social Sciences Press, Beijing</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kan HS, Chan PK, Chiu KY, Yan CH, Yeung SS, Ng YL, Shiu KW, Ho T (2019) Non-surgical treatment of knee osteoarthritis. Hong Kong Med J 25(2):127&#x2013;133</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30919810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Z, Wang G, Li C, Qian D, Zhang J, Li D, Yan L, Xing D, Wang B (2022) Interpretation and evaluation of the Guidelines for the Diagnosis and Treatment of Osteoarthritis in China (2021 edition). Chin J Evid-Based Med 22(06):621&#x2013;627</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang Z, Wanyan P, Zhang B, Wang M, Wang X (2023) A systematic review, umbrella review, and quality assessment on clinical translation of stem cell therapy for knee osteoarthritis: are we there yet? Stem Cell Res Ther 14(1):91</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13287-023-03332-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37061744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10105961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chuang CH, Kuo CC, Chiang YF, Lee PY, Wang FH, Hsieh CY, Shen CI, Chung YH, Lee KD, Wu SF, Su HL, Lin CL (2023) Enriched peripheral blood-derived mononuclear cells for treating knee osteoarthritis. Cell Transplant 32:9636897221149445</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/09636897221149445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36661223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu H, Zhou L, Wang Q, Cai Q, Yang F, Jin H, Chen Y, Song Y, Zhang C (2023) Glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists as a disease-modifying therapy for knee osteoarthritis mediated by weight loss: findings from the Shanghai Osteoarthritis Cohort. Ann Rheum Dis. https://doi.org/10.1136/ard-2023-223845</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ard-2023-223845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37595989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kloppenburg M, Berenbaum F (2020) Osteoarthritis year in review 2019: epidemiology and therapy. Osteoarthritis Cartilage 28(3):242&#x2013;248</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joca.2020.01.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31945457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roemer FW, Kraines J, Aydemir A, Wax S, Hochberg MC, Crema MD, Guermazi A (2020) Evaluating the structural effects of intra-articular sprifermin on cartilage and non-cartilaginous tissue alterations, based on sqMRI assessment over 2 years. Osteoarthr Cartilage 28(9):1229&#x2013;1234</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joca.2020.05.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazici Y, McAlindon TE, Gibofsky A, Lane NE, Lattermann C, Skrepnik N, Swearingen CJ, Simsek I, Ghandehari H, DiFrancesco A, Gibbs J, Tambiah JRS, Hochberg MC (2021) A phase 2b randomized trial of lorecivivint, a novel intra-articular CLK2/DYRK1A inhibitor and Wnt pathway modulator for knee osteoarthritis. Osteoarthr Cartilage 29(5):654&#x2013;666</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joca.2021.02.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G, Liu S, Chen Y, Xu H, Qi T, Xiong A, Wang D, Yu F, Weng J, Zeng H (2022) Teriparatide ameliorates articular cartilage degradation and aberrant subchondral bone remodeling in DMM mice. J Orthop Translat 38:241&#x2013;255</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jot.2022.10.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36514714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9731868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuire D, Bowes M, Brett A, Segal NA, Miller M, Rosen D, Kumagai Y (2021) Study TPX-100-5: intra-articular TPX-100 significantly delays pathological bone shape change and stabilizes cartilage in moderate to severe bilateral knee OA. Arthritis Res Ther 23(1):242</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13075-021-02622-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34535197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8447757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Merchan EC (2023) The current role of disease-modifying osteoarthritis drugs. Arch Bone Jt Surg 11(1):11&#x2013;22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36793668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9903308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Posnett J, Dixit S, Oppenheimer B, Kili S, Mehin N (2015) Patient preference and willingness to pay for knee osteoarthritis treatments. Patient Prefer Adherence 9:733&#x2013;744</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26089650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4468999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf6;k&#xe7;e Kutsal Y, Eyig&#xf6;r S, Karahan S, G&#xfc;nayd&#x131;n R, &#x130;rdesel J, Sar&#x131;do&#x11f;an M, Borman P, Sar&#x131; A, Ordu G&#xf6;kkaya K, Binay SV (2021) Incorporating patient preferences into osteoarthritis treatment. Arch Rheumatol 36(4):577&#x2013;586</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35382376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8957764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Omari B, McMeekin P (2020) Patients&#x2019; preferences regarding osteoarthritis medications: an adaptive choice-based conjoint analysis study. Patient Prefer Adherence 14:2501&#x2013;2515</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/PPA.S283922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33376311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7765685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conrozier T, Renevier JL, Parisaux JM, Balblanc JC (2019) Predictive factors of adherence to an association of glucosamine sulfate, copper, and ginger extracts in patients with symptomatic osteoarthritis: a prospective open-label French noninterventional study (the PREDOA study). Patient Prefer Adherence 13:915&#x2013;921</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/PPA.S200892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31239649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6559715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McArthur BA, Dy CJ, Fabricant PD, Valle AG (2012) Long term safety, efficacy, and patient acceptability of hyaluronic acid injection in patients with painful osteoarthritis of the knee. Patient Prefer Adherence 6:905&#x2013;910</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23271899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3526887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moorman CT, Kirwan T, Share J, Vannabouathong C (2017) Patient preferences regarding surgical interventions for knee osteoarthritis. Clin Med Insights Arthritis Musculoskelet Disord. https://doi.org/10.1177/1179544117732039</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1179544117732039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28974919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5613842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>