<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41170278</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Management of Diabetic Kidney Disease With Persistent Hypotension: A Case of Lifestyle-Driven Renal Recovery.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e93484</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e93484</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e93484</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.93484</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Diabetic kidney disease (DKD) is typically accompanied by hypertension, which enables guideline-directed renoprotective therapy. We describe a 61-year-old woman with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) and persistent hypotension (&#x2248;92/55-98/65 mmHg) without albuminuria, in whom angiotensin-converting enzyme (ACE) inhibitors/angiotensin receptor blockers (ARBs) and sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 (SGLT2) inhibitors were deemed unsafe due to baseline low blood pressure. Management, therefore, emphasized non-pharmacologic measures, tight glycemic control, weight reduction (~10 lb), hydration, and avoidance of nephrotoxins in a resource-limited setting. Renal function improved from an eGFR of 55 mL/min/1.73 m&#xb2; (2023) to 69 (2024) and stabilized at 67.2 (2025) with HbA1c 6.3-6.6% and continued lack of albuminuria; neurologic and ophthalmic diabetic manifestations remained stable. This case illustrates a guideline gap: when persistent hypotension and absent albuminuria preclude standard agents, individualized metabolic and lifestyle strategies may achieve renal stabilization. Although causality cannot be inferred, the temporal association between improved weight/glycemia and estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) recovery suggests a pragmatic pathway for hypotensive T2DM patients outside conventional algorithms.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Song et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Sungmin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Trinity School of Medicine, Warner Robins, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Obioha</LastName><ForeName>Okoro</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Medicine, Central Georgia Pediatrics, Macon, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Yoobin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Trinity School of Medicine, Warner Robins, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic kidney disease&#xa0;(ckd)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">complication of type-2 diabetes mellitus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypotension treatment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">types 2 diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">underdeveloped community</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Not applicable &#x2013; single case report issued approval N/A. Written informed consent was obtained from the patient for publication of this case report. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41170278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12570721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.93484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>KDIGO 2022 clinical practice guideline for diabetes management in chronic kidney disease. KDIGO Diabetes Work Group. Kidney Int. 2022;102:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36272764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Introduction and methodology: standards of care in diabetes-2024. American Diabetes Association Professional Practice Committee. Diabetes Care. 2024;47:0&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albuminuria is an appropriate therapeutic target in patients with CKD: the pro view. Gansevoort TR, Heerspink LJH. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/25887073/ Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2015;10(6):1079&#x2013;1088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4455219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25887073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Non-albuminuric diabetic kidney disease phenotype: beyond albuminuria. D'Marco L, Guerra-Torres X, Viejo I, et al. touchREV Endocrinol. 2022;18:102&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9835813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36694889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidney disease and increased mortality risk in type 2 diabetes. Afkarian M, Sachs MC, Kestenbaum B, et al. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2013;24:302&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3559486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23362314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blood pressure in chronic kidney disease: conclusions from a Kidney Disease: Improving Global Outcomes (KDIGO) Controversies Conference. Cheung AK, Chang TI, Cushman WC, et al. Kidney Int. 2019;95:1027&#x2013;1036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31010478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2017 ACC/AHA/AAPA/ABC/ACPM/AGS/APhA/ASH/ASPC/NMA/PCNA Guideline for the prevention, detection, evaluation, and management of high blood pressure in adults: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Whelton PK, Carey RM, Aronow WS, et al. Hypertension. 2018;71:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29133356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiac autonomic neuropathy in diabetes mellitus. Agashe S, Petak S. Methodist Debakey Cardiovasc J. 2018;14:251&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6369622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30788010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiac autonomic neuropathy in diabetes mellitus: pathogenesis, epidemiology, diagnosis and clinical implications: a narrative review. Gogan A, Potre O, Avram VF, et al. J Clin Med. 2025;14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11818907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39941342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonalbuminuric diabetic kidney disease and risk of all-cause mortality and cardiovascular and kidney outcomes. Kristensen SL, R&#xf8;rth R, Jhund PS, et al. Diabetes Care. 2022;45:1429&#x2013;1437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dapagliflozin in patients with chronic kidney disease. Heerspink HJ, Stef&#xe1;nsson BV, Correa-Rotter R, et al. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:1436&#x2013;1446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32970396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SGLT2 inhibitors for primary and secondary prevention of cardiovascular and renal outcomes in type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis of cardiovascular outcome trials. Zelniker TA, Wiviott SD, Raz I, et al. Lancet. 2019;393(10166):31&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30424892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blood pressure effects of canagliflozin and clinical outcomes in type 2 diabetes and chronic kidney disease: insights from the CREDENCE trial. Ye N, Jardine MJ, Oshima M, et al. Circulation. 2021;143:1735&#x2013;1749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33554616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liraglutide and cardiovascular outcomes in type 2 diabetes. Marso SP, Daniels GH, Brown-Frandsen K, et al. N Engl J Med. 2016;375:311&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4985288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27295427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiovascular, mortality, and kidney outcomes with GLP-1 receptor agonists in patients with type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis of cardiovascular outcome trials. Kristensen SL, R&#xf8;rth R, Jhund PS, et al. Lancet. 2019;7(10):776&#x2013;785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31422062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists on secretions of insulin and glucagon and gastric emptying in Japanese individuals with type 2 diabetes: A prospective, observational study. Kuwata H, Yabe D, Murotani K, et al. J Diabetes Investig. 2021;12:2162&#x2013;2171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8668059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34022121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaps in hypertension guidelines for patients with chronic kidney disease. Ku E, Grams ME, Rebholz CM, et al. Amr Jr Kid Dis. 2019;73(2):235&#x2013;243.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>