<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39584499</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1526-4998</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>81</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pest management science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pest Manag Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Testing low-risk bioactive compounds on Halyomorpha halys: an improved pipeline of analyses to investigate their effects on the bacterial endosymbiont Candidatus Pantoea carbekii.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1615</StartPage><EndPage>1623</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1615-1623</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ps.8564</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The brown marmorated stink bug Halyomorpha halys has become an invasive insect pest of many crops. A promising control strategy to manage the proliferation of H. halys is based on the suppression of its obligate and vertically transmitted uncultivated symbiotic bacterium Candidatus Pantoea carbekii through surface-sterilization of H. halys eggs. Indeed, the application of antimicrobial formulations on the eggs of H. halys could cause mortality of endosymbiont and consequently of newly emerged nymphs. In this study, a microbial live/dead assay was applied directly on H. halys eggs to evaluate Ca. P. carbekii loss of viability after treatments with seven commercial formulations including fungicides (copper hydroxide, sulphur, sweet orange essential oil) and plant biostimulants (flavonoids and chestnut tannin extract) compared with two disinfectants for civil and industrial use (sodium hypochlorite/hydrated sodium/tetraborate decahydrate and peracetic acid/hydrogen peroxide). Impact of mode of application was also evaluated, as surface treatment of egg masses was performed through spraying and dipping in laboratory conditions. Antimicrobial activity data were finally complemented with observations of egg hatching and vitality of the nymphs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The optimization of live/dead staining is useful for evaluating Ca. P. carbekii mortality directly on eggs, providing a rapid and reliable culture-independent approach. Sodium hypochlorite, copper, sulphur, tannins and sweet orange essential oil showed an antimicrobial effect against Ca. P. carbekii and a H. halys egg hatching reduction and nymph's vitality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The antimicrobial and insecticidal effects of these commercial products should be further studied to assess their in-field efficiency as well as the impact of these substances on non-target organisms. The approach followed in this study could be considered a robust pipeline of analyses to evaluate the effectiveness of antimicrobial eco-friendly compounds in symbiotic control of H. halys. &#xa9; 2024 Society of Chemical Industry.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Society of Chemical Industry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Checchia</LastName><ForeName>Ilaria</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Andreolli</LastName><ForeName>Marco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>VUCC-DBT Verona University Culture Collection, Department of Biotechnology, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lanza</LastName><ForeName>Francesco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Agrea Contract Research Organization, San Giovanni Lupatoto, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santoiemma</LastName><ForeName>Giacomo</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Agronomy, Food, Natural Resources, Animals and Environment (DAFNAE), University of Padova, Legnaro, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mori</LastName><ForeName>Nicola</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5736-9584</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pasini</LastName><ForeName>Massimiliano</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Agrea Contract Research Organization, San Giovanni Lupatoto, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lampis</LastName><ForeName>Silvia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>VUCC-DBT Verona University Culture Collection, Department of Biotechnology, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Felis</LastName><ForeName>Giovanna E</ForeName><Initials>GE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6506-6911</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>VUCC-DBT Verona University Culture Collection, Department of Biotechnology, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>I.C. Ph.D. scholarship is supported by REACT-EU FSE fund in the frame of PON "Dottorati su tematiche green" (Action IV.5), 2014-2020 (DM 1061/2021). Code BIO04, DOT1340225, Borsa 1 CUP B39J21026610001</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Pest Manag Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100898744</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1526-498X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005659">Fungicides, Industrial</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004202">Disinfectants</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pantoea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020062" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heteroptera</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013559" MajorTopicYN="Y">Symbiosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010063" MajorTopicYN="N">Ovum</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009758" MajorTopicYN="N">Nymph</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005659" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fungicides, Industrial</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004202" MajorTopicYN="Y">Disinfectants</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Candidatus Pantoea carbekii</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Halyomorpha halys</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antimicrobial activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eco&#x2010;friendly compounds</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">live/dead assay</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">symbiotic control</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39584499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ps.8564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Hoebeke ER and Carter ME, Halyomorpha halys (St&#xe5;l) (Heteroptera: Pentatomidae): a polyphagous plant pest from Asia newly detected in North America. Proc Entomol Soc Wash 105:225&#x2013;237 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haye T, Abdallah S, Gariepy T and Wyniger D, Phenology, life table analysis and temperature requirements of the invasive brown marmorated stink bug, Halyomorpha halys, in Europe. J Pest Sci 87:407&#x2013;418 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bariselli M, Bugiani R and Maistrello L, Distribution and damage caused by Halyomorpha halys in Italy. EPPO Bull 46:332&#x2013;334 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maistrello L, Vaccari G, Caruso S, Costi E, Bortolini S, Macavei LI et al., Monitoring of the invasive Halyomorpha halys, a new key pest of fruit orchards in northern Italy. J Pest Sci 90:1231&#x2013;1244 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiman NG, Walton VM, Shearer PW, Rondon SI and Lee JC, Factors affecting flight capacity of brown marmorated stink bug, Halyomorpha halys (Hemiptera: Pentatomidae). J Pest Sci 88:37&#x2013;47 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rice KB, Bergh CJ, Bergmann EJ, Biddinger DJ, Dieckhoff C, Dively G et al., Biology, ecology, and management of brown marmorated stink bug (Hemiptera: Pentatomidae). J Integr Pest Manag 5:1&#x2013;13 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee D&#x2010;H and Leskey TC, Flight behavior of foraging and overwintering brown marmorated stink bug, Halyomorpha halys (Hemiptera: Pentatomidae). Bull Entomol Res 105:566&#x2013;573 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee D&#x2010;H, Short BD, Joseph SV, Bergh JC and Leskey TC, Review of the biology, ecology, and management of Halyomorpha halys (Hemiptera: Pentatomidae) in China, Japan, and the Republic of Korea. Environ Entomol 42:627&#x2013;641 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leskey TC, Short BD, Butler BR and Wright SE, Impact of the invasive brown marmorated stink bug, Halyomorpha halys (St&#xe5;l), in mid&#x2010;atlantic tree fruit orchards in the United States: case studies of commercial management. Psyche 2012:1&#x2013;14 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamburini G, Laterza I, Nardi D, Mele A, Mori N, Pasini M et al., Effect of landscape composition on the invasive pest Halyomorpha halys in fruit orchards. Agric Ecosyst Environ 353:108530 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cira TM, Burkness EC and Hutchison WD, Halyomorpha halys mortality and sublethal feeding effects following insecticide exposure. J Pest Sci 90:1257&#x2013;1268 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuhar TP and Kamminga K, Review of the chemical control research on Halyomorpha halys in the USA. J Pest Sci 90:1021&#x2013;1031 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rani L, Thapa K, Kanojia N, Sharma N, Singh S, Grewal AS et al., An extensive review on the consequences of chemical pesticides on human health and environment. J Clean Prod 283:124657 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson DA, Lehmler H&#x2010;J, Kolpin DW, Hladik ML, Vargo JD, Schilling KE et al., A critical review on the potential impacts of neonicotinoid insecticide use: current knowledge of environmental fate, toxicity, and implications for human health. Environ Sci: Processes Impacts 22:1315&#x2013;1346 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syromyatnikov MY, Isuwa MM, Savinkova OV, Derevshchikova MI and Popov VN, The effect of pesticides on the microbiome of animals. Agri 10:79 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor CM, Coffey PL, DeLay BD and Dively GP, The importance of gut symbionts in the development of the brown marmorated stink bug, Halyomorpha halys (St&#xe5;l). PLoS One 9:e90312 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonella E, Orr&#xf9; B and Alma A, Egg masses treatment with micronutrient fertilizers has a suppressive effect on newly&#x2010;emerged nymphs of the brown marmorated stink bug Halyomorpha halys. Entomol Gen 39:231&#x2013;238 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonella E and Alma A, The role of symbiont&#x2010;targeted strategies in the management of Pentatomidae and Tephritidae pests under an integrated vision. Agronomy 13:868 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal R, Michel AP and Sabree ZL, The crypt&#x2010;dwelling primary bacterial symbiont of the polyphagous pentatomid pest Halyomorpha halys (Hemiptera: Pentatomidae). Environ Entomol 43:617&#x2013;625 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenyon LJ, Meulia T and Sabree ZL, Habitat visualization and genomic analysis of &#x201c;Candidatus Pantoea carbekii,&#x201d; the primary symbiont of the Brown marmorated stink bug. Genome Biol Evol 7:620&#x2013;635 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otero&#x2010;Bravo A and Sabree ZL, Inside or out? Possible genomic consequences of extracellular transmission of crypt&#x2010;dwelling stinkbug mutualists. Front Ecol Evol 3:64 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duron O and No&#xeb;l V, A wide diversity of Pantoea lineages are engaged in mutualistic symbiosis and cospeciation processes with stinkbugs: Pantoea symbiosis in stinkbugs. Environ Microbiol Rep 8:715&#x2013;727 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prado SS, Rubinoff D and Almeida RPP, Vertical transmission of a pentatomid caeca&#x2010;associated symbiont. Ann Entomol Soc Am 99:577&#x2013;585 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukatsu T and Hosokawa T, Capsule&#x2010;transmitted gut symbiotic bacterium of the japanese common plataspid stinkbug, Megacopta punctatissima. Appl Environ Microbiol 68:389&#x2013;396 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oishi S, Moriyama M, Koga R and Fukatsu T, Morphogenesis and development of midgut symbiotic organ of the stinkbug Plautia stali (Hemiptera: Pentatomidae). Zoological Lett 5:16 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown SA, Davis JA and Richter AR, Efficacy of foliar insecticides on eggs of Nezara viridula (Hemiptera: Pentatomidae). Fla Entomol 95:1182&#x2013;1186 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team, R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. R Fundation for Statistical computing, Vienna, Austria (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenth RV, Buerkner P, Herve M, Love J, Riebl H and Singmann H, Emmeans: estimated marginal means, aka least&#x2010;squares means [R package emmeans version 1.8.9] (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox J and Weisberg S, An R Companion to Applied Regression, 3rd edn. Sage, Thousand Oaks, California (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libenson L, Hadley FP, McIlroy AP, Wetzel VM and Mellon RR, Antibacterial effect of elemental sulfur. J Infec Dis 93:28&#x2013;35 (1953).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scaccini D, Mirandola E, Sirapu S, Simoni F, Fornasiero D, Duso C et al., Wettable sulphur application for Halyomorpha halys (St&#xe5;l) (Hemiptera: Pentatomidae) management: laboratory and semi&#x2010;field experiments. Pest Manag Sci 80:3620&#x2013;3627 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nannini R, Bortolotti PP, Casoli L and Boselli M, Prime indagini sull'attivit&#xe0; di alcuni insetticidi e strategie di difesa nei confronti di Halyomorpha halys. Giornate Fitopatol 1:179&#x2013;190 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isman MB, Botanical insecticides, deterrents, and repellents in modern agriculture and an increasingly regulated world. Annu Rev Entomol 51:45&#x2013;66 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isman MB, Commercial development of plant essential oils and their constituents as active ingredients in bioinsecticides. Phytochem Rev 19:235&#x2013;241 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panini M, Manicardi GC, Moores GD and Mazzoni E, An overview of the main pathways of metabolic resistance in insects. Invertebrate Surv J 13:326&#x2013;335 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finetti L, Civolani S and Bernacchia G, Monoterpenes&#x2010;induced toxicity in nymphal stages of Halyomorpha halys. J Plant Dis Prot 128:1371&#x2013;1375 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Bryan CA, Crandall PG, Chalova VI and Ricke SC, Orange essential oils antimicrobial activities against Salmonella spp. J Food Sci 73:M264&#x2013;M267 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Y, Sun Z and Chen W, Antimicrobial susceptibility and antibacterial mechanism of limonene against listeria monocytogenes. Molecules 25:33 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A, Jeyakumar E and Lawrence R, Journey of limonene as an antimicrobial agent. J Pure Appl Microbiol 15:1094&#x2013;1110 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bargiacchi E, Miele S, Romani A and Campo M, Biostimulant activity of hydrolyzable tannins from sweet chestnut (Castanea sativa mill.). Acta Hortic 1009:111&#x2013;116 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaczmarek B, Tannic acid with antiviral and antibacterial activity as a promising component of biomaterials. Materials 13:3224 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miele S, Tegli S, Izquierdo CG, Cerboneschi M and Bargiacchi E, Hydrolysable tannins in agriculture, in Tannins&#x2010;structural properties, biological properties and current knowledge, ed. by Aires A, Vol. 5. Intechopen, Portugal (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petchidurai G, Sahayaraj K, Al&#x2010;Shuraym LA, Albogami BZ and Sayed SM, Insecticidal activity of tannins from selected brown macroalgae against the cotton leafhopper Amrasca devastans. Plan Theory 12:3188 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bigiotti G, Pastorelli R, Belcari A and Sacchetti P, Symbiosis interruption in the olive fly: effect of copper and propolis on Candidatus Erwinia dacicola. J Appl Entomol 143:357&#x2013;364 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casalone E, Cavalieri D, Daly G, Vitali F and Perito B, Propolis hosts a diverse microbial community. World J Microbiol Biotechnol 36:1&#x2013;11 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Machado GMC, Leon LL and de Castro SL, Activity of brazilian and bulgarian propolis against different species of leishmania. Mem Inst Oswaldo Cruz 102:73&#x2013;77 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adebola AO, Ibikunle AO, Issa GA and Dende IA, Propolis production by honey bee Apis mellifera (Hymenoptera: Apidae) and its potential for the management of the larger grain borer Prostephanus truncatus (horn) (coleoptera: Bostrichidae) on maize grains. J Plant Prot Res 50:61&#x2013;66 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajao AM, Ojo JA, Bamidele JA and Oladimeji Y, Bee propolis as protectant of stored grains against insect pests' damage in Kwara state. Tech Sci J Community Dev Afr 1:103&#x2013;108 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mari M, Cembali T, Baraldi E and Casalini L, Peracetic acid and chlorine dioxide for postharvest control of Monilinia laxa in stone fruits. Plant Dis 83:773&#x2013;776 (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myrta A, Youssef K, Dimartino M, Cariddi C, Vitale A, Ippolito A et al., JetFive, a new disinfectant for the agri&#x2010;food chain: evaluation of the fungicide and bactericide activity. Giornate Fitopatol 2:123&#x2013;132 (2010).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>