<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39554613</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2573-2102</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Translational animal science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Transl Anim Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Administration of sodium hyaluronate to adult horses prior to and immediately after exercise does not alter the range of motion in either the tarsus or metacarpophalangeal joints.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>txae153</StartPage><MedlinePgn>txae153</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">txae153</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/tas/txae153</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hyaluronic acid (HA), a glycosaminoglycan found in joint synovial fluid, is administered to horses as an anti-inflammatory with lubrication properties. This experiment examined the effects of HA administered before and shortly after an exercise test on metacarpophalangeal (MCP; fetlock) and tibiotarsal (hock) joint range of motion (ROM). Horses were injected intravenously (IV) with placebo (4&#xa0;mL, saline) or HA (4&#xa0;mL, 40&#xa0;mg) 24&#xa0;h before performing a standardized exercise test (SET) on a high-speed treadmill and again at 6-h post-SET. Passive fetlock flexion was measured at 4 and 24&#xa0;h post-SET. Hock flexion and extension were measured at 24&#xa0;h post-SET by videography and kinematic evaluation at the trot. Parameters of the SET were sufficient to cause peak lactate values of 6.6&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;0.15&#xa0;mM and a maximum heart rate of 203.6&#x2005;&#xb1;&#x2005;4.8 bpm. A minor gain (<i>P</i>&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.08) in fetlock flexion prior to SET was observed in HA horses that were not retained at either 4 or 24&#xa0;h post-SET. Hock flexion in both limbs was greater (<i>P</i>&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;0.05) at 24&#xa0;h post-SET, independent of treatment. Horses receiving HA exhibited reduced (<i>P</i>&#x2005;=&#x2005;0.04) right hock extension. No differences in either right or left hock ROM were observed between control and HA-treated horses. From these results, it is concluded that IV HA injections surrounding an exercise stressor offer no substantive gains in either fetlock or hock ROM.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2024. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the American Society of Animal Science.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Riley</LastName><ForeName>Julia W</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Animal Sciences, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, VA 24061, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chance</LastName><ForeName>Lara M</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Animal Sciences, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, VA 24061, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barshick</LastName><ForeName>Madison R</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Animal Sciences, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, VA 24061, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnson</LastName><ForeName>Sally E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9514-4220</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Animal Sciences, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, VA 24061, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Transl Anim Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101738705</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2573-2102</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomechanics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">horse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hyaluronic acid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">range of motion</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39554613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11568345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/tas/txae153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">txae153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Adair, H., Marcellin-Little D., and Levine D... 2016. Validity and repeatability of goniometry in normal horses. Vet. Comp. Orthop. Traumatol. 29:314&#x2013;319. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.3415/vcot-15-11-0182</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3415/vcot-15-11-0182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27124214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agreste, F. R., Moreira J. J., F&#xfc;lber J., Bogossian P. M., Chaible L. M., Silva L. C. L. C., Michelacci Y. M., and Baccarin R. Y. A... 2021. Arthroscopic evaluation of the synovial membrane and its relationship with histological changes and biomarkers in equine joint disease. Res. Vet. Sci. 140:212&#x2013;220. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1016/j.rvsc.2021.09.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rvsc.2021.09.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34534902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austin, J. W., Gilchrist C., and Fehlings M. G... 2012. High molecular weight hyaluronan reduces lipopolysaccharide mediated microglial activation. J. Neurochem. 122:344&#x2013;355. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1111/j.1471-4159.2012.07789.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1471-4159.2012.07789.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22587438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergh, A., Lauridsen N. G., and Hesbach A. L... 2020. Concurrent validity of equine joint range of motion measurement: A Novel Digital Goniometer versus Universal Goniometer. Animals. 10:2436. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.3390/ani10122436</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani10122436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7767303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33352686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burger, D., Vidondo B., Gerber V., Deillon D., M&#xfc;ller A., Scheidegger M., K&#xe4;ser R., and Ramseyer A... 2023. High&#x2010;level competition exercise and related fatigue are associated with stride and jumping characteristics in eventing horses. Equine Vet. J. 56:631&#x2013;641. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1111/evj.13999</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/evj.13999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37694590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busse, N. I., Gonzalez M. L., Krason M. L., and Johnson S. E... 2021. &#x3b2;-Hydroxy &#x3b2;-methylbutyrate supplementation to adult Thoroughbred geldings increases type IIA fiber content in the gluteus medius. J. Anim. Sci. 99:skab264. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1093/jas/skab264</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skab264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8493890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34516615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carmona, J. U., Arg&#xfc;elles D., Deulofeu R., Mart&#xed;nez-Puig D., and Prades M... 2009. Effect of the administration of an oral hyaluronan formulation on clinical and biochemical parameters in young horses with osteochondrosis. Vet. Comp. Orthop. Traumatol. 22:455&#x2013;459. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.3415/VCOT-09-01-0001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3415/VCOT-09-01-0001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19876524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Clifford, L. T., Lowe J. N., McKellar C. D., McGowan C., and David F... 2021. A double-blinded positive control study comparing the relative efficacy of 2.5% polyacrylamide hydrogel (PAAG) against triamcinolone acetonide (TA) and sodium hyaluronate (HA) in the management of middle carpal joint lameness in racing thoroughbreds. J. Equine Vet. Sci. 107:103780. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1016/j.jevs.2021.103780</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jevs.2021.103780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34802625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crawford, K. L., and Ahern B. J... 2022. Investigations into Thoroughbred racehorse welfare in Queensland Australia focused on musculoskeletal injuries and retirement. Anim. Front. 12:59&#x2013;62. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1093/af/vfac018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/af/vfac018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9197301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35711502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasanello, D. C., Su J., Deng S., Yin R., Colville M. J., Berenson J. M., Kelly C. M., Freer H., Rollins A., Wagner B.,. et al. 2021. Hyaluronic acid synthesis, degradation, and crosslinking in equine osteoarthritis: TNF-&#x3b1;-TSG-6-mediated HC-HA formation. Arthritis Res. Ther. 23:218. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1186/s13075-021-02588-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13075-021-02588-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8377964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34416923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frisbie, D. D., McIlwraith C. W., Kawcak C. E., and Werpy N. M... 2016. Efficacy of intravenous administration of hyaluronan, sodium chondroitin sulfate, and N-acetyl-d-glucosamine for prevention or treatment of osteoarthritis in horses. Am. J. Vet. Res. 77:1064&#x2013;1070. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.2460/ajvr.77.10.1064</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2460/ajvr.77.10.1064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27668577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregg, S. R., Barshick M. R., and Johnson S. E... 2023. Intravenous injection of sodium hyaluronate diminishes basal inflammatory gene expression in equine skeletal muscle. Animals. 13:3030. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.3390/ani13193030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani13193030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10571686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37835636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji, R. -R., Chamessian A., and Zhang Y. -Q... 2016. Pain regulation by non-neuronal cells and inflammation. Science 354:572&#x2013;577. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1126/science.aaf8924</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aaf8924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5488328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27811267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, X., Shi M., Wang Q., Hui J., Shofaro J. H., Erkhembayar R., Hui M., Gao C., and Gantumur M. -A... 2023. Anti-inflammatory effects of the 35kDa hyaluronic acid fragment (B-HA/HA35). J. Inflamm. Res. 16:209&#x2013;224. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.2147/JIR.S393495</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/JIR.S393495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9846287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36686276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawcak, C. E., Frisbie D. D., Trotter G. W., McIlwraith C. W., Gillette S. M., Powers B. E., and Walton R. M... 1997. Effects of intravenous administration of sodium hyaluronate on carpal joints in exercising horses after arthroscopic surgery and osteochondral fragmentation. Am. J. Vet. Res. 58:1132&#x2013;1140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9328667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krause, D. M., Pezzanite L. M., Griffenhagen G. M., and Hendrickson D. A... 2022. Comparison of equine synovial sepsis rate following intrasynovial injection in ambulatory versus hospital settings. Equine Vet. J. 54:523&#x2013;530. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1111/evj.13485</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/evj.13485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8664890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34115426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leguillette, R., Bond S. L., Lawlor K., de Haan T., and Weber L. M... 2020. Comparison of physiological demands in Warmblood show jumping horses over a standardized 1.10 m jumping course versus a standardized exercise test on a track. BMC Vet. Res. 16:182&#x2013;189. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1186/s12917-020-02400-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12917-020-02400-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7282170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32513241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macpherson, M. L., Gigu&#xe8;re S., Pozor M. A., Burden C. A., Berghaus L. J., Berghaus R. D., Varner J. C., Hayna J. T., Benson S. M., Randell S. A.,. et al. 2021. Evidence for anti&#x2010;inflammatory effects of firocoxib administered to mares with experimentally induced placentitis. Am. J. Reprod. Immunol. 86:e13396. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1111/aji.13396</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aji.13396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33569862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mercer, M. A., Davis J. L., and McKenzie H. C... 2023. The clinical pharmacology and therapeutic evaluation of non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs in adult horses. Animals. 13:1597. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.3390/ani13101597</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani13101597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10215112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37238029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Much, M. L., Leatherwood J. L., Martinez R. E., Silvers B. L., Basta C. F., Gray L. F., and Bradbery A. N... 2020. Evaluation of an oral joint supplement on gait kinematics and biomarkers of cartilage metabolism and inflammation in mature riding horses. Transl Anim Sci 4:txaa150. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1093/tas/txaa150</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/tas/txaa150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7497898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32968713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munsters, C., van den Broek J., Welling E., van Weeren R., and van Oldruitenborgh-Oosterbaan M. S... 2013. A prospective study on a cohort of horses and ponies selected for participation in the European Eventing Championship: reasons for withdrawal and predictive value of fitness tests. BMC Vet. Res. 9:182. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1186/1746-6148-9-182</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1746-6148-9-182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3848563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24034152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuenschwander, H. M., Moreira J. J., Vendruscolo C. P., F&#xfc;lber J., Seidel S. R. T., Michelacci Y. M., and Baccarin R. Y. A... 2019. Hyaluronic acid has chondroprotective and joint-preserving effects on LPS-induced synovitis in horses. J. Vet. Sci. 20:e67. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.4142/jvs.2019.20.e67</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4142/jvs.2019.20.e67</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6883190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31775194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peal, B. T., Gagliardi R., Su J., Fortier L. A., Delco M. L., Nixon A. J., and Reesink H. L... 2020. Synovial fluid lubricin and hyaluronan are altered in equine osteochondral fragmentation, cartilage impact injury, and full&#x2010;thickness cartilage defect models. J. Orthop. Res. 38:1826&#x2013;1835. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1002/jor.24597</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jor.24597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7354223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31965593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plevin, S., McLellan J., van Schie H., and Parkin T... 2019. Ultrasound tissue characterisation of the superficial digital flexor tendons in juvenile Thoroughbred racehorses during early race training. Equine Vet. J. 51:349&#x2013;355. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1111/evj.13006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/evj.13006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30125384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellam, J., and Berenbaum F... 2010. The role of synovitis in pathophysiology and clinical symptoms of osteoarthritis. Nat. Rev. Rheumatol. 6:625&#x2013;635. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1038/nrrheum.2010.159</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrrheum.2010.159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20924410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith, L. C. R., Wylie C. E., Palmer L., and Ramzan P. H. L... 2019. Synovial sepsis is rare following intrasynovial medication in equine ambulatory practice. Equine Vet. J. 51:595&#x2013;599. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1111/evj.13063</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/evj.13063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30589107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urayama, S., Tanaka A., Kusano K., Sato H., Muranaka M., Mita H., Nagashima T., and Matsuda H... 2023. Oral administration of meloxicam and flunixin meglumine have similar analgesic effects after lipopolysaccharide-induced inflammatory response in thoroughbred horses. J. Equine Vet. Sci. 121:104205. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1016/j.jevs.2022.104205</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jevs.2022.104205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36586521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker, V. A., Tranquille C. A., Newton J. R., Dyson S. J., Brandham J., Northrop A. J., and Murray R. C... 2017. Comparison of limb kinematics between collected and lengthened (medium/extended) trot in two groups of dressage horses on two different surfaces. Equine Vet. J. 49:673&#x2013;680. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1111/evj.12661</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/evj.12661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28052378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilsher, S., Allen W. R., and Wood J. L. N... 2006. Factors associated with failure of Thoroughbred horses to train and race. Equine Vet. J. 38:113&#x2013;118. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.2746/042516406776563305</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2746/042516406776563305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16536379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xavier, A. A. S., da Rosa P. P., Mackmill L. de B., and Roll V. F. B... 2021. An assessment of the effectiveness of hyaluronic acid and polyacrylamide hydrogel in horses with osteoarthritis: systematic review and network meta-analysis. Res. Vet. Sci. 134:42&#x2013;50. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1016/j.rvsc.2020.11.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rvsc.2020.11.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33290979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, X., Sugita S., Liu A., Naito Y., Hwang W., Qiu H., Sakamoto A., Sawa T., Matthay M. A., and Lee J. -W... 2021. Therapeutic effects of high molecular weight hyaluronic acid in severe Pseudomonas aeruginosa pneumonia in ex vivo perfused human lungs. Am. J. Physiol. Lung Cell. Mol. Physiol. 321:L827&#x2013;L836. doi: https://doi.org/ 10.1152/ajplung.00626.2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajplung.00626.2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8616617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34524905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>