<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41294578</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2310-2861</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Gels (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Gels</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative Analysis of Gel Properties of Sodium Citrate-Treated Giant Squid and Pork for Surimi Production.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">893</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/gels11110893</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The giant squid, despite its abundance as a resource, is underutilized for surimi production due to its distinctive odor and poor gel-forming ability. While soaking (e.g., in sodium citrate) can alleviate the odor, its impact on the gel properties remains unclear. This study employed a comparative approach using pork, a benchmark for high-quality gels, to critically evaluate the gel properties of deodorized giant squid. The rheological, textural, and microstructural properties, as well as the water-holding capacity and water distribution, of squid (after sodium citrate soaking) and pork gels were compared. The results demonstrated that the squid gels exhibited a significantly lower storage modulus and higher tan &#x3b4; value than pork gels, indicating inferior rheological properties. After cooking, the squid gel exhibited a bent shape and markedly lower hardness (approximately 259.78 g) and chewiness (approximately 226.09 g) compared to the pork gels (approximately 3305.92 g and 2781.27 g, respectively). Microstructurally, the squid gels presented a coarse, porous, and discontinuous network with larger pores, contrasting sharply with the fine, dense, and uniform matrix of the pork gels. Correspondingly, the squid gels had inferior water-holding capacity and a higher proportion of free water. This comparison demonstrates that the gel from sodium citrate-soaked giant squid is weak. More importantly, it provides mechanistic insights by highlighting the specific structural and hydration deficiencies responsible for its poor performance. The findings underscore that targeted strategies to modify the protein network are necessary for the effective utilization of giant squid in surimi production.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mu</LastName><ForeName>Hongliang</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Food Science and Engineering, Ningbo University, Ningbo 315832, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Zufang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Food Science and Engineering, Ningbo University, Ningbo 315832, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Gels</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101696925</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2310-2861</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dosidicus gigas</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LF-NMR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">WHC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gel properties</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microstructure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rheological properties</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41294578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12652862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/gels11110893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">gels11110893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ding H.C., Li X.P., Li R.Z., Yi S.M., Xu Y.X., Mi H.B., Li J.R. Changes of water state and gel characteristics of Hairtail (Trichiurus lepturus) surimi during thermal processing. J. Texture Stud. 2019;50:332&#x2013;340. doi: 10.1111/jtxs.12393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jtxs.12393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30786028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Q., Wu W., Han J., Chung H.Y., Gao P., Yu D., Yu P., Xu Y., Xia W. Characteristics of silver carp surimi gel under high temperature (&#x2265;100 &#xb0;C): Quality changes, water distribution and protein pattern. Int. J. Food Sci. Technol. 2022;57:4613&#x2013;4627. doi: 10.1111/ijfs.15799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijfs.15799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu W., Qin Y., Ruan Z. Effects of high hydrostatic pressure on color, texture, microstructure, and proteins of the tilapia (Orechromis niloticus) surimi gels. J. Texture Stud. 2021;52:177&#x2013;186. doi: 10.1111/jtxs.12572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jtxs.12572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33191516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen N., Gao P., Jiang Q., Yu X., Li P., Xu Y., Yu D., Yang F., Xia W. Effects of deheading and rinsing pretreatment on the quality of white leg shrimp (Litopenaeus vannamei) surimi based on endogenous proteases. Food Res. Int. 2022;160:111678. doi: 10.1016/j.foodres.2022.111678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodres.2022.111678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36076389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tolano-Villaverde I.J., Santos-Sauceda I., Santacruz-Ortega H., Ram&#xed;rez-Wong B., Brown-Boj&#xf3;rquez F., Su&#xe1;rez-Jim&#xe9;nez G.M., M&#xe1;rquez-R&#xed;os E. Evaluation of the gelling ability of actomyosin-paramyosin from giant squid mantle (Dosidicus gigas) Int. Food Res. J. 2020;27:712&#x2013;719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf3;mez-Guill&#xe9;n M.C., Montero P., Solas M.T., Border&#xed;as A.J. Thermally induced aggregation of giant squid (Dosidicus gigas) mantle proteins. physicochemical contribution of added ingredients. J. Agric. Food Chem. 1998;46:3440&#x2013;3446. doi: 10.1021/jf9801116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jf9801116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Brambila G.Y., Alvarez-Manilla G., Soto-Cordova F., Lyon B.G., Pacheco-Aguilar R. Identification and characterization of the off-flavor in mantle muscle of jumbo squid (Dosidicus gigas) from the Gulf of California. J. Aquat. Food Prod. Technol. 2004;13:55&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1300/J030v13n01_06.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1300/J030v13n01_06</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang R., Xu A., Chen Y., Sun N., Zhang J., Jia R., Huang T., Yang W. Effect of laver powder on textual, rheological properties and water distribution of squid (Dosidicus gigas) surimi gel. J. Texture Stud. 2020;51:968&#x2013;978. doi: 10.1111/jtxs.12556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jtxs.12556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32799359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu Y., Deng S., Lv G., Li M., Bao H., Gao Y., Jia R. Improvement of gel quality of squid (Dosidicus gigas) meat by using sodium gluconate, sodium citrate, and sodium tartrate. Foods. 2022;11:173. doi: 10.3390/foods11020173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/foods11020173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8775022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35053905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu F., Li X., Lin C., Hu X., Zhang B., Pan W. The mechanism of egg white protein to enhance the thermal gel properties of giant squid (Dosidicus gigas) surimi. Food Chem. 2025;469:142601. doi: 10.1016/j.foodchem.2024.142601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2024.142601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39724697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreno H.M., Cardoso C., Solas M.T., Border&#xed;as A.J. Improvement of cold and thermally induced gelation of giant squid (Dosidicus gigas) surimi. J. Aquat. Food Prod. Technol. 2009;18:312&#x2013;330. doi: 10.1080/10498850903223788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10498850903223788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campo-Dea&#xf1;o L., Tovar C.A., Jes&#xfa;s Pombo M., Teresa Solas M., Javier Border&#xed;as A. Rheological study of giant squid surimi (Dosidicus gigas) made by two methods with different cryoprotectants added. J. Food Eng. 2009;94:26&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1016/j.jfoodeng.2009.02.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfoodeng.2009.02.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang W., Chen S., Yu S., Zhang Y. Effects of different soaking processes and additives on the acid removal efficiency of squid. Jiangxi Fish. Sci. Technol. 2019;5:45&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X., Kang M. Deacidification of Peru squid. Food Sci. Technol. 2015;40:137&#x2013;139. doi: 10.13684/j.cnki.spkj.2015.08.029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13684/j.cnki.spkj.2015.08.029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H., Xu Y., Li X., Zhu W., Yi S., Li J., Li Y. Effect of ultrasonic-assisted deacidification on quality of Dosidicus gigas. Food Res. Dev. 2019;40:91&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z., Gao Y., Wu M., Zhao C., Liu X., Zhang X., Zhang L., Chen Y. Effects of phosphorylated ovalbumin on the quality of pork myofibrillar protein gel: An insight into gelling and physicochemical properties. J. Futur Foods. 2024;4:149&#x2013;158. doi: 10.1016/j.jfutfo.2023.06.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfutfo.2023.06.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji L., Zhou Y., Nie Q., Luo Y., Yang R., Kang J., Zhao Y., Zeng M., Jia Y., Dong S., et al. The potential correlation between bacterial diversity and the characteristic volatile flavor compounds of Sichuan sauce-flavored sausage. Foods. 2024;13:2350. doi: 10.3390/foods13152350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/foods13152350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11312067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39123542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X., Yan F., Qu D., Wan T., Xi L., Hu C.Y. Aroma characterization of Sichuan and Cantonese sausages using electronic nose, gas chromatography&#x2013;mass spectrometry, gas chromatography-olfactometry, odor activity values and metagenomic. Food Chem. X. 2024;24:101924. doi: 10.1016/j.fochx.2024.101924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fochx.2024.101924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11582465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39582659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi L., Wang Q., Xie Z., Wu C., Peng T., Nian X., Li L., Li H., Chen T. The changes of fungal community and flavor substances in Yunnan-style sausages: A comparative analysis of different drying methods. Food Chem. 2024;460:140750. doi: 10.1016/j.foodchem.2024.140750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2024.140750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39128368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Y., Chen F., Shi M., Wang Y., Xiao X., Wu C. Gel properties and protein structures of minced pork prepared with &#x3ba;-carrageenan and non-meat proteins. Gels. 2024;10:305. doi: 10.3390/gels10050305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/gels10050305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11120799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38786222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H., Sheng W., Nunekpeku X., Li C., Zhang W., Wang Y. Mechanistic insights into gel quality changes in pork batters induced by ultrasound: From myofibrillar protein aggregation to conformation. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2025;318:145301. doi: 10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2025.145301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2025.145301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40527378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Guo X., Xiong H., Zhu T. Effect of modified soy protein isolate on dough rheological properties and noodle qualities. J. Food Process. Preserv. 2022;46:e16371. doi: 10.1111/jfpp.16371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jfpp.16371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X., Cui H., Yuan Z., Xu J., Li J., Liu J., Liu H., Zhu D. Effects of different combinations of probiotics on rheology, microstructure, and moisture distribution of soy materials-based yogurt. J. Food Sci. 2022;87:2820&#x2013;2830. doi: 10.1111/1750-3841.16204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1750-3841.16204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35638330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khatkar A.B., Kaur A. Effect of protein incorporation on functional, thermal, textural and overall quality characteristics of instant noodles. J. Food Meas. Charact. 2018;12:2218&#x2013;2229. doi: 10.1007/s11694-018-9838-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11694-018-9838-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y., Xia W., Yang F., Nie X. Protein molecular interactions involved in the gel network formation of fermented silver carp mince inoculated with Pediococcus pentosaceus. Food Chem. 2010;120:717&#x2013;723. doi: 10.1016/j.foodchem.2009.10.068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2009.10.068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao J., Shi H., Wang J., Xia G., Zhao Y., Yu G., Shen X. Investigation of the gel properties and gelation mechanism of a surimi blend composed of skipjack tuna (Katsuwonus pelamis) and purpleback flying squid (Symplectoteuthis oualaniensis) Foods. 2025;14:621. doi: 10.3390/foods14040621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/foods14040621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11854482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40002064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X., Liu Q., Wang P., Song C., Ma H., Hong P., Zhou C. Tapioca starch improves the quality of Virgatus nemipterus surimi gel by enhancing molecular interaction in the gel system. Foods. 2024;13:169. doi: 10.3390/foods13010169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/foods13010169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10779019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38201197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Sun Q., Pan Y., Wei S., Xia Q., Liu S., Ji H., Deng C., Hao J. Investigation on the correlation between changes in water and texture properties during the processing of surimi from golden pompano (Trachinotus ovatus) J. Food Sci. 2021;86:376&#x2013;384. doi: 10.1111/1750-3841.15581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1750-3841.15581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33438246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan J., Jia H., Shang M., Xu C., Lian H., Li H., Dong X. Physiochemical properties and tastes of gels from Japanese Spanish mackerel (Scomberomorus niphonius) surimi by different washing processes. J. Texture Stud. 2018;49:578&#x2013;585. doi: 10.1111/jtxs.12357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jtxs.12357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30156294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin M., Zhou Y., Xu Y., Tang J., Yang W., Xu P. Changes of biochemical properties of muscle protein during the process of Dosidicus gigas frozen goods. Sci. Technol. Food Ind. 2012;33:353&#x2013;357. doi: 10.13386/j.issn1002-0306.2012.14.092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13386/j.issn1002-0306.2012.14.092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y., Xia W., Yang F., Kim J.M., Nie X. Effect of fermentation temperature on the microbial and physicochemical properties of silver carp sausages inoculated with Pediococcus pentosaceus. Food Chem. 2010;118:512&#x2013;518. doi: 10.1016/j.foodchem.2009.05.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2009.05.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y., Xia W., Ge C. Effect of mixed starter cultures fermentation on the characteristics of silver carp sausages. World J. Microbiol. Biotechnol. 2007;23:1021&#x2013;1031. doi: 10.1007/s11274-006-9330-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11274-006-9330-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu H., Weng P., Wu Z. Effect of inoculation with Lacticaseibacillus casei and Staphylococcus carnosus on the quality of squid (Dosidicus gigas) surimi sausage. Fermentation. 2023;9:794. doi: 10.3390/fermentation9090794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/fermentation9090794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu H., Weng P., Wu Z. Mixed inoculation with Lacticaseibacillus casei and Staphylococcus carnosus improves safety, gel properties and flavor of giant squid surimi without added seasonings. Fermentation. 2025;11:404. doi: 10.3390/fermentation11070404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/fermentation11070404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mi J., Ni W., Huang P., Hong J., Jia R., Deng S., Yu X., Wei H., Yang W. Effect of acetylated distarch adipate on the physicochemical characteristics and structure of shrimp (Penaeus vannamei) myofibrillar protein. Food Chem. 2022;373:131530. doi: 10.1016/j.foodchem.2021.131530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2021.131530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34774379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu X., Wang Y., Xie Y., Wei S., Ding H., Yu C., Dong X. Gelation properties and protein conformation of grass carp fish ball as influenced by egg white protein. J. Texture Stud. 2022;53:277&#x2013;286. doi: 10.1111/jtxs.12668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jtxs.12668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35229305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>