<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39872597</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Pharmaceutical Composition of Rocuronium Bromide May Promote Catecholamine Release From PC-12 Cells.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e76537</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e76537</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e76537</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.76537</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Several cases of pheochromocytoma presenting with hypertensive crises after anesthesia induction, possibly caused by rocuronium injection, have been reported. Rocuronium has two compositions: rocuronium bromide (RB) in sodium acetate hydrate/acetic acid buffer solution (acetic acid vehicle)&#xa0;and RB in glycine/hydrochloric acid buffer solution (hydrochloric acid vehicle). This study assessed the effect of rocuronium composition on the release of catecholamine from PC-12 rat adrenal pheochromocytoma cells.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">PC-12 cells (3x10<sup>5</sup> cells) were cultured for 96 hours, then 1 mL of reagent was added for five minutes. First, the experiment used phosphate-buffered saline (PBS (-)), RB in PBS (-), an acetic acid vehicle, and RB in the acetic acid-based vehicle. Next, the experiment used an acetic acid vehicle and a hydrochloric acid vehicle. Then the experiment used an acetic acid vehicle and a mixed solution of 0.2 mL acetic acid vehicle + 0.8 mL normal saline (NS). Cell supernatants were collected and norepinephrine (NE) and dopamine (DA) concentrations were measured using high-performance liquid chromatography.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Release of NE and DA was caused by acetic acid vehicle, not by RB in PBS (-). Hydrochloric acid vehicles similarly showed a significantly lower release of NE and DA than acetic vehicle acid (NE, P=0.002; DA, P=0.002). In addition, the acetic acid vehicle diluted 5-fold with NS showed a significantly lower release of NE and DA than the acetic acid vehicle alone (NE, P=0.005; DA, P=0.002).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The concentration of acetic acid in the buffer solution, not RB, caused the release of catecholamines from PC-12 cells.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024, Itaya et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Itaya</LastName><ForeName>Tomoaki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesiology, Nihon University School of Medicine, Tokyo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takagi</LastName><ForeName>Shunichi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesiology, Nihon University School of Medicine, Tokyo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamiya</LastName><ForeName>Takefumi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesiology, Nihon University School of Medicine, Tokyo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakazawa</LastName><ForeName>Keisuke</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesiology, Nihon University School of Medicine, Tokyo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Katagiri</LastName><ForeName>Seidai</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesiology, Nihon University School of Medicine, Tokyo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suzuki</LastName><ForeName>Takahiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesiology, Nihon University School of Medicine, Tokyo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertensive crisis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">paraganglioma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pc-12</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pheochromocytoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rocuronium</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve human participants or tissue. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39872597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11772068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.76537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cardiovascular manifestations and complications of pheochromocytomas and paragangliomas. Y-Hassan S, Falhammar H. J Clin Med. 2020;9:2435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7465968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32751501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocuronium can trigger a hypertensive crisis in a patient with paraganglioma: a case report. Itaya T, Takagi S, Saito T, Suzuki T. Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11157463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38854215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Was a hypertensive crisis in a patient with pheochromocytoma caused by rocuronium?: a case report. Jeong CW, Lee HG, Kim WM, Shin SH, Bae HB. Korean J Anesthesiol. 2009;57:249&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30625868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Induction of anesthesia triggers hypertensive crisis in a patient with undiagnosed pheochromocytoma: could rocuronium be to blame? Holldack HJ. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2007;21:858&#x2013;862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18068067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catecholamine crisis during induction of general anesthesia: a&#xa0;case report. Sonntagbauer M, Koch A, Strouhal U, Zacharowski K, Weber CF. Anaesthesist. 2018;67:209&#x2013;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29404657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuromuscular relaxants as antagonists for M2 and M3 muscarinic receptors. Hou VY, Hirshman CA, Emala CW. Anesthesiology. 1998;88:744&#x2013;750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9523819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of non-depolarizing neuromuscular blocking agents on norepinephrine release from human atrial tissue obtained during cardiac surgery. Sato K, Windisch K, Matko I, Vizi ES. Br J Anaesth. 1999;82:904&#x2013;909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10562787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pharmacological prevention of rocuronium-induced injection pain or withdrawal movements: a meta-analysis. Kwak HJ, Kim JY, Kim YB, Min SK, Moon BK, Kim JY. J Anesth. 2013;27:742&#x2013;749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23519582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reduction of the rocuronium-induced withdrawal reflex by MR13A10A, a generic rocuronium with a novel solution: a randomized, controlled study. Shimizu M, Amaya F, Kinoshita M, Yamasaki M, Yokota I, Sawa T. PLoS One. 2019;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6821093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31665172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Generic rocuronium reduces withdrawal movements compared to original rocuronium under target-controlled infusion induction with propofol. Hamada K, Takahashi K, Tokinaga Y, Iwasaki S, Yamakage M. J Anesth. 2021;35:184&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33420819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Advances in paraganglioma-pheochromocytoma cell lines and xenografts. Bayley JP, Devilee P. Endocr Relat Cancer. 2020;27:0&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33112800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocuronium Bromide Formulation Safety Data Sheets.  [
Apr;
2023 
]. 2023. https://www.msd.com/docs/product/safety-data-sheets/hh-sds/Rocuronium%20Bromide%20Formulation_HH_JP_6N.pdf https://www.msd.com/docs/product/safety-data-sheets/hh-sds/Rocuronium%20Bromide%20Formulation_HH_JP_6N.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A new rocuronium formulation not causing vascular pain in a flexor reflex model of anesthetized rats. Jimbo K, Itsuji Y, Kubo E, Kumagai M, Masui K, Yamamura Y. J Anesth. 2018;32:806&#x2013;812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30242475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The pharmacodynamics and pharmacokinetics of Org 9426, a new non-depolarizing neuromuscular blocking agent, in patients anaesthetized with nitrous oxide, halothane and fentanyl. Wierda JM, Kleef UW, Lambalk LM, Kloppenburg WD, Agoston S. Can J Anaesth. 1991;38:430&#x2013;435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1829656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Investigation of the freely available easy-to-use software 'EZR' for medical statistics. Kanda Y. Bone Marrow Transplant. 2013;48:452&#x2013;458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3590441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23208313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A TRPA1-dependent mechanism for the pungent sensation of weak acids. Wang YY, Chang RB, Allgood SD, Silver WL, Liman ER. J Gen Physiol. 2011;137:493&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3105510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21576376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The role of TRPA1 channels in thermosensation. Zhang H, Wang C, Zhang K, Kamau PM, Luo A, Tian L, Lai R. Cell Insight. 2022;1:100059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10120293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37193355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molecular determinants of TRPM8 function: key clues for a cool modulation. Pertusa M, Solorza J, Madrid R. Front Pharmacol. 2023;14:1213337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10301734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37388453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cold stimulation evokes exocytotic vesicle release from PC12 cells. Yoshimura R, Nakagawa M, Endo Y. Biomed Res. 2016;37:381&#x2013;383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28003585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oxidant-induced increase in norepinephrine secretion from PC12&#x202f;cells is dependent on TRPM8 channel-mediated intracellular calcium elevation. Peixoto-Neves D, Soni H, Adebiyi A. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2018;506:709&#x2013;715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30376995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>