<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40572836</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigation into Improving the Water Resistance and Mechanical Properties of Calcined Gypsum from Phosphogypsum Composites.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2703</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma18122703</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study aimed to improve the mechanical properties and water resistance of calcined gypsum from phosphogypsum (CGP) by incorporating organic additives and inorganic admixtures. The effects of the dosage of these additives-including kaolin, nano-SiO<sub>2</sub>, polycarboxylic acid superplasticizer, and sodium methyl silicate-on the properties (flexural strength, compressive strength, water absorption, and softening coefficient) of CGP composites (CGPCs) were investigated. A high water resistance of the CGPCs was achieved using nano-SiO<sub>2</sub> and sodium methyl silicate modification, superplasticizer addition, and the partial replacement of gypsum with mineral admixtures. The results showed that the flexural and compressive strength of the composites hit 4.61 MPa and 19.54 MPa, respectively, while the softening coefficient was 0.70 and the water absorption rate was 19.85%. Microstructural investigation confirmed that the combination of nano-SiO<sub>2</sub> and kaolin led to the formation of calcium silicate hydrate. Additionally, the superplasticizer played a crucial role in reducing the water-to-cement ratio, while unhydrated mineral particles had a filling effect, thereby enhancing the density of the hardened paste. The sodium methyl silicate formed a hydrophobic film on the surface of the hardened paste, increasing the contact angle to 109.01&#xb0; and improving the water resistance of the CGPCs.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Qing</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Engineering Technology Research Center for Disaster Prevention and Mitigation, China Three Gorges University, Yichang 443002, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil Engineering and Architecture, China Three Gorges University, Yichang 443002, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lou</LastName><ForeName>Yuanyuan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil Engineering and Architecture, China Three Gorges University, Yichang 443002, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Yanzhou</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4490-5242</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hubei Engineering Technology Research Center for Disaster Prevention and Mitigation, China Three Gorges University, Yichang 443002, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil Engineering and Architecture, China Three Gorges University, Yichang 443002, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Weiqi</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wuhan Zhiyuan Construction Group Co., Ltd., Wuhan 430000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Xiaohui</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil Engineering and Architecture, China Three Gorges University, Yichang 443002, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Abutu Simon John</ForeName><Initials>ASJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Federal University of Technology, Babura 732104, Nigeria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>D20015</GrantID><Agency>Program of Introducing Talents of Discipline to Universities</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2021EJD026</GrantID><Agency>111 Project of Hubei Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>SC211006</GrantID><Agency>Hubei Three Gorges Laboratory Opening &amp; Innovation Fund project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">calcined gypsum from phosphogypsum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">kaolin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nano-SiO2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sodium methyl silicate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">water contact angle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">water resistance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Author Weiqi Wang was employed by the company Wuhan Zhiyuan Construction Group Co., Ltd. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40572836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12194404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma18122703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma18122703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yang J., Ma L., Liu H., Guo Z., Bounkhong K. Chemical behavior of fluorine and phosphorus in chemical looping gasification using phosphogypsum as an oxygen carrier. Chemosphere. 2020;248:125979. doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2020.125979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2020.125979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32028158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou J., Li X., Zhao Y., Shu Z., Shen X. Preparation of paper-free and fiber-free plasterboard with high strength using phosphogypsum. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;243:118091. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B., Shu J., Chen M., Zeng X., Liu R., Yang Y. A new basic burning raw material for simultaneous stabilization/solidification of PO43&#x2212;-P and F&#x2212; in phosphogypsum. Ecotox Environ. Safe. 2023;252:114582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36731180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh M. Treating waste phosphogypsum for cement and plaster manufacture. Cem. Concr. Res. 2002;32:1033&#x2013;1038. doi: 10.1016/S0008-8846(02)00723-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0008-8846(02)00723-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X., Gao J., Zhao Y. Investigation on the hydration of hemihydrate phosphogypsum after post treatment. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;229:116864. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.116864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.116864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero-Hermida M.I., Flores-Al&#xe9;s V., Hurtado-Berm&#xfa;dez S.J., Santos A., Esquivias L. Environmental impact of phosphogypsum-derived building materials. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health. 2020;17:4248. doi: 10.3390/ijerph17124248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17124248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7345951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32545903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Z., Deng Z. Research hotspots and trends of comprehensive utilization of phosphogypsum: Bibliometric analysis. J. Environ. Radioact. 2022;242:106778. doi: 10.1016/j.jenvrad.2021.106778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvrad.2021.106778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34847525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tayibi H., Choura M., Lopez F.A., Alguacil F.J., Lopez-Delgado A. Environmental impact and management of phosphogypsum. J. Environ. Manage. 2009;90:2377&#x2013;2386. doi: 10.1016/j.jenvman.2009.03.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2009.03.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19406560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashad A.M. Phosphogypsum as a construction material. J. Clean. Prod. 2017;166:732&#x2013;743. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2017.08.049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2017.08.049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chernysh Y., Yakhnenko O., Chubur V., Roub&#xed;k H. Phosphogypsum recycling: A review of environmental issues, current trends, and prospects. Appl. Sci. 2021;11:1575. doi: 10.3390/app11041575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app11041575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu F., Liu X., Wang C., Qu G., Liu L., Chen B. New dawn of solid waste resource treatment: Preparation of high-performance building materials from waste-gypsum by mechanical technology. Constr. Build. Mater. 2022;318:126204. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.126204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.126204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzouvalas G., Rantis G., Tsimas S. Alternative calcium-sulfate-bearing materials as cement retarders: Part II. FGD gypsum. Cem. Concr. Res. 2004;34:2119&#x2013;2125. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2004.03.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2004.03.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q., Ma H., Chen Q., Huang Z., Zhang C., Yang T. Preparation of waterproof block by silicate clinker modified FGD gypsum. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;214:318&#x2013;325. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.04.053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.04.053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fornes I.V., Vai&#x10d;iukynien&#x117; D., Nizevi&#x10d;ien&#x117; D., Doro&#x161;evas V., Dvo&#x159;&#xe1;k K. A method to prepare a high-strength building material from press-formed phosphogypsum purified with waste zeolite. J. Build. Eng. 2021;34:101919. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He T., Kang Z., Chen C. Influence of Sodium Methyl Silicate on Waterproof Property of Desulfurized Gypsum Block. J. Build. Mater. 2021;24:247&#x2013;253+259. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaziliunas A., Leskeviciene V., Vektaris B., Valancius Z. The study of neutralization of the dihydrate phosphogypsum impurities. Ceram. Silik. 2006;50:178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sui S., Li J., Guan R., Wang D., Li G. Research on Water Resistance Performance of Gypsum Products. J. Build. Mater. 2005;8:328&#x2013;331. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan H., Li G. Emulsion Waterproof Agent and Its Effects on Intrinsic Properties of Gypsum. Asian J. Chem. 2013;25:5042&#x2013;5046. doi: 10.14233/ajchem.2013.14456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14233/ajchem.2013.14456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Z., Xing W., Chen W. Cementitious Materials Science. Wuhan University of Technology Press; Wuhan, China: 2014. pp. 88&#x2013;94. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y., Yue W., Dong R. Gypsum Building Materials. 2nd ed. China Building Materials Industry Press; Beijing, China: 2003. pp. 154&#x2013;196. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan R. Cementitious Materials. Wuhan University of Technology Press; Wuhan, China: 1989. pp. 103&#x2013;121. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao J., Li J., Jiang Y., Wang S., Ding Y., Ding Y., Oh W. Improvement in water resistance of desulfurized gypsum by novel modification of silicone oil paraffin composite emulsion-based waterproofing agent. J. Korean Ceram. Soc. 2019;56:558&#x2013;565. doi: 10.4191/kcers.2019.56.6.10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4191/kcers.2019.56.6.10</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W. Study on Improvement Method of Water-Resistance of Hemihydrate Phosphogypsum. China Three Gorges University; Yichang, China: 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu D., Wang W., Peng Y., Shi H., Li D., Wang B. Study on the Strength and Hydration Characteristics of Phosphogypsum-phosphorus Slag Composite Cementitious Material. Met. Mine. 2022;555:230&#x2013;237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J. Influence of Silica Fume on Properties of Gypsum-based Self-leveling Mortar. China Concr. Cem. Prod. 2020;5:80&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K., Wang A., Sun D., Chen W. Recent Progress of Ettringite Formation and Its Expansion Mechanisms during Sulfate Attack. Bull. Chin. Ceram. Soc. 2016;35:4014&#x2013;4019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Z., Chen Y., Wu J., Tan Y. Study on the Behavior of Swelling-Shrinkage in Hydration Process of Phosphogypsum-based super Sulfated Cement. J. China Three Gorges Univ. Nat. Sci. 2023;45:63&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., Yuan Q., Liu X., Mou X. Application of Silane Materials in Concrete Protection. Constr. Sci. Technol. 2018;19:40&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gypsum Plasters-Determination of Mechanical Properties. State Bureau of Technical Supervision; Beijing, China: 1999. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Cao J., Ren Q., Ding Y., Zhu H., Xiong C., Chen R. Effect of nano-silica and silicone oil paraffin emulsion composite waterproofing agent on the water resistance of flue gas desulfurization gypsum. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;287:123055. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Tao Z., Wu L., Zhang Z., Zhao Z. Study on Effect of Nano-CaCO3 on Properties of Phosphorus Building Gypsum. Materials. 2023;16:3354. doi: 10.3390/ma16093354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16093354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10179624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37176235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokarev Y., Ginchitsky E., Sychugov S., Krutikov V., Yakovlev G., Buryanov A., Senkov S. Modification of gypsum binders by using carbon nanotubes and mineral additives. Procedia Eng. 2017;172:1161&#x2013;1168. doi: 10.1016/j.proeng.2017.02.135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.proeng.2017.02.135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraire-Luna P.E., Escalante-Garcia J.I., Gorokhovsky A. Composite systems fluorgypsum-blastfurnance slag-metakaolin, strength and microstructures. Cem. Concr. Res. 2006;36:1048&#x2013;1055. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2006.02.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2006.02.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan B., Ye Q., Zhang J., Lou W., Wu Z. Interaction between &#x3b1;-calcium sulfate hemihydrate and superplasticizer from the point of adsorption characteristics, hydration and hardening process. Cem. Concr. Res. 2010;40:253&#x2013;259. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2009.08.027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2009.08.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Xu K., Peng J., Wang J., Zhang J., Li Q. Study on mechanical strength and water resistance of organosilicon waterproofing agent blended recycled gypsum plaster. Case Stud. Constr. Mat. 2021;14:e00546. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q., Ma H., Chen Q., Gu B., Li S., Zhu H. Effect of silane modified styrene-acrylic emulsion on the waterproof properties of flue gas desulfurization gypsum. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;19:506&#x2013;512. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.11.185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.11.185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C., Ma F., He T., Kang Z., Wang Y., Shi C. Improved water and efflorescence resistance of flue gas desulfurization gypsum-based composites by generating hydrophobic coatings. J. Clean. Prod. 2022;371:133711. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.133711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.133711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui G., Kong D., Huang Y., Qiu W., Cheng L., Wang L. Effects of Different Admixtures on the Mechanical and Thermal Insulation Properties of Desulfurization Gypsum-Based Composites. Coatings. 2023;13:1089. doi: 10.3390/coatings13061089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/coatings13061089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekaterina F., Elena V., Oleg B., Andreev V. Some aspects on improvement of water resistant perfornace of gypsum binders. Matec Web Conf. 2016;86:04065.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumagai S., Ohama Y. Development of Highly Water-Resistant Gypsum-Based Composites. Zairyo J. Soc. Mater. Sci. 2002;51:1129&#x2013;1134. doi: 10.2472/jsms.51.1129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2472/jsms.51.1129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L., Li B., Chen P., Yin S. Modification and Mechanism of Phosphorus Building Gypsum Using Admixtures. Bull. Chin. Ceram. Soc. 2022;41:2400&#x2013;2410. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S., Yang B., Zhai W., Li S., Kong G. Composition and properties of methyl silicate/silicate composite coatings. J. Mater. Eng. 2021;49:163&#x2013;170. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min J., Park J.H., Sohn H.K., Park J.M. Synergistic effect of potassium metal siliconate on silicate conversion coating for corrosion protection of galvanized steel. J. Ind. Eng. Chem. 2012;18:655&#x2013;660. doi: 10.1016/j.jiec.2011.11.057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jiec.2011.11.057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giovambattista N., Debenedetti P.G., Rossky P.J. Effect of surface polarity on water contact angle and interfacial hydration structure. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2007;111:9581&#x2013;9587. doi: 10.1021/jp071957s.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp071957s</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17658789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian W., Wang Q., Zhang Y., Xu F., Chen S. Study on the Properties of Phosphogypsum Mixed with Sulphoaluminate Cement for Concrete Canvas. J. China Three Gorges Univ. Nat. Sci. 2020;42:56&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation> [(accessed on 12 May 2025)]; Available online:  http://zj.yichang.gov.cn/content-62527-985084-1.html.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>