<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41322739</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Severe Rhabdomyolysis in an Elderly Patient With Diabetes and Vascular Disease: Interplay of Statin Therapy, Sodium-Glucose Cotransporter-2 (SGLT2) Inhibition, and Thiazide-Induced Hypokalemia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e95693</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e95693</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e95693</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.95693</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Rhabdomyolysis is a potentially life-threatening complication of drug therapy, particularly in elderly patients exposed to polypharmacy. Statins are a well-known cause, while thiazide-induced hypokalemia and volume depletion can further predispose to muscle injury. Sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 (SGLT2) inhibitors such as empagliflozin provide cardio-renal benefits but may potentiate statin toxicity and exacerbate dehydration and electrolyte imbalance, amplifying rhabdomyolysis risk. We report a 78-year-old woman with diabetes, hypertension, hyperlipidemia, and carotid artery disease, hypothyroidism, who developed severe rhabdomyolysis, acute kidney injury, and transaminitis while taking simvastatin, hydrochlorothiazide, and empagliflozin. She presented with generalized weakness, muscle soreness, and exertional dyspnea; labs showed a creatine kinase of 12,165 U/L, hypokalemia of 2.9 mmol/L, and elevated troponin. Management included intravenous hydration, electrolyte repletion, and discontinuation of offending agents, resulting in clinical and biochemical improvement. This case underscores the multifactorial etiology of rhabdomyolysis in elderly vascular patients, where dehydration and hypokalemia from thiazides and SGLT2 inhibitors may synergize with statin-induced myotoxicity, complicating evaluation when troponin is elevated without ischemic changes. Clinicians should maintain a high index of suspicion for rhabdomyolysis in patients with new muscle pain, weakness, or fatigue after starting empagliflozin, especially when combined with statins and diuretics, and prioritize early recognition, medication review, and hydration to prevent serious complications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Kothia et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kothia</LastName><ForeName>Darpan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Florida State University College of Medicine/ Ascension Sacred Heart, Pensacola, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Habeb</LastName><ForeName>Bola</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal medicine, Florida State University College of Medicine/ Ascension Sacred Heart, Pensacola, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ermolenko</LastName><ForeName>Felix</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Florida State University College of Medicine/ Ascension Sacred Heart, Pensacola, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-traumatic rhabdomyolysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polypharmacy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 (sglt-2) inhibitors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">statin-induced rhabdomyolysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thiazide diuretics in elderly</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41322739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12662601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.95693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rhabdomyolysis: A syndrome to be considered. (Article in Spanish) Baeza-Trinidad R. Med Clin (Barc) 2022;158:277&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34872769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevention of occupational heat-related illnesses. Tustin A, Sayeed Y, Berenji M, et al. J Occup Environ Med. 2021;63:0&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34597285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhabdomyolysis and acute kidney injury. Bosch X, Poch E, Grau JM. N Engl J Med. 2009;361:62&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19571284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diagnostic evaluation of rhabdomyolysis. Nance JR, Mammen AL. Muscle Nerve. 2015;51:793&#x2013;810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4437836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25678154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk factors and future directions for preventing and diagnosing exertional rhabdomyolysis. Carneiro A, Viana-Gomes D, Macedo-da-Silva J, et al. Neuromuscul Disord. 2021;31:583&#x2013;595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34193371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statin-induced rhabdomyolysis: A complication of a commonly overlooked drug interaction. Ezad S, Cheema H, Collins N. Oxf Med Case Reports. 2018;2018:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5853001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29593874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A narrative review of statin-induced rhabdomyolysis: Molecular mechanism, risk factors, and management. Safitri N, Alaina MF, Pitaloka DA, Abdulah R. Drug Healthc Patient Saf. 2021;13:211&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8593596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34795533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhabdomyolysis and sodium-glucose-linked transport inhibitors in patients taking statins. Harel Z, Jeyakumar N, Smith G, Ray JG, Clemens KK, Juurlink DN. JAMA Netw Open. 2024;7:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11565259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39541123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Severe rhabdomyolysis due to presumed drug interactions of dapagliflozin with rosuvastatin: A case report. Udayashankar A, Mukherjee T, George K, KrishneGowda K. Indian J Nephrol. 2025;35:557&#x2013;559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12392232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40896633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Concomitant use of statins and sodium-glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitors and the risk of myotoxicity reporting: A disproportionality analysis. Gravel CA, Krewski D, Mattison DR, Momoli F, Douros A. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2023;89:2430&#x2013;2445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36912450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhabdomyolysis due to diuretic treatment. Antoniadis DJ, Vavouranakis EM, Tsioufis KP, Toutouzas PK. http://chrome-extension://efaidnbmnnnibpcajpcglclefindmkaj/https://www.hellenicjcardiol.org/archive/full_text/2003/1/2003_1_80.pdf Hellenic J Cardiol. 2003;44:80&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A rare case of hypokalemia-induced rhabdomyolysis. He R, Guo WJ, She F, et al.  https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29915623/ J Geriatr Cardiol. 2018;15:321&#x2013;324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5997613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29915623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potential drug-drug interaction between sodium-glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitors and statins: Pharmacological and clinical evidence. Lalagkas PN, Poulentzas G, Kontogiorgis C, Douros A. Expert Opin Drug Metab Toxicol. 2021;17:697&#x2013;705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33888031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration. Empagliflozin (Jardiance) NDA 204629, Clinical Pharmacology Review.  [
Sep;
2025 
]. 2025. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/nda/2020/204629Orig1s008.pdf https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/nda/2020/204629Orig1s008.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A method for estimating the probability of adverse drug reactions. Naranjo CA, Busto U, Sellers EM, et al. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 1981;30:239&#x2013;245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7249508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elevated serum cardiac troponin I in rhabdomyolysis. Punukollu G, Gowda RM, Khan IA, Mehta NJ, Navarro V, Vasavada BC, Sacchi TJ. Int J Cardiol. 2004;96:35&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15203259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>From cholesterol control to critical illness: A case of statin-associated rhabdomyolysis with concurrent acute kidney injury and hepatotoxicity. Habeb B, Khair S, Fowler S. Cureus. 2025;17:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12269334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40677502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2018 AHA/ACC/AACVPR/AAPA/ABC/ACPM/ADA/AGS/APhA/ASPC/NLA/PCNA Guideline on the Management of Blood Cholesterol: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task&#xa0;Force&#xa0;on&#xa0;Clinical Practice Guidelines. Grundy SM, Stone NJ, Bailey AL, et al. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2019;73:0&#x2013;350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crestor. Food and Drug Administration. Updated date: 2024-07-31.  [
Jan;
2024 
]. 2024. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2024/021366s046lbl.pdf https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2024/021366s046lbl.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corrigendum to: "Lipid management in patients with endocrine disorders: An Endocrine Society Clinical Practice Guideline". J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2021;106:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33783530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>