<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41622218</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2661-801X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC chemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Chem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acemetacin-loaded bilosomal gel formulations prepared using different polymers for topical application: Box-Behnken design for bilosomes formulation optimization and in vitro evaluation of the formulations.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">33</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13065-026-01732-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Acemetacin (ACIN) is a poorly water-soluble nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drug, which limits its effectiveness in topical therapeutic applications. This study aimed to enhance the delivery potential and dermal applicability of ACIN through the development of bilosome-loaded hydrogel formulations. Bilosomes were prepared using the thin-film hydration method and optimized using Box-Behnken Design (BBD). The amount of phosphotidylcholine (lecithin), cholesterol and sodium taurocholate were chosen as the formulation parameters and their effects were evaluated on the resulting vesicle size, zeta potential and entrapemnet efficiency percentage (EE%). The optimized formulation displayed a vesicle size of 137.3&#xa0;nm, a zeta potential of -30.1 mV, a polydispersity index (PDI) of 0.384 and EE% of 84.5%. Bilosomes were incorporated into hydrogel bases containing hydroxypropyl methylcellulose (HPMC) or Carbopol. HPMC-based gels exhibited a favorable pH (~4) for skin application and were selected for further evaluation. These gels provided sustained drug release for up to eight hours. Cytocompatibility testing on L929 fibroblasts using the 3-(4,5-dimethylthiazol-2-yl)-2,5-diphenyltetrazolium bromide (MTT) assay demonstrated cell viability above 90% within the tested concentration range (0.05-2&#xa0;&#xb5;g/mL), indicating good biocompatibility. The bilosome-loaded HPMC gel formulation exhibited desirable physicochemical properties, sustained drug release, and excellent cytocompatibility, making it a promising vehicle for topical delivery of ACIN. Further anti-inflammatory and in vivo studies are recommended to confirm its potential for topical or anti-inflammatory applications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Demirturk</LastName><ForeName>Esra</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Technology, Faculty of Pharmacy, &#xc7;ukurova University, Adana, Turkey. demirturkesra@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xc7;evikelli</LastName><ForeName>Tilbe</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Technology, School of Pharmacy, Bah&#xe7;e&#x15f;ehir University, &#x130;stanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xd6;zyurt</LastName><ForeName>Aylin Balc&#x131;</ForeName><Initials>AB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Toxicology, School of Pharmacy, Bah&#xe7;e&#x15f;ehir University, &#x130;stanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barre</LastName><ForeName>Liban</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Technology, Graduate School, Anadolu University, Eskisehir, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cetin</LastName><ForeName>Meltem</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Technology, Faculty of Pharmacy, Atat&#xfc;rk University, Erzurum, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaynak</LastName><ForeName>Mustafa Sinan</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Technology, Faculty of Pharmacy, Anadolu University, Eskisehir, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Chem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101741142</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2661-801X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acemetacin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bilosomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Box-Behnken design</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hydrogels</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Topical drug delivery</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study did not involve any experiments on human or animal subjects; therefore, ethical approval from an institutional review board or animal ethics committee was not required. Consent for publication: Not applicable. This manuscript does not contain any individual person&#x2019;s data in any form (including images, videos, or personal details). Therefore, consent for publication is not required. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41622218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12927240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13065-026-01732-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13065-026-01732-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Johnson MD, Shively JE. A rheological characterization of Carbopol&#xae; 940 dispersions neutralized with inorganic bases. J Pharm Sci. 2001;90(3):298&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/1520-6017(200103)903&lt;298:AID-JPS5&gt;</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandrasekharan NV. xPharm: The Comprehensive Pharmacology Reference. Elsevier; 2007. 10.1016/B978-008055232-3.61155-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Directorate for the Quality of Medicines. European Pharmacopoeia. 10th ed. Strasbourg: Council of Europe; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cayman Chemical. Product insert for Item No. 29615.&#xa0;https://cdn.caymanchem.com/cdn/insert/29615.pdf. Accessed on 2025 Jul 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore RA, Derry S, McQuay HJ. Single dose oral acemetacin for acute postoperative pain in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2009;(3):CD007589. 10.1002/14651858.CD007589.pub2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD007589.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4170991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19588437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun L, Chen K, Jiang Z, Chen X, Ma J, Ma Q, et al. Indometacin inhibits the proliferation and activation of human pancreatic stellate cells through the downregulation of COX-2. Oncol Rep. 2018;39(5):2243&#x2013;51. 10.3892/or.2018.6321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/or.2018.6321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29565462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucena MI, Andrade RJ, Kaplowitz N, Garc&#xed;a-Cort&#xe9;s M, Fern&#xe1;ndez MC, Romero-G&#xf3;mez M, et al. Hepatic toxicity of nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs. Ann Hepatol. 2009;8(2):141&#x2013;7. 10.1016/S1665-2681(19)31793-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1665-2681(19)31793-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Gharani H, Al-Kinani K. Formulation and in vitro evaluation of Acemetacin nanosuspension. Iraqi J Pharm Sci. 2025;33(4SI):133&#x2013;46. 10.31351/vol33iss(4SI)pp133-146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31351/vol33iss(4SI)pp133-146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abduljaleel ZZ, Al-Kinani KK. Formulation of self-emulsifying microemulsion for Acemetacin using D-optimal design: enteric-coated capsule for targeted intestinal release and bioavailability enhancement. Pharmaceutics. 2025;17(10):1270. 10.3390/pharmaceutics17101270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pharmaceutics17101270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12567528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41155907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira-Leite C, Nunes C, Grahl D, Bozelli JC Jr., Schreier S, Kamma-Lorger CS, et al. Acemetacin&#x2013;phosphatidylcholine interactions are determined by the drug ionization state. Phys Chem Chem Phys. 2018;20(21):14398&#x2013;409. 10.1039/C8CP01698D.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C8CP01698D</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29770409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng M, Li J, Li Z, Zhang G, Zhao P, Fu Q. Recrystallization mediates the gelation of amorphous drugs: the case of Acemetacin. Pharmaceutics. 2023;15(1):219. 10.3390/pharmaceutics15010219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pharmaceutics15010219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9860709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36678848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldawsari MF, Khafagy E-S, Alotaibi HF, Abu Lila AS. Vardenafil-loaded bilosomal mucoadhesive sponge for buccal delivery: optimization, characterization, and in vivo evaluation. Polymers. 2022;14(19):4184. 10.3390/polym14194184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym14194184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9573218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36236132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sideek SA, El-Nassan HB, Fares AR, Elkasabgy NA, ElMeshad AN. Cross-linked alginate dialdehyde/chitosan hydrogel encompassing curcumin-loaded bilosomes for enhanced wound healing activity. Pharmaceutics. 2024;16(1):90. 10.3390/pharmaceutics16010090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pharmaceutics16010090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10819348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38258101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan P, Svirskis D, Waterhouse GIN, Wu Z. Hydroxypropyl methylcellulose bioadhesive hydrogels for topical application and sustained drug release: the effect of polyvinylpyrrolidone on the physicomechanical properties of hydrogel. Pharmaceutics. 2023;15(9):2360. 10.3390/pharmaceutics15092360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pharmaceutics15092360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10537184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37765328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Giuseppe E, Corbi F, Funiciello F, Massmeyer A, Santimano TN, Rosenau M, et al. Characterization of Carbopol&#xae; hydrogel rheology for experimental tectonics and geodynamics. Tectonophysics. 2015;642:29&#x2013;45. 10.1016/j.tecto.2014.12.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tecto.2014.12.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panzade P, Puranik PK. Carbopol polymers: a versatile polymer for pharmaceutical applications. Res J Pharm Technol. 2010;3(3):672&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lubrizol Advanced Materials, Inc. Neutralizing Carbopol<sup>&#xae;</sup> and Pemulen&#x2122; in aqueous and hydroalcoholic systems (TDS-237).&#xa0;https://www.lubrizol.com/-/media/Lubrizol/Health/TDS/TDS-237_Neutralizing_Carbopol_Pemulen_in_Aqueous_Hydroalcoholic_Systems--PH.pdf. Accessed on 2025 Jul 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed S, Kassem MA, Sayed S. Bilosomes as promising nanovesicular carriers for improved transdermal delivery: construction, in vitro optimization, ex vivo permeation and in vivo evaluation. Int J Nanomedicine. 2020;15:9783&#x2013;98. 10.2147/IJN.S278688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJN.S278688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7733410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33324052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawar K, Kamble R, Patil S. Linagliptin-loaded bilosomes for oral administration: formulation, optimization by Box&#x2013;Behnken design, in-vitro, and in-vivo assessment. J Drug Deliv Sci Technol. 2025;108:106879. 10.1016/j.jddst.2025.106879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jddst.2025.106879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elkomy MH, Alruwaili NK, Elmowafy M, Shalaby K, Zafar A, Ahmad N, et al. Surface-modified bilosomes nanogel bearing a natural plant alkaloid for safe management of rheumatoid arthritis inflammation. Pharmaceutics. 2022;14(3):563. 10.3390/pharmaceutics14030563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pharmaceutics14030563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8951435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35335939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waglewska E, Pucek-Kaczmarek A, Bazyli&#x144;ska U. Novel surface-modified bilosomes as functional and biocompatible nanocarriers of hybrid compounds. Nanomaterials. 2020;10(12):2472. 10.3390/nano10122472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nano10122472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7763575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33321762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim TM. Exploitation of transdermal nanobilosomal gel platforms for ameliorating anti-diabetic activity of empagliflozin following I-optimal design. J Drug Deliv Sci Technol. 2023;84:104455. 10.1016/j.jddst.2023.104455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jddst.2023.104455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullah HD, Kamal I, Sabry SA, Abd Elghany M, Ramadan AE. Effective tailoring of cefepime into bilosomes: a promising nanoplatform for enhancing oral absorption, extending half-life, and evaluating biocompatibility, antibacterial, anti-biofilm, anti-breast cancer activity, ex-vivo, and in-vivo studies. Int J Pharm. 2025;668:125001. 10.1016/j.ijpharm.2024.125001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2024.125001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39586513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;evikelli T, G&#xfc;ven UM, &#xd6;zt&#xfc;rk AA. Metronidazole loaded novel microemulsion formulation for topical delivery and characterization with validated new UPLC method. FABAD J Pharm Sci. 2024;49(1):111&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akaki S, Hosokawa M, Maeda S, Kono Y, Maeda H, Ogawara K-i. Efficient loading into and controlled release of lipophilic compound from liposomes by using cyclodextrin as novel trapping agent. Biol Pharm Bull. 2024;47(11):1832&#x2013;5. 10.1248/bpb.b24-00558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1248/bpb.b24-00558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39522976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Conference on Harmonisation (ICH). Validation of analytical procedures: text and methodology Q2(R1). Geneva: ICH; 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips DJ, Pygall SR, Cooper VB, Mann JC. Overcoming sink limitations in dissolution testing: a review of traditional methods and the potential utility of biphasic systems. J Pharm Pharmacol. 2012;64(11):1549&#x2013;59. 10.1111/j.2042-7158.2012.01523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.2042-7158.2012.01523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23058042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alruwaili NK, Zafar A, Alsaidan OA, Yasir M, Mostafa EM, Alnomasy SF, et al. Development of surface modified bilosomes for the oral delivery of quercetin: optimization, characterization in-vitro antioxidant, antimicrobial, and cytotoxicity study. Drug Deliv. 2022;29(1):3035&#x2013;50. 10.1080/10717544.2022.2122634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10717544.2022.2122634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9848422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36120935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Bhatnagar S, Tiwari A, Meena R. Cold Spring Harb Protoc. 2018. 10.1101/pdb.prot095505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/pdb.prot095505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narayanan D, Phanishayee A, Shi K, Chen X, Zaharia M. Memory-efficient pipeline-parallel DNN training. ArXiv Http. 2020. 10.48550/arXiv.2006.09503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48550/arXiv.2006.09503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szyma&#x144;ska E, Sosnowska K, Miltyk W, Rusak M, Basa A, Winnicka K. The effect of &#x3b2;-glycerophosphate crosslinking on chitosan cytotoxicity and properties of hydrogels for vaginal application. Polymers. 2015;7(11):2223&#x2013;44. 10.3390/polym7111510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym7111510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagai N, Ogata F, Nakazawa Y, Yamamoto M, Kawashima A, Yamasaki Y. Preparation of fucoidan&#x2013;chitosan hydrogel and its application as burn healing accelerator on rabbits. Biol Pharm Bull. 2008;31(2):2326&#x2013;31. 10.1248/bpb.31.2326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1248/bpb.31.2326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19043221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valenta C, Kast CE. Effect of thiolated polymers on the textural and mucoadhesive properties of vaginal gel formulations prepared with polycarbophil. AAPS PharmSciTech. 2008;9(3):1153&#x2013;8. 10.1208/s12249-008-9132-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1208/s12249-008-9132-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2977016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18709556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambers H, Piessens S, Bloem A, Pronk H, Finkel P. Natural skin surface pH is on average below 5, which is beneficial for its resident flora. Int J Cosmet Sci. 2006;28(5):359&#x2013;69. 10.1111/j.1467-2494.2006.00344.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-2494.2006.00344.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18489300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luki&#x107; M, Panteli&#x107; I, Savi&#x107; SD. Towards optimal pH of the skin and topical formulations: from the current state of the art to tailored products. Cosmetics. 2021;8(3):69. 10.3390/cosmetics8030069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cosmetics8030069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed S, Kassem MA, Sayed S. Bilosomes as promising nanovesicular carriers for improved transdermal delivery: construction, in vitro optimization, ex vivo permeation and in vivo evaluation. Int J Nanomed. 2020;15:9783&#x2013;98. 10.2147/IJN.S278688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJN.S278688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7733410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33324052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zafar A, Alruwaili NK, Imam SS, Alsaidan OA, Yasir M, Ghoneim MM, et al. Development and evaluation of luteolin loaded pegylated bilosome: optimization, in vitro characterization, and cytotoxicity study. Drug Deliv. 2021;28(1):2562&#x2013;73. 10.1080/10717544.2021.2008055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10717544.2021.2008055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8654410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34866534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siepmann J, Peppas NA. Modeling of drug release from delivery systems based on hydroxypropyl Methylcellulose (HPMC). Adv Drug Deliv Rev. 2001;48(2&#x2013;3):139&#x2013;57. 10.1016/S0169-409X(01)00112-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0169-409X(01)00112-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11369079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>W&#x105;troba M, Bednarczyk W, Szewczyk PK, et al. In vitro cytocompatibility and antibacterial studies on biodegradable Zn alloys supplemented by a critical assessment of direct contact cytotoxicity assay. J Biomed Mater Res B Appl Biomater. 2023;111(2):241&#x2013;60. 10.1002/jbm.b.35147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jbm.b.35147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10086991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36054531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>