<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40150294</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2076-2615</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Animals : an open access journal from MDPI</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Animals (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>In Vitro Assessment of the Effectiveness of Mineral Adsorbents in Sequestering Boar Taint Compounds.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">765</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ani15060765</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The utility of four mineral adsorbents as potential feed additives to bind the boar taint compounds, androstenone and skatole, was assessed with an in vitro system. The adsorbents were bentonite (BNT), diatomaceous earth (DE), spent filter aid (SFA) and hydrated sodium-calcium aluminosilicate (HSCAS), with activated charcoal (AC) as a positive control. The binding capacity (B<sub>max</sub>) and binding affinity (K) of androstenone (AND), estrone (E1), estrone sulfate (E1S), and skatole were estimated using the modified Michaelis-Menten kinetics. The Langmuir and Freundlich isotherm models were also used to assess the adsorption behaviour. The B<sub>max</sub> values with AND were 77.7 &#xb1; 1.12%, 71.9 &#xb1; 1.93%, 55.0 &#xb1; 7.85%, and 69.5 &#xb1; 1.39% for BNT, DE, SFA, and HSCAS, respectively, with no differences in the binding affinity K (<i>p</i> &gt; 0.05). All the mineral adsorbents had very low binding with E1S. SFA bound skatole with a B<sub>max</sub> of 89.9 &#xb1; 1.09%, while the B<sub>max</sub> values for skatole binding by BNT, DE and HCAS were approximately 15%. Most adsorbent-adsorbate complexes fit best with the Freundlich isotherm model. We conclude that all four mineral adsorbents bound androstenone, but not E1S, and only SFA effectively bound skatole. This suggests that SFA may act as a selective dietary binding agent to control boar taint, but further research using animal models is needed to explore the utility and selectivity of these adsorbents as feed additives to control boar taint.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Sanghyuk</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Biosciences, University of Guelph, Guelph, ON N1G 2W1, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Squires</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5288-5600</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Animal Biosciences, University of Guelph, Guelph, ON N1G 2W1, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>RGPIN-2019-03936</GrantID><Agency>Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>SIP 039-17a</GrantID><Agency>Swine Innovation Porc</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Animals (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101635614</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2076-2615</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">activated charcoal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">androstenone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bentonite</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">boar taint</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diatomaceous earth</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydrated sodium&#x2013;calcium aluminosilicate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skatole</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spent filter aid</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest. The funders had no role in the design of the study; in the collection, analyses, or interpretation of data; in the writing of the manuscript; or in the decision to publish the results.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40150294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11939741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani15060765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ani15060765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Prunier A., Bonneau M., von Borell E.H., Cinotti S., Gunn M., Fredriksen B., Giersing M., Morton D.B., Tuyttens F.A.M., Velarde A. A review of the welfare consequences of surgical castration in piglets and the evaluation of non-surgical methods. Anim. Welf. 2006;15:277&#x2013;289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Squires E.J., Bone C., Cameron J. Pork production with entire males: Directions for control of boar taint. Animals. 2020;10:1665. doi: 10.3390/ani10091665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani10091665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7552340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32947846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiler U., Font-i-Furnols M., Tomasevic I., Bonneau M. Alternatives to piglet castration: From issues to solutions. Animals. 2021;11:1041. doi: 10.3390/ani11041041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani11041041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8067991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33917235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinclair P.A., Squires E.J. Testicular sulfoconjugation of the 16-androstene steroids by hydroxysteroid sulfotransferase: Its effect on the concentrations of 5alpha-androstenone in plasma and fat of the mature domestic boar. J. Anim. Sci. 2005;83:358&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15644508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laderoute H., Bone C., Squires E.J. The sulfoconjugation of androstenone and dehydroepiandrosterone by human and porcine sulfotransferase enzymes. Steroids. 2018;136:8&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29792900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okour M., Brundage R.C. Modeling enterohepatic circulation. Curr. Pharmacol. Rep. 2017;3:301&#x2013;313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jen K., Squires E.J. Efficacy of non-nutritive sorbent materials as intestinal-binding agents for the control of boar taint. Animal. 2011;5:1814&#x2013;1820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22440422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi S.W., Lee H.G., So K.M., Kim E., Jung Y.H., Kim M., Jeong J.Y., Kim K.H., Oem J.K., Hur T.Y., et al. Effect of feeding raw potato starch on the composition dynamics of the piglet intestinal microbiome. Anim. Biosci. 2022;35:1698&#x2013;1710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9659463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36108705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Jensen B.B., Canibe N. The mode of action of chicory roots on skatole production in entire male pigs is neither via reducing the population of skatole-producing bacteria nor increased butyrate production in the hindgut. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 2019;85:e023278</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6414384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30635386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang Y.N., Jung M.W. Biochemical changes and biological origin of key odor compound generations in pig slurry during indoor storage periods: A pyrosequencing approach. BioMed Res. Int. 2018;2018:3503658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6157135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30276204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knarreborg A., Beck J., Jensen M.T., Laue A., Agergaard N., Jensen B.B. Effect of non-starch polysaccharides on production and absorption of indolic compounds in entire male pigs. Anim. Sci. 2002;74:445&#x2013;453.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wesoly R., Weiler U. Nutritional influences on skatole formation and skatole metabolism in the pig. Animals. 2012;2:221&#x2013;242. doi: 10.3390/ani2020221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani2020221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4494329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26486918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tambyrajah W.S., Doran E., Wood J.D., McGivan J.D. The pig CYP2E1 promoter is activated by COUP-TF1 and HNF-1 and is inhibited by androstenone. Arch. Biochem. Biophys. 2004;431:252&#x2013;260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15488474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Gregorio M.C., de Neeff D.V., Jager A.V., Corassin C.H., de Pinho Car&#xe3;o &#xc1;.C., de Albuquerque R., de Azevedo A.C., Oliveira C.A.F. Mineral adsorbents for prevention of mycotoxins in animal feeds. Toxin Rev. 2014;33:125&#x2013;135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x10c;olovi&#x107; R., Puva&#x10d;a N., Cheli F., Avantaggiato G., Greco D., &#x110;uragi&#x107; O., Kos J., Pinotti L. Decontamination of mycotoxin-contaminated feedstuffs and compound feed. Toxins. 2019;11:617. doi: 10.3390/toxins11110617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/toxins11110617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6891401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31731462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malekinejad H., Maas-Bakker R., Fink-Gremmels J. Species differences in the hepatic biotransformation of zearalenone. Vet. J. 2006;172:96&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15907386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devreese M., De Backer P., Croubels S. Different methods to counteract mycotoxin production and its impact on animal health. Vlaams Diergeneeskd. Tijdschr. 2013;82:181&#x2013;190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solfrizzo M., Carratu M.R., Avantaggiato G., Galvano F., Pietri A., Visconti A. Ineffectiveness of activated carbon in reducing the alteration of sphingolipid metabolism in rats exposed to fumonisin-contaminated diets. Food Chem. Toxicol. 2001;39:507&#x2013;511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11313118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choy J.H., Choi S.J., Oh J.M., Park T. Clay minerals and layered double hydroxides for novel biological applications. Appl. Clay Sci. 2007;36:122&#x2013;132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J., Fratta D., Palomino A.M. The effect of diatom content on the physical, electrical, and mechanical properties of soils. Acta Geotech. 2024;19:2251&#x2013;2271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reka A.A., Pavlovski B., Fazlija E., Berisha A., Pacarizi M., Daghmehchi M., Sacalis C., Jovanovski G., Makreski P., Oral A. Diatomaceous Earth: Characterization, thermal modification, and application. Open Chem. 2021;19:451&#x2013;461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jen K., Squires E.J. In vitro assessment of the effectiveness of non-nutritive sorbent materials as binding agents for boar taint compounds. Animal. 2011;5:1821&#x2013;1828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22440423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanthier F., Lou Y., Squires E.J. Skatole metabolism in the intact pre-pubescent male pig: The relationship between hepatic enzyme activity and skatole concentrations in plasma and fat. Livest. Sci. 2007;106:145&#x2013;153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foo K.Y., Hameed B.H. Insights into the modeling of adsorption isotherm systems. Chem. Eng. J. 2010;156:2&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho Y.S., Porter J.F., McKay G. Equilibrium isotherm studies for the sorption of divalent metal ions onto peat: Copper, nickel and lead single component systems. Water Air Soil Pollut. 2002;141:1&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukasa-Tebandeke I., Ssebuwufu P., Nyanzi S., Nyakairu G., Ntale M., Lugolobi F., Andreas S. Adsorption behavior of acid-leached clays in bleaching of oil. Am. J. Anal. Chem. 2015;6:495&#x2013;512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolster C.H., Hornberger G.M. On the use of linearized Langmuir equations. Soil Sci. Soc. Am. J. 2007;71:1796&#x2013;1806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto R.P., Mata F., Pires P., Barros M., Ara&#xfa;jo J.P., Vaz-velho M. The use of sugar beet pulp in pig diet to control skatole analysed by HPLC. Sci. Agric. 2023;80:e20220093.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aly S.E., Abdel-Galil M.M., Abdel-Wahhab M.A. Application of adsorbent agents technology in the removal of aflatoxin B1 and fumonisin B1 from malt extract. Food Chem. Toxicol. 2004;42:1825&#x2013;1831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15350680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langmuir I. The adsorption of gases on plane surface of glass, mica and platinum. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 1916;40:1361&#x2013;1403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohn S., Kim D. Modification of Langmuir isotherm in solution systems&#x2014;Definition and utilization of concentration dependent factor. Chemosphere. 2005;58:115&#x2013;123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15522340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvano F., Pietri A., Bertuzzi T., Bognanno M., Chies L., de Angelis A., Galvano M. Activated carbons: In vitro affinity for fumonisin B1 and relation of adsorption ability to physicochemical parameters. J. Food Prot. 1997;60:985&#x2013;991.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31207806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schubert D.C., Chuppava B., Witte F., Terjung N., Visscher C. Evaluation of coated biochar as an intestinal binding agent for skatole and indole in male intact finishing pigs. Animals. 2021;11:760. doi: 10.3390/ani11030760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani11030760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7998114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33801873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>