<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41606482</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2229</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC plant biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Plant Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Spatial stability of photosynthetic and optical traits in common bean leaves under moderate drought revealed by imaging-based phenotyping.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">360</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12870-026-08233-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Leaves are structurally and functionally heterogeneous organs, and their photosynthetic performance often varies across the lamina. Environmental stress, particularly drought, is often assumed to increase this heterogeneity by disrupting stomatal behaviour, mesophyll function, and pigment content. However, the extent to which moderate water deficit alters the spatial organisation of gas exchange, photochemistry, and spectral traits within a single leaf remains unclear. This study investigated within-leaf variability in Phaseolus vulgaris under well-watered and moderate drought conditions by combining gas exchange with chlorophyll fluorescence and multispectral imaging. The aim was to determine whether drought amplifies or reduces intrinsic spatial patterns and to assess whether imaging-derived parameters reflect micro-scale variation in stomatal conductance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Control leaves showed subtle but consistent spatial gradients, including slightly lower photosynthetic activity, photochemical efficiency, and pigment-related indices at the apical region compared with basal and middle segments. Stomatal traits also varied modestly along the lamina, reflecting developmental polarity. Drought substantially reduced net photosynthesis, stomatal conductance, relative electron transport rate, and vegetation indices, yet generally reduced positional differences across measured traits. Leaf relative water content declined without significant positional differences, indicating coherent hydration under stress. Chlorophyll fluorescence and multispectral imaging demonstrated strong reductions in trait magnitude under drought but only weak spatial divergence, with widespread increases in non-photochemical quenching and pigment-related indices. Canonical discriminant analysis clearly separated leaf regions in control plants but showed reduced discrimination under drought, confirming a loss of spatial differentiation. Partial least squares regression revealed strong predictive links between imaging traits and stomatal conductance under control conditions but poor prediction under drought, indicating reduced predictive performance once stomatal conductance becomes strongly constrained.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Moderate drought did not intensify within-leaf heterogeneity. Instead, it promoted a higher degree of spatially coherent down-regulation of photosynthesis, photochemistry, and optical properties. These findings suggest that common bean maintains coordinated stomatal, hydraulic, and photoprotective responses across the lamina under moderate water deficit, preserving functional integrity despite reduced assimilation. The results underscore the importance of accounting for spatial stability when interpreting drought responses and highlight the utility of imaging-based phenotyping for assessing coordinated leaf-level acclimation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lazarevi&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Boris</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Plant Nutrition, University of Zagreb, Faculty of Agriculture, Zagreb, Croatia. blazarevic@agr.hr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Excellence for Biodiversity and Molecular Plant Breeding (CroP-BioDiv), Zagreb, Croatia. blazarevic@agr.hr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Javornik</LastName><ForeName>Tomislav</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Excellence for Biodiversity and Molecular Plant Breeding (CroP-BioDiv), Zagreb, Croatia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Plant Biodiversity, University of Zagreb, Faculty of Agriculture, Zagreb, Croatia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carovi&#x107;-Stanko</LastName><ForeName>Klaudija</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Excellence for Biodiversity and Molecular Plant Breeding (CroP-BioDiv), Zagreb, Croatia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Plant Biodiversity, University of Zagreb, Faculty of Agriculture, Zagreb, Croatia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vodnik</LastName><ForeName>Dominik</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Agronomy, Biotechnical Faculty, University of Ljubljana, Ljubljana, Slovenia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>PK.1.1.10.0008</GrantID><Agency>Research and Development of Plant Genetic Resources for Sustainable Agriculture, Center of Excellence for Biodiversity and Molecular Plant Breeding (CoE CroP-Bio-Div), Zagreb, Croatia</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Plant Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100967807</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2229</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>1406-65-1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002734">Chlorophyll</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010788" MajorTopicYN="Y">Photosynthesis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018515" MajorTopicYN="Y">Plant Leaves</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055864" MajorTopicYN="Y">Droughts</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D027805" MajorTopicYN="Y">Phaseolus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010641" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054046" MajorTopicYN="N">Plant Stomata</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002734" MajorTopicYN="N">Chlorophyll</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="N">Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005453" MajorTopicYN="N">Fluorescence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chlorophyll fluorescence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Common bean (Phaseolus vulgaris)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drought stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High-throughput phenotyping</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Leaf-level phenotyping</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multispectral imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Photosynthesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spatial heterogeneity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stomatal conductance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. This study is not a clinical trial; therefore, clinical trial registration is not applicable. It involved only common bean (Phaseolus vulgaris) plants and did not include any human subjects or animals requiring ethical approval. Consent for publication: Not applicable. The manuscript does not contain any individual person&#x2019;s data in any form. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41606482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12924378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12870-026-08233-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12870-026-08233-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Adams WWI, Terashima I. The leaf: a platform for performing photosynthesis. Advances in Photosynthesis and Respiration 44. Springer; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong D, Yu T, Liu X, Li Y, Peng S, Huang J. Heterogeneity of photosynthesis within leaves is associated with alteration of leaf structural features and leaf N content per leaf area in rice. Funct Plant Biol. 2015;42:687&#x2013;96. 10.1071/FP15057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/FP15057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32480712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borsuk AM, Brodersen CR. The spatial distribution of chlorophyll in leaves. Plant Physiol. 2019;180:1406&#x2013;17. 10.1104/pp.19.00094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1104/pp.19.00094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6752913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30944156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperdouli I, Moustakas M. Spatio-temporal heterogeneity in Arabidopsis thaliana leaves under drought stress. Plant Biol. 2012;14:118&#x2013;28. 10.1111/j.1438-8677.2011.00473.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1438-8677.2011.00473.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21972900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bresson J, Vasseur F, Dauzat M, Koch G, Granier C, Vile D. Quantifying spatial heterogeneity of chlorophyll fluorescence during plant growth and in response to water stress. Plant Methods. 2015;11:1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13007-015-0067-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4394423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25870650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mott KA, Buckley TN. Patchy stomatal conductance: emergent collective behaviour of stomata. Trends Plant Sci. 2000;5:258&#x2013;62. 10.1016/S1360-1385(00)01648-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1360-1385(00)01648-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10838617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweet KJ, Peak D, Mott KA. Stomatal heterogeneity in responses to humidity and temperature: testing a mechanistic model. Plant Cell Environ. 2017;40:2771&#x2013;9. 10.1111/pce.13051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pce.13051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28777880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyschlag W, Eckstein J. Towards a causal analysis of stomatal patchiness: the role of stomatal size variability and hydrological heterogeneity. Acta Oecol. 2001;22:161&#x2013;73. 10.1016/S1146-609X(01)01110-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1146-609X(01)01110-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanourakis D, Heuvelink E, Carvalho SMP. Spatial heterogeneity in stomatal features during leaf elongation: an analysis using Rosa hybrida. Funct Plant Biol. 2015;42:737&#x2013;45. 10.1071/FP15008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/FP15008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32480717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polania JA, Salazar-Chavarr&#xed;a V, Gonzalez-Lemes I, Acosta-Maspons A, Chater CCC, Covarrubias AA. Contrasting phaseolus crop water use patterns and stomatal dynamics in response to terminal drought. Front Plant Sci. 2022;13:894657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2022.894657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9194640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35712594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang FJ, Zhang KK, Du CZ, Li J, Xing YX, Yang LT, et al. Effect of drought stress on anatomical structure and chloroplast ultrastructure in leaves of sugarcane. Sugar Tech. 2015;17:41&#x2013;8. 10.1007/s12355-014-0337-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12355-014-0337-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahan E, Sharwood RE, Tissue DT. Effects of leaf age during drought and recovery on photosynthesis, mesophyll conductance and leaf anatomy in wheat leaves. Front Plant Sci. 2023;14:1091418. 10.3389/fpls.2023.1091418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10318540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37409304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Wang S, Zhu L, Zhang P, Qi H, Zhang K, et al. Leaf hydraulic decline coordinates stomatal and photosynthetic limitations through anatomical adjustments under drought stress in cotton. Front Plant Sci. 2025;16:1622308. 10.3389/fpls.2025.1622308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12287040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40708581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchin RM, Medlyn BE, Tjoelker MG, Ellsworth DS. Decoupling between stomatal conductance and photosynthesis occurs under extreme heat in broadleaf tree species regardless of water access. Glob Chang Biol. 2023;29:6319&#x2013;35. 10.1111/gcb.16929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/gcb.16929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37698501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckley TN, John GP, Scoffoni C, Sack L. The sites of evaporation within leaves. Plant Physiol. 2017;173:1763&#x2013;82. 10.1104/pp.16.01605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1104/pp.16.01605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5338672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28153921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brodribb TJ, Cochard H. Hydraulic failure defines the recovery and point of death in water-stressed conifers. Plant Physiol. 2009;149:575&#x2013;84. 10.1104/pp.108.129783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1104/pp.108.129783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2613726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19011001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terashima I, Wong SC, Osmond CB, Farquhar GD. Characterisation of non-uniform photosynthesis induced by abscisic acid in leaves having different mesophyll anatomies. Plant Cell Physiol. 1988;29:385&#x2013;94. 10.1093/oxfordjournals.pcp.a077506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/oxfordjournals.pcp.a077506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyschlag W, Pfanz H. A fast method to detect the occurrence of nonhomogeneous distribution of stomatal aperture in heterobaric plant leaves - Experiments with arbutus Unedo L. during the diurnal course. Oecologia. 1990;82:52&#x2013;5. 10.1007/BF00318533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00318533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28313137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downton WJS, Loveys BR, Grant WJR. Stomatal closure fully accounts for the inhibition of photosynthesis by abscisic acid. New Phytol. 1988;108:263&#x2013;6. 10.1111/j.1469-8137.1988.tb04161.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-8137.1988.tb04161.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33873929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medrano H, Escalona JM, Bota J, Gul&#xed;as J, Flexas J. Regulation of photosynthesis of C3 plants in response to progressive drought: stomatal conductance as a reference parameter. Ann Bot. 2002;89:895&#x2013;905. 10.1093/aob/mcf079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/aob/mcf079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4233802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12102515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Q, Roche D, Monaco TA, Hole D. Stomatal conductance is a key parameter to assess limitations to photosynthesis and growth potential in barley genotypes. Plant Biol. 2006;8:515&#x2013;21. 10.1055/s-2006-923964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2006-923964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16906488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West JD, Peak D, Peterson JQ, Mott KA. Dynamics of stomatal patches for a single surface of xanthium strumarium L. leaves observed with fluorescence and thermal images. Plant Cell Environ. 2005;28:633&#x2013;41. 10.1111/j.1365-3040.2005.01309.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-3040.2005.01309.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Moreiras AM, Gra&#xf1;a E, Reigosa MJ, Araniti F. Imaging of chlorophyll a fluorescence in natural compound-induced stress detection. Front Plant Sci. 2020;11:583590. 10.3389/fpls.2020.583590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7779684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33408728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song G, Wang Q, Zhuang J, Jin J. Dynamics of leaf chlorophyll fluorescence parameters can well be tracked by coupling VIS-NIR-SWIR hyperspectral reflectance and light drivers in partial least-squares regression. Sci Hortic (Amsterdam). 2024;325:112651. 10.1016/j.scienta.2023.112651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scienta.2023.112651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunasekera D, Berkowitz GA. Heterogenous stomatal closure in response to leaf water deficits is not a universal phenomenon. Plant Physiol. 1992;98:660&#x2013;5. 10.1104/pp.98.2.660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1104/pp.98.2.660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1080241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16668692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoagland DR, Arnon DI. The water-culture method for growing plants without soil. Circ Calif Agric Exp Stn. 1950;347:1&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazarevi&#x107; B, &#x160;atovi&#x107; Z, Nimac A, Vidak M, Gunja&#x10d;a J, Politeo O, et al. Application of phenotyping methods in detection of drought and salinity stress in Basil (<i>Ocimum Basilicum</i> L). Front Plant Sci. 2021;12:1&#x2013;13. 10.3389/fpls.2021.629441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2021.629441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7929983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33679843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitajima M, Butler WL. Quenching of chlorophyll fluorescence and primary photochemistry in chloroplasts by dibromothymoquinone. Biochim Biophys Acta (BBA)-Bioenergetics. 1975;376:105&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0005-2728(75)90209-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1125215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genty B, Briantais JM, Baker NR. The relationship between the quantum yield of photosynthetic electron transport and quenching of chlorophyll fluorescence. Biochim Biophys Acta - Gen Subj. 1989;990:87&#x2013;92. 10.1016/S0304-4165(89)80016-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0304-4165(89)80016-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilger W, Bj&#xf6;rkman O. Role of the xanthophyll cycle in photoprotection elucidated by measurements of light-induced absorbance changes, fluorescence and photosynthesis in leaves of Hedera canariensis. Photosynth Res. 1990;25:173&#x2013;85. 10.1007/BF00033159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00033159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24420348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiber U, Schliwa U, Bilger W. Continuous recording of photochemical and non-photochemical chlorophyll fluorescence quenching with a new type of modulation fluorometer. Photosynth Res. 1986;10:51&#x2013;62. 10.1007/BF00024185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00024185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24435276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer DM, Johnson G, Kiirats O, Edwards GE. New fluorescence parameters for the determination of Q A redox state and excitation energy fluxes. Photosynth Res. 2004;79:209&#x2013;18. 10.1023/B:PRES.0000015391.99477.0d.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/B:PRES.0000015391.99477.0d</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16228395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genty B, Harbinson J, Cailly AL, Rizza F. March. Fate of excitation at PS II in leaves: the non-photochemical side. In: third BBSRC Robert Hill symposium on photosynthesis, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gitelson AA, Merzlyak MN, Chivkunova OB. Optical properties and nondestructive estimation of anthocyanin content in plant leaves. Photochem Photobiol. 2001;74:38. 10.1562/0031-8655(2001)0740038OPANEO2.0.CO2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1562/0031-8655(2001)0740038OPANEO2.0.CO2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11460535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gitelson AA, Gritz Y, Merzlyak MN. Relationships between leaf chlorophyll content and spectral reflectance and algorithms for non-destructive chlorophyll assessment in higher plant leaves. J Plant Physiol. 2003;160:271&#x2013;82. 10.1078/0176-1617-00887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1078/0176-1617-00887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12749084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rouse JW, Haas RH, Schell JA, Deering DW. Monitoring vegetation systems in the great plains with ERTS. NASA Spec Publ. 1974;351:309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merzlyak MN, Gitelson AA, Chivkunova OB, Rakitin VY. Non-destructive optical detection of pigment changes during leaf senescence and fruit ripening. Physiol Plant. 1999;106:135&#x2013;41. 10.1034/j.1399-3054.1999.106119.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1034/j.1399-3054.1999.106119.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penuelas J, Baret F, Filella I. Semi-empirical indices to assess carotenoids/chlorophyll a ratio from leaf spectral reflectance. Photosynthetica. 1995;31:221&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gobron N, Pinty B, Verstraete MM, Widlowski J-L. Advanced vegetation indices optimized for up-coming sensors: design, performance, and applications. IEEE Trans Geosci Remote Sens. 2000;38:2489&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/36.885197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gitelson AA, Merzlyak MN. Remote Estimation of chlorophyll content in higher plant leaves. Int J Remote Sens. 1997;18:2691&#x2013;7. 10.1080/014311697217558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/014311697217558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weyers JDB, Meidner H. Methods in stomatal research. Harlow: Longman Scientific &amp; Technical; 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider CA, Rasband WS, Eliceiri KW. NIH image to imageJ: 25 years of image analysis. Nat Methods. 2012;9:671&#x2013;5. 10.1038/nmeth.2089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nmeth.2089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5554542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22930834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weatherley PE. Studies in the water relations of the cotton plant: I. the field measurement of water deficits in leaves. New Phytol. 1950;49:81&#x2013;97. 10.1111/j.1469-8137.1950.tb05146.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-8137.1950.tb05146.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Littell RC, Pendergast J, Natarajan R. Modelling covariance structure in the analysis of repeated measures data. Stat Med. 2000;19:1793&#x2013;819. 10.1002/1097-0258(20000715)19:13%3C1793::AID-SIM482%3E3.0.CO;2-Q.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/1097-0258(20000715)19:13&lt;1793::AID-SIM482&gt;3.0.CO;2-Q</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10861779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawson T, Blatt MR. Stomatal size, speed, and responsiveness impact on photosynthesis and water use efficiency. Plant Physiol. 2014;164:1556&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1104/pp.114.237107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3982722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24578506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z, Li S, Wan X, Liu S. Strategies of tree species to adapt to drought from leaf stomatal regulation and stem embolism resistance to root properties. Front Plant Sci. 2022;13:926535. 10.3389/fpls.2022.926535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9552884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36237513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drake PL, Froend RH, Franks PJ. Smaller, faster stomata: scaling of stomatal size, rate of response, and stomatal conductance. J Exp Bot. 2013;64:495&#x2013;505. 10.1093/jxb/ers347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jxb/ers347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3542046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23264516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan R, Ma X, Hussain Q, Chen K, Farooq S, Asim M, et al. Transcriptome and anatomical studies reveal alterations in leaf thickness under long-term drought stress in tobacco. J Plant Physiol. 2023;281:153920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jplph.2023.153920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36680840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Liu J, Liu H, Qiu R, Gao Y, Duan A. Role of hydraulic signal and ABA in decrease of leaf stomatal and mesophyll conductance in soil Drought-Stressed tomato. Front Plant Sci. 2021;12:653186. 10.3389/fpls.2021.653186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8118518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33995449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou H, Zhou G, He Q, Zhou L, Ji Y, Lv X. Capability of leaf water content and its threshold values in reflection of soil&#x2013;plant water status in maize during prolonged drought. Ecol Indic. 2021;124:107395. 10.1016/j.ecolind.2021.107395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2021.107395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiorin L, Brodribb TJ, Anfodillo T. Transport efficiency through uniformity: organization of veins and stomata in angiosperm leaves. New Phytol. 2016;209:216&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nph.13577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26224215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stokes VJ, Morecroft MD, Morison JIL. Boundary layer conductance for contrasting leaf shapes in a deciduous broadleaved forest canopy. Agric Meteorol. 2006;139:40&#x2013;54. 10.1016/j.agrformet.2006.05.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.agrformet.2006.05.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flexas J, Medrano H. Drought-inhibition of photosynthesis in C3 plants: stomatal and non-stomatal limitations revisited. Ann Bot. 2002;89:183&#x2013;9. 10.1093/aob/mcf027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/aob/mcf027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4233792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12099349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flexas J, Ribas-Carbo M, Diaz&#x2010;Espejo A, Galm&#xe9;s J, Medrano H. Mesophyll conductance to CO2: current knowledge and future prospects. Plant Cell Environ. 2008;31:602&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-3040.2007.01757.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17996013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Th&#xe9;roux-Rancourt G, &#xc9;thier G, Pepin S. Threshold response of mesophyll CO2 conductance to leaf hydraulics in highly transpiring hybrid Poplar clones exposed to soil drying. J Exp Bot. 2014;65:741&#x2013;53. 10.1093/jxb/ert436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jxb/ert436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3904724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24368507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe1;rquez DA, Stuart-Williams H, Cernusak LA, Farquhar GD. Assessing the CO2 concentration at the surface of photosynthetic mesophyll cells. New Phytol. 2023;238:1446&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nph.18784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36751879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalaji MH, Goltsev VN, &#x17b;uk-Golaszewska K, Zivcak M, Brestic M. Chlorophyll fluorescence: understanding crop performance - basics and applications. CRC; 2017. 10.1201/9781315153605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murchie EH, Niyogi KK. Manipulation of photoprotection to improve plant photosynthesis. Plant Physiol. 2011;155:86&#x2013;92. 10.1104/pp.110.168831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1104/pp.110.168831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3075776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21084435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lichtenthaler HK, Buschmann C, Knapp M. How to correctly determine the different chlorophyll fluorescence parameters and the chlorophyll fluorescence decrease ratio R Fd of leaves with the PAM fluorometer. Photosynthetica. 2005;43:379&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11099-005-0062-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidi L, Lo Piccolo E, Landi M. Chlorophyll fluorescence, photoinhibition and abiotic stress: does it make any difference the fact to be a C3 or C4 species? Front Plant Sci. 2019;10:174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2019.00174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6382737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30838014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Digrado A, de la Motte LG, Bachy A, Mozaffar A, Schoon N, Bussotti F, et al. Decrease in the photosynthetic performance of temperate grassland species does not lead to a decline in the gross primary production of the ecosystem. Front Plant Sci. 2018;9:67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpls.2018.00067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5807415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29459875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milliken AL. Exploring natural variation in foliar and non-foliar tissues to improve yield potential in Pisum sativum. Doctoral thesis. University of Essex; 2025. 10.5526/ERR-00040686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu F, Zhang Y, Guo J. Effects of drought stress on photosynthetic physiological characteristics, leaf microstructure, and related gene expression of yellow horn. Plant Signal Behav. 2023;18:2215025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15592324.2023.2215025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10228403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37243677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javornik T, Carovi&#x107;-Stanko K, Gunja&#x10d;a J, Vidak M, Lazarevi&#x107; B. Monitoring drought stress in common bean using chlorophyll fluorescence and multispectral imaging. Plants. 2023;12:1386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants12061386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10059887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36987074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serrano L. Effects of leaf structure on reflectance estimates of chlorophyll content. Int J Remote Sens. 2008;29:5265&#x2013;74. 10.1080/01431160802036359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01431160802036359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacquemoud S, Ustin S. Variation due to leaf structural, chemical, and physiological traits. In: Leaf Optical Properties. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press; 2019. p. 170&#x2013;194. 10.1017/9781108686457.006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q, Jin J. Leaf transpiration of drought tolerant plant can be captured by hyperspectral reflectance using PLSR analysis. IForest. 2016;9:30&#x2013;7. 10.3832/ifor1634-008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3832/ifor1634-008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaei Nejad A, Harbinson J, Van Meeteren U. Dynamics of spatial heterogeneity of stomatal closure in Tradescantia virginiana altered by growth at high relative air humidity. J Exp Bot. 2006;57:3669&#x2013;78. 10.1093/jxb/erl114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jxb/erl114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16982653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer S, Genty B. Mapping intercellular CO2 mole fraction (Ci) in Rosa rubiginosa leaves fed with abscisic acid by using chlorophyll fluorescence imaging: significance of ci estimated from leaf gas exchange. Plant Physiol. 1998;116:947&#x2013;57. 10.1104/pp.116.3.947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1104/pp.116.3.947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC35096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9501127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brodribb T, Brodersen CR, Carriqui M, Tonet V, Rodriguez Dominguez C, McAdam S. Linking xylem network failure with leaf tissue death. New Phytol. 2021;232:68&#x2013;79. 10.1111/nph.17577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nph.17577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34164816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song G, Wang Q. Developing hyperspectral indices for assessing seasonal variations in the ratio of chlorophyll to carotenoid in deciduous forests. Remote Sens. 2022;14:1324. 10.3390/rs14061324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/rs14061324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wise RR, Ortiz-Lopez A, Ort DR. Spatial distribution of photosynthesis during drought in field-grown and acclimated and nonacclimated growth chamber-grown cotton. Plant Physiol. 1992;100:26&#x2013;32. 10.1104/pp.100.1.26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1104/pp.100.1.26</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1075512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16652956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Detto M, Pacala SW. Plant hydraulics, stomatal control, and the response of a tropical forest to water stress over multiple temporal scales. Glob Chang Biol. 2022;28:4359&#x2013;76. 10.1111/gcb.16179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/gcb.16179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35373899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veselova TV, Veselovskii VA, Chernavskii DS. Stress u rastenii (biofizicheskii podkhod). Plant stress: a biophys approach. Moscow: Mosk Gos Univ; 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckley TN, Mott KA. Stomatal responses to non-local changes in PFD: evidence for long&#x2010;distance hydraulic interactions. Plant Cell Environ. 2000;23:301&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-3040.2000.00552.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>