<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41491965</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6543</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in nephrology and hypertension</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Nephrol Hypertens</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>From stones to system: integrating kidney stones disease into the cardiovascular-kidney-metabolic continuum.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>226</StartPage><EndPage>235</EndPage><MedlinePgn>226-235</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MNH.0000000000001149</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To reposition kidney stone disease within the cardiovascular-kidney-metabolic continuum and synthesize recent evidence on therapeutics, clinician-supervised digital monitoring, and value-based care implementation to modernize prevention and follow-up.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Epidemiology shows a rise in kidney stone disease prevalence across cardiovascular-kidney-metabolic stages independent of demographics. Comparative-effectiveness analyses suggest fewer stone events with sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitor(s) vs. active comparators, while early randomized data demonstrate meaningful reductions in urinary supersaturation in phenotype-matched stone formers. Digital hydration programs using validated connected bottles and just-in-time prompts increase 24-h urine output in feasibility studies; at-home urine pH and urine conductivity measurement offer pragmatic proxies for day-to-day risk. However, clinical validation, privacy governance, and regulatory readiness of software-as-a-medical-device remain variable.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Embedding kidney stone disease prevention within a cardiovascular-kidney-metabolic program supports value-based outcomes. A hybrid "Care, Remote Monitoring, Medication optimization, Nudges pathway" links early risk identification to telemonitoring and titration. Integrating urinary lithogenic profiling into cardiovascular-kidney-metabolic screening flags asymptomatic patients with lithogenic profiles before a first stone, enabling prevention of stones and chronic kidney disease progression. Priorities consist in validation of digital urinary biomarkers (time-in-target volume/pH) and deployment of hybrid care. This patient-centred hybrid model can shift current episodic procedures to anticipatory, measurable, and scalable prevention within routine cardiovascular-kidney-metabolic care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pozdzik</LastName><ForeName>Agnieszka</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>REMEDIAB Center.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kidney Stone Clinic.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire (CHU) HELORA, Mons, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakhaee</LastName><ForeName>Khashayar</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Division of Mineral Metabolism, Charles and Jane Pak Centre for Mineral Metabolism and Clinical Research, UT Southwestern, Dallas, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Colin</LastName><ForeName>Ides M</ForeName><Initials>IM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>REMEDIAB Center.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kidney Stone Clinic.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Nephrol Hypertens</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9303753</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1062-4821</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000077203">Sodium-Glucose Transporter 2 Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007669" MajorTopicYN="Y">Kidney Calculi</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002318" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiovascular Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077203" MajorTopicYN="N">Sodium-Glucose Transporter 2 Inhibitors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007668" MajorTopicYN="Y">Kidney</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiovascular-kidney-metabolic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nephrolithiasis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">telemonitoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urine pH</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41491965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MNH.0000000000001149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00041552-202603000-00013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pozdzik A, Maalouf N, Letavernier E, et al. Meeting report of the &#x201c;Symposium on kidney stones and mineral metabolism: calcium kidney stones in 2017&#x201d;. J Nephrol 2019; 32:681&#x2013;698.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Liao X. Kidney stone disease increases the risk of cardiovascular events. PLoS One 2025; 20:e0330069.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maroufizadeh S, Joukar F, Sheida F, et al. The relationship between metabolic syndrome and kidney stone disease: a cross-sectional study from the PERSIAN Guilan Cohort Study. Metab Syndr Relat Disord 2025; 23:305&#x2013;311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habib T, Zaidan N, Jaber K, et al. Association of kidney stone disease with metabolic dysfunction associated liver disease and metabolic dysfunction associated steatohepatitis: a national inpatient sample study. JGH Open 2025; 9:e70280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganesan C, Thomas IC, Romero R, et al. Osteoporosis, fractures, and bone mineral density screening in Veterans with kidney stone disease. J Bone Miner Res 2021; 36:872&#x2013;878.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Ni J, Zhou Y, Liu X. Association between body mass index, urine metabolic disturbances, and nephrolithiasis in pediatric patients. Pediatr Nephrol 2025; doi: 10.1007/s00467-025-06865-4. [Epub ahead of print].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00467-025-06865-4.</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kou T, Qian X, Liu Y, et al. Global, regional, and national burden of peripheral artery disease: a systematic analysis of prevalence, incidence, deaths, and DALYs with projections for the next 15&#x200a;years. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis 2025; 35:104226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song L, Maalouf NM, Feingold KR, et al. Wilson DP, editors. Endotext [Internet]. South Dartmouth (MA): MDText.com, Inc.; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bargagli M, Scoglio M, Howles SA, Fuster DG. Kidney stone disease: risk factors, pathophysiology and management. Nat Rev Nephrol 2025; 21:794&#x2013;808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arivoli K, Valicevic AN, Oerline MK, et al. Preventive pharmacological therapy and risk of recurrent urinary stone disease. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 2024; 19:565&#x2013;572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Ambrosio V, Ferraro PM, Lombardi G, et al. Unravelling the complex relationship between diet and nephrolithiasis: the role of nutrigenomics and nutrigenetics. Nutrients 2022; 4961.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collaboration NCDRF: worldwide trends in hypertension prevalence and progress in treatment and control from 1990 to 2019: a pooled analysis of 1201 population-representative studies with 104 million participants. Lancet 2021; 398:957&#x2013;980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziemba JB, Matlaga BR. Epidemiology and economics of nephrolithiasis. Investig Clin Urol 2017; 58:299&#x2013;306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambaro A, Lombardi G, Caletti C, et al. Nephrolithiasis: a red flag for cardiovascular risk. J Clin Med 2022; 11:5512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Ambrosio V, Moochhala S, Unwin RJ, Ferraro PM. Why is diagnosis, investigation, and improved management of kidney stone disease important? Nonpharmacological and pharmacological treatments for nephrolithiasis. Expert Rev Clin Pharmacol 2022; 15:407&#x2013;414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K, Ge J, Han W, et al. Risk factors for kidney stone disease recurrence: a comprehensive meta-analysis. BMC Urol 2022; 22:62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Monsalve M, Duran-Poveda M, Gomez Dos Santos V, et al. Impact of obesity on hospitalization burden of urolithiasis in Spain between 1997 and 2021. J Clin Med 2025; 14:381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu G, Tian J, Shi F, et al. Association of cardiovascular-kidney-metabolic syndrome stages with kidney stone prevalence: a population-based analysis of NHANES. BMJ Open 2025; 15:e096533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambaro G, Tzelves L, Skolarikos A, et al. The new guidelines of the European Association of Urology on Urolithiasis: the urology-nephrology intersection. Nephrol Dial Transplant 2023; 38:258&#x2013;260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geraghty RM, Davis NF, Tzelves L, et al. Best practice in interventional management of urolithiasis: an update from the European Association of Urology Guidelines Panel for Urolithiasis. Eur Urol Focus 2023; 9:199&#x2013;208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skolarikos A, Geraghty R, Somani B, et al. European Association of Urology Guidelines on the Diagnosis and Treatment of Urolithiasis. Eur Urol 2025; 88:64&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quhal F, Seitz C. Guideline of the guidelines: urolithiasis. Curr Opin Urol 2021; 31:125&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng G, Zhu W, Somani B, et al. International Alliance of Urolithiasis (IAU) guidelines on the management of pediatric urolithiasis. Urolithiasis 2024; 52:124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng G, Zhu W, Robertson WG, et al. International Alliance of Urolithiasis (IAU) guidelines on the metabolic evaluation and medical management of urolithiasis. Urolithiasis 2022; 51:4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papatsoris A, Geavlete B, Radavoi GD, et al. Management of urinary stones by experts in stone disease (ESD 2025). Arch Ital Urol Androl 2025; 97:14085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahrreiss V, Seitz C, Quhal F. Medical management of urolithiasis: great efforts and limited progress. Asian J Urol 2024; 11:149&#x2013;155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez Cuellar CI, Wang PZT, Freundlich M, Filler G. Educational review: role of the pediatric nephrologists in the work-up and management of kidney stones. Pediatr Nephrol 2020; 35:383&#x2013;397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harmouch SS, Abou-Haidar H, Elhawary H, et al. Metabolic evaluation guidelines in patients with nephrolithiasis: are they being followed? Results of a national, multiinstitutional, quality-assessment study. Can Urol Assoc J 2018; 12:313&#x2013;318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scales CD Jr, Desai AC, Harper JD, et al. Prevention of urinary stones with hydration (PUSH): design and rationale of a clinical trial. Am J Kidney Dis 2021; 77:898&#x2013;906. e891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tahar A, Zrour H, Dupont S, Pozdzik A. Noninvasive approaches to hydration assessment: a literature review. Urolithiasis 2024; 52:132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shastri S, Patel J, Sambandam KK, Lederer ED. Kidney stone pathophysiology, evaluation and management: core curriculum. Am J Kidney Dis 2023; 82:617&#x2013;634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsampoukas G, Hossain MF, Katsouri A, et al. Urine pH, citrate, and beyond: challenges of pharmaceutical stone management in daily urological practice. Arch Ital Urol Androl 2025; 97:13798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pozdzik A, Grillo V, Sakhaee K. Gaps in kidney stone disease management: from clinical theory to patient reality. Urolithiasis 2024; 52:61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tasian GE, Denburg MR, Ellison JS. Early-onset kidney stone disease-consequences and opportunities. JAMA Pediatr 2021; 175:1203&#x2013;1204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borofsky MS, Dauw CA, York N, et al. Accuracy of daily fluid intake measurements using a &#x201c;smart&#x201d; water bottle. Urolithiasis 2018; 46:343&#x2013;348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahmoradi L, Azizpour A, Bejani M, et al. Prevention and control of urinary tract stones using a smartphone-based self-care application: design and evaluation. BMC Med Inform Decis Mak 2021; 21:299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cune J, Fernandez X, Carne X, et al. Pilot study of the usability and functionality of a smart ph meter and a mobile medical application for urine ph monitoring. Arch Esp Urol 2021; 74:692&#x2013;698.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez JM, Mainez JA, Mora Christian J, et al. Usefulness and acceptability of a Smart pH meter and mobile medical App as a monitoring tool in patients with urolithiasis: short-term prospective study. Arch Esp Urol 2022; 75:60&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conroy DE, Marks J, Cutshaw A, et al. Promoting fluid intake to increase urine volume for kidney stone prevention: protocol for a randomized controlled efficacy trial of the sip(IT) intervention. Contemp Clin Trials 2024; 138:107454.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mainez JA, Galan JA, Lopez JM, et al. User profile and engagement with a digital health application for urolithiasis management: a descriptive study of the first 699 users. Actas Urol Esp (Engl Ed) 2025; 49:501819.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winoker JS, Koo K, Huang MM, et al. Systematic evaluation of smartphone applications for the medical management of nephrolithiasis. J Endourol 2021; 35:1058&#x2013;1066.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen R, Fernie G, Roshan Fekr A. Monitoring fluid intake by commercially available smart water bottles. Sci Rep 2022; 12:4402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naik N, Talyshinskii A, Rassweiler J, et al. Digital health innovations in urology: telemedicine, wearables, and mobile applications - a systematic review of literature. Curr Opin Urol 2024; 34:116&#x2013;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talyshinskii A, Bakhman G, Hameed BZ, et al. Current state of mobile health apps in endourology: a review of mobile platforms in marketplaces and literature. Ther Adv Urol 2023; 15:17562872231176368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ungerer GN, Winoker JS, Healy KA, et al. Mobile and eHealth technologies in the management and prevention of nephrolithiasis: a systematic review. Actas Urol Esp (Engl Ed) 2024; 48:25&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borghi L, Meschi T, Amato F, et al. Urinary volume, water and recurrences in idiopathic calcium nephrolithiasis: a 5-year randomized prospective study. J Urol 1996; 155:839&#x2013;843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Littlejohns TJ, Neal NL, Bradbury KE, et al. Fluid intake and dietary factors and the risk of incident kidney stones in UK Biobank: a population-based prospective cohort study. Eur Urol Focus 2020; 6:752&#x2013;761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Streeper NM, Lehman K, Conroy DE. Acceptability of mobile health technology for promoting fluid consumption in patients with nephrolithiasis. Urology 2018; 122:64&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright HC, Alshara L, DiGennaro H, et al. The impact of smart technology on adherence rates and fluid management in the prevention of kidney stones. Urolithiasis 2022; 50:29&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Streeper NM, Fairbourn JD, Marks J, et al. Feasibility of Mini sip(IT) behavioral intervention to increase urine volume in patients with kidney stones. Urology 2023; 179:39&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naik N, Surendranath N, Raju SAB, et al. Hybrid deep learning-enabled framework for enhancing security, data integrity, and operational performance in Healthcare Internet of Things (H-IoT) environments. Sci Rep 2025; 15:31039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naik N, Hameed BMZ, Sooriyaperakasam N, et al. Transforming healthcare through a digital revolution: a review of digital healthcare technologies and solutions. Front Digit Health 2022; 4:919985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edvardsson VO, Indridason OS, Haraldsson G, et al. Temporal trends in the incidence of kidney stone disease. Kidney Int 2013; 83:146&#x2013;152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ndumele CE, Rangaswami J, Chow SL, et al. Cardiovascular-kidney-metabolic health: a presidential advisory from the American Heart Association. Circulation 2023; 148:1606&#x2013;1635.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saenz-Medina J, Gomez Dos Santos V, Rodriguez-Monsalve M, et al. Cardiovascular and cerebrovascular morbidity in patients with urolithiasis: an epidemiological approach based on hospitalization burden data from 1997 to 2021. J Clin Med 2024; 13:3564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stepanova N. Balancing stone prevention and kidney function: a therapeutic dilemma. J Clin Med 2025; 14:3678.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vervaet BA, Verhulst A, De Broe ME, D&#x2019;Haese PC. The tubular epithelium in the initiation and course of intratubular nephrocalcinosis. Urol Res 2010; 38:249&#x2013;256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vervaet BA, D&#x2019;Haese PC, De Broe ME, Verhulst A. Crystalluric and tubular epithelial parameters during the onset of intratubular nephrocalcinosis: illustration of the &#x2019;fixed particle&#x2019; theory in vivo. Nephrol Dial Transplant 2009; 24:3659&#x2013;3668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robijn S, Vervaet BA, Hoppe B, et al. Lanthanum carbonate inhibits intestinal oxalate absorption and prevents nephrocalcinosis after oxalate loading in rats. J Urol 2013; 189:1960&#x2013;1966.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilzkovitz M, Kayembe EE, Geers C, Pozdzik A. Kidney stones, proteinuria and renal tubular metabolic acidosis: what is the link? Healthcare (Basel) 2022; 10:836.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao B, Daniel R, McGregor R, Tasian GE. Pediatric nephrolithiasis. Healthcare (Basel) 2023; 11:552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alfandary H, Haskin O, Davidovits M, et al. Increasing prevalence of nephrolithiasis in association with increased body mass index in children: a population based study. J Urol 2018; 199:1044&#x2013;1049.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pozdzik A, Van Haute C, Maalouf N, et al. Trust my morphology&#x201d;, the key message from a kidney stone. Urolithiasis 2021; 49:493&#x2013;494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams JC Jr, Gambaro G, Rodgers A, et al. Urine and stone analysis for the investigation of the renal stone former: a consensus conference. Urolithiasis 2021; 49:1&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crivelli JJ, Maalouf NM, Paiste HJ, et al. Disparities in kidney stone disease: a scoping review. J Urol 2021; 206:517&#x2013;525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moe OW, Pearle MS, Sakhaee K. Pharmacotherapy of urolithiasis: evidence from clinical trials. Kidney Int 2011; 79:385&#x2013;392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vallon V. State-of-the-art-review: mechanisms of action of SGLT2 inhibitors and clinical implications. Am J Hypertens 2024; 37:841&#x2013;852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CJ, Ho KT, Huang HS, et al. Sodium glucose co-transporter 2 inhibitor prevents nephrolithiasis in nondiabetes by restoring impaired autophagic flux. EBioMedicine 2025; 114:105668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollingsworth JM, Oerline MK, Hsi RS, et al. Real-world effectiveness of preventive pharmacological therapy in patients with urolithiasis: a retrospective cohort study. Am J Kidney Dis 2024; 84:83&#x2013;93. e81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldfarb DS, Modersitzki F, Asplin JR, Nazzal L. Correction to: effect of a high-citrate beverage on urine chemistry in patients with calcium kidney stones. Urolithiasis 2023; 51:105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langham RG, Kalantar-Zadeh K, Bonner A, et al. Kidney health for all: bridging the gap in kidney health education and literacy. Kidney Int 2022; 101:432&#x2013;440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deligiannis P, Lardas M, Tzelves L, et al. Diet adherence in urolithiasis patients: a mini review. Curr Urol Rep 2025; 26:61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price D, Taisan G, Sheridan K, et al. Dissemination of a patient-prioritized research agenda for kidney stone disease: patient perceptions and opportunities. Urology 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patil V, Singhal DK, Naik N, et al. Factors affecting the usage of wearable device technology for healthcare among Indian adults: a cross-sectional study. J Clin Med 2022; 11:7019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talyshinskii A, Naik N, Hameed BMZ, et al. Telemedicine in endourology for patient management and healthcare delivery: current status and future perspectives. Curr Urol Rep 2024; 25:299&#x2013;310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Meulemeester J, Keymeulen B, De Block C, et al. One-year real-world benefits of Tandem Control-IQ technology on glucose management and person-reported outcomes in adults with type 1 diabetes: a prospective observational cohort study. Diabetologia 2025; 68:948&#x2013; 960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pak CY, Kaplan R, Bone H, et al. A simple test for the diagnosis of absorptive, resorptive and renal hypercalciurias. N Engl J Med 1975; 292:497&#x2013;500.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>