<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41049335</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Neurohumoral Dysregulation in Acute Myocardial Infarction With Chronic Kidney Disease: Implications for Prognosis and Management.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e93692</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e93692</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e93692</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.93692</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Acute myocardial infarction (AMI) and chronic kidney disease (CKD) often coexist, and both are associated with neurohumoral imbalances that may worsen cardiovascular outcomes. Reduced kidney function can contribute to arterial stiffness and activation of the renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system (RAAS), which promotes vasoconstriction, sodium and water retention, myocardial remodeling, and fibrosis, mechanisms that exacerbate both cardiac and renal dysfunction. Endothelial injury is also common in these patients, and von Willebrand factor (vWF) serves as a recognized marker of endothelial dysfunction, contributing to thrombotic risk and microvascular impairment. Objective To explore the cross-sectional associations between renal function and the biomarkers aldosterone, angiotensin-converting enzyme (ACE), atrial natriuretic peptide (ANP), and vWF in patients with AMI and heart failure. Methods In this cross-sectional study, 106 patients hospitalized for AMI and heart failure were stratified by estimated glomerular filtration rate (GFR) into Group 1 (&#x2264;90 mL/min) and Group 2 (&gt;90 mL/min). While CKD is conventionally defined as GFR &lt;60 mL/min, the &#x2264;90 mL/min cutoff was chosen to evaluate biomarker variation across a broader renal function range, including early decline. All eligible patients from the study period were included; no formal power calculation was performed. Neurohumoral markers were measured via enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA). Heart failure was an inclusion criterion for all participants. Results Baseline characteristics were comparable between groups. Aldosterone and ACE were higher in patients with GFR &#x2264;90 mL/min (p-values 0.01-0.05; below the prespecified &#x3b1; = 0.01). ANP and vWF did not differ between groups, which may reflect limited sensitivity to early renal function differences or other physiological influences. Conclusion The observed association between reduced GFR and elevated aldosterone and ACE suggests RAAS-related neurohumoral activation in AMI patients with heart failure. The lack of difference in ANP and vWF highlights potential marker-specific limitations. Targeting RAAS and other relevant pathways may offer therapeutic benefits for improving outcomes in this population; however, such approaches require confirmation in prospective interventional trials. These findings are exploratory and hypothesis-generating, underscoring the need for larger, longitudinal, and interventional studies to clarify the&#xa0;prognostic and therapeutic implications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Polianska et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Polianska</LastName><ForeName>Oksana</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Physical Rehabilitation and Sport Medicine, Bukovin&#x456;an State Medical University, Chernivtsi, UKR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tashchuk</LastName><ForeName>Victor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Physical Rehabilitation and Sports Medicine, Bukovinian State Medical University, Chernivtsi, UKR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hulaha</LastName><ForeName>Olha</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Clinic Optima Medycyna, Opole, POL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Olinchuk</LastName><ForeName>Valentyna</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Bukovinian State Medical University, Chernivtsi, UKR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moskaliuk</LastName><ForeName>Inna</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, University of Opole, Opole, POL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kushnir</LastName><ForeName>Yevhen</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, St. Barnabas Hospital, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aldosterone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">angiotensin-converting enzyme</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic kidney disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myocardial infarction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurohumoral imbalance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Commission on Biomedical Ethics of Bukovinian State Medical University issued approval 6. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41049335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12489866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.93692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chronic kidney disease management in the United Kingdom: NEOERICA project results. Stevens PE, O'Donoghue DJ, de Lusignan S, et al. Kidney Int. 2007;72:92&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17440495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association of plasma aldosterone with cardiovascular mortality in patients with low estimated GFR: the Ludwigshafen Risk and Cardiovascular Health (LURIC) Study. Tomaschitz A, Pilz S, Ritz E, Grammer T, Drechsler C, Boehm BO, M&#xe4;rz W. Am J Kidney Dis. 2011;57:403&#x2013;414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21186074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spironolactone to prevent cardiovascular events in early-stage chronic kidney disease (STOP-CKD): Study protocol for a randomized controlled pilot trial. Ng KP, Jain P, Heer G, et al. Trials. 2014;15:158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4113230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24886272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldosterone and cardiovascular diseases. Parksook WW, Williams GH. Cardiovasc Res. 2023;119:28&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35388416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Current strategies to achieve further cardiac and renal protection through enhanced renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system inhibition. Alfie J, Aparicio LS, Waisman GD. Rev Recent Clin Trials. 2011;6:134&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21241234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2023 ESC Guidelines for the management of acute coronary syndromes. Byrne RA, Rossello X, Coughlan JJ, et al. Eur Heart J. 2023;44:3720&#x2013;3826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37622654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prediction of creatinine clearance from serum creatinine. Cockcroft DW, Gault MH. Nephron. 1976;16:31&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1244564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>KDIGO 2024 Clinical practice guideline for the evaluation and management of chronic kidney disease. Kidney Disease: Improving Global Outcomes (KDIGO) CKD Work Group. https://kdigo.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/KDIGO-2024-CKD-Guideline.pdf Kidney Int. 2024;105:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38490803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adrenal aldosterone biosynthesis is elevated in a model of chronic renal failure--Role of local adrenal renin-angiotensin system. Endemann DH, Wolf K, Boeger CA, Riegger GA, Kr&#xe4;mer BK. Nephron Physiol. 2004;97:0&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15218317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serum aldosterone and death, end-stage renal disease, and cardiovascular events in blacks and whites: Findings from the Chronic Renal Insufficiency Cohort (CRIC) Study. Deo R, Yang W, Khan AM, et al. Hypertension. 2014;64:103&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4089190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24752431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>High plasma aldosterone levels on admission are associated with death in patients presenting with acute ST-elevation myocardial infarction. Beygui F, Collet JP, Benoliel JJ, Vignolles N, Dumaine R, Barth&#xe9;l&#xe9;my O, Montalescot G. Circulation. 2006;114:2604&#x2013;2610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17116769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plasma aldosterone levels are associated with increased cardiovascular mortality: The Ludwigshafen Risk and Cardiovascular Health (LURIC) study. Tomaschitz A, Pilz S, Ritz E, Meinitzer A, Boehm BO, M&#xe4;rz W. Eur Heart J. 2010;31:1237&#x2013;1247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20200015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mineralcorticoid receptor blockers in chronic kidney disease. Erraez S, L&#xf3;pez-Mesa M, G&#xf3;mez-Fern&#xe1;ndez P. Nefrologia (Engl Ed) 2021;41:258&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36166243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldosterone stimulates proliferation of cardiac fibroblasts by activating Ki-RasA and MAPK1/2 signaling. Stockand JD, Meszaros JG. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2003;284:0&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12388314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Role of renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system inhibitors in heart failure and chronic kidney disease. Singhania N, Bansal S, Mohandas S, Nimmatoori DP, Ejaz AA, Singhania G. Drugs Context. 2020;9:2020&#x2013;2027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7673621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33240389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathophysiology of the cardio-renal syndromes types 1-5: An uptodate. Di Lullo L, Bellasi A, Barbera V, et al. Indian Heart J. 2017;69:255&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5415026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28460776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldosterone and mineralocorticoid receptors-Physiology and pathophysiology. Funder JW. Int J Mol Sci. 2017;18:1032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5454944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28492512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldosterone and mineralocorticoid receptors in regulation of the cardiovascular system and pathological remodelling of the heart and arteries. Sztechman D, Czarzasta K, Cudnoch-Jedrzejewska A, Szczepanska-Sadowska E, Zera T. J Physiol Pharmacol. 2018;69</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30898981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Does aldosterone upregulate the brain renin-angiotensin system in rats with heart failure? Yu Y, Wei SG, Zhang ZH, Gomez-Sanchez E, Weiss RM, Felder RB. Hypertension. 2008;51:727&#x2013;733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2790402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18227408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brain mineralocorticoid receptors in cognition and cardiovascular homeostasis. Gomez-Sanchez EP. Steroids. 2014;91:20&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4302001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25173821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epithelial Na&#x207a; sodium channels in magnocellular cells of the rat supraoptic and paraventricular nuclei. Teruyama R, Sakuraba M, Wilson LL, Wandrey NE, Armstrong WE. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2012;302:273&#x2013;285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3287361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22045317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mineralocorticoid receptors in the heart: Lessons from cell-selective transgenic animals. Young MJ, Rickard AJ. J Endocrinol. 2015;224:0&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25335936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldosterone in heart and kidney diseases. Rentoukas EI, Lazaros GA, Zirogiannis PN. http://www.hellenicjcardiol.org/archive/full_text/2005/6/2005_6_408.pdf Hell J Cardiol. 2005;46:408&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16422128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of finerenone on chronic kidney disease outcomes in type 2 diabetes. Bakris GL, Agarwal R, Anker SD, et al. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:2219&#x2013;2229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33264825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angiotensin-neprilysin inhibition and renal outcomes in heart failure with preserved ejection fraction. Mc Causland FR, Lefkowitz MP, Claggett B, et al. Circulation. 2020;142:1236&#x2013;1245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32845715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldosterone in chronic kidney disease and renal outcomes. Verma A, Vaidya A, Subudhi S, Waikar SS. Eur Heart J. 2022;43:3781&#x2013;3791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10147385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36219773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>