<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41571706</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Rheological characterisation of clay-cement sealing suspensions with fractionated coal fly ashes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2856</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2856</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2856</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-30793-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study investigates the rheological behaviour of clay-cement sealing suspensions modified with dry size-fractionated coal fly ashes of contrasting chemical composition. High-calcium S1 ashes and siliceous S2 ashes were separated into ultrafine (&lt;&#x2009;10&#xa0;&#x3bc;m), fine (5-20&#xa0;&#x3bc;m), and middle (20-100&#xa0;&#x3bc;m) fractions to isolate size-dependent reactivity. Rotational and oscillatory rheometry demonstrate that Ca-rich fractions induce rapid structuration: at 20wt% ash addition, the Bingham yield stress rises from ~&#x2009;20-30&#xa0;Pa in reference suspensions to &gt;&#x2009;150&#xa0;Pa, and exceeds 400&#xa0;Pa at 30wt% S1 loading, accompanied by steep increases in storage modulus (G' up to 10&#x2077;-10&#x2078;Pa for ultrafine fractions). In contrast, S2 ashes disperse the clay-cement network, lowering yield stress to ~&#x2009;15-60&#xa0;Pa even at 40 wt% replacement and maintaining moderate viscoelastic stiffness (G'~10&#x2074;-10&#x2075;Pa). Particle fineness amplifies these trends: S1.UF promotes early hydration products precipitation and slip-layer formation, whereas S2.UF preserves fluidity. Sodium-silicate activation introduces a distinct threshold-at 1.0-1.5wt% Na&#x2082;SiO&#x2083; the S1 systems undergo a sol-gel transition, with &#x3c4;&#x2080; surging above 200&#xa0;Pa, while S2 systems respond gradually. These results quantitatively shows how ash chemistry and granulometry govern early yield stress, viscosity, and G'/G&#x2033; ratios, and identify composition windows for either rapid sealing (Ca-rich, fine fractions) or long-distance pumpability (Si-rich, fine fractions). The work demonstrates that fractionated fly ash provides an effective design tool for tailoring rheology of low-cement, sustainable sealing slurries for hydraulic and geotechnical applications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Delihowski</LastName><ForeName>Jurij</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Materials Science and Ceramics, AGH University of Science and Technology, Cracow, Poland. ydeli@agh.edu.pl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Izak</LastName><ForeName>Piotr</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Materials Science and Ceramics, AGH University of Science and Technology, Cracow, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clay-cement suspensions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coal fly ash</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Particle size fractions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rheology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sealing suspensions</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41571706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12827270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-30793-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-30793-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Huang, X. et al. Use of self-hardening slurry for trench cutoff wall: A review. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>286</b>, 122959 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skutnik, Z., Bajda, M. &amp; Lech, M. The selection of sealing technologies of the subsoil and hydrotechnical structures and quality assurance. <i>Open. Eng.</i><b>9</b>, 420&#x2013;427 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourg, I. C., Ajo-Franklin, J. B. &amp; Clay Water, and salt: controls on the permeability of Fine-Grained sedimentary rocks. <i>Acc. Chem. Res.</i><b>50</b>, 2067&#x2013;2074 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28862427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jefferis, S. Cement-Bentonite Slurry Systems. in <i>Grouting and Deep Mixing 2012</i> 1&#x2013;24American Society of Civil Engineers, Reston, VA, (2012). 10.1061/9780784412350.0001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kipko, E. R. &amp; Po&#x142;ozow, J. A. Kompleksnyj metod tamponaza pri stroitelstwie szacht. <i>Nedra, Moskwa</i> (1984).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan, C. R. &amp; Day, S. R. Soil-Cement-Bentonite Slurry Walls. in <i>Deep Foundations 2002</i> 713&#x2013;727American Society of Civil Engineers, Reston, VA, (2002). 10.1061/40601(256)51</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inazumi, S., Tazuke, K. &amp; Kashima, S. Time-Dependent rheological behavior and MPS simulation of Cement&#x2013;Bentonite slurries with hydration accelerators for borehole backfilling applications. <i>J. Compos. Sci.</i><b>9</b>, 361 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan, C., Ruffing, D. &amp; Evans, J. C. Soil Bentonite Slurry Trench Cutoff Walls: History, Design, and Construction Practices. in <i>Geo-Congress 2022</i> 89&#x2013;99American Society of Civil Engineers, Reston, VA, (2022). 10.1061/9780784484050.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Njock, P. G. A., Chen, J., Modoni, G., Arulrajah, A. &amp; Kim Y.-H. A review of jet grouting practice and development. <i>Arab. J. Geosci.</i><b>11</b>, 459 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Z., Zhang, Y., Zhu, Y., Li, Y. &amp; Fu, R. The Strength, Permeability, and microstructure of Cement&#x2013;Bentonite Cut-Off walls enhanced by polypropylene fiber. <i>Sustainability</i><b>17</b>, 3656 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jefferis, S. A. Bentonite-cement slurries for hydraulic cut-offs. <i>International Conference Soil Mechanics and Foundation Engineering</i> 1, 435&#x2013;440 (1981).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izak, P. Reologia w ceramice. <i>Wydawnictwa AGH: Krak&#xf3;w, Poland</i> (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stempkowska, A., W&#xf3;jcik, &#x141;., Ostrowski, K. A. &amp; Gawenda, T. Low-Energy Clay&#x2013;Cement slurries find application as waterproofing membranes for limiting the migration of Contaminants&#x2014;Case studies in Poland. <i>Energies (Basel)</i>. <b>16</b>, 230 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benyounes, K. Rheological behavior of cement-based Grout with Algerian bentonite. <i>SN Appl. Sci.</i><b>1</b>, 1037 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onyelowe, K. C. &amp; Kontoni, D. P. N. A critical review of rheological models in self-compacting concrete for sustainable structures. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>13</b>, 21296 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10693590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38042887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao, C., Kutchko, B. G., Rosenbaum, E. &amp; Massoudi, M. A. Review of rheological modeling of cement slurry in oil well applications. <i>Energies (Basel)</i>. <b>13</b>, 570 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, H., Fall, M., Yilmaz, E., Li, Y. &amp; Yang, L. Effect of mineral admixtures on flow properties of fresh cemented paste backfill: assessment of time dependency and Thixotropy. <i>Powder Technol.</i><b>372</b>, 258&#x2013;266 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesboua, N., Benyounes, K. &amp; Benmounah, A. Study of the impact of bentonite on the physico-mechanical and flow properties of cement Grout. <i>Cogent Eng.</i><b>5</b>, 1446252 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, H., Zhang, Y., Zhu, W., Zhong, Q. &amp; Huang, X. Optimisation of synchronous grouting mix ratio for shield tunnels. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>14</b>, 4098 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nachbaur, L., Mutin, J. C., Nonat, A. &amp; Choplin, L. Dynamic mode rheology of cement and tricalcium silicate pastes from mixing to setting. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>31</b>, 183&#x2013;192 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roussel, N. A Thixotropy model for fresh fluid concretes: Theory, validation and applications. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>36</b>, 1797&#x2013;1806 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tregger, N. A., Pakula, M. E. &amp; Shah, S. P. Influence of clays on the rheology of cement pastes. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>40</b>, 384&#x2013;391 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrot, A., Rangeard, D. &amp; Pierre, A. Structural built-up of cement-based materials used for 3D-printing extrusion techniques. <i>Mater. Struct.</i><b>49</b>, 1213&#x2013;1220 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentz, D. P. A review of early-age properties of cement-based materials. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>38</b>, 196&#x2013;204 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mostafa, A. M. &amp; Yahia, A. New approach to assess build-up of cement-based suspensions. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>85</b>, 174&#x2013;182 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shakeel, A., Kirichek, A. &amp; Chassagne, C. Rheology and yielding transitions in mixed kaolinite/bentonite suspensions. <i>Appl. Clay Sci.</i><b>211</b>, 106206 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roussel, N., Lema&#xee;tre, A., Flatt, R. J. &amp; Coussot, P. Steady state flow of cement suspensions: A micromechanical state of the Art. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>40</b>, 77&#x2013;84 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, C. et al. Rheological properties of cement-based slurry and evaluation of rheological model: influence of particle size and shape. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>406</b>, 133498 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, F., Pu, S., Zhou, Y., Zhang, H. &amp; Zhang, Z. Effect of ultrafine mineral admixtures on the rheological properties of fresh cement paste: A review. <i>J. Building Eng.</i><b>51</b>, 104313 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaci, A., Chaouche, M. &amp; Andr&#xe9;ani, P. A. Influence of bentonite clay on the rheological behaviour of fresh mortars. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>41</b>, 373&#x2013;379 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobias, S. et al. Soil sealing and unsealing: state of the Art and examples. <i>Land. Degrad. Dev.</i><b>29</b>, 2015&#x2013;2024 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juenger, M. C. G., Winnefeld, F., Provis, J. L. &amp; Ideker, J. H. Advances in alternative cementitious binders. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>41</b>, 1232&#x2013;1243 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Heede, P. &amp; De Belie, N. Environmental impact and life cycle assessment (LCA) of traditional and &#x2018;green&#x2019; concretes: literature review and theoretical calculations. <i>Cem. Concr Compos.</i><b>34</b>, 431&#x2013;442 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashraf, M. et al. Developing a sustainable concrete incorporating bentonite clay and silica fume: mechanical and durability performance. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>337</b>, 130315 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>William, C. E., Akobo, Z. S., Ngekpe, B. E. &amp; I. &amp; Effect of Metakaolin as a partial replacement for cement on the compressive strength of high strength concrete at varying Water/Binder ratios. <i>Int. J. Civil Eng.</i><b>6</b>, 1&#x2013;6 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gil, D. M. &amp; Golewski, G. L. Potential of siliceous fly ash and silica fume as a substitute for binder in cementitious concretes. <i>E3S Web of Conferences</i> 49, 00030 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robalo, K., Costa, H., do Carmo, R. &amp; J&#xfa;lio, E. Enhanced mechanical and durability performances of low cement concrete with natural Pozzolan addition. <i>J. Adv. Concr. Technol.</i><b>19</b>, 519&#x2013;535 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wili&#x144;ska, I., Pacewska, B. &amp; Ostrowski, A. Investigation of different ways of activation of fly ash&#x2013;cement mixtures. <i>J. Therm. Anal. Calorim.</i><b>138</b>, 4203&#x2013;4213 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komljenovi&#x107;, M., Petra&#x161;inovi&#x107;-Stojkanovi&#x107;, L., Ba&#x161;&#x10d;arevi&#x107;, Z., Jovanovi&#x107;, N. &amp; Rosi&#x107;, A. Fly Ash as the potential Raw mixture component for Portland cement clinker synthesis. <i>J. Therm. Anal. Calorim.</i><b>96</b>, 363&#x2013;368 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramjan, S. et al. Influence of cement replacement with fly Ash and ground sand with different fineness on Alkali-Silica reaction of mortar. <i>Materials</i><b>14</b>, 1528 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8004033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33804759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devarangadi, M. &amp; Uma Shankar, M. Effect on engineering properties of ground granulated blast furnace slag admixed with laterite soil, cement and bentonite mixtures as a liner in landfill. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>329</b>, 129757 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, J. et al. A comprehensive review on the ground granulated blast furnace slag (GGBS) in concrete production. <i>Sustainability</i><b>14</b>, 8783 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mollamahmuto&#x11f;lu, M. &amp; Avc&#x131;, E. Engineering properties of Slag-Based superfine Cement-Stabilized clayey soil. <i>ACI Mater. J</i><b>115</b>, (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam, M. T., Dai, B., Wu, X., Hoadley, A. &amp; Zhang, L. A critical review of Ash slagging mechanisms and viscosity measurement for low-rank coal and bio-slags. <i>Front. Energy</i>. <b>15</b>, 46&#x2013;67 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasiliev, V. V. &amp; Vasileva, E. A. Pozzolanic activity of fly Ash. <i>Silic. Indus.</i><b>68</b>, 111&#x2013;117 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golewski, G. L. The role of pozzolanic activity of siliceous fly Ash in the formation of the structure of sustainable cementitious composites. <i>Sustainable Chem.</i><b>3</b>, 520&#x2013;534 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollanders, S., Adriaens, R., Skibsted, J., Cizer, &#xd6;. &amp; Elsen, J. Pozzolanic reactivity of pure calcined clays. <i>Appl. Clay Sci.</i><b>132&#x2013;133</b>, 552&#x2013;560 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almenares, R. S. et al. Industrial calcination of kaolinitic clays to make reactive Pozzolans. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater.</i><b>6</b>, 225&#x2013;232 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, C. K., Noh, M. H. &amp; Park, T. H. Rheological properties of cementitious materials containing mineral admixtures. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>35</b>, 842&#x2013;849 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, H. J., Chang, H. L., Tang, C. W. &amp; Yang, T. Y. Application of biomineralization technology to Self-Healing of Fiber-Reinforced lightweight concrete after exposure to high temperatures. <i>Materials</i><b>15</b>, 7796 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9657245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36363387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awang, H., Ahmad, M. H., &amp; Al-Mulali, M. Z. Influence of Kenaf and polypropylene fibers on mechanical and durability properties of fibre reinforced lightweight foamed concrete. <i>J. Eng. Sci. Technol.</i><b>10</b> (4), 496&#x2013;508 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, M., Cao, M. &amp; Ali, M. Cracking behaviour and constitutive modelling of hybrid fibre reinforced concrete. <i>J. Building Eng.</i><b>30</b>, 101272 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, W. et al. Fiber-reinforced viscoelastomers show extraordinary crack resistance that exceeds metals. <i>Adv. Mater.</i><b>32</b> (31), 1907180. 10.1002/adma.201907180 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32583491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, P. et al. Rheological and mechanical properties of Bentonite&#x2013;Cement paste reinforced with basalt fibers. <i>Materials</i><b>16</b>, 3226 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10146701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37110062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y., Shen, J., Lin, H. &amp; Li, Y. Optimization design for alkali-activated slag-fly Ash geopolymer concrete based on artificial intelligence considering compressive strength, cost, and carbon emission. <i>J. Building Eng.</i><b>75</b>, 106929 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salvador, R. P., Cavalaro, S. H. P., Segura, I., Figueiredo, A. D. &amp; P&#xe9;rez, J. Early age hydration of cement pastes with alkaline and alkali-free accelerators for sprayed concrete. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>111</b>, 386&#x2013;398 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palomo, A., Grutzeck, M. W. &amp; Blanco, M. T. Alkali-activated fly ashes. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>29</b>, 1323&#x2013;1329 (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gismera, S., Alonso, M. M., Palacios, M. &amp; Puertas, F. Rheology of Alkali-Activated mortars: influence of particle size and nature of aggregates. <i>Minerals</i><b>10</b>, 726 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi, Y., Li, C. &amp; Songyu Liu. Alkali-activated ground-granulated blast furnace slag for stabilization of marine soft clay. <i>J. Mater. Civil Eng.</i><b>27</b> (4), 04014146 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komljenovi&#x107;, M., Ba&#x161;&#x10d;arevi&#x107;, Z. &amp; Bradi&#x107;, V. Mechanical and microstructural properties of alkali-activated fly Ash geopolymers. <i>J. Hazard. Mater.</i><b>181</b>, 35&#x2013;42 (2010).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20554110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palacios, M., Alonso, M. M., Varga, C. &amp; Puertas, F. Influence of the alkaline solution and temperature on the rheology and reactivity of alkali-activated fly Ash pastes. <i>Cem. Concr Compos.</i><b>95</b>, 277&#x2013;284 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kala, K. &amp; Subramaniam, K. V. L. Alkali-activated fly ash-blast furnace slag blend rheology: evaluation of yield and Maxwell responses. <i>Clean. Eng. Technol.</i><b>6</b>, 100398 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alnahhal, M. F., Kim, T. &amp; Hajimohammadi, A. Evolution of flow properties, plastic viscosity, and yield stress of alkali-activated fly ash/slag pastes. <i>RILEM Tech. Lett.</i><b>5</b>, 141&#x2013;149 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmaruzzaman, M. A review on the utilization of fly ash. <i>Progr. Energy Combust. Sci.</i><b>36</b>, 327&#x2013;363. 10.1016/j.pecs.2009.11.003 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khairul Nizar, H. &amp; Kamarudin Mohd sobri Idris. Pysical, chemical &amp; mineralogical properties of Fly-ash. <i>J. Nuclear Relat. Technol.</i><b>4</b>, 47&#x2013;51 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gollakota, A. R. K., Volli, V. &amp; Shu, C. M. Progressive utilisation prospects of coal fly ash: A review. <i>Sci. Total Environ.</i><b>672</b>, 951&#x2013;989 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30981170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatt, A. et al. Physical, chemical, and geotechnical properties of coal fly ash: A global review. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater.</i><b>11</b>, e00263 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das, S. K. Yudhbir. Geotechnical characterization of some Indian fly ashes. <i>J. Mater. Civ. Eng.</i><b>17</b>, 544&#x2013;552 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, T. et al. Effect of fly Ash microsphere on the rheology and microstructure of alkali-activated fly Ash/slag pastes. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>109</b>, 198&#x2013;207 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bicer, A. Effect of fly Ash particle size on thermal and mechanical properties of fly Ash-cement composites. <i>Therm. Sci. Eng. Progress</i>. <b>8</b>, 78&#x2013;82 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das, D. et al. Stabilization and rheological behavior of fly Ash&#x2013;Water slurry using a natural dispersant in pipeline transportation. <i>ACS Omega</i>. <b>4</b>, 21604&#x2013;21611 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6921645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31867557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, S. H., Kim, H. J., Sakai, E. &amp; Daimon, M. Effect of particle size distribution of fly ash&#x2013;cement system on the fluidity of cement pastes. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>33</b>, 763&#x2013;768 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aigbe, U. O. et al. Fly ash-based adsorbent for adsorption of heavy metals and dyes from aqueous solution: a review. <i>J. Mater. Res. Technol.</i><b>14</b>, 2751&#x2013;2774 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lupu, C., Jackson, K. L., Bard, S., Barron, A. R. &amp; Water Acid, and calcium carbonate pretreatment of fly ash: the effect on setting of Cement&#x2009;&#x2013; fly Ash mixtures. <i>Ind. Eng. Chem. Res.</i><b>46</b>, 8018&#x2013;8025 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Jim&#xe9;nez, A., Palomo, A., Pastor, J. Y. &amp; Mart&#xed;n, A. New cementitious materials based on Alkali&#x2010;Activated fly ash: performance at high temperatures. <i>J. Am. Ceram. Soc.</i><b>91</b>, 3308&#x2013;3314 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MCCARTHY, M. &amp; DHIR, R. Development of high volume fly Ash cements for use in concrete construction. <i>Fuel</i><b>84</b>, 1423&#x2013;1432 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, G. et al. Fly Ash application as supplementary cementitious material: A review. <i>Materials</i><b>15</b>, 2664 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9000507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35407996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shehata, M. H., Thomas, M. D. A. &amp; Bleszynski, R. F. The effects of fly Ash composition on the chemistry of pore solution in hydrated cement pastes. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>29</b>, 1915&#x2013;1920 (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chindaprasirt, P., Homwuttiwong, S. &amp; Sirivivatnanon, V. Influence of fly Ash fineness on strength, drying shrinkage and sulfate resistance of blended cement mortar. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>34</b>, 1087&#x2013;1092 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasaniya, M., Thomas, M. D. A. &amp; Moffatt, E. G. Pozzolanic reactivity of natural pozzolans, ground glasses and coal bottom ashes and implication of their incorporation on the chloride permeability of concrete. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>139</b>, 106259 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wattimena, O. K. &amp; Hardjito, D. Antoni A review on the effect of fly Ash characteristics and their variations on the synthesis of fly Ash based geopolymer. in <b>020041</b> (2017). 10.1063/1.5003524</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WARD, C. &amp; FRENCH, D. Determination of glass content and Estimation of glass composition in fly Ash using quantitative X-ray diffractometry. <i>Fuel</i><b>85</b>, 2268&#x2013;2277 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aughenbaugh, K. L., Stutzman, P. &amp; Juenger, M. C. G. Identifying glass compositions in fly Ash. <i>Front. Mater.</i><b>3</b>, 1&#x2013;10. 10.3389/fmats.2016.00001 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vassilev, S. V. &amp; Vassileva, C. G. A new approach for the classification of coal fly ashes based on their origin, composition, properties, and behaviour. <i>Fuel</i><b>86</b>, 1490&#x2013;1512 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. L., Cui, S. P., Tian, G. P., Lan, M. Z. &amp; Wang, Z. H. Effect of fly Ash composition and structure on the formation of cement clinker. <i>Key Eng. Mater.</i><b>680</b>, 429&#x2013;434 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho, Y. K., Jung, S. H. &amp; Choi, Y. C. Effects of chemical composition of fly Ash on compressive strength of fly Ash cement mortar. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>204</b>, 255&#x2013;264 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vassilev, S. V., Menendez, R., Alvarez, D., Diaz-Somoano, M. &amp; Martinez-Tarazona, M. R. Phase-mineral and chemical composition of coal fly ashes as a basis for their multicomponent utilization. 1. Characterization of feed coals and fly ashes&#x2606;. <i>Fuel</i><b>82</b>, 1793&#x2013;1811 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z., Xu, G. &amp; Shi, X. Reactivity of coal fly Ash used in cementitious binder systems: A state-of-the-art overview. <i>Fuel</i><b>301</b>, 121031 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraris, C. F., Obla, K. H. &amp; Hill, R. The influence of mineral admixtures on the rheology of cement paste and concrete. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>31</b>, 245&#x2013;255 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geso&#x11f;lu, M., G&#xfc;neyisi, E., Kocaba&#x11f;, M. E., Bayram, V. &amp; Mermerda&#x15f;, K. Fresh and hardened characteristics of self compacting concretes made with combined use of marble powder, limestone filler, and fly Ash. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>37</b>, 160&#x2013;170 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemalatha, T. &amp; Ramaswamy, A. A review on fly Ash characteristics &#x2013; Towards promoting high volume utilization in developing sustainable concrete. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>147</b>, 546&#x2013;559 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diamond, S. On the glass present in low-calcium and in high-calcium flyashes. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>13</b>, 459&#x2013;464 (1983).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooton, R., Tishmack, J., Olek, J. &amp; Diamond, S. Characterization of High-Calcium fly ashes and their potential influence on ettringite formation in cementitious systems. <i>Cem. Concrete Aggregates</i>. <b>21</b>, 82 (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao, Z. T. et al. A comprehensive review on the applications of coal fly Ash. <i>Earth Sci. Rev.</i><b>141</b>, 105&#x2013;121 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelechi, S. E. et al. A comprehensive review on coal fly Ash and its application in the construction industry. <i>Cogent Eng.</i><b>9</b> (1), 1&#x2013;26. 10.1080/23311916.2022.2114201 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chancey, R. T., Stutzman, P., Juenger, M. C. G. &amp; Fowler, D. W. Comprehensive phase characterization of crystalline and amorphous phases of a class F fly Ash. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>40</b>, 146&#x2013;156 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas, M. Optimizing the use of fly Ash in concrete. <i>Portl. Cem. Ass.</i><b>5420</b>, 1&#x2013;26 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy, M. J., Zheng, L., Dhir, R. K. &amp; Tella, G. Dry-processing of long-term wet-stored fly Ash for use as an addition in concrete. <i>Cem. Concr Compos.</i><b>92</b>, 205&#x2013;215 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv, B. et al. Separation of unburned carbon from coal fly ash: Pre-classification in liquid&#x2013;solid fluidized beds and subsequent flotation. <i>Process Saf. Environ. Prot.</i><b>165</b>, 408&#x2013;419 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrus, H. T. B. M. et al. Performance of dry-separation processes in the recovery of cenospheres from fly Ash and their implementation in a recovery unit. <i>Int. J. Min. Process.</i><b>98</b>, 15&#x2013;23 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vassilev, S. V. et al. Phase-mineral and chemical composition of fractions separated from composite fly ashes at the Soma power station, Turkey. <i>Int. J. Coal Geol.</i><b>61</b>, 65&#x2013;85 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, Y., Jow, J., Su, J. &amp; Lai, S. Fly ash separation technology and its potential applications. <i>World of Coal Ash (WOCA) Conference</i> 22, 25 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharonova, O. M., Natalia, A., Oreshkina, L., Kurteeva, I. &amp; Alexander, G. Aerodynamic separation of fly ashes of selective sampling from pulverized combustion of coals of different ranks. <i>Eng. Technol.</i><b>5</b>, 72&#x2013;86 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muratov, B. et al. Physico-Chemical study of the possibility of utilization of coal Ash by processing as secondary Raw materials to obtain a composite cement clinker. <i>J. Compos. Sci.</i><b>7</b>, 234 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim, M., Rahman, M. K., Najamuddin, S. K., Alhelal, Z. S. &amp; Acero, C. E. A review on utilization of industrial by-products in the production of controlled low strength materials and factors influencing the properties. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>325</b>, 126704 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakir, S., Raman, S. N., Safiuddin, M., Kaish, A. B. M. A. &amp; Mutalib, A. A. Utilization of By-Products and wastes as supplementary cementitious materials in structural mortar for sustainable construction. <i>Sustainability</i><b>12</b>, 3888 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azad, N. M. &amp; Samarakoon, S. M. S. M. K. Utilization of industrial By-Products/Waste to manufacture geopolymer Cement/Concrete. <i>Sustainability</i><b>13</b>, 873 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurniati, E. O., Pederson, F. &amp; Kim, H. J. Application of steel slags, ferronickel slags, and copper mining waste as construction materials: A review. <i>Resour. Conserv. Recycl</i>. <b>198</b>, 107175 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taha, Y. et al. Towards an integrated approach for zero coal mine waste storage: solutions based on materials circularity and sustainable resource governance. <i>Miner. Process. Extr. Metall. Rev.</i><b>44</b>, 375&#x2013;388 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acordi, J. et al. Waste valorization of coal mining waste from a circular economy perspective: A Brazilian case study based on environmental and physicochemical features. <i>Resour. Policy</i>. <b>80</b>, 103243 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ROSIEK, J. The implementation of circular economy concept in the Polish coal combustion products Sector &#x2013; selected problems. <i>Economic Environ. Stud.</i><b>18</b>, 353&#x2013;373 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pactwa, K., Wo&#x17a;niak, J. &amp; Dudek, M. Coal mining waste in Poland in reference to circular economy principles. <i>Fuel</i><b>270</b>, 117493 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blissett, R. S. &amp; Rowson, N. A. A review of the multi-component utilisation of coal fly Ash. <i>Fuel</i><b>97</b>, 1&#x2013;23 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, S., Krist&#xe1;ly, F. &amp; Mucsi, G. Geopolymerisation behaviour of size fractioned fly Ash. <i>Adv. Powder Technol.</i><b>26</b>, 24&#x2013;30 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, Z., Wang, X., Dai, S., Huang, B. &amp; He, Q. Fractional characteristics of coal fly Ash for beneficial use. <i>J. Mater. Civ. Eng.</i><b>25</b>, 63&#x2013;69 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wrona, J., &#x17b;ukowski, W., Brad&#x142;o, D. &amp; Czupry&#x144;ski, P. Recovery of cenospheres and fine fraction from coal fly Ash by a novel dry separation method. <i>Energies (Basel)</i>. <b>13</b>, 3576 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimar, Z. et al. Application of coal fly Ash in pavement subgrade stabilisation: A review. <i>J. Environ. Manage.</i><b>312</b>, 114926 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35364515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kouakou, C. H. &amp; Morel, J. C. Strength and elasto-plastic properties of non-industrial Building materials manufactured with clay as a natural binder. <i>Appl. Clay Sci.</i><b>44</b>, 27&#x2013;34 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Sao&#xfb;t, G., Lothenbach, B., Hori, A., Higuchi, T. &amp; Winnefeld, F. Hydration of Portland cement with additions of calcium sulfoaluminates. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>43</b>, 81&#x2013;94 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koukouzas, N., H&#xe4;m&#xe4;l&#xe4;inen, J., Papanikolaou, D., Tourunen, A. &amp; J&#xe4;ntti, T. Mineralogical and elemental composition of fly Ash from pilot scale fluidised bed combustion of lignite, bituminous coal, wood chips and their blends. <i>Fuel</i><b>86</b>, 2186&#x2013;2193 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GOODARZI, F. Characteristics and composition of fly Ash from Canadian coal-fired power plants. <i>Fuel</i><b>85</b>, 1418&#x2013;1427 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X. Y. &amp; Park, K. B. Analysis of compressive strength development of concrete containing high volume fly Ash. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>98</b>, 810&#x2013;819 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delihowski, J. et al. Size fraction characterisation of highly-calcareous and siliceous fly ashes. <i>J. Therm. Anal. Calorim.</i><b>149</b>, 10587&#x2013;10603 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delihowski, J., Gajek, M., Izak, P. &amp; Jarosz, M. Thermal studies of fractionated lignite and brown coal fly ashes. <i>Materials</i><b>17</b>, 3464 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11277734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39063755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anastasopoulou, A. Industrial separation processes: Fundamentals. <i>Green Process. Synthesis</i><b>2</b> (5), 533&#x2013;534 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirajima, T. et al. Recovery of cenospheres from coal fly Ash using a dry separation process: separation Estimation and potential application. <i>Int. J. Min. Process.</i><b>95</b>, 18&#x2013;24 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta, A. Yan. D. Mineral Processing Design and Operations (eds Gupta, A. &amp; Yan, D.). Elsevier, 2nd edn (2016). 10.1016/C2014-0-01236-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray, M. L. et al. Physical cleaning of high carbon fly Ash. <i>Fuel Process. Technol.</i><b>76</b>, 11&#x2013;21 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Itskos, G., Itskos, S. &amp; Koukouzas, N. Size fraction characterization of highly-calcareous fly Ash. <i>Fuel Process. Technol.</i><b>91</b>, 1558&#x2013;1563 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanzerstorfer, C. Fly Ash from coal combustion: dependence of the concentration of various elements on the particle size. <i>Fuel</i><b>228</b>, 263&#x2013;271 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, S., Singh, J. &amp; Mohapatra, S. K. Role of particle size in assessment of physico-chemical properties and trace elements of Indian fly Ash. <i>Waste Manage. Research: J. Sustainable Circular Econ.</i><b>36</b>, 1016&#x2013;1022 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30307833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryszard, W. Potrzeba ochrony Beidelitowych i&#x142;&#xf3;w w KWB Be&#x142;chat&#xf3;w. <i>Przegl&#x105;d Geologiczny</i><b>41</b> (9), 612&#x2013;620 (1993).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratajczak, T., Hycnar, E. &amp; Bo&#x17c;&#x119;cki, P. The beidellite clays from the Be&#x142;chat&#xf3;w lignite deposit as a Raw material for constructing waterproofing barriers. <i>Gospodarka Surowcami Mineralnymi</i>. <b>33</b>, 53&#x2013;67 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hycnar, E. Mucha, J, Wasilewska-B&#x142;aszczyk, M. Ratajczak, T. Documentation of accompanying minerals on the example of limestones from the be&#x142;chat&#xf3;w lignite deposit (Central Poland), <i>Conf.: 18th Inter. Multidisc. Sci. Geoconf.</i> SGEM2018, Albena, Bulgaria, <b>18</b> (1.3) (2018). </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#x119;kala, A. The mineral character and Geomechanical properties of the transitional rocks from the Mesozoic-Neogene contact zone in the Be&#x142;chat&#xf3;w lignite deposit. <i>J. Sustainable Min.</i><b>13</b>, 10&#x2013;14 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandal, R., Panda, S. K. &amp; Nayak, S. Rheology of concrete: critical Review, recent Advancements, and future prospectives. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>392</b>, 132007 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macosko, C. Rheology: Principles, Measurements, and applications. <i>Engineering Mater. Sci. Phy.</i><b>1</b>, 1&#x2013;350 (1994).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larson, R. G. &amp; Wei, Y. A review of Thixotropy and its rheological modeling. <i>J. Rheol (N Y N Y)</i>. <b>63</b>, 477&#x2013;501 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation><i>Theory of Viscoelasticity</i>. Elsevier, (1982). 10.1016/B978-0-12-174252-2.X5001-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyun, K. et al. A review of nonlinear oscillatory shear tests: analysis and application of large amplitude oscillatory shear (LAOS). <i>Prog Polym. Sci.</i><b>36</b>, 1697&#x2013;1753 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Mat&#xe9;, M., Santacruz, I., De la Torre, &#xc1;. G., Le&#xf3;n-Reina, L. &amp; Aranda, M. A. G. Rheological and hydration characterization of calcium sulfoaluminate cement pastes. <i>Cem. Concr Compos.</i><b>34</b>, 684&#x2013;691 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan, Z., Zhang, H. &amp; Zhu, Y. Hydration kinetics of sulfoaluminate cement with different water/cement ratios as grouting material used for coal mines. <i>Magazine Concrete Res.</i><b>74</b>, 1056&#x2013;1064 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mondal, S. K., Clinton, C., Ma, H., Kumar, A. &amp; Okoronkwo, M. U. Effect of class C and class F fly Ash on Early-Age and Mature-Age properties of calcium sulfoaluminate cement paste. <i>Sustainability</i><b>15</b>, 2501 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Carrasco, L. &amp; V&#xe1;zquez, E. Reactions of fly Ash with calcium aluminate cement and calcium sulphate. <i>Fuel</i><b>88</b>, 1533&#x2013;1538 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porbaha, A., Pradhan, T. B. S. &amp; Yamane, N. Time effect on shear strength and permeability of fly Ash. <i>J. Energy Eng.</i><b>126</b>, 15&#x2013;31 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, W., Wu, F. &amp; Zhang, Y. Early hydration and setting process of fly Ash-blended cement paste under different curing temperatures. <i>J. Wuhan Univ. Technology-Mater Sci. Ed.</i><b>35</b>, 551&#x2013;560 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prince, W., Espagne, M. &amp; A&#xef;tcin, P. C. Ettringite formation. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>33</b>, 635&#x2013;641 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Famy, C. &amp; Taylor, H. Ettringite in hydration of Portland cement concrete and its occurrence in mature concretes. <i>ACI Mater. J.</i><b>98</b>, 350&#x2013;356 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>John, E. &amp; Lothenbach, B. Cement hydration mechanisms through time &#x2013; a review. <i>J. Mater. Sci.</i><b>58</b>, 9805&#x2013;9833 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ylm&#xe9;n, R., J&#xe4;glid, U., Steenari, B. M. &amp; Panas, I. Early hydration and setting of Portland cement monitored by IR, SEM and Vicat techniques. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>39</b>, 433&#x2013;439 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakob, C. et al. Relating ettringite formation and rheological changes during the initial cement hydration: A comparative study applying XRD Analysis, rheological measurements and modeling. <i>Materials</i><b>12</b>, 2957 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6766233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31547266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malkin, A. Y. &amp; Patlazhan, S. A. Wall slip for complex liquids &#x2013; Phenomenon and its causes. <i>Adv. Colloid Interface Sci.</i><b>257</b>, 42&#x2013;57 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29934140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marinho, T. O., Marchesini, F. H., de Oliveira, M. C. K. &amp; Nele, M. Apparent wall slip effects on rheometric measurements of waxy gels. <i>J. Rheol (N Y N Y)</i>. <b>65</b>, 257&#x2013;272 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tianhong Chen. Preventing wall slip in rheology experiments. <i>Applications TA Instruments</i> 1&#x2013;3 (2004). https://www.tainstruments.com/applications-notes/preventing-wall-slip-in-rheology-experiments/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Priezjev, N. V., Darhuber, A. A. &amp; Troian, S. M. Slip behavior in liquid films on surfaces of patterned wettability: comparison between continuum and molecular dynamics simulations. <i>Phys. Rev. E</i>. <b>71</b>, 041608 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15903683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazar, S., Yang, J., Thomas, B. S., Azim, I. &amp; Ur Rehman, S. K. Rheological properties of cementitious composites with and without nano-materials: A comprehensive review. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>272</b>, 122701 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roussel, N., Ovarlez, G., Garrault, S. &amp; Brumaud, C. The origins of Thixotropy of fresh cement pastes. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>42</b>, 148&#x2013;157 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corstanje, W. A., Stein, H. N. &amp; Stevels, J. M. Hydration reactions in pastes C3S&#x2009;+&#x2009;C3A&#x2009;+&#x2009;CaSO4.2aq&#x2009;+&#x2009;H2O at 25&#xb0;C.I. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>3</b>, 791&#x2013;806 (1973).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alterary, S. S. &amp; Marei, N. H. Fly Ash properties, characterization, and applications: A review. <i>J. King Saud Univ. Sci.</i><b>33</b>, 101536 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iribarne, A. P., Iribarne, J. V. &amp; Anthony, E. J. Reactivity of calcium sulfate from FBC systems. <i>Fuel</i><b>76</b>, 321&#x2013;327 (1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentz, D. P., Ferraris, C. F., Galler, M. A., Hansen, A. S. &amp; Guynn, J. M. Influence of particle size distributions on yield stress and viscosity of cement&#x2013;fly Ash pastes. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>42</b>, 404&#x2013;409 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luce, R. W., Bartlett, R. W. &amp; Parks, G. A. Dissolution kinetics of magnesium silicates. <i>Geochim. Cosmochim. Acta</i>. <b>36</b>, 35&#x2013;50 (1972).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishiki, Y. et al. Formation of magnesium silicate hydrate (M-S-H) at pH 10 and 50&#xb0;C in open-flow systems. <i>Appl. Geochem.</i><b>148</b>, 105544 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardner, L. J. et al. Characterisation of magnesium potassium phosphate cements blended with fly Ash and ground granulated blast furnace slag. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>74</b>, 78&#x2013;87 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutkhil, H. et al. Strength characteristics and rheological behavior of a high level of fly Ash in the production of concrete. <i>ACS Omega</i>. <b>9</b>, 14419&#x2013;14428 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10976435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38559963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alrefaei, Y., Wang, Y. S., Qian, Y. &amp; Dai, J. G. Effects of solid activator and fly Ash on rheology and Thixotropy of One-Part Alkali-Activated pastes. <i>J. Adv. Concr. Technol.</i><b>20</b>, 139&#x2013;151 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hower, J. C. et al. Coal-derived unburned carbons in fly ash: A review. <i>Int. J. Coal Geol.</i><b>179</b>, 11&#x2013;27 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, C. R., Tang, W., Huo, Y. L., Zhan, B. J. &amp; Kou, S. C. Investigation of fresh properties of Self-Leveling Cement-Based pastes with CFB fly Ash as an SCM. <i>Buildings</i><b>15</b>, 966 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelletier-Chaignat, L. et al. Influence of the calcium sulphate source on the hydration mechanism of Portland cement&#x2013;calcium sulphoaluminate clinker&#x2013;calcium sulphate binders. <i>Cem. Concr Compos.</i><b>33</b>, 551&#x2013;561 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc1;lvarez-Pinazo, G., Santacruz, I. &amp; Aranda, M. A. G. De La Torre, &#xc1;. G. Hydration of belite&#x2013;ye&#x2019;elimite&#x2013;ferrite cements with different calcium sulfate sources. <i>Adv. Cem. Res.</i><b>28</b>, 529&#x2013;543 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L. &amp; Glasser, F. P. Hydration of calcium sulfoaluminate cement at less than 24 h. <i>Adv. Cem. Res.</i><b>14</b>, 141&#x2013;155 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J., Ke, G. &amp; Liu, Y. Early hydration heat of calcium sulfoaluminate cement with influences of supplementary cementitious materials and water to binder ratio. <i>Materials</i><b>14</b>, 642 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7866813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33573301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniels, K. A. et al. Gel formation at the front of expanding calcium bentonites. <i>Minerals</i><b>11</b>, 215 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dananaj, I., Frankovsk&#xe1;, J. &amp; Janotka, I. The influence of smectite content on microstructure and geotechnical properties of calcium and sodium bentonites. <i>Appl. Clay Sci.</i><b>28</b>, 223&#x2013;232 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ines Garc&#xed;a-Lodeiro. Hybrid alkaline cements. Part I: fundamentals. <i>Romanian J. Mater.</i><b>42</b>, 330&#x2013;335 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, B., Miao, S., Gao, Q., Chen, B. &amp; Li, S. Hydration mechanism of sustainable Clinker-Free steel slag binder and its application in mine backfill. <i>JOM</i><b>73</b>, 1053&#x2013;1061 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nath, S. K. &amp; Kumar, S. Role of particle fineness on engineering properties and microstructure of fly Ash derived geopolymer. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>233</b>, 117294 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang, X. Y. et al. Fly ash-based geopolymer: clean production, properties and applications. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>125</b>, 253&#x2013;267 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogt, U. Ballschmiede &amp; Koenders. Reactivity and microstructure of Metakaolin based geopolymers: effect of fly Ash and Liquid/Solid contents. <i>Materials</i><b>12</b>, 3485 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6862292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31653060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Temuujin, J., van Riessen, A. &amp; Williams, R. Influence of calcium compounds on the mechanical properties of fly Ash geopolymer pastes. <i>J. Hazard. Mater.</i><b>167</b>, 82&#x2013;88 (2009).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19201089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neaman, A. &amp; Singer, A. Rheological properties of aqueous suspensions of Palygorskite. <i>Soil Sci. Soc. Am. J.</i><b>64</b>, 427&#x2013;436 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yahia, A. Effect of solid concentration and shear rate on shear-thickening response of high-performance cement suspensions. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>53</b>, 517&#x2013;521 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ran, R. et al. Understanding the rheology of kaolinite clay suspensions using bayesian inference. <i>J. Rheol (N Y N Y)</i>. <b>67</b>, 241&#x2013;252 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bingham, E. C. Eugene Cook. Fluidity and plasticity. McGraw-Hill, <i>McGraw-Hill</i> (1922). (1922).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer, P. Rheometry of Pastes, suspensions and granular Materials &#x2013; Application in industry and environment. <i>Appl. Rheology</i>. <b>16</b>, 181&#x2013;181 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vance, K., Kumar, A., Sant, G. &amp; Neithalath, N. The rheological properties of ternary binders containing Portland cement, limestone, and Metakaolin or fly Ash. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>52</b>, 196&#x2013;207 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W&#xf3;jcik, &#x141;., Izak, P. &amp; Ku&#x15b;, R. The influence of composition changes on properties of clay-cement binders. <i>Ceramika Materia&#x142;y Ogniotrwa&#x142;e ISSN</i>. <b>-1505-1269 61</b>, 27&#x2013;30 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izak, P., W&#xf3;jcik, &#x141;. &amp; S&#x142;owikowski, D. Rheology of soil binder dispersions. <i>Ceramika Materia&#x142;y Ogniotrwa&#x142;e; ISSN: 1505 &#x2013; 1269</i>. <b>67</b>, 162&#x2013;163 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luckham, P. F. &amp; Rossi, S. The colloidal and rheological properties of bentonite suspensions. <i>Adv. Colloid Interface Sci.</i><b>82</b>, 43&#x2013;92 (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mostafa, A. M. &amp; Yahia, A. Physico-chemical kinetics of structural build-up of neat cement-based suspensions. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>97</b>, 11&#x2013;27 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ovarlez, G., Tocquer, L., Bertrand, F. &amp; Coussot, P. Rheopexy and tunable yield stress of carbon black suspensions. <i>Soft Matter</i>. <b>9</b>, 5540 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuville, M. et al. Rheology of a gypsum suspension in the presence of different superplasticizers. <i>J. Rheol (N Y N Y)</i>. <b>56</b>, 435&#x2013;451 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demeusy, Y., Gauffinet, S. &amp; Labbez, C. Paste Rheology and Surface Charge of Calcined Kaolinite. (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu, X., Liu, Y., Lu, J. &amp; Sun, R. Order-disorder transition during shear thickening in bidisperse dense suspensions. <i>J. Colloid Interface Sci.</i><b>662</b>, 1044&#x2013;1051 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38387366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catherall, A. A., Melrose, J. R. &amp; Ball, R. C. Shear thickening and order&#x2013;disorder effects in concentrated colloids at high shear rates. <i>J. Rheol (N Y N Y)</i>. <b>44</b>, 1&#x2013;25 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurnon, A. K. &amp; Wagner, N. J. Microstructure and rheology relationships for shear thickening colloidal dispersions. <i>J. Fluid Mech.</i><b>769</b>, 242&#x2013;276 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessler, V. G. Sol&#x2013;Gel precursors. in The Sol-Gel Handbook 195&#x2013;224 (Wiley, doi:10.1002/9783527670819.ch06. (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koohestani, B., Mokhtari, P., Yilmaz, E., Mahdipour, F. &amp; Darban, A. K. Geopolymerization mechanism of binder-free mine tailings by sodium silicate. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>268</b>, 121217 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Jim&#xe9;nez, A., V&#xe1;zquez, T. &amp; Palomo, A. Effect of sodium silicate on calcium aluminate cement hydration in highly alkaline media: A microstructural characterization. <i>J. Am. Ceram. Soc.</i><b>94</b>, 1297&#x2013;1303 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robayo, R. A., Mulford, A. &amp; Munera, J. Mej&#xed;a de Guti&#xe9;rrez, R. Alternative cements based on alkali-activated red clay brick waste. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>128</b>, 163&#x2013;169 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, S. et al. Delaying the hydration of Portland cement by sodium silicate: setting time and retarding mechanism. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>205</b>, 543&#x2013;548 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z., Sun, Y., Zhang, S. &amp; Wang, Y. Effect of sodium silicate on Portland cement/calcium aluminate cement/gypsum rich-water system: strength and microstructure. <i>RSC Adv.</i><b>9</b>, 9993&#x2013;10003 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9088715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35558996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Jim&#xe9;nez, A. &amp; Palomo, A. Composition and microstructure of alkali activated fly Ash binder: effect of the activator. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>35</b>, 1984&#x2013;1992 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vance, K., Dakhane, A., Sant, G. &amp; Neithalath, N. Observations on the rheological response of alkali activated fly Ash suspensions: the role of activator type and concentration. <i>Rheol Acta</i>. <b>53</b>, 843&#x2013;855 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krizan, D. &amp; Zivanovic, B. Effects of dosage and modulus of water glass on early hydration of alkali&#x2013;slag cements. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>32</b>, 1181&#x2013;1188 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roussel, N. Rheology of fresh concrete: from measurements to predictions of casting processes. <i>Mater. Struct.</i><b>40</b>, 1001&#x2013;1012 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dullaert, K. &amp; Mewis, J. A structural kinetics model for Thixotropy. <i>J. Nonnewton Fluid Mech.</i><b>139</b>, 21&#x2013;30 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes, H. A. Thixotropy&#x2014;a review. <i>J. Nonnewton Fluid Mech.</i><b>70</b>, 1&#x2013;33 (1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dullaert, K., Mewis, J. &amp; Thixotropy Build-up and breakdown curves during flow. <i>J. Rheol (N Y N Y)</i>. <b>49</b>, 1213&#x2013;1230 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoaib, M., Cruz, N. &amp; Bobicki, E. R. Effect of pH-modifiers on the rheological behaviour of clay slurries: difference between a swelling and non-swelling clay. <i>Colloids Surf. Physicochem Eng. Asp</i>. <b>643</b>, 128699 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landrou, G., Brumaud, C. &amp; Habert, G. Clay particles as binder for Earth buildings materials: a fresh look into rheology of dense clay suspensions. <i>EPJ Web Conf.</i><b>140</b>, 13010 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du, M., Liu, J., Clode, P. &amp; Leong, Y. K. Microstructure and rheology of bentonite slurries containing multiple-charge phosphate-based additives. <i>Appl. Clay Sci.</i><b>169</b>, 120&#x2013;128 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, Q., Maierdan, Y., Chen, B., Ge, J. &amp; Liu, N. Comparative research on the application of slag as an alternative to cement in binder-bentonite cutoff wall backfills. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>325</b>, 126817 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duong, L. H. &amp; Nguyen, M. N. Colloidal interaction of fly Ash and soil clay. <i>Colloids Surf. Physicochem Eng. Asp</i>. <b>692</b>, 133944 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdo&#x11f;an, S. T., Martys, N. S., Ferraris, C. F. &amp; Fowler, D. W. Influence of the shape and roughness of inclusions on the rheological properties of a cementitious suspension. <i>Cem. Concr Compos.</i><b>30</b>, 393&#x2013;402 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuenzel, C. &amp; Ranjbar, N. Dissolution mechanism of fly Ash to quantify the reactive aluminosilicates in geopolymerisation. <i>Resour. Conserv. Recycl</i>. <b>150</b>, 104421 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Fami, N., Ez-zaki, H., Sassi, O., Boukhari, A. &amp; Diouri, A. Rheology, calorimetry and electrical conductivity related-properties for monitoring the dissolution and precipitation process of cement-fly Ash mixtures. <i>Powder Technol.</i><b>411</b>, 117937 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolawole, J. T., Combrinck, R. &amp; Boshoff, W. P. Rheo-viscoelastic behaviour of fresh cement-based materials: cement paste, mortar and concrete. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>248</b>, 118667 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonet, A., Stryczek, S. &amp; Kremieniewski, M. Modern methods of strengthening and sealing salt mines. <i>Energies (Basel)</i>. <b>15</b>, 5303 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basga, S. D., Tsozue, D., Temga, J. P., Balna, J. &amp; Nguetnkam, J. P. Land use impact on clay dispersion/flocculation in irrigated and flooded vertisols from Northern Cameroon. <i>Int. Soil. Water Conserv. Res.</i><b>6</b>, 237&#x2013;244 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kameda, J. &amp; Morisaki, T. Sensitivity of clay suspension rheological properties to pH, Temperature, Salinity, and Smectite-Quartz ratio. <i>Geophys. Res. Lett.</i><b>44</b>, 9615&#x2013;9621 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwan, A. K. H. &amp; Chen, J. J. Adding fly Ash microsphere to improve packing density, flowability and strength of cement paste. <i>Powder Technol.</i><b>234</b>, 19&#x2013;25 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans, J. C. &amp; Larrahondo, J. M. Yeboah, N. N. N. Fate of bentonite in slag&#x2013;cement&#x2013;bentonite slurry trench cut-off walls for polluted sites. <i>Environ. Geotechnics</i>. <b>10</b>, 319&#x2013;331 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, B., Zhang, Y. &amp; Al-Tabbaa, A. SEBS-Polymer-Modified Slag&#x2013;Cement&#x2013;Bentonite for resilient slurry walls. <i>Sustainability</i><b>14</b>, 2093 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, J., Zhang, H., Wang, D., Wang, H. &amp; Chen, G. Rheological properties of cement paste containing ground fly Ash based on particle morphology analysis. <i>Cryst. (Basel)</i>. <b>12</b>, 524 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, H. L., Jin, F., Ni, J. &amp; Du, Y. J. Engineering properties of vertical cutoff walls consisting of reactive Magnesia-Activated slag and bentonite: Workability, Strength, and hydraulic conductivity. <i>J. Mater. Civil Eng.</i><b>31</b> (11), 04019263 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szostak, B. &amp; Golewski, G. L. Rheology of cement pastes with siliceous fly Ash and the CSH Nano-Admixture. <i>Materials</i><b>14</b>, 3640 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8269633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34209995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultz, M. A. &amp; Struble, L. J. Use of oscillatory shear to study flow behavior of fresh cement paste. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>23</b>, 273&#x2013;282 (1993).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, T. et al. Evaluation of microstructural changes in fresh cement paste using AC impedance spectroscopy vs. oscillation rheology and 1H NMR relaxometry. <i>Cem. Concr Res.</i><b>149</b>, 106556 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assaad, J. Khayat, K. Effect of viscosity-enhancing admixtures on formwork pressure and thixotropy of self-consolidating concrete. <i>ACI Mater. J.</i><b>103</b>, 280&#x2013;287 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, K., Mezhov, A. &amp; Schmidt, W. Chemical and thixotropic contribution to the structural build-up of cementitious materials. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>345</b>, 128307 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, B., Chen, J. &amp; Al-Tabbaa, A. Crack-resistant cement&#x2013;bentonite cut-off wall materials incorporating superabsorbent polymers. <i>Can. Geotech. J.</i><b>58</b>, 800&#x2013;810 (2021).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>