<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40314917</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2731-9229</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Discover nano</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Discov Nano</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Layer-by-layer coating strategy to functionalize the magnetic nanoparticles for their multi-functionalization.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>74</StartPage><MedlinePgn>74</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">74</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s11671-025-04250-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Magnetic nanoparticles (MNPs) hold significant potential for a wide range of applications, however, surface modification or bio-conjugation of MNPs often leads to their aggregation and instability. To address this, we proposed a facile method using a layer-by-layer (LbL) coating technique with polyallylamine hydrochloride (PAH) and poly(styrene sulfonic acid) sodium salt (PSS), so as to maintain the dispersion stability and functionality of MNPs. This method enabled us to develop the powerful MNPs towards to their use in the electrochemical biosensor, by combining both the redox probes (ferrocene (Fc), anthraquinone (AQ), or monocarboxymethylene blue (MB)) and bio-probes (IgG). The redox molecules were effectively anchored to the MNPs under the organic solvents, while such functionalized MNPs surface were subsequently protected by the LbL coating process prior to dispersing in high ionic strength solutions (e.g. Phosphate-buffered saline). And the out-layer of polyelectrolyte shell allowed biomolecules to attach to the MNP surface without chemical cross-linking. Our results demonstrated that the TEM size of MNPs@Fc, MNP@AQ and MNP@MB after LbL coating were characterized as 11.0&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.0&#xa0;nm, 10.5&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.1&#xa0;nm and 12.4&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.2&#xa0;nm and these developed redox MNPs of MNPs@Fc, MNPs@AQ and MNPs@MB were characterized by square wave voltammetry (SWV) with their redox intensity of 0.64&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.10&#xa0;&#xb5;A, 23.25&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.73&#xa0;&#xb5;A and 0.48&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.13&#xa0;&#xb5;A, respectively. In addition, the binding efficiency of adsorption between the MNPs and IgG was up to 78%, evidenced&#xa0;by SDS-PAGE gel analysis. This facile method offered a versatile and effective way to functionalize MNPs, combining redox and biological properties for potential applications in disease diagnosis and point-of-care diagnostics.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Research, Shanghai University of Medicine and Health Sciences Affliated Zhoupu Hospital, The College of Medical Technology, Shanghai University of Medicine and Health Sciences, Shanghai, 201318, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Ye</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Huangyan District Center for Disease Control and Prevention, Taizhou, 318020, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Hongjie</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Peking University Third Hospital; Institute of Sports Medicine of Peking University; Beijing Key Laboratory of Sports Injuries; Engineering Research Center of Sports Trauma Treatment Technology and Devices, Ministry of Education, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Feixiong</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for BioNano Interactions, School of Chemistry and Chemical Biology, University College Dublin, Dublin, Dublin 4, Ireland. feixiong.chen@oulu.fi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Disease Networks Research Unit, Faculty of Biochemistry and Molecular Medicine, University of Oulu, 90014, Oulu, Finland. feixiong.chen@oulu.fi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>832847</GrantID><Agency>Marie Sk&#x142;odowska-Curie Individual Fellowship</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>355747.</GrantID><Agency>Research Council of Finland</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>24305099116</GrantID><Agency>University of Oulu and the City of Oulu</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Discov Nano</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918540788706676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2731-9229</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bio-nano interaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electroactive molecules</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electrochemical sensing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Layer-by-layer (LbL) technique</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic nanoparticles</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: There is no ethics issue in this study. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40314917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12048377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s11671-025-04250-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s11671-025-04250-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Anik MI, Hossain MK, Hossain I, et al. Recent progress of magnetic nanoparticles in biomedical applications: a review. Nano Sel. 2021;2:1146&#x2013;86. 10.1002/nano.202000162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nano.202000162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Yang B, Chen X, et al. Capture and separation of circulating tumor cells using functionalized magnetic nanocomposites with simultaneous in situ chemotherapy. Nanotechnology. 2019;30:285706. 10.1088/1361-6528/ab0e25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1361-6528/ab0e25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30849773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SY, Chen F, Lee TY. Tryptamine-functionalized magnetic nanoparticles for highly sensitive detection of: salmonella typhimurium. Analyst. 2021;146:2559&#x2013;66. 10.1039/d0an02458a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d0an02458a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33899066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen F, Kim S, Na JH, et al. A single-tube sample preparation method based on a dual-electrostatic interaction strategy for molecular diagnosis of gram-negative bacteria. Microchim Acta. 2020;187:1&#x2013;12. 10.1007/s00604-020-04536-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00604-020-04536-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32914337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen F, Lee S, Han K, Lee TY. N, N-dimethyl-4,4-azodianiline functionalized magnetic nanoparticles for enhanced sensitivity of nucleic acid amplification tests. Sens Actuators B Chem. 2021;332:129461. 10.1016/j.snb.2021.129461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.snb.2021.129461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mollarasouli F, Zor E, Ozcelikay G, Ozkan SA. Magnetic nanoparticles in developing electrochemical sensors for pharmaceutical and biomedical applications. Talanta. 2021;226:122108. 10.1016/j.talanta.2021.122108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.talanta.2021.122108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33676664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu YL, Chen D, Shang P, Yin DC. A review of magnet systems for targeted drug delivery. J Control Release. 2019;302:90&#x2013;104. 10.1016/j.jconrel.2019.03.031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jconrel.2019.03.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30946854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad F, Salem-Bekhit MM, Khan F, et al. Unique properties of surface-functionalized nanoparticles for bio-application: functionalization mechanisms and importance in application. Nanomaterials. 2022;12:1333. 10.3390/nano12081333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nano12081333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9031869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35458041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia T, Wang J, Wu C, et al. Novel complex-coprecipitation route to form high quality triethanolamine-coated Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> nanocrystals: their high saturation magnetizations and excellent water treatment properties. CrystEngComm. 2012;14:5741&#x2013;4. 10.1039/c2ce25813g.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c2ce25813g</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soenen SJH, De Cuyper M. Assessing iron oxide nanoparticle toxicity in vitro: current status and future prospects. Nanomedicine. 2010;5:1261&#x2013;75. 10.2217/nnm.10.106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/nnm.10.106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21039201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Yu B, Wang S, et al. Preparation, surface functionalization and application of Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> magnetic nanoparticles. Adv Colloid Interface Sci. 2020;281:102165. 10.1016/j.cis.2020.102165.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cis.2020.102165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32361408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Chen F. Co-crosslinking strategy for dual functionalization of small magnetic nanoparticles with redox probes and biological probes. Microchim Acta. 2024;191:448. 10.1007/s00604-024-06517-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00604-024-06517-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11229446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38967796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bian Y, Song D, Fu Z, et al. Carboxyl PEGylation of magnetic nanoparticles as antithrombotic and thrombolytic agents by calcium binding. J Colloid Interface Sci. 2023;638:672&#x2013;85. 10.1016/j.jcis.2023.01.129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2023.01.129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36780849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hacene YC, Loiseau A, Maio VDP, et al. Isolating nanoparticles from complex biological media by Immunoprecipitation. Nano Lett. 2021. 10.1021/acs.nanolett.0c05056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.nanolett.0c05056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34042452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Chen Y, Chen F. Surface engineering magnetic nanoparticles with redox and biological properties. Langmuir. 2025;41(13):8647&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c05147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40143677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen F, Haddour N, Frenea-Robin M, et al. Polyamidoamine dendrimers as crosslinkers for efficient electron transfer between redox probes onto magnetic nanoparticles. ChemistrySelect. 2018;3:2823&#x2013;9. 10.1002/slct.201703135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/slct.201703135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen F, Haddour N, Frenea-Robin M, et al. Electroactive magnetic nanoparticles under magnetic attraction on a microchip electrochemical device. J Magn Magn Mater. 2019;475:345&#x2013;51. 10.1016/j.jmmm.2018.11.091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmmm.2018.11.091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valsesia A, Desmet C, Ojea-Jim&#xe9;nez I, et al. Direct quantification of nanoparticle surface hydrophobicity. Commun Chem. 2018;1:53. 10.1038/s42004-018-0054-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s42004-018-0054-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fratoddi I. Hydrophobic and hydrophilic Au and Ag nanoparticles. Breakthroughs and perspectives. Nanomaterials. 2018;8:11. 10.3390/nano8010011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nano8010011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5791098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29280980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keeney M, Jiang XY, Yamane M, et al. Nanocoating for biomolecule delivery using layer-by-layer self-assembly. J Mater Chem B. 2015;3:8757&#x2013;70. 10.1039/c5tb00450k.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c5tb00450k</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4835036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27099754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapel JP, Berret JF. Versatile electrostatic assembly of nanoparticles and polyelectrolytes: coating, clustering and layer-by-layer processes. Curr Opin Colloid Interface Sci. 2012;17:97&#x2013;105. 10.1016/j.cocis.2011.08.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cocis.2011.08.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheeveewattanagul N, Rijiravanich P, Surareungchai W, Somasundrum M. Loading of silicon nanoparticle labels with redox mediators for detection of multiple DNA targets within a single voltammetric sweep. J Electroanal Chem. 2016;779:61&#x2013;6. 10.1016/j.jelechem.2016.05.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jelechem.2016.05.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Z, Qin H, Wan H, et al. Layer-by-layer assembly of multilayer polysaccharide coated magnetic nanoparticles for the selective enrichment of glycopeptides. Chem Commun. 2013;49:9284&#x2013;6. 10.1039/c3cc45008b.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c3cc45008b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23995097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferjaoui Z, Nahle S, Chang CS, et al. Layer-by-layer self-assembly of polyelectrolytes on superparamagnetic nanoparticle surfaces. ACS Omega. 2020;5:4770&#x2013;7. 10.1021/acsomega.9b02963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.9b02963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7081293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32201762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olariu C, Yiu H, Bouffier L, Nedjadi T. Multifunctional Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> nanoparticles for targeted bi-modal imaging of pancreatic cancer&#x2013;suplementary infos. J Mater Chem. 2011;2:2&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefan M, Leostean C, Pana O, et al. Synthesis and characterization of Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> @ZnS and Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> @Au@ZnS core-shell nanoparticles. Appl Surf Sci. 2014;288:180&#x2013;92. 10.1016/j.apsusc.2013.10.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2013.10.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuznetsova OV, Timerbaev AR. Magnetic nanoparticles for highly robust, facile and efficient loading of metal-based drugs. J Inorg Biochem. 2022;227:111685. 10.1016/j.jinorgbio.2021.111685.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinorgbio.2021.111685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34902764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halbus AF, Horozov TS, Paunov VN. Surface-modified zinc oxide nanoparticles for antialgal and antiyeast applications. ACS Appl Nano Mater. 2020;3:440&#x2013;51. 10.1021/acsanm.9b02045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsanm.9b02045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Q, Song TY, Yuan P, et al. QDs-labeled microspheres for the adsorption of rabbit immunoglobulin G and fluoroimmunoassay. Colloids Surf B Biointerfaces. 2008;64:248&#x2013;54. 10.1016/j.colsurfb.2008.01.027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfb.2008.01.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18342495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caruso F, Niikura K, Furlong DN, Okahata Y. Assembly of alternating polyelectrolyte and protein multilayer films for imiminosensing. Langmuir. 1997;13:3427&#x2013;33. 10.1021/la9608223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la9608223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bezinge L, Suea-Ngam A, Demello AJ, Shih CJ. Nanomaterials for molecular signal amplification in electrochemical nucleic acid biosensing: recent advances and future prospects for point-of-care diagnostics. Mol Syst Des Eng. 2020;5:49&#x2013;66. 10.1039/c9me00135b.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c9me00135b</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Wei Q, He J, et al. Electrochemical immunosensors for cancer biomarker with signal amplification based on ferrocene functionalized iron oxide nanoparticles. Biosens Bioelectron. 2011;26:3590&#x2013;5. 10.1016/j.bios.2011.02.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bios.2011.02.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21388798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng T, Qiao X, Wang H, et al. A sandwich-type electrochemical immunosensor for carcinoembryonic antigen based on signal amplification strategy of optimized ferrocene functionalized Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>@SiO<sub>2</sub> as labels. Biosens Bioelectron. 2016;79:48&#x2013;54. 10.1016/j.bios.2015.11.001.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bios.2015.11.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26686923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arshadi M, Zandi H, Akbari J, Shameli A. Ferrocene functionalized nanoscale mixed-oxides as a potent phosphate adsorbent from the synthetic and real (Persian Gulf) waters. J Colloid Interface Sci. 2015;450:424&#x2013;33. 10.1016/j.jcis.2015.03.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2015.03.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25867679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng R, Zhang W, Ran Q, et al. Magnetically switchable bioelectrocatalytic system based on ferrocene grafted iron oxide nanoparticles. Langmuir. 2011;27:2910&#x2013;6. 10.1021/la1040486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la1040486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21299195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budny A, Novak F, Plumer&#xe9; N, et al. Redox-active silica nanoparticles. Part 1. Electrochemistry and catalytic activity of spherical, nonporous silica particles with nanometric diameters and covalently bound redox-active modifications. Langmuir. 2006;22:10605&#x2013;11. 10.1021/la061107o.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la061107o</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17129036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novak F, Plumer&#xe9; N, Schetter B, et al. Redox-active silica nanoparticles. Part 4. Synthesis, size distribution, and electrochemical adsorption behavior of ferrocene- and (diamine)(diphosphine) -ruthenium(II)-modified St&#xf6;ber silica colloidal particles. J Solid State Electrochem. 2010;14:289&#x2013;303. 10.1007/s10008-009-0811-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10008-009-0811-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cursi L, Vercellino S, McCafferty MM, et al. Multifunctional superparamagnetic nanoparticles with a fluorescent silica shell for the in vitro study of bio-nano interactions at the subcellular scale. Nanoscale. 2021;13:16324&#x2013;38. 10.1039/d1nr04582b.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d1nr04582b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34570135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villa S, Riani P, Locardi F, Canepa F. Functionalization of Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> NPs by silanization: use of amine (APTES) and thiol (MPTMS) silanes and their physical characterization. Materials (Basel). 2016;9:826. 10.3390/ma9100826.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma9100826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5456583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28773946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bollhorst T, Shahabi S, W&#xe7;rz K, et al. Bifunctional submicron colloidosomes coassembled from fluorescent and superparamagnetic nanoparticles. Angew Chem Int Ed. 2015;54:118&#x2013;23. 10.1002/anie.201408515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.201408515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25370462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas SS, Coleman M, Carroll E, et al. Locating reactive groups on nanomaterials with gold nanoclusters: toward a surface reactive site map. Langmuir. 2017;33:5086&#x2013;97. 10.1021/acs.langmuir.7b00952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.7b00952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28463506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bee A, Massart R, Neveu S. Synthesis of very fine maghemite particles. J Magn Magn Mater. 1995. 10.1016/0304-8853(95)00317-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0304-8853(95)00317-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Tian J, Meng J, et al. Modification and characterization of Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> nanoparticles for use in adsorption of alkaloids. Molecules. 2018;23:562. 10.3390/molecules23030562.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules23030562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6017166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29498692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Xiong GM, Ali Y, et al. Layer-by-layer coated nanoliposomes for oral delivery of insulin. Nanoscale. 2021;13:776&#x2013;89. 10.1039/d0nr06104b.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d0nr06104b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33295926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xed;ez P, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Mu&#xf1;oz M, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Gonz&#xe1;lez M, et al. Functional insights into the cellular response triggered by a bile-acid platinum compound conjugated to biocompatible ferric nanoparticles using quantitative proteomic approaches. Nanoscale. 2017;9:9960&#x2013;72. 10.1039/c7nr02196h.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c7nr02196h</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28681874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge D, Levicky R. A comparison of five bioconjugatable ferrocenes for labeling of biomolecules. Chem Commun. 2010;46:7190&#x2013;2. 10.1039/c0cc02044c.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c0cc02044c</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2975373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20740226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall DW, Russell CD. Substituent effects in the chronopotentiometric oxidation of ferrocene derivatives. Internal solvation of certain substituted ferricenium ions. J Am Chem Soc. 1967;89:2316&#x2013;22. 10.1021/ja00986a012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ja00986a012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang M, Perry D, Kim YR, et al. Time-resolved detection and analysis of single nanoparticle electrocatalytic impacts. J Am Chem Soc. 2015;137:10902&#x2013;5. 10.1021/jacs.5b05856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.5b05856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26264494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson DA, Edwards MA, Ren H, White HS. Effects of instrumental filters on electrochemical measurement of single-nanoparticle collision dynamics. ChemElectroChem. 2018;5:3059&#x2013;67. 10.1002/celc.201800696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/celc.201800696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patrice FT, Qiu K, Ying YL, Long YT. Single nanoparticle electrochemistry. Annu Rev Anal Chem. 2019;12:347&#x2013;70. 10.1146/annurev-anchem-061318-114902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-anchem-061318-114902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31018101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kush P, Kumar P, Singh R, Kaushik A. Aspects of high-performance and bio-acceptable magnetic nanoparticles for biomedical application. Asian J Pharm Sci. 2021;16:704&#x2013;37. 10.1016/j.ajps.2021.05.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajps.2021.05.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8737424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35027950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Carvalho SJ, Metzler R, Cherstvy AG. Inverted critical adsorption of polyelectrolytes in confinement. Soft Matter. 2015;11:4430&#x2013;43. 10.1039/c5sm00635j.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c5sm00635j</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25940939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maia G, Maschion FC, Tanimoto ST, et al. Attachment of anthraquinone derivatives to glassy carbon and the electrocatalytic behavior of the modified electrodes toward oxygen reduction. J Solid State Electrochem. 2007;11:1411&#x2013;20. 10.1007/s10008-007-0299-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10008-007-0299-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cursi L, Vercellino S, McCafferty MM, et al. Multifunctional superparamagnetic nanoparticles with a fluorescent silica shell for the: In vitro study of bio-nano interactions at the subcellular scale. Nanoscale. 2021;13:16324&#x2013;38. 10.1039/d1nr04582b.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d1nr04582b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34570135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feld&#xf6;t&#xf6; Z, Lundin M, Braesch-Andersen S, Blomberg E. Adsorption of IgG on/in a PAH/PSS multilayer film: layer structure and cell response. J Colloid Interface Sci. 2011;354:31&#x2013;7. 10.1016/j.jcis.2010.10.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2010.10.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21055766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tonigold M, Simon J, Estupi&#xf1;&#xe1;n D, et al. Pre-adsorption of antibodies enables targeting of nanocarriers despite a biomolecular corona. Nat Nanotechnol. 2018;13:862&#x2013;9. 10.1038/s41565-018-0171-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41565-018-0171-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29915272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>