<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39328230</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2092-6456</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><Issue>14</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Food science and biotechnology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Food Sci Biotechnol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Inactivation effects of combined thermosonication and potassium sorbate treatments on <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> spores.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3357</StartPage><EndPage>3366</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3357-3366</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10068-024-01577-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study aimed to investigate the inactivation effect of combined TS (thermosonication) and PS (potassium sorbate) treatments on <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> spores. The inactivation effect and potential mechanisms were examined using plate counts, OD<sub>600</sub> values, nucleic acid leakage, DPA (dipicolinic acid) leakage, flow cytometry, and FTIR (Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy). The results showed that, after TS&#x2009;+&#x2009;PS treatments, the integrity of the inner membrane was lost, the permeability of the inner membrane to water molecules was increased, and the intraspore substances leaked. Furthermore, the OD<sub>600</sub> value was reduced, indicating that the spore core hydration was enhanced. Spores proportion with damaged inner membrane was significantly increased to 66%, the ordered secondary structure of the protein was changed into a disordered structure and nucleic acid was fragmented after TS&#x2009;+&#x2009;PS treatment. The results indicated that the combined TS and PS treatments may be a useful method for inactivating bacterial spores in food processing and sterilization.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Korean Society of Food Science and Technology 2024. Springer Nature or its licensor (e.g. a society or other partner) holds exclusive rights to this article under a publishing agreement with the author(s) or other rightsholder(s); author self-archiving of the accepted manuscript version of this article is solely governed by the terms of such publishing agreement and applicable law.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Jiajia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Food Science and Engineering, Ningxia University, Yinchuan, 750021 People's Republic of China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/04j7b2v61</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.260987.2</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2181 583X</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Zhong</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Food Science and Engineering, Ningxia University, Yinchuan, 750021 People's Republic of China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/04j7b2v61</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.260987.2</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2181 583X</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Qinghuan</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Food Science and Engineering, Ningxia University, Yinchuan, 750021 People's Republic of China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/04j7b2v61</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.260987.2</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2181 583X</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yongxia</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Food Science and Engineering, Ningxia University, Yinchuan, 750021 People's Republic of China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/04j7b2v61</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.260987.2</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2181 583X</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yichang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Food Science and Engineering, Ningxia University, Yinchuan, 750021 People's Republic of China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/04j7b2v61</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.260987.2</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2181 583X</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Food Sci Biotechnol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9816587</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1226-7708</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bacillus subtilis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inactivation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Potassium sorbate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spore</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Thermosonication</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interestThe authors declare that there are no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39328230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11422313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10068-024-01577-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aboelkheir MG, Bedor PBA, Leite SGF, Pal K, Toledo Filho RD, Gomes de Souza F. Biodegradation of Vulcanized SBR: a Comparison between <i>Bacillus subtilis, Pseudomonas aeruginosa and Streptomyces</i> sp. Scientific Reports. 9: 19304 (2019)
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-55530-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6917721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31848361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldrete-Tapia JA, Torres JA. Enhancing the Inactivation of Bacterial Spores during Pressure-Assisted Thermal Processing. Food Engineering Reviews. 13: 431-441 (2020)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12393-020-09252-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzate P, Gerschenson LN, Flores SK. Ultrasound application for production of nano-structured particles from esterified starches to retain potassium sorbate. Carbohydrate Polymers. 247: 116759 (2020)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbpol.2020.116759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32829872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bene JED, Jordan MJT. 1999. Vibrational spectroscopy of the hydrogen bond: an ab initio quantum-chemical perspective. International Reviews in Physical Chemistry. 18: 119-162 (1999)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/014423599230026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bermudez-Aguirre D, Mobbs T, Barbosa-C&#xe1;novas GV. Ultrasound applications in food processing. Food Engineering Reviews. 63: 65-105 (2011)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao J-X, Wang F, Li X, Sun Y, Wang Y, Ou C, Shao X, Pan D, Wang D-Y. The influence of microwave sterilization on the ultrastructure, permeability of cell membrane and expression of proteins of <i>Bacillus cereus</i>. Frontiers in Microbiology. 9: 1870 (2018)
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2018.01870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6131623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30233502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho WI, Chung M-S. <i>Bacillus</i> spores: a review of their properties and inactivation processing technologies. Food Science and Biotechnology. 29: 1447-1461 (2020)
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10068-020-00809-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7538368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33041624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;&#x131;nar S, Czeslik C. Secondary structure and folding stability of proteins adsorbed on silica particles&#x2014;pressure versus temperature denaturation. Colloids and Surfaces. B, Biointerfaces. 129: 161-168 (2015)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfb.2015.03.043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25858190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>den Besten HMW, van Melis CCJ, Sanders JW, Nierop Groot MN, Abee T. Impact of sorbic acid on germination and outgrowth heterogeneity of <i>Bacillus cereus ATCC 14579</i> spores. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 78: 8477-8480 (2012)
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.02361-12</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3497378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23001664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong W, Wang H, Ning Z, Hu K, Luo X. Bioadsorption of terbium(III) by spores of <i>Bacillus subtilis</i>. Minerals. 12: 866 (2022)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min12070866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evelyn, Chairul, Ramadhani F, Khairunnisa RA. The effects of ultrasound and ultrasound combined thermal treatment on the resistance of <i>mold</i> spores (<i>Paecilomyces variotii</i>) in orange juice. Materials Today: Proceedings. 87: 106-110 (2023)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evelyn, Silva FVM. High pressure processing pretreatment enhanced the thermosonication inactivation of <i>Alicyclobacillus acidoterrestris</i> spores in orange juice. Food Control. 62: 365-372 (2016)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodcont.2015.11.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evelyn, Silva FVM. Ultrasound assisted thermal inactivation of spores in foods: Pathogenic and spoilage bacteria, molds and yeasts. Trends in Food Science &amp; Technology. 105: 402-415 (2020)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tifs.2020.09.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan L, Ismail BB, Hou F, Muhammad AI, Ding T, Liu D. Ultrasound pretreatment enhances the inhibitory effects of nisin/carvacrol against germination, outgrowth and vegetative growth of spores of <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> ATCC6633 in laboratory medium and milk: population and single-cell analysis. International Journal of Food Microbiology. 311: 108329 (2019a)
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfoodmicro.2019.108329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31669928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan L, Ismail BB, Hou F, Muhammad AI, Zou M, Ding T, Liu D. Thermosonication damages the inner membrane of <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> spores and impels their inactivation. Food Research International. 125: 108514 (2019b)
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodres.2019.108514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31554087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hauck-Tiburski J, Rosenthal A, Iaconnelli C, Perrier-Cornet J-M, Gervais P. Inactivation of dried spores of <i>Bacillus subtilis 168</i> by a treatment combining high temperature and pressure. International Journal of Food Microbiology. 295: 1-7 (2019)
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfoodmicro.2019.01.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30772603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jos&#xe9; JFBDS, Andrade NJd, Ramos AM, Vanetti MCD, Stringheta PC, Chaves JBP. Decontamination by ultrasound application in fresh fruits and vegetables. Food Control. 45: 36-50 (2014)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodcont.2014.04.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakagianni M, Chatzitzika C, Koutsoumanis KP, Valdramidis VP. The impact of high power ultrasound for controlling spoilage by <i>Alicyclobacillus acidoterrestris</i>: a population and a single spore assessment. Innovative Food Science and Emerging Technologies. 64: 102405 (2020)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ifset.2020.102405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanal SN, Anand SK, Muthukumarappan K. Evaluation of high-intensity ultrasonication for the inactivation of endospores of 3 <i>Bacillus</i> species in nonfat milk. Journal of Dairy Science. 97(10): 5952-5963 (2014)
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3168/jds.2014-7950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25087024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JU, Shahbaz HM, Cho JS, Lee H, Park J. Inactivation of <i>Bacillus cereus</i> spores using a combined treatment of UV-TiO<sub>2</sub> photocatalysis and high hydrostatic pressure. Innovative Food Science and Emerging Technologies. 70: 102676 (2021)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ifset.2021.102676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv R, Zou M, Chantapakul T, Chen W, Muhammad AI, Zhou J, Ding T, Ye X, Liu D. Effect of ultrasonication and thermal and pressure treatments, individually and combined, on inactivation of <i>Bacillus cereus</i> spores. Applied Microbiology and Biotechnology. 103: 2329-2338 (2019)
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00253-018-9559-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30627794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyu F, Zhang T, Gui M, Wang Y, Zhao L, Wu X, Rao L, Liao X. The underlying mechanism of bacterial spore germination: An update review. Comprehensive Reviews in Food Science and Food Safety. 22: 2728-2746 (2023)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1541-4337.13160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37125461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majeed U, Majeed H, Shafi A, Liu X-y, Ye J, Wang Y, Xue W, Luo Y, Yue T. DNA binding peptide CF-14 enhances bactericidal efficacy of eugenol/carvacrol nanoparticles to <i>Escherichia coli</i>. Food Chemistry. 429: 136861 (2023)
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2023.136861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37499503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason TJ. Sonochemistry: current uses and future prospects in the chemical and processing industries. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London. Series A: Mathematical, Physical and Engineering Sciences. 357: 355-369 (1999)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rsta.1999.0331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng J, Gong Y, Qian P, Yu J-Y, Zhang X-J, Lu R. Combined effects of ultra-high hydrostatic pressure and mild heat on the inactivation of <i>Bacillus subtilis</i>. LWT-Food Science and Technology. 68: 59-66 (2016)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lwt.2015.12.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadzadeh-Aghdash H, Sohrabi Y, Mohammadi A, Shanehbandi D, Dehghan P, Dolatabadi JEN. Safety assessment of sodium acetate, sodium diacetate and potassium sorbate food additives. Food Chemistry. 257: 211-215 (2018)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2018.03.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29622200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ovissipour M, Rai R, Nitin N. DNA-based surrogate indicator for sanitation verification and predict inactivation of <i>Escherichia coli</i> O<sub>157</sub>:H<sub>7</sub> using vibrational spectroscopy (FTIR). Food Control. 100: 67-77 (2019)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodcont.2018.12.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey R, Pieper GH, Ter Beek A, Vischer NOE, Smelt JPPM, Manders EMM, Brul S. Quantifying the effect of sorbic acid, heat and combination of both on germination and outgrowth of <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> spores at single cell resolution. Food Microbiology. 52: 88-96 (2015)
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fm.2015.06.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26338121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perna G, Capozzi V, Lasalvia M. A comparison between FTIR spectra from HUKE and SH-SY5Y cell lines grown on different substrates. Applied Sciences. 10: 8825 (2020)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app10248825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian J, Zhao F, Zhang Z, Huo S, Ma H. Effects of ultrasound combined with mild heat and potassium sorbate on <i>Pichia membranaefaciens</i> and the quality of soy sauce. Flavour and Fragrance Journal. 38: 368-377 (2023)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ffj.3752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao L, Wang Y, Chen F, Hu X, Liao X, Zhao L. High pressure CO<sub>2</sub> reduces the wet heat resistance of <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> spores by perturbing the inner membrane. Innovative Food Science and Emerging Technologies. 60: 102291 (2020)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ifset.2020.102291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen S, Yang K, Lin D. Biomacromolecular and toxicity responses of bacteria upon the nano-bio interfacial interactions with Ti<sub>3</sub>C<sub>2</sub>Tx nanosheets. Environmental Science &amp; Technology. 57: 12991-13003 (2023)
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.3c02397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37608586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun F, Wang H, Liu Q, Kong B, Chen Q. Effects of temperature and pH on the structure of a protease from <i>Lactobacillus brevis</i> R4 isolated from harbin dry sausage and molecular docking of the protease to the meat proteins. Food Bioscience. 42: 101099 (2021)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fbio.2021.101099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33548144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X, Kong X, Li C, Wang M, Yi J, Deng Z, Niu B, Chen Q. Sporicidal mechanism of the combination of ortho-phthalaldehyde and benzyldimethyldodecylammonium chloride as a disinfectant against the <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> spores. Brazilian Journal of Microbiology. 53: 547-556 (2022)
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42770-022-00695-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9151947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35143017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tehri N, Kumar N, Raghu HV, Thakur G, Kumar Sharma P. Role of stereospecific nature of germinants in <i>Bacillus megaterium</i> spores germination. 3 Biotech. 7: 1-10 (2017)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13205-017-0897-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5524629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28744426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiburski JH, Rosenthal A, Guyot S, Perrier-Cornet J-M, Gervais P. Water distribution in bacterial spores: a key factor in heat resistance. Food Biophysics. 9: 10-19 (2014)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11483-013-9312-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trevisan DAC, Batista AFP, Campanerut-S&#xe1; PAZ, de Medeiros Ara&#xfa;jo DC, Ribeiro TDVR, de Mello JCP, Mikcha JMG. Synergistic activity of <i>Stryphnodendron</i><i>adstringens</i> and potassium sorbate against foodborne bacteria. Archives of Microbiology. 204: 292 (2022)
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00203-022-02904-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35503382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeargers EK. Basic Biophysics for Biology: the hydrogen bond. 1st Edition. CRC Press, Boca Raton pp. 108&#x2013;116 (2018)</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>