<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40760469</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1129-2377</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The journal of headache and pain</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Headache Pain</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pretreatment with an anti-CGRP monoclonal antibody attenuates mild TBI-induced tactile hypersensitivity in mice.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>175</StartPage><MedlinePgn>175</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">175</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s10194-025-02108-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Post-traumatic headache (PTH) can develop following a mild traumatic brain injury (mTBI), such as a concussion. It is especially common among active-duty military personnel, Veterans, and athletes. The high prevalence and chronic nature of PTH highlight the importance of studying these conditions in animal models to develop new, effective treatments. Since the symptoms associated with PTH resemble those of migraine, we focused on the neuropeptide calcitonin gene-related peptide (CGRP) as a potential therapeutic target.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We used a mouse model of mTBI involving three repeated closed head impacts to assess the therapeutic efficacy of a monoclonal antibody (mAb) that blocks CGRP. To validate the model, we first assessed and optimized the development of periorbital and plantar tactile hypersensitivity in outbred CD1 mice. We then tested these responses after intraperitoneal injection of two migraine triggers: CGRP and sodium nitroprusside (SNP), a nitric oxide donor. Then, we assessed the efficacy of the anti-CGRP mAb using different administration paradigms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Early administration of an anti-CGRP mAb before induction of TBI did not fully prevent the initial transient periorbital tactile hypersensitivity observed following multiple closed head injuries. However, the mAb did partially reduce persistent periorbital tactile hypersensitivity to a sub-threshold trigger. Administration of the mAb immediately after the injuries was also able to partially reduce persistent hypersensitivity. Importantly, injection of the anti-CGRP mAb 24&#xa0;h prior to injection of a sub-threshold dose of CGRP or SNP fully prevented periorbital hypersensitivity to these triggers during the persistent sensitivity phase.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">These results indicate that an anti-CGRP mAb can partially, but not fully, attenuate cephalic tactile hypersensitivity when administered immediately before or after the mTBI event. In contrast, a stronger rescue was seen when the anti-CGRP mAb was administered just prior to CGRP and nitric oxide triggers. Thus, depending on the timing of administration, the anti-CGRP mAb can block persistent sensitization to headache triggers after mTBI.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s10194-025-02108-x.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wattiez</LastName><ForeName>Anne-Sophie</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Physiology and Biophysics, University of Iowa, 51 Newton Rd., Iowa City, IA, 52242, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for the Prevention and Treatment of Visual Loss, Veterans Administration Health Center, Iowa City, IA, 52246, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Present Address: Center for Scientific Review, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, MD, 20982, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Kuburas</LastName><ForeName>Adisa</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Physiology and Biophysics, University of Iowa, 51 Newton Rd., Iowa City, IA, 52242, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castonguay</LastName><ForeName>William C</ForeName><Initials>WC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Physiology and Biophysics, University of Iowa, 51 Newton Rd., Iowa City, IA, 52242, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Present Address: Department of Neurology Translational Research, University of Utah Hospitals and Clinics, Salt Lake City, UT, 84132, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fejgin</LastName><ForeName>Kim</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>H. Lundbeck A/S, Research DK, Valby, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klewe</LastName><ForeName>Ib V</ForeName><Initials>IV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>H. Lundbeck A/S, Research DK, Valby, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Russo</LastName><ForeName>Andrew F</ForeName><Initials>AF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular Physiology and Biophysics, University of Iowa, 51 Newton Rd., Iowa City, IA, 52242, USA. andrew-russo@uiowa.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Iowa, Iowa City, IA, 52242, USA. andrew-russo@uiowa.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for the Prevention and Treatment of Visual Loss, Veterans Administration Health Center, Iowa City, IA, 52246, USA. andrew-russo@uiowa.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>I01 RX003523</GrantID><Acronym>RX</Acronym><Agency>RRD VA</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS075599</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 NS075599</GrantID><Acronym>GF</Acronym><Agency>NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>I01 RX003523-01</GrantID><Agency>Iowa City Veterans Affairs Medical Center</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Headache Pain</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100940562</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1129-2369</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Calcitonin gene-related peptide</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Monoclonal antibody</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-traumatic headache</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Traumatic brain injury</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical approval&#xa0;was obtained for experiments with CGRP and SNP from the University of Iowa Animal Care and Use Committee and carried out in accordance with the standards set by the US National Institutes of Health. Competing interests: AFR is a consultant and/or on advisory boards for Lundbeck, AbbVie, Pfizer, Vedana Pharmaceuticals, Arrowhead Pharmaceuticals, and Delphian Therapeutics, and holds patents on the CGRP monoclonal antibody for photophobia and diarrhea, on the PACAP monoclonal antibody for photophobia, and on the CGRP HO enhancer element. AK is a consultant for Vedana Pharmaceuticals. KF and IVK are employees of Lundbeck. A-SW and WCC declare no competing interests. Disclaimer: this work was performed while A-S Wattiez was employed at the University of Iowa. The opinions expressed in this article are the authors&#x2019; own and do not reflect the views of the National Institutes of Health, the Department of Health and Human Services, or the United States government.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40760469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12323213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s10194-025-02108-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s10194-025-02108-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Khellaf A, Khan DZ, Helmy A (2019) Recent advances in traumatic brain injury. J Neurol 266(11):2878&#x2013;2889</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6803592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31563989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation><i>CDC Traumatic Brain Injury &amp; Concussion</i>. [cited (2024); Available from: https://www.cdc.gov/traumatic-brain-injury/data-research/?CDC_AAref_Val=https://www.cdc.gov/traumaticbraininjury/data/index.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nampiaparampil DE (2008) Prevalence of chronic pain after traumatic brain injury: a systematic review. JAMA 300(6):711&#x2013;719</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18698069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capizzi A, Woo J, Verduzco-Gutierrez M (2020) Traumatic brain injury: an overview of epidemiology, pathophysiology, and medical management. Med Clin North Am 104(2):213&#x2013;238</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32035565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashina H, Dodick DW (2022) Post-traumatic headache: Pharmacologic management and targeting CGRP signaling. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep 22(2):105&#x2013;111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35138589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aditya S, Rattan A (2023) Advances in CGRP monoclonal antibodies as migraine therapy: A narrative review. Saudi J Med Med Sci 11(1):11&#x2013;18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9997852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36909005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozge A et al (2024) Revolutionizing migraine management: advances and challenges in CGRP-targeted therapies and their clinical implications. Front Neurol 15:1402569</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11210524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38938785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Hernandez A, Villalon CM (2025) The influence of pharmacodynamics and pharmacokinetics on the antimigraine efficacy and safety of novel anti-CGRPergic pharmacotherapies: a narrative review. Expert Opin Drug Metab Toxicol 21(1):41&#x2013;52</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39319681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashina H et al (2020) Hypersensitivity to calcitonin Gene-Related peptide in Post-Traumatic headache. Ann Neurol 88(6):1220&#x2013;1228</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32959458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashina H et al (2020) Low plasma levels of calcitonin gene-related peptide in persistent post-traumatic headache attributed to mild traumatic brain injury. Cephalalgia 40(12):1276&#x2013;1282</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32689824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashina H et al (2020) Efficacy, tolerability, and safety of erenumab for the preventive treatment of persistent post-traumatic headache attributed to mild traumatic brain injury: an open-label study. J Headache Pain 21(1):62</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7271543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32493206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanderEnde J et al (2020) Use of CGRP receptor blocker erenumab in the management of post-traumatic headache: a case series of 5 women. Brain Inj 34(10):1431&#x2013;1434</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32790533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blumenfeld A, McVige J, Knievel K (2022) Post-traumatic headache: pathophysiology and management - A review. J Concussion 6:20597002221093478</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wattiez AS et al (2021) Different forms of traumatic brain injuries cause different tactile hypersensitivity profiles. Pain 162(4):1163&#x2013;1175</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33027220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason BN et al (2017) Induction of Migraine-Like photophobic behavior in mice by both peripheral and central CGRP mechanisms. J Neurosci 37(1):204&#x2013;216</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5214631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28053042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen SL et al (2019) Targeting CGRP via receptor antagonism and antibody neutralisation in two distinct rodent models of migraine-like pain. Cephalalgia 39(14):1827&#x2013;1837</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31288556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rea BJ et al (2018) Peripherally administered calcitonin gene-related peptide induces spontaneous pain in mice: implications for migraine. Pain 159(11):2306&#x2013;2317</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6193822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29994995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaiser EA et al (2017) Anti-CGRP antibodies block CGRP-induced diarrhea in mice. Neuropeptides 64:95&#x2013;99</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5429995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27865545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avona A et al (2019) Dural calcitonin Gene-Related peptide produces Female-Specific responses in rodent migraine models. J Neurosci 39(22):4323&#x2013;4331</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6538861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30962278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixon W (1965) The up-and-down method for small samples. J Am Stat Assoc 60(312):967&#x2013;978</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaplan SR et al (1994) Quantitative assessment of tactile allodynia in the rat paw. J Neurosci Methods 53(1):55&#x2013;63</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7990513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen LX et al (2018) Relationship of calcitonin gene-related peptide with disease progression and prognosis of patients with severe traumatic brain injury. Neural Regen Res 13(10):1782&#x2013;1786</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6128048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30136693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scher AI et al (2023) Plasma calcitonin gene-related peptide and nerve growth factor as headache and pain biomarkers in recently deployed soldiers with and without a recent concussion. Headache 63(9):1240&#x2013;1250</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37796114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xe1;rate G et al (2024) Untangling the mess of CGRP levels as a migraine biomarker: an in-depth literature review and analysis of our experimental experience. J Headache Pain 25(1):69</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11057141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38684990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian J et al (2020) Exogenous CGRP regulates apoptosis and autophagy to alleviate traumatic brain injury through akt/mtor signalling pathway. Neurochem Res 45(12):2926&#x2013;2938</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33063244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z et al (2017) Tetramethylpyrazine attenuates periorbital allodynia and neuroinflammation in a model of traumatic brain injury. J Inflamm (Lond) 14:13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5465454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28603455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moye LS et al (2019) The development of a mouse model of mTBI-induced post-traumatic migraine, and identification of the delta opioid receptor as a novel therapeutic target. Cephalalgia 39(1):77&#x2013;90</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6472897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29771142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eggertsen PP et al (2024) Serum calcitonin gene-related peptide in patients with persistent post-concussion symptoms, including headache: a cohort study. J Neurol 271(5):2458&#x2013;2472</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11055722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38231270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spierings ELH et al (2021) A phase 2 study of fremanezumab as a treatment for posttraumatic headache in adult patients (1588). Neurology 96(15supplement):1588</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ClinicalTrials gov. Available from: https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT03347188?tab=results.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bree D, Levy D (2018) Development of CGRP-dependent pain and headache related behaviours in a rat model of concussion: implications for mechanisms of post-traumatic headache. Cephalalgia 38(2):246&#x2013;258</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6454269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27899434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navratilova E et al (2019) CGRP-dependent and independent mechanisms of acute and persistent post-traumatic headache following mild traumatic brain injury in mice. Cephalalgia 39(14):1762&#x2013;1775</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31550910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tvedskov JF et al (2010) CGRP receptor antagonist olcegepant (BIBN4096BS) does not prevent Glyceryl trinitrate-induced migraine. Cephalalgia 30(11):1346&#x2013;1353</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20959429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sureda-Gibert P, Romero-Reyes M, Akerman S (2022) Nitroglycerin as a model of migraine: clinical and preclinical review. Neurobiol Pain 12:100105</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10039393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36974065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellamy J et al (2006) Nitric oxide regulation of calcitonin gene-related peptide gene expression in rat trigeminal ganglia neurons. Eur J Neurosci 23(8):2057&#x2013;2066</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1486900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16630053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marone IM et al (2018) TRPA1/NOX in the Soma of trigeminal ganglion neurons mediates migraine-related pain of Glyceryl trinitrate in mice. Brain 141(8):2312&#x2013;2328</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6061846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29985973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Logu F et al (2022) Schwann cell endosome CGRP signals elicit periorbital mechanical allodynia in mice. Nat Commun 13(1):646</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8813987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35115501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eberhardt M et al (2014) H2S and NO cooperatively regulate vascular tone by activating a neuroendocrine HNO-TRPA1-CGRP signalling pathway. Nat Commun 5:4381</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4104458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25023795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dux M et al (2016) Meningeal blood flow is controlled by H2 S-NO crosstalk activating a HNO-TRPA1-CGRP signalling pathway. Br J Pharmacol 173(3):431&#x2013;445</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4728414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25884403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bree D, Levy D (2019) Intact mast cell content during mild head injury is required for development of latent pain sensitization: implications for mechanisms underlying post-traumatic headache. Pain 160(5):1050&#x2013;1058</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6476678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30624345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bree D, Stratton J, Levy D (2020) Increased severity of closed head injury or repetitive subconcussive head impacts enhances post-traumatic headache-like behaviors in a rat model. Cephalalgia 40(11):1224&#x2013;1239</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7541737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32600065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bree D et al (2020) Enhanced post-traumatic headache-like behaviors and diminished contribution of peripheral CGRP in female rats following a mild closed head injury. Cephalalgia 40(7):748&#x2013;760</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7525829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32077327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Navratilova E et al (2025) Sex differences in effectiveness of CGRP receptor antagonism for treatment of acute and persistent headache-like pain in a mouse model of mild traumatic brain injury. Cephalalgia 45(2):3331024251321087</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39980371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopruszinski CM et al (2021) CGRP monoclonal antibody prevents the loss of diffuse noxious inhibitory controls (DNIC) in a mouse model of post-traumatic headache. Cephalalgia 41(6):749&#x2013;759</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33615840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo AF, Hay DL (2023) CGRP physiology, pharmacology, and therapeutic targets: migraine and beyond. Physiol Rev 103(2):1565&#x2013;1644</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9988538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36454715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortez MM et al (2021) Photophobia and allodynia in persistent post-traumatic headache are associated with higher disease burden. Cephalalgia 41(10):1089&#x2013;1099</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8410663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33910382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>