<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39661548</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-5733</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Blood coagulation &amp; fibrinolysis : an international journal in haemostasis and thrombosis</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Blood Coagul Fibrinolysis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The determination of euglobulin clot lysis time reference intervals in Beckton Dickinson and Kima 3.2% sodium citrate coagulation tubes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>14</StartPage><EndPage>17</EndPage><MedlinePgn>14-17</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MBC.0000000000001334</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Enhanced fibrinolysis or hyperfibrinolysis may lead to life-threatening blood loss, while reduced activity may contribute to thrombosis. Euglobulin clot lysis time (ECLT) is a manual method that measures plasma fibrinolytic activity and is considered the gold standard. However, the data on reference interval is scarce and outdated. We have employed one-sided reference interval (&gt;3&#x200a;h) since the implementation of ECLT in our laboratory; therefore, we aimed to establish reliable ECLT reference interval and to explore the possible preanalytical influence of different blood collection tubes on the established ECLT reference interval. Establishing a reference interval for fibrinolysis was performed according to CLSI EP28-A3c guidelines by employing a posteriori direct sampling technique. The predefined exclusion criteria included a history of malignant or hepatobiliary disease, a history of deep vein thrombosis/pulmonary embolism (DVT/PE), an acute inflammatory state at the time of the venipuncture. We collected vein blood samples in Vacutest plastic coagulation tubes (Kima, Italy) and Vacutainer glass coagulation tubes (Beckton Dickinson, USA) containing 0.109&#x200a;mol/l buffered trisodium citrate as an anticoagulant at a blood-to-anticoagulant ratio 9&#x200a;:&#x200a;1. We calculated two-sided reference interval and presented as 2.5th and 97.5th percentiles. ECLT values did not differ between sexes or the types of tubes enrolled in the study ( P &#x200a;=&#x200a;0.8979). The established reference interval ranged from 130 to 297&#x200a;min for the KIMA Vacutest tube and from 120 to 292&#x200a;min for the BD Vacutainer tube. The established ECLT reference interval differed significantly from the currently used cut-off value in our laboratory, thus enabling the assessment of hyperfibrinolysis by employing double-sided reference interval.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kukti&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Ivona</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory of Medical Biochemistry and Transfusion Medicine, General Hospital Dr An&#x111;elko Vi&#x161;i&#x107;, Bjelovar.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pa&#x161;ali&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Ante</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine Clinic, University Hospital Sveti Duh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#x10c;an&#x10d;arevi&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Ognjen</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine Clinic, University Hospital Sveti Duh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gali&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Edvard</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine Clinic, University Hospital Sveti Duh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, University of Zagreb.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sara&#x10d;evi&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Laboratory Diagnostics, University Hospital Sveti Duh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Radi&#x161;i&#x107; Biljak</LastName><ForeName>Vanja</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Laboratory Diagnostics, University Hospital Sveti Duh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport and Exercise Medicine, Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Blood Coagul Fibrinolysis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9102551</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0957-5235</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>1Q73Q2JULR</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000077559">Sodium Citrate</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012016" MajorTopicYN="N">Reference Values</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063285" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fibrin Clot Lysis Time</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000295" MajorTopicYN="N">instrumentation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077559" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sodium Citrate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005342" MajorTopicYN="N">Fibrinolysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39661548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MBC.0000000000001334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00001721-202501000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ilich A, Bokarev I, Key NS. Global assays of fibrinolysis. Int J Lab Hematol 2017; 39:441&#x2013;447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boudjeltia KZ, Cauchie P, Remacle C, Guillaume M, Broh&#xe9;e D, Hubert JL, Vanhaeverbeek M. A new device for measurement of fibrin clot lysis: application to the euglobulin clot lysis time. BMC Biotechnol 2002; 2:8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longstaff C. Measuring fibrinolysis: from research to routine diagnostic assays. J Thromb Haemost 2018; 16:652&#x2013;662.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borawski J, My&#x15b;liwiec M. Plasma fibrinogen level is an important determinant of prolonged euglobulin clot lysis time in hemodialysis patients. Clin Appl Thromb Hemost 2001; 7:296&#x2013;299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiting D, DiNardo JA. TEG and ROTEM: technology and clinical applications. Am J Hematol 2014; 89:228&#x2013;232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilich A, Kumar V, Ferrara MJ, Henderson MW, Noubouossie DF, Jenkins DH, et al. Euglobulin clot lysis time reveals a high frequency of fibrinolytic activation in trauma. Thromb Res 2021; 204:22&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilich A, Noubouossie DF, Henderson M, Ellsworth P, Betbadal KF, Campello E, et al. Development and application of global assays of hyper- and hypofibrinolysis. Res Pract Thromb Haemost 2019; 4:46&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prisco D, Paniccia R, Bandinelli B, Filippini M, Brunelli T, Zarone N, et al. Euglobulin lysis time in fresh and stored samples. Am J Clin Pathol 1994; 102:794&#x2013;796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glassman A, Abram M, Baxter G, Swett A. Euglobulin lysis times: an update. Ann Clin Lab Sci 1993; 23:329&#x2013;332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AA, Jacobson LJ, Miller BI, Hathaway WE, Manco-Johnson MJ. A new euglobulin clot lysis assay for global fibrinolysis. Thromb Res 2003; 112:329&#x2013;337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roullet S, Labrouche S, Mouton C, Quinart A, Nouette-Gaulain K, Laurent C, Freyburger G. Lysis Timer: a new sensitive tool to diagnose hyperfibrinolysis in liver transplantation. J Clin Pathol 2019; 72:58&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CLSI. Defining, Establishing, and Verifying Reference Intervals in the Clinical Laboratory; Approved Guideline &#x2013; Third Edition. CLSI document EP28-A3c. Wayne, PA: Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute. 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simundic AM, B&#xf6;lenius K, Cadamuro J, Church S, Cornes MP, van Dongen-Lases EC, et al. Working Group for Preanalytical Phase (WG-PRE), of the European Federation of Clinical Chemistry and Laboratory Medicine (EFLM) and Latin American Working Group for Preanalytical Phase (WG-PRE-LATAM) of the Latin America Confederation of Clinical Biochemistry (COLABIOCLI). Joint EFLM-COLABIOCLI Recommendation for venous blood sampling. Clin Chem Lab Med 2018; 56:2015&#x2013;2038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakrabarti R, Bielawiec M, Evans JF, Fearnley GR. Methodological study and a recommended technique for determining the euglobulin lysis time. J Clin Pathol 1968; 21:698&#x2013;701.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapin JC, Hajjar KA. Fibrinolysis and the control of blood coagulation. Blood Rev 2015; 29:17&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bockenstedt PL. Loscalzo J, Schafer AI. Laboratory methods in hemostasis. Thrombosis and hemorrhage . Boston: Blackwell Scientific Publications; 1994. 455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gosselin RC, Bowyer A, Favaloro EJ, Johnsen JM, Lippi G, Marlar RA, et al. Guidance on the critical shortage of sodium citrate coagulation tubes for hemostasis testing. J Thromb Haemost 2021; 19:2857&#x2013;2861.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gosselin RC, Janatpour K, Larkin EC, Lee YP, Owings JT. Comparison of samples obtained from 3.2% sodium citrate glass and two 3.2% sodium citrate plastic blood collection tubes used in coagulation testing. Am J Clin Pathol 2004; 122:843&#x2013;848.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yava&#x15f; S, Ayaz S, K&#xf6;se SK, Ulus F, Ulus AT. Influence of blood collection systems on coagulation tests. Turk J Haematol 2012; 29:367&#x2013;375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radi&#x161;i&#x107; Biljak V, Tomas M, Lapi&#x107; I. Guidance on the Critical Shortage of Sodium Citrate Coagulation Tubes for Hemostasis Testing: comment from Radi&#x161;i&#x107; Biljak et al . J Thromb Haemost 2024; 22:886&#x2013;888.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Lim HY, Nandurkar H, Ho P. Age, sex and racial differences in fibrin formation and fibrinolysis within the healthy population. Blood Coagul Fibrinolysis 2022; 33:141&#x2013;144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzahrani SH, Hess K, Price JF, Strachan M, Baxter PD, Cubbon R, et al. Gender-specific alterations in fibrin structure function in type 2 diabetes: associations with cardiometabolic and vascular markers. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2012; 97:E2282&#x2013;E2287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talens S, Malfliet JJ, Rude&#x17e; G, Spronk HM, Janssen NA, Meijer P, et al. Biological variation in tPA-induced plasma clot lysis time. Thromb Haemost 2012; 108:640&#x2013;646.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>