<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40534635</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2251-6581</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of diabetes and metabolic disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Diabetes Metab Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Combined effects of sodium alginate supplementation with HIIT and MICT on CCK and PYY levels in men with metabolic syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>150</StartPage><MedlinePgn>150</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">150</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40200-025-01664-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Abdominal obesity is a prevalent characteristic of individuals with Metabolic Syndrome (MetS). Effective weight management strategies that induce satiety play a crucial role in reducing the risk of obesity and, consequently, MetS. This study aimed to investigate the impact of sodium alginate supplementation in conjunction with High-Intensity Interval Training (HIIT) and Moderate-Intensity Continuous Training (MICT) on the increment of Cholecystokinin (CCK) and Peptide YY (PYY) levels in men with MetS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Forty men with MetS volunteered for this study and were randomly assigned to one of five groups: HIIT (high-intensity interval training), HIIT&#x2009;+&#x2009;S (high-intensity interval training&#x2009;+&#x2009;sodium alginate supplementation), MICT (moderate-intensity interval training), MICT&#x2009;+&#x2009;S (moderate-intensity interval training&#x2009;+&#x2009;sodium alginate supplementation), and control (C), which received no intervention. The HIIT groups performed four bouts of four minutes at 85-95% of their Peak Heart Rate (HR peak), with three minutes of active recovery at 50-70% HR peak, three sessions per week. The MICT groups engaged in 30&#xa0;min of exercise at 60-70% HR peak, three sessions per week. The HIIT&#x2009;+&#x2009;S and MICT&#x2009;+&#x2009;S groups consumed 1.5&#xa0;g of Sigma sodium alginate solution (manufactured in the USA) dissolved in 100&#xa0;mg of sweet water (containing 7&#xa0;g of fructose) 30&#xa0;min before their three main meals, three days per week, for eight weeks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">After eight weeks of interventions, CCK and PYY levels significantly increased in all studied groups. The HIIT&#x2009;+&#x2009;S group exhibited a significantly greater increase compared to the other groups. Additionally, the MetS Z score significantly decreased in all studied groups, with the HIIT&#x2009;+&#x2009;S group demonstrating a significantly greater decrease compared to the other groups (<i>P</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The findings of this study indicate that both HIIT and MICT contribute to overall improvement in men with MetS. However, the combination of sodium alginate supplementation with exercise further enhances these improvements. These findings support integrating sodium alginate and exercise into MetS management to enhance satiety and improve metabolic profiles. Limitations include the short duration (8 weeks) and small sample size, which limit long-term conclusions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The trial, with the reference number IR.KUMS.REC.1398.214, underwent approval by the Research Ethics Committees of Kermanshah University of Medical Sciences. The trial was subsequently registered in the Iranian Clinical Trial Registration Center under the code IRCT20190916044788N1 on 03/12/2020.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Tehran University of Medical Sciences 2025. Springer Nature or its licensor (e.g. a society or other partner) holds exclusive rights to this article under a publishing agreement with the author(s) or other rightsholder(s); author self-archiving of the accepted manuscript version of this article is solely governed by the terms of such publishing agreement and applicable law.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ebrahimi</LastName><ForeName>Alireza</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Physiology, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Mazandaran University, Mazandaran, Iran.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/05fp9g671</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.411622.2</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0000 9618 7703</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azizi</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Physiology, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Razi University, Kermanshah, Iran.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/02ynb0474</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412668.f</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0000 9149 8553</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tahmasebi</LastName><ForeName>Worya</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Physiology, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Razi University, Kermanshah, Iran.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/02ynb0474</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412668.f</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0000 9149 8553</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoseini</LastName><ForeName>Rastegar</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Physiology, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Razi University, Kermanshah, Iran.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/02ynb0474</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.412668.f</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0000 9149 8553</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>J Diabetes Metab Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101590741</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2251-6581</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolic syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Weight management</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interestsThe authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40534635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12170976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40200-025-01664-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gierach M, Junik R. Insulin resistance in metabolic syndrome depending on the occurrence of its components. Endokrynologia Polska. 2021;72(3):243&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34010436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen JA. Hyperinsulinemia and its pivotal role in aging, obesity, type 2 diabetes, cardiovascular disease and cancer. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(15):7797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8345990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34360563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emamat H, Jamshidi A, Farhadi A, Ghalandari H, Ghasemi M, Tangestani H. The association between the visceral to subcutaneous abdominal fat ratio and the risk of cardiovascular diseases: a systematic review. BMC Public Health. 2024;24(1):1827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11232263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38982435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nwankwo M, Okamkpa CJ, Danborno B. Comparison of diagnostic criteria and prevalence of metabolic syndrome using WHO, NCEP-ATP III, IDF and harmonized criteria: A case study from urban Southeast Nigeria. Diabetes Metabolic Syndrome: Clin Res Reviews. 2022;16(12):102665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36417829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yousefzadeh G, Sayyadi A, Najafipour H, Sabaghnejad V, Pezeshki S. Comparing the association of two metabolic syndrome definitions, NCEP ATP III and IDF, with the risk of developing atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease: an analytical cross-sectional study. Endocrinol Diabetes Metabolism. 2024;7(1):e468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10794157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38268305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shehzad A, Rabail R, Munir S, Jan H, Fern&#xe1;ndez-L&#xe1;zaro D, Aadil RM. Impact of Oats on appetite hormones and body weight management: a review. Curr Nutr Rep. 2023;12(1):66&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9930024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36790719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babaei P, Hoseini R. Exercise training modulates adipokine dysregulations in metabolic syndrome. Sports Med Health Sci. 2022;4(1):18&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9219261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35782776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuckuck S, Van Der Valk ES, Scheurink AJ, Lengton R, Mohseni M, Visser JA, Iyer AM, Van den Berg SA, Van Rossum EF. Levels of hormones regulating appetite and energy homeostasis in response to a 1.5-Year combined lifestyle intervention for obesity. Front Physiol. 2023;14:1010858.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9986487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36891140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao J, Huang J, Wang S, Xiang M, Wang D, Deng H, Yin H, Xu F, Hu M. Effects of exercise and diet intervention on appetite-regulating hormones associated with MiRNAs in obese children. Eat Weight Disorders-Studies Anorexia Bulimia Obes. 2021;26:457&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32072570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schalla MA, Tach&#xe9; Y, Stengel A. Neuroendocrine peptides of the gut and their role in the regulation of food intake. Compr Physiol. 2011;11(2):1679&#x2013;730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33792904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X, Qiu Y, Liang L, Fu X. Interkingdom signaling between Gastrointestinal hormones and the gut Microbiome. Gut Microbes. 2025;17(1):2456592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11776477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39851261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H, Zhao X, Wu X, Yang J, Wang J, Hou L. High-intensity interval training versus moderate-intensity continuous training on patient quality of life in cardiovascular disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):13915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10457360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37626066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu M, Kong Z, Shi Q, Nie J. Acute effect of high-intensity interval training versus moderate-intensity continuous training on appetite-regulating gut hormones in healthy adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Heliyon 2023, 9(2).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9898666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36747559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flack KD, Stults-Kolehmainen MA, Creasy SA, Khullar S, Boullosa D, Catenacci VA, King N. Altered motivation States for physical activity and &#x2018;appetite&#x2019;for movement as compensatory mechanisms limiting the efficacy of exercise training for weight loss. Front Psychol. 2023;14:1098394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10176969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37187558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alloyarova YV, Kolotova DS, Derkach SR. Nutritional and therapeutic potential of functional components of brown seaweed: A review. Foods Raw Mater. 2024;12(2):398&#x2013;419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odunsi ST, V&#xe1;zquez-Roque MI, Camilleri M, Papathanasopoulos A, Clark MM, Wodrich L, Lempke M, McKinzie S, Ryks M, Burton D. Effect of alginate on satiation, appetite, gastric function, and selected gut satiety hormones in overweight and obesity. Obesity. 2010;18(8):1579&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2911486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19960001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng J, Qin Z, Farmanfarmaee A, Kong F. Comparing gastric emptying of cellulose nanocrystals with sodium alginate and pectin using a dynamic in vitro stomach model. Int J Biol Macromol. 2024;280:135892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39317287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tayebi SM, Hekmatikar AA, Ghanbari-Niaki A, Fathi R. Ghrelin behavior in exercise and training. J Med Sci. 2020;27:85&#x2013;111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutehall S, Muniz-Pardos B, Bosch AN, Galloway SD, Pitsiladis Y. The impact of sodium alginate hydrogel on exogenous glucose oxidation rate and Gastrointestinal comfort in well-trained runners. Front Nutr. 2022;8:810041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8811475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35127792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maturana FM, Martus P, Zipfel S, NIE AM. Effectiveness of HIIE versus MICT in improving cardiometabolic risk factors in health and disease: a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021;53(3):559&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32890201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuddy TF, Ramos JS, Dalleck LC. Reduced exertion high-intensity interval training is more effective at improving cardiorespiratory fitness and cardiometabolic health than traditional moderate-intensity continuous training. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019;16(3):483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6388288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30736402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delioglan A, Pancar Z, Darendeli MK, K&#x131;l&#x131;co&#x11f;lu Y, Ulusal H, Dal M, Tasdogan AM, Yan X. The effect of Curcumin supplementation on irisin, Nesfatin-1, and leptin levels in rats subjected to treadmill exercise Long-Term. Annals Appl Sport Sci 2024:0&#x2013;0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azizi M, Ebrahimi A, Tahmasebi W, Hoseini R. The effect of eight weeks high intensity interval training with alginate sodium and lipid profile on PYY levels in men with metabolic syndrome. J Appl Health Stud Sport Physiol. 2018;5(1):18&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tayebi SM, Saeidi A, Shahghasi R, Golmohammadi M. The eight-week circuit resistance training decreased the serum levels of WISP-1 and WISP-2 in individuals with type 2 diabetes. Annals Appl Sport Sci. 2023;11(4):0&#x2013;0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen LL, Lambert MNT, Haubek D, Bastani NE, Sk&#xe5;lhegg BS, Overgaard K, Jensen J, Jeppesen PB. The effect of alginate encapsulated plant-based carbohydrate and protein supplementation on recovery and subsequent performance in athletes. Nutrients. 2024;16(3):413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10857232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38337697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun F, Williams CA, Sun Q, Hu F, Zhang T. Effect of eight-week high-intensity interval training versus moderate-intensity continuous training programme on body composition, cardiometabolic risk factors in sedentary adolescents. Front Physiol. 2024;15:1450341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11341307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39183975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Peng Y, Min Q, Lian Y, Wang D, Song X, Zhou L. Effects of combined high-intensity interval and moderate-intensity continuous training vs. moderate-intensity continuous training alone in male adolescents: a randomized controlled trial. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1):13353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12006400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40246941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holliday A, Johnson KO, Kaiseler M, Crabtree DR. APPetite: validation of a smartphone app-based tool for the remote measure of free-living subjective appetite. Br J Nutr. 2023;129(9):1615&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34503591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikami Y, Motokawa K, Shirobe M, Edahiro A, Ohara Y, Iwasaki M, Hayakawa M, Watanabe Y, Inagaki H, Kim H. Relationship between eating alone and poor appetite using the simplified nutritional appetite questionnaire. Nutrients. 2022;14(2):337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8779964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35057518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismael SA. Effects of low carbohydrate diet compared to low fat diet on reversing the metabolic syndrome, using NCEP ATP III criteria: A randomized clinical trial. BMC Nutr. 2021;7:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8564990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34727975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf6;kkaya N, Cant&#xfc;rk Z, Cetinarslan B, Tarkun I, Yildiz M. A comparative analysis of the impact of metabolic syndrome on cognitive functions in Middle-Aged adults according to NCEP ATP III and WHO criteria. South Clin Istanbul Eurasia. 2025;36(1):103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos JS, Dalleck LC, Fennell M, Martini A, Welmans T, Stennett R, Keating SE, Fassett RG, Coombes JS. Exercise training intensity and the fitness-fatness index in adults with metabolic syndrome: A randomized trial. Sports Medicine-Open. 2021;7(1):100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8709799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolnes KJ, Petersen MH, Lien-Iversen T, H&#xf8;jlund K, Jensen J. Effect of exercise training on fat loss&#x2014;energetic perspectives and the role of improved adipose tissue function and body fat distribution. Front Physiol. 2021;12:737709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8497689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34630157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojeda ML, Carreras O, Nogales F. The role of Selenoprotein tissue homeostasis in MetS programming: energy balance and cardiometabolic implications. Antioxidants. 2022;11(2):394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8869711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35204276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoseini R, Hoseini Z, Kamangar A. Myogenic differentiation markers in muscle tissue after aerobic training. Heliyon 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11787638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39897925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wieczorek E, &#x106;wikli&#x144;ska A, Kuchta A, Kortas-Stempak B, Gliwi&#x144;ska A, Jankowski M. The differential effects of HDL subpopulations on lipoprotein lipase (LPL)-mediated VLDL catabolism. Biomedicines. 2021;9(12):1839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8698418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34944655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Dun Y, Zhang W, You B, Liu Y, Fu S, Qiu L, Cheng J, Ripley-Gonzalez JW, Liu S. Exercise improves lipid droplet metabolism disorder through activation of AMPK-mediated lipophagy in NAFLD. Life Sci. 2021;273:119314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33667513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiang T, Wang J, Jiang L, Xiong K. Modulation of hyperglycemia by sodium alginate is associated with changes of serum metabolite and gut microbiota in mice. Carbohydr Polym. 2022;291:119359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35698318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilcox MD, Chater PI, Stanforth KJ, Woodcock AD, Dettmar PW, Pearson JP. The rheological properties of an alginate satiety formulation in a physiologically relevant human model gut system. Annals Esophagus 2022, 5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ueda S-y, Miyamoto T, Nakahara H, Shishido T, Usui T, Katsura Y, Yoshikawa T, Fujimoto S. Effects of exercise training on gut hormone levels after a single bout of exercise in middle-aged Japanese women. Springerplus. 2013;2:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3597337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23504454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins C, Aschehoug I, Ludviksen M, Holst J, Finlayson G, Wisloff U, Morgan L, King N, Kulseng B. High-intensity interval training, appetite, and reward value of food in the obese. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017;49(9):1851&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28398946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmstrup M, Fairchild T, Keslacy S, Weinstock R, Kanaley J. Satiety, but not total PYY, is increased with continuous and intermittent exercise. Obesity. 2013;21(10):2014&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3661741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23418154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones TE, Basilio J, Brophy P, McCammon M, Hickner R. Long-term exercise training in overweight adolescents improves plasma peptide YY and resistin. Obesity. 2009;17(6):1189&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3845441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19247279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy SF, Tucker JA, Hazell TJ. Exercise-induced appetite suppression: an update on potential mechanisms. Physiological Rep. 2024;12(16):e70022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11347021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39187396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du H, Zhou Y, Du X, Zhang P, Cao Z, Sun Y. Insulin-like growth factor binding protein 5b of Trachinotus ovatus and its heparin-binding motif play a critical role in host antibacterial immune responses via NF-&#x3ba;B pathway. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1126843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9972581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36865533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro FM, Silva MA, Lyssa V, Marques G, Lima HK, Franco OL, Petriz B. The molecular signaling of exercise and obesity in the microbiota-gut-brain axis. Front Endocrinol. 2022;13:927170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9365995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35966101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy SF, Bornath DP, Jarosz C, Tucker JA, Medeiros PJ, Kenno KA, Hazell TJ. Intense interval exercise induces lactate accumulation and a greater suppression of acylated Ghrelin compared with submaximal exercise in middle-aged adults. J Appl Physiol. 2023;134(5):1177&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37022960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bateman LA, Slentz CA, Willis LH, Shields AT, Piner LW, Bales CW, Houmard JA, Kraus WE. Comparison of aerobic versus resistance exercise training effects on metabolic syndrome (from the studies of a targeted risk reduction intervention through defined Exercise-STRRIDE-AT/RT). Am J Cardiol. 2011;108(6):838&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3752599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21741606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batacan RB, Duncan MJ, Dalbo VJ, Tucker PS, Fenning AS. Effects of high-intensity interval training on cardiometabolic health: a systematic review and meta-analysis of intervention studies. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(6):494&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27797726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>