<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39733449</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0273-1223</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>90</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Water science and technology : a journal of the International Association on Water Pollution Research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Water Sci Technol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Influence of aqueous constituents on hexafluoropropylene oxide trimer acid (HFPO-TA) defluorination by UV/sulfite/iodide system.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3180</StartPage><EndPage>3192</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3180-3192</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2166/wst.2024.392</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hexafluoropropylene oxide trimer acid (HFPO-TA) is an emerging alternative to traditional perfluoroalkyl substances (PFASs), which is characterized by its biotoxicity and persistence. The UV/sulfite/iodide photo-induced hydrated electrons system can effectively degrade HFPO-TA under mild conditions. However, the effects of water quality on this system need to be urgently investigated. This study explored the impact of common aqueous constituents, such as Cl-, HCO3-, PO43- and humic acid (HA) on the defluorination efficiency of HFPO-TA by the UV/sulfite/iodide system. Results indicated that low concentrations of Cl- (&lt;1.0 mM), PO43- (&lt;0.01 mM), and HA (&lt;1.0 mg/L) have little effect on defluorination efficiency. However, as concentrations increase, these constituents can interact with photosensitizers or reactive species within the system, leading to a decrease in defluorination efficiency. HCO3-, in their various solution states, can compete with HFPO-TA for the hydrated electron (eaq-) or engage directly with the photosensitizer, resulting in a hindrance to the defluorination capabilities of the system. Furthermore, it was identified that the components in Xiaoqing River, especially Cl- and HCO3-, could greatly inhibit the defluorination and degradation efficiency of HFPO-TA by the system. Pretreatment such as nanofiltration would effectively mitigate this problem.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Authors This is an Open Access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution Licence (CC BY-NC 4.0), which permits copying, adaptation and redistribution for non-commercial purposes, provided the original work is properly cited (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Pollution Control and Resources Reuse, College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 200092, China; Shanghai Institute of Pollution Control and Ecological Security, Shanghai 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Chaojie</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3108-8271</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Pollution Control and Resources Reuse, College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 200092, China; Shanghai Institute of Pollution Control and Ecological Security, Shanghai 200092, China E-mail: myrazh@tongji.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chu</LastName><ForeName>Liquan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Pollution Control and Resources Reuse, College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Yunmeng</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Pollution Control and Resources Reuse, College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 200092, China; Shanghai Institute of Pollution Control and Ecological Security, Shanghai 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhai</LastName><ForeName>Zhenyu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Pollution Control and Resources Reuse, College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 200092, China; Shanghai Institute of Pollution Control and Ecological Security, Shanghai 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Xuefei</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Pollution Control and Resources Reuse, College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 200092, China; Shanghai Institute of Pollution Control and Ecological Security, Shanghai 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yalei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Pollution Control and Resources Reuse, College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 200092, China; Shanghai Institute of Pollution Control and Ecological Security, Shanghai 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>21976135</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Water Sci Technol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9879497</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0273-1223</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007454">Iodides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014874">Water Pollutants, Chemical</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005466">Fluorocarbons</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014466" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ultraviolet Rays</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007454" MajorTopicYN="N">Iodides</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014874" MajorTopicYN="N">Water Pollutants, Chemical</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005466" MajorTopicYN="N">Fluorocarbons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018508" MajorTopicYN="N">Water Purification</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">UV/sulfite/iodide</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Xiaoqing River</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aqueous constituents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hexafluoropropylene oxide trimer acid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydrated electron</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare there is no conflict.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39733449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/wst.2024.392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">wst_2024_392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Amador C. K., Cavalli H., Tenorio R., Tetu H., Higgins C. P., Vyas S. &amp; Strathmann T. J. (2023) Influence of carbonate speciation on hydrated electron treatment processes, Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 57 (20), 7849&#x2013;7857.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao Y., Cagnetta G., Huang J. &amp; Yu G. (2020) Degradation of hexafluoropropylene oxide oligomer acids as PFOA alternatives in simulated nanofiltration concentrate: effect of molecular structure, Chemical Engineering Journal, 382, 122866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentel M. J., Yu Y., Xu L., Li Z., Wong B. M., Men Y. &amp; Liu J. (2019) Defluorination of per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFASs) with hydrated electrons: structural dependence and implications to PFAS remediation and management, Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 53 (7), 3718&#x2013;3728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentel M. J., Liu Z., Yu Y., Gao J., Men Y. &amp; Liu J. (2020) Enhanced degradation of perfluorocarboxylic acids (PFCAs) by UV/Sulfite treatment: reaction mechanisms and system efficiencies at pH 12, Environmental Science &amp; Technology Letters, 7 (5), 351&#x2013;357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buxton G. V., Greenstock C. L., Helman W. P. &amp; Ross A. B. (2009) Critical review of rate constants for reactions of hydrated electrons, hydrogen atoms and hydroxyl radicals (-OH/-O-) in aqueous solution, Journal of Physical and Chemical Reference Data, 17 (2), 513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui Q., Pan Y., Zhang H., Sheng N., Wang J., Guo Y. &amp; Dai J. (2018) Occurrence and tissue distribution of novel perfluoroether carboxylic and sulfonic acids and legacy per/polyfluoroalkyl substances in black-spotted frog (<i>Pelophylax nigromaculatus</i>), Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 52 (3), 982&#x2013;990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui J., Gao P. &amp; Deng Y. (2020) Destruction of per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFAS) with advanced reduction processes (ARPs): a critical review, Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 54 (7), 3752&#x2013;3766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding X., Song X., Xu M., Yao J., Xu C., Tang Z. &amp; Zhang Z. (2022) Co-occurrence and correlations of PFASs and chlorinated volatile organic compounds (cVOCs) in subsurface in a fluorochemical industrial park: laboratory and field investigations, Science of the Total Environment, 814, 152814.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dixit F., Dutta R., Barbeau B., Berube P. &amp; Mohseni M. (2021) PFAS removal by ion exchange resins: a review, Chemosphere, 272, 129777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33582507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng X., Ye M., Li Y., Zhou J., Sun B., Zhu Y. &amp; Zhu L. (2020) Potential sources and sediment-pore water partitioning behaviors of emerging per/polyfluoroalkyl substances in the South Yellow Sea, Journal of Hazardous Materials, 389, 122124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng X., Chen X., Yang Y., Yang L., Zhu Y., Shan G., Zhu L. &amp; Zhang S. (2021) External and internal human exposure to PFOA and HFPOs around a mega fluorochemical industrial park, China: differences and implications, Environment International, 157, 106824.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giesy J. P. &amp; Kannan K. (2002) Perfluorochemical surfactants in the environment, Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 36 (7), 146A&#x2013;152A.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu P., Zhang C., Sun Z., Zhang H., Zhou Q., Lin S., Rong J. &amp; Hoffmann M. R. (2020) Enhanced photoreductive degradation of perfluorooctanesulfonate by UV irradiation in the presence of ethylenediaminetetraacetic acid, Chemical Engineering Journal, 379, 122338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han M., Jafarikojour M. &amp; Mohseni M. (2021) The impact of chloride and chlorine radical on nitrite formation during vacuum UV photolysis of water, Science of the Total Environment, 760, 143325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart E. J. (1964) The hydrated electron: properties and reactions of this most reactive and elementary of aqueous negative ions are discussed, Science (New York, N.Y.), 146 (3640), 19&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17790794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou C., Deng J., Li S., Li H., Zhou Y. &amp; Zhai Y. (2023) Differences between reductive defluorination of perfluorooctanoic acid by chlorination, bromination, and iodization in the vacuum-ultraviolet/sulfite process, Journal of Hazardous Materials, 460, 132459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji Y., Zhou L., Ferronato C., Yang X., Salvador A., Zeng C. &amp; Chovelon J.-M. (2013) Photocatalytic degradation of atenolol in aqueous titanium dioxide suspensions: kinetics, intermediates and degradation pathways, Journal of Photochemistry &amp; Photobiology, A: Chemistry, 254, 35&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim T. H., Park C., Shin E. B. &amp; Kim S. (2003) Effects of Cl-based chemical coagulants on electrochemical oxidation of textile wastewater, Desalination, 155 (1), 59&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kremleva T. A. &amp; Moiseenko T. I. (2017) Evaluation of the pH buffer capacity of natural lake waters in Western Siberia: criteria of resistance to acidification, Geochemistry International, 55 (6), 559&#x2013;568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Ma J., Liu G., Fang J., Yue S., Guan Y., Chen L. &amp; Liu X. (2012) Efficient reductive dechlorination of monochloroacetic acid by sulfite/UV process, Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 46 (13), 7342&#x2013;7349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Li T., Bao J., Hu X., Zhao X., Shao L., Li C. &amp; Lu M. (2022) A review of treatment techniques for short-chain perfluoroalkyl substances, Applied Sciences-Basel, 12 (4), 1941.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy E. M., Zachara J. M. &amp; Smith S. C. (2002) Influence of mineral-bound humic substances on the sorption of hydrophobic organic compounds, Environmental Science Technology, 24 (10), 1507&#x2013;1516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neta P. &amp; Huie R. E. (1985) Free-radical chemistry of sulfite, Environmental Health Perspectives, 64, 209&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1568601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3830699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neta P., Huie R. E. &amp; Ross A. B. (2009) Rate constants for reactions of inorganic radicals in aqueous solution, Journal of Physical and Chemical Reference Data, 17 (3), 1027&#x2013;1284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen T.-T., Min X., Xia W., Qiang Z., Khandge R. S., Yu H.-K., Wang J.-W., Wang Y. &amp; Ma X. (2024) Anionic covalent organic framework membranes for the removal of per-and polyfluoroalkyl substances with enhanced selectivity, Journal of Membrane Science, 705, 122925.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connor N., Patch D., Noble D., Scott J., Koch I., Mumford K. G. &amp; Weber K. (2023) Forever no more: complete mineralization of per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFAS) using an optimized UV/sulfite/iodide system, The Science of The Total Environment, 888, 164137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Y., Zhang H., Cui Q., Sheng N., Yeung L. W. Y., Guo Y., Sun Y. &amp; Dai J. (2017) First report on the occurrence and bioaccumulation of hexafluoropropylene oxide trimer acid: an emerging concern, Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 51 (17), 9553&#x2013;9560.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Y., Zhang H., Cui Q., Sheng N., Yeung L. W. Y., Sun Y., Guo Y. &amp; Dai J. (2018) Worldwide distribution of novel perfluoroether carboxylic and sulfonic acids in surface water, Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 52 (14), 7621&#x2013;7629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park H., Vecitis C. D., Cheng J., Choi W., Mader B. T. &amp; Hoffmann M. R. (2009) Reductive defluorination of aqueous perfluorinated alkyl surfactants: Effects of ionic headgroup and chain length, Journal of Physical Chemistry A, 113 (4), 690&#x2013;696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19123849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park H., Vecitis C. D., Cheng J., Dalleska N. F., Mader B. T. &amp; Hoffmann M. R. (2011) Reductive degradation of perfluoroalkyl compounds with aquated electrons generated from iodide photolysis at 254 nm, Photochemical &amp; Photobiological Sciences, 10 (12), 1945&#x2013;1953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raven J. A., Gobler C. J. &amp; Hansen P. J. (2020) Dynamic CO<sub>2</sub> and pH levels in coastal, estuarine, and inland waters: theoretical and observed effects on harmful algal blooms, Harmful Algae, 91, 101594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32057340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Z., Bergmann U. &amp; Leiviska T. (2021) Reductive degradation of perfluorooctanoic acid in complex water matrices by using the UV/sulfite process, Water Research, 205, 117676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Polo M., Lopez-Penalver J., Prados-Joya G., Ferro-Garcia M. A. &amp; Rivera-Utrilla J. (2009) Gamma irradiation of pharmaceutical compounds, nitroimidazoles, as a new alternative for water treatment, Water Research, 43 (16), 4028&#x2013;4036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19541339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sauer M. C., Crowell R. A. &amp; Shkrob I. A. (2004) Electron photodetachment from aqueous anions. 1. Quantum yields for generation of hydrated electron by 193 and 248 nm laser photoexcitation of miscellaneous inorganic anions, Journal of Physical Chemistry A, 108 (25), 5490&#x2013;5502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarz H. A. (1992) Reaction of the hydrated electron with water, Journal of Physical Chemistry, 96 (22), 8937&#x2013;8941.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seminskaya O. O., Balakina M. N., Kucheruk D. D. &amp; Nanieva A. V. (2020) Effect of concomitant ions on nanofiltration dephosphatation of water, Journal of Water Chemistry and Technology, 42 (3), 196&#x2013;203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang E., Li Y., Niu J., Li S., Zhang G. &amp; Wang X. (2018) Photocatalytic degradation of perfluorooctanoic acid over Pb-bifeo<sub>3</sub>/rGO catalyst: kinetics and mechanism, Chemosphere, 211, 34&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30071434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharpless C. M. &amp; Blough N. V. (2014) The importance of charge-transfer interactions in determining chromophoric dissolved organic matter (CDOM) optical and photochemical properties, Environmental Science. Processes &amp; Impacts, 16 (4), 654&#x2013;671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y., Babatunde A., Bockelmann-Evans B., Li Q. &amp; Zhang L. (2020) On-going nitrification in chloraminated drinking water distribution system (DWDS) is conditioned by hydraulics and disinfection strategies, Journal of Environmental Sciences, 96, 151&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun M., Arevalo E., Strynar M., Lindstrom A., Richardson M., Kearns B., Pickett A., Smith C. &amp; Knappe D. R. U. (2016) Legacy and emerging perfluoroalkyl substances are important drinking water contaminants in the cape fear river watershed of North Carolina, Environmental Science &amp; Technology Letters, 3 (12), 415&#x2013;419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Z., Zhang C., Chen P., Zhou Q. &amp; Hoffmann M. R. (2017) Impact of humic acid on the photoreductive degradation of perfluorooctane sulfonate (PFOS) by UV/Iodide process, Water Research, 127, 50&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29031799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Cousins I. T., Scheringer M. &amp; Hungerbuehler K. (2015) Hazard assessment of fluorinated alternatives to long-chain perfluoroalkyl acids (PFAAs) and their precursors: status quo, ongoing challenges and possible solutions, Environment International, 75, 172&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25461427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W., Shao H., Sun C., Jiang X., Zhou S., Yu G. &amp; Deng S. (2022) Preparation of magnetic covalent triazine frameworks by ball milling for efficient removal of PFOS and PFOA substitutes from water, Environmental Science-Nano, 9 (4), 1466&#x2013;1475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Shi C., Hao X., van Loosdrecht M. C. M. &amp; Wu Y. (2023) Synergy of phosphate recovery from sludge-incinerated ash and coagulant production by desalinated brine, Water Research, 231, 119658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L., He L., Xue J., Ma Y., Shi Y., Wu L. &amp; Zhang Z. (2020) UV/SO<sub>3</sub><sup>2&#x2212;</sup> based advanced reduction processes of aqueous contaminants: current status and prospects, Chemical Engineering Journal, 397, 125412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yanghai Y., Liying F., Junlian Q. &amp; Xiaohong G. (2022) New insights into bromate removal by UV/sulfite process: influencing factors, mechanism, and energy efficiency, Journal of Water Process Engineering, 48, 102917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu K., Li X., Chen L., Fang J., Chen H., Li Q., Chi N. &amp; Ma J. (2018) Mechanism and efficiency of contaminant reduction by hydrated electron in the sulfite/iodide/UV process, Water Research, 129, 357&#x2013;364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29169109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu X., Gocze Z., Cabooter D. &amp; Dewil R. (2021) Efficient reduction of carbamazepine using UV-activated sulfite: assessment of critical process parameters and elucidation of radicals involved, Chemical Engineering Journal, 404, 126403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zekun L., Zhanghao C., Jinyu G., Yaochun Y., Yujie M., Cheng G. &amp; Jinyong L. (2022) Accelerated degradation of perfluorosulfonates and perfluorocarboxylates by UV/Sulfite + iodide: reaction mechanisms and system efficiencies, Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 56 (6), 3699&#x2013;3709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9481055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai Z., Zhang C., Chu L., Zhao Y., Zhou X. &amp; Zhang Y. (2024) Effective defluorination of novel hexafluoropropylene oxide oligomer acids under mild conditions by UV/sulfite/iodide: mechanisms and ecotoxicity, Water Research, 258, 121804&#x2013;121804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38781621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Zhang H., Liu X., Cui F. &amp; Zhao Z. (2022) Efficient reductive and oxidative decomposition of haloacetic acids by the vacuum-ultraviolet/sulfite system, Water Research, 210, 117974.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuo Q., Deng S., Yang B., Huang J., Wang B., Zhang T. &amp; Yu G. (2012) Degradation of perfluorinated compounds on a boron-doped diamond electrode, Electrochimica Acta, 77, 17&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou M., You T., Yan Z., Zhu X., Pi M., Zeng X., Wang S. &amp; Jia Y. (2024) Iodide and sulfite synergistically accelerate the photo-reduction and recovery of As(V) and As(III) in sulfite/iodide/UV process: Efficiency and mechanism, Water Research, 252, 121210.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>