<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40762311</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1613-6829</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>38</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Small (Weinheim an der Bergstrasse, Germany)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Small</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Enhanced Performance of Zn Electrodes Coated with Heterogeneous Nanoparticle-Based Interphase Layer Deposited via a Direct Precipitation Reaction.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e06779</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e06779</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/smll.202506779</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Zn ion batteries have suffered from various problems, such as hydrogen gas evolution (HER), passivation of corrosion byproduct, and dendritic growth of Zn metal. Moreover, these critical issues are generally correlated with each other and the sluggish desolvation kinetics of Zn ion is one of the important causes of them. Herein, a concept of heterogeneous nanoparticle-based interphase layer (HeNIL) composed of zincophilic aluminum fluoride and hydrophilic aluminum oxide with nanodomains is firstly introduced for multifunctional protective layer of Zn metal to effectively prevent the parasitic side reactions, facilitated ion desolvation kinetics, and suppressing dendritic growth. HeNIL could enable well-balanced ion transfer process with accelerated desolvation process, ascribed to dynamic interaction between hydrated Zn ion and HeNIL. As a result, HeNIL coated Zn metal symmetric cell exhibits an enhanced lifetime over 1000 h utilizing 2.5 mAh cm<sup>-2</sup>, and Zn/MnO<sub>2</sub> full cell demonstrates splendid capacity retention of 90.1% after 200 cycles using high areal high areal capacity (4.6 mAh cm<sup>-2</sup>) positive electrode. This work primally provides unique guidance of design utilizing HeNIL for improving ion transfer kinetics and realizing long-life Zn metal batteries.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Wiley&#x2010;VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Dong Wook</ForeName><Initials>DW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Batteries Research Center Korea Electronics Technology Institute, Seongnam, Gyeonggi-do, 13509, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical Engineering, Sungkyunkwan University, Suwon, Gyeonggi-do, 16419, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Seung Hwa</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Batteries Research Center Korea Electronics Technology Institute, Seongnam, Gyeonggi-do, 13509, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical Engineering, Sungkyunkwan University, Suwon, Gyeonggi-do, 16419, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kwak</LastName><ForeName>Myung-Jun</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Batteries Research Center Korea Electronics Technology Institute, Seongnam, Gyeonggi-do, 13509, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Ho-Sik</ForeName><Initials>HS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Energy and Chemical Engineering, Ulsan National Institute of Sci. &amp; Tech. (UNIST), 50 Unist-gil, Ulsan, 44919, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Im</LastName><ForeName>Sung Woo</ForeName><Initials>SW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Batteries Research Center Korea Electronics Technology Institute, Seongnam, Gyeonggi-do, 13509, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeong</LastName><ForeName>Goojin</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Batteries Research Center Korea Electronics Technology Institute, Seongnam, Gyeonggi-do, 13509, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hwang</LastName><ForeName>Chihyun</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7469-3119</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Batteries Research Center Korea Electronics Technology Institute, Seongnam, Gyeonggi-do, 13509, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical, Biological &amp; Battery Engineering, Gachon University, Seongnam-si, Gyeonggi-do, 13120, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Ho Seok</ForeName><Initials>HS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemical Engineering, Sungkyunkwan University, Suwon, Gyeonggi-do, 16419, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Youngkwon</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6870-8118</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Batteries Research Center Korea Electronics Technology Institute, Seongnam, Gyeonggi-do, 13509, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2021354B10-2123-AC03</GrantID><Agency>Korea Forest Service</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>RS-2024-00407015</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Science and ICT, South Korea</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Small</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101235338</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1613-6810</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aqueous zinc&#x2010;ion battery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">desolvation kinetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electrode&#x2013;electrolyte interface</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heterogeneous nanoparticle&#x2010;based interphase layer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interfacial stability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">solid&#x2013;electrolyte interphase</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40762311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202506779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>a) S. Liu, R. Zhang, C. Wang, J. Mao, D. Chao, C. Zhang, S. Zhang, Z. Guo, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 63, 202400045;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) C. Nie, G. Wang, D. Wang, M. Wang, X. Gao, Z. Bai, N. Wang, J. Yang, Z. Xing, S. Dou, Adv. Energy Mater. 2023, 13, 2300606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) P. Wang, T. C. Li, J. Zhou, S. Liang, H. Y. Yang, Mater. Today 2024, 78, 231;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) J. Jiang, Z. Li, Z. Pan, S. Wang, Y. Chen, Q. Zhuang, Z. Ju, X. Zhang, Energy Environ. Mater. 2023, 6, 12410.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Yi, G. Chen, F. Hou, L. Wang, J. Liang, Adv. Energy Mater. 2021, 11, 2003065.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) J. Chen, W. Zhao, J. Jiang, X. Zhao, S. Zheng, Z. Pan, X. Yang, Energy Storage Mater. 2023, 59, 102767;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Q. Li, L. Han, Q. Luo, X. Liu, J. Yi, Batteries Supercaps 2022, 5, 202100417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) B. Li, X. Zhang, T. Wang, Z. He, B. Lu, S. Liang, J. Zhou, Nano&#x2010;Micro Lett. 2022, 14, 1;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) H. Li, Z. Chen, L. Zheng, J. Wang, H. Adenusi, S. Passerini, H. Zhang, Small Methods 2024, 8, 2300554;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) Y. Zou, X. Yang, L. Shen, Y. Su, Z. Chen, X. Gao, J. Zhou, J. Sun, Energy Environ. Sci. 2022, 15, 5017;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>d) Y. Zong, H. He, Y. Wang, M. Wu, X. Ren, Z. Bai, N. Wang, X. Ning, S. X. Dou, Adv. Energy Mater. 2023, 13, 2300403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) M. Zhou, Y. Chen, G. Fang, S. Liang, Energy Storage Mater. 2022, 45, 618;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) L. Ma, C. Zhi, Electrochem. Commun. 2021, 122, 106898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) L. Yuan, J. Hao, C.&#x2010;C. Kao, C. Wu, H.&#x2010;K. Liu, S.&#x2010;X. Dou, S.&#x2010;Z. Qiao, Energy Environ. Sci. 2021, 14, 5669;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Y. Li, Z. Yu, J. Huang, Y. Wang, Y. Xia, Angew. Chem. 2023, 135, 202309957.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) M. Liu, Y. Wang, Y. Li, F. Wu, H. Li, Y. Li, X. Feng, B. Long, Q. Ni, C. Wu, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2406145;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) F. Ling, L. Wang, F. Liu, M. Ma, S. Zhang, X. Rui, Y. Shao, Y. Yang, S. He, H. Pan, Adv. Mater. 2023, 35, 2208764.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Yang, C. Liu, Z. Lv, H. Yang, Y. Zhang, M. Ye, L. Chen, J. Zhao, C. C. Li, Adv. Mater. 2021, 33, 2007388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Deng, X. Xie, J. Han, Y. Tang, J. Gao, C. Liu, X. Shi, J. Zhou, S. Liang, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2020, 30, 2000599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Chen, W. Zhang, C. Guan, Y. Zhou, I. Gilmore, H. Tang, Z. Zhang, H. Dong, Y. Dai, Z. Du, Angew. Chem. 2024, 136, 202401987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Liang, Z. Tang, B. Han, J. Zhu, A. Chen, Q. Li, Z. Chen, Z. Huang, X. Li, Q. Yang, Adv. Mater. 2023, 35, 2210051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Y. Sakashita, T. Yoneda, J. Catal. 1999, 185, 487;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) C. Wen, X. Zheng, X. Li, M. Yuan, H. Li, G. Sun, Chem. Eng. J. 2021, 409, 128102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) R. Andreeva, E. Stoyanova, A. Tsanev, D. Stoychev, J. Phys.: Conf. Ser., 2016, 1492,&#xa0;012049;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) A. Makarowicz, C. L. Bailey, N. Weiher, E. Kemnitz, S. L. Schroeder, S. Mukhopadhyay, A. Wander, B. G. Searle, N. M. Harrison, Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2009, 11, 5664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) J. Han, H. Euchner, M. Kuenzel, S. M. Hosseini, A. Gross, A. Varzi, S. Passerini, ACS Energy Lett. 2021, 6, 3063;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) S. So, Y. N. Ahn, J. Ko, I. T. Kim, J. Hur, Energy Storage Mater. 2022, 52, 40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) H. Du, Y. Wang, X. Liu, X. Wu, Z. Yan, J. Chen, Adv. Energy Mater. 2024, 14, 2304144;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Y. Song, Y. Liu, S. Luo, Y. Yang, F. Chen, M. Wang, L. Guo, S. Chen, Z. Wei, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 34, 2316070.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) X. Zhang, C. Qu, X. Zhang, X. Peng, Y. Qiu, Y. Su, J. Zeng, Z. Liu, X. Liu, W. Qi, Adv. Energy Mater. 2024, 14, 2401139;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) X. Zhang, Y. Liu, P. Shen, L. Ren, D. Han, M. Feng, H. G. Wang, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 34, 2400032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) X. Cai, X. Wang, Z. Bie, Z. Jiao, Y. Li, W. Yan, H. J. Fan, W. Song, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2306734;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) L. Wang, B. Zhang, W. Zhou, Z. Zhao, X. Liu, R. Zhao, Z. Sun, H. Li, X. Wang, T. Zhang, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2024, 146, 6199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Cao, X. Wang, D. Zhang, D. Luo, L. Zhang, J. Qin, X. Zhang, X. Yang, Small 2024, 20, 2403622.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) J. Yang, S. Wang, L. Du, S. Bi, J. Zhu, L. Liu, Z. Niu, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 34, 2314426;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) L. Hong, X. Wu, C. Ma, W. Huang, Y. Zhou, K.&#x2010;X. Wang, J.&#x2010;S. Chen, J. Mater. Chem. A 2021, 9, https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202503493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Y. Zhang, M. Zhu, G. Wang, F. H. Du, F. Yu, K. Wu, M. Wu, S. X. Dou, H. K. Liu, C. Wu, Small Methods 2021, 5, 2100650;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) D. Xie, Z. W. Wang, Z. Y. Gu, W. Y. Diao, F. Y. Tao, C. Liu, H. Z. Sun, X. L. Wu, J. W. Wang, J. P. Zhang, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2022, 32, 2204066.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S. Zhang, M. Ye, Y. Zhang, Y. Tang, X. Liu, C. C. Li, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2023, 33, 2208230;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) X. Cheng, Y. Zuo, Y. Zhang, X. Zhao, L. Jia, J. Zhang, X. Li, Z. Wu, J. Wang, H. Lin, Adv. Sci. 2024, 11, 2401629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) W. Zhou, Z. Chen, S. Zhao, S. Chen, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 34, 2409520;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Y. Meng, M. Wang, J. Wang, X. Huang, X. Zhou, M. Sajid, Z. Xie, R. Luo, Z. Zhu, Z. Zhang, Nat. Commun. 2024, 15, 8431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) M. Zhu, H. Wang, H. Wang, C. Li, D. Chen, K. Wang, Z. Bai, S. Chen, Y. Zhang, Y. Tang, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 63, 202316904;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Y. Huang, R. Guo, Z. Li, J. Zhang, W. Liu, F. Kang, Adv. Sci. 2024, 11, 2407201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Li, R. Zhao, W. Zhou, L. Wang, W. Li, D. Zhao, D. Chao, JACS Au 2023, 3, 2107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) K. Roy, A. Rana, J. N. Heil, B. M. Tackett, J. E. Dick, Angew. Chem. 2024, 136, 202319010;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) F. Li, D. Ma, K. Ouyang, M. Yang, J. Qiu, J. Feng, Y. Wang, H. Mi, S. Sun, L. Sun, Adv. Energy Mater. 2023, 13, 2204365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) X. Luo, M. Zhou, Z. Luo, T. Shi, L. Li, X. Xie, Y. Sun, X. Cao, M. Long, S. Liang, Energy Storage Mater. 2023, 57, 628;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) X. Zhang, C. Wang, J. Huang, C. Li, G. Qu, N. Li, S. Zhao, T. Li, D. Li, H. Qin, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 63, 202411884.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Y. Yang, C. Liu, Z. Lv, H. Yang, X. Cheng, S. Zhang, M. Ye, Y. Zhang, L. Chen, J. Zhao, Energy Storage Mater. 2021, 41, 230;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) C. Zhou, L. Shan, Q. Nan, J. Zhang, Z. Fan, B. Tang, J. Li, J. Yang, H. Zhang, Z. Kang, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 34, 2312696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Fu, G. Zhang, T. Qiu, J. Liu, X. Sun, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 35, 2412733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) J. Cao, H. Wu, D. Zhang, D. Luo, L. Zhang, X. Yang, J. Qin, G. He, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 63, 202319661;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) J. H. Park, M. J. Kwak, C. Hwang, K. N. Kang, N. Liu, J. H. Jang, B. A. Grzybowski, Adv. Mater. 2021, 33, 2101726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Xu, X. Ren, H. Li, Y. Zhou, S. Chai, Y. Chen, H. Li, L. Bai, Z. Chang, A. Pan, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 63, 202402833.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) D. Xie, Y. Sang, D. H. Wang, W. Y. Diao, F. Y. Tao, C. Liu, J. W. Wang, H. Z. Sun, J. P. Zhang, X. L. Wu, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2023, 62, 202216934;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) K. Guan, L. Tao, R. Yang, H. Zhang, N. Wang, H. Wan, J. Cui, J. Zhang, H. Wang, H. Wang, Adv. Energy Mater. 2022, 12, 2103557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) M. Zhang, C. Sun, G. Chen, Y. Kang, Z. Lv, J. Yang, S. Li, P. Lin, R. Tang, Z. Wen, Nat. Commun. 2024, 15, 9455;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) P. Wu, L. Xu, X. Xiao, X. Ye, Y. Meng, S. Liu, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2306601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Zhang, Q. Yu, G. Qu, X. Wang, C. Li, C. Wang, N. Li, J. Huang, C. Han, H. Li, J. Energy Chem. 2024, 98, 670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) P. Xiong, Y. Kang, N. Yao, X. Chen, H. Mao, W.&#x2010;S. Jang, D. M. Halat, Z.&#x2010;H. Fu, M.&#x2010;H. Jung, H. Y. Jeong, ACS Energy Lett. 2023, 8, 1613;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) P. Xiong, Y. Kang, H. Yuan, Q. Liu, S. H. Baek, J. M. Park, Q. Dou, X. Han, W.&#x2010;S. Jang, S. J. Kwon, Appl. Phys. Rev. 2022, 9, 011401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Yan, F. He, L. Feng, L. Zhu, P. Li, J. Tang, H. He, Y. Liu, Y. Zhu, G. Li, D. Li, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025, 2503493.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>