<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40825931</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2055-7434</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Microsystems &amp; nanoengineering</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Microsyst Nanoeng</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A self-powered hydration-monitoring and drug-delivery skin patch for closed-loop treatment of atopic dermatitis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>156</StartPage><MedlinePgn>156</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">156</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41378-025-01000-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Atopic dermatitis is a chronic inflammatory skin condition that typically manifests in infancy and is characterized by dry, irritated skin. Here, we propose a self-powered hydration-monitoring and drug-delivery skin patch for closed-loop treatment of atopic dermatitis. The patch is composed of piezoelectric generator, hydration sensing unit, microneedle treatment module and flexible circuit. The piezoelectric PZT generator can achieve self-powering by harvesting mechanical energy from patient activities, allowing for long-term work of the system without external power sources. The hydration sensing unit can rapidly and accurately detect changes in skin hydration by estimating the thermal conductivity. Upon detecting abnormal skin hydration levels for 65&#x2009;s, the treatment module is automatically activated, heating hyaluronic acid-based microneedles (~42&#x2009;&#xb0;C) to release dexamethasone sodium phosphate (DEX), thereby providing timely targeted therapy and moisturization to the affected area within minutes. Therapeutic results in mice model of atopic dermatitis demonstrate that our patch can effectively treat this skin disease, improving the epidermal thickness, IL-4, spleen size and mass. The system achieves closed-loop detection and treatment of atopic dermatitis without external intervention, offering a novel approach to managing skin disease and expanding the scope of self-powered biomedical engineering systems. A self-powered hydration-monitoring and drug-delivery skin patch is designed for closed-loop treatment of atopic dermatitis. The patch composes of piezoelectric generator, hydration sensing unit, microneedle treatment module, and flexible circuit. This integrated system achieves closed-loop detection and treatment of atopic dermatitis without external intervention, offering a novel approach to managing skin disease and expanding the scope of self-powered biomedical engineering systems.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Shan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physics, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, 611731, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Shiwei</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Breast, Sichuan Clinical Research Center for Cancer, Sichuan Cancer Hospital &amp; Institute, Sichuan Cancer Center, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, 610041, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Long</LastName><ForeName>Zhihe</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3815-2029</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physics, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, 611731, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xiaojiao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physics, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, 611731, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Qian</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, 610054, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Xianhao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physics, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, 611731, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xing</LastName><ForeName>Lili</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physics, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, 611731, China. xinglili@uestc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xue</LastName><ForeName>Xinyu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1379-6813</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physics, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, 611731, China. xuexinyu@uestc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Meihua</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Radiation Oncology Key Laboratory of Sichuan Province, Sichuan Clinical Research Center for Cancer, Sichuan Cancer Hospital &amp; Institute, Sichuan Cancer Center, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, 610041, China. chenmeihua@scszlyy.org.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Microsyst Nanoeng</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101695458</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2055-7434</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Ethical declaration: Ethics approval and informed consent were obtained from all participants, and the protocol was approved by the Ethics Committee for Medical Research and New Medical Technology of Sichuan Cancer Hospital (SCCHEC-04-2023-026).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40825931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12361490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41378-025-01000-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41378-025-01000-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Weidinger, S. &amp; Novak, N. Atopic dermatitis. <i>Lancet</i><b>387</b>, 1109&#x2013;1122 (2016).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26377142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung, D. Y. M. &amp; Bieber, T. Atopic dermatitis. <i>Lancet</i><b>361</b>, 151&#x2013;160 (2003).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12531593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nutten, S. Atopic dermatitis: Global epidemiology and risk factors. <i>Ann. Nutr. Metab.</i><b>66</b>, 8&#x2013;16 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25925336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boguniewicz, M. &amp; Leung, D. Y. M. Atopic dermatitis: a disease of altered skin barrier and immune dysregulation. <i>Immunol. Rev.</i><b>242</b>, 233&#x2013;246 (2011).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3122139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21682749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong, P. Y. et al. Endogenous antimicrobial peptides and skin infections in atopic dermatitis. <i>N. Engl. J. Med.</i><b>347</b>, 1151&#x2013;1160 (2002).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12374875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weidinger, S., Beck, L. A., Bieber, T., Kabashima, K. &amp; Irvine, A. D. Atopic dermatitis. <i>Nat. Rev. Dis. Prim.</i><b>4</b>, 1 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29930242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luger, T. et al. Atopic dermatitis: role of the skin barrier, environment, microbiome, and therapeutic agents. <i>J. Dermatol. Sci.</i><b>102</b>, 142&#x2013;157 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34116898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds, G. et al. Developmental cell programs are co-opted in inflammatory skin disease. <i>Science</i><b>371</b>, 364 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7611557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33479125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricarico, P. M. et al. Aquaporins are one of the critical factors in the disruption of the skin barrier in inflammatory skin diseases. <i>Int. J. Mol. Sci.</i><b>23</b>, 4020 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8999368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35409378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Addor, F. A. S., Takaoka, R., Rivitti, E. A. &amp; Aoki, V. Atopic dermatitis: correlation between non-damaged skin barrier function and disease activity. <i>Int. J. Dermatol.</i><b>51</b>, 672&#x2013;676 (2012).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22607284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, H. et al. Seeking better topical delivery technologies of moisturizing agents for enhanced skin moisturization. <i>Expert Opin. Drug Deliv.</i><b>15</b>, 17&#x2013;31 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28286978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoeger, P. H. &amp; Enzmann, C. C. Skin physiology of the neonate and young infant: a prospective study of functional skin parameters during early infancy. <i>Pediatr. Dermatol.</i><b>19</b>, 256&#x2013;262 (2002).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12047648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eberlein-K&#xf6;nig, B. et al. Skin surface pH, stratum corneum hydration, trans-epidermal water loss and skin roughness related to atopic eczema and skin dryness in a population of primary school children. <i>Acta Derm. Venereol.</i><b>80</b>, 188&#x2013;191 (2000).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10954209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madhvapathy, S. R. et al. Reliable, low-cost, fully integrated hydration sensors for monitoring and diagnosis of inflammatory skin diseases in any environment. <i>Sci. Adv.</i><b>6</b>, eabd7146 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7821898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33277260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon, K. et al. Wireless, soft electronics for rapid, multisensor measurements of hydration levels in healthy and diseased skin. <i>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA</i><b>118</b>, e2020398118 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7865173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33468630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt, J. et al. Assessment of clinical signs of atopic dermatitis: a systematic review and recommendation. <i>J. Allergy Clin. Immunol.</i><b>132</b>, 1337&#x2013;1347 (2013).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24035157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, Y. Z. et al. A breathable, passive-cooling, non-inflammatory, and biodegradable aerogel electronic skin for wearable physical-electrophysiological-chemical analysis. <i>Adv. Mater.</i><b>35</b>, 202209300 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10006339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36576895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H. G. et al. Breathable and skin-conformal electronics with hybrid integration of microfabricated multifunctional sensors and kirigami-structured nanofibrous substrates. <i>Adv. Funct. Mater.</i><b>32</b>, 2202792 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, S. M. &amp; Chung, W. Y. Monitoring transepidermal water loss and skin wettedness factor with battery-free NFC sensor. <i>Sensors</i><b>20</b>, 5549 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7583755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32998315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, S. X. et al. &#x201c;Cut-and-Paste&#x201d; manufacture of multiparametric epidermal sensor systems. <i>Adv. Mater.</i><b>27</b>, 6423&#x2013;6430 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26398335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, B. W. &amp; Detzel, P. R. Treatment of childhood atopic dermatitis and economic burden of illness in Asia Pacific countries. <i>Ann. Nutr. Metab.</i><b>66</b>, 18&#x2013;24 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25925337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wollenberg, A. et al. European guideline (EuroGuiDerm) on atopic eczema &#x2013; Part II: Non-systemic treatments and treatment recommendations for special AE patient populations. <i>J. Eur. Acad. Dermatol. Venereol.</i><b>36</b>, 1904&#x2013;1926 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36056736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H. G., Zhang, Z., Zhang, H., Guo, Y. F. &amp; Yao, Z. R. Update on the pathogenesis and therapy of atopic dermatitis. <i>Clin. Rev. Allergy Immunol.</i><b>61</b>, 324&#x2013;338 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34338977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hengge, U. R. et al. Adverse effects of topical glucocorticosteroids. <i>J. Am. Acad. Dermatol.</i><b>54</b>, 1&#x2013;15 (2006).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16384751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrara, G. et al. Clinical use and molecular action of corticosteroids in the pediatric age. <i>Int. J. Mol. Sci.</i><b>20</b>, 444 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6359239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30669566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, H. et al. A graphene-based electrochemical device with thermoresponsive microneedles for diabetes monitoring and therapy. <i>Nat. Nanotechnol.</i><b>11</b>, 566&#x2013;572 (2016).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26999482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, H. et al. Wearable/disposable sweat-based glucose monitoring device with multistage transdermal drug delivery module. <i>Sci. Adv.</i><b>3</b>, e1601314 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5342654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28345030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, J. C. et al. Glucose-responsive insulin patch for the regulation of blood glucose in mice and minipigs. <i>Nat. Biomed. Eng.</i><b>4</b>, 499&#x2013;506 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7231631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32015407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, M. L. et al. Nanoparticles-encapsulated polymeric microneedles for transdermal drug delivery. <i>J. Control. Release</i><b>325</b>, 163&#x2013;175 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32629134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, G. J. &amp; Wu, C. Microneedle, bio-microneedle and bio-inspired microneedle: a review. <i>J. Control. Release</i><b>251</b>, 11&#x2013;23 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28215667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Y. et al. Improved pharmacodynamics of epidermal growth factor via microneedles-based self-powered transcutaneous electrical stimulation. <i>Nat. Commun.</i><b>13</b>, 6908 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9663450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36376334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, L. et al. Implantable microarray patch: engineering at the nano and macro scale for sustained therapeutic release via synthetic biodegradable polymers. <i>Adv. Mater. Technol.</i><b>9</b>, 202400346 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knopf-Marques, H. et al. Hyaluronic acid and its derivatives in coating and delivery systems: applications in tissue engineering, regenerative medicine and immunomodulation. <i>Adv. Healthc. Mater.</i><b>5</b>, 2841&#x2013;2855 (2016).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27709832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuo, F., Abourehab, M. A. S. &amp; Hussain, Z. Hyaluronic acid decorated tacrolimus-loaded nanoparticles: efficient approach to maximize dermal targeting and anti-dermatitis efficacy. <i>Carbohydr. Polym.</i><b>197</b>, 478&#x2013;489 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30007638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huynh, A. &amp; Priefer, R. Hyaluronic acid applications in ophthalmology, rheumatology, and dermatology. <i>Carbohydr. Res.</i><b>489</b>, 107950 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32070808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anilkumar, T. V. et al. Advantages of hyaluronic acid as a component of fibrin sheet for care of acute wound. <i>Biologics</i><b>39</b>, 81&#x2013;88 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21334921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, J. et al. Multifunctional hyaluronic acid microneedle patch embedded by cerium/zinc-based composites for accelerating diabetes wound healing. <i>Adv. Healthc. Mater.</i><b>12</b>, 2300725 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37086396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng, Y. Y. et al. Multifunctional polysaccharide composited microneedle for oral ulcers healing. <i>Mater. Today Bio</i><b>22</b>, 100782 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10495667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37706204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J. B. et al. A novel natural polysaccharide dissolving microneedle capable of adsorbing pus to load EGCG for the treatment of acne vulgaris. <i>Mater. Des.</i><b>238</b>, 112639 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, C. et al. Portable and wearable self-powered systems based on emerging energy harvesting technology. <i>Microsyst. Nanoeng.</i><b>7</b>, 25 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8433392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34567739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnan, S. et al. Multimodal epidermal devices for hydration monitoring. <i>Microsyst. Nanoeng.</i><b>3</b>, 17014 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6444991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31057861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webb, R. C. et al. Ultrathin conformal devices for precise and continuous thermal characterization of human skin. <i>Nat. Mater.</i><b>12</b>, 938&#x2013;944 (2013).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3825211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24037122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustafsson, S. E. Transient plane source techniques for thermal conductivity and thermal diffusivity measurements of solid materials. <i>Rev. Sci. Instrum.</i><b>62</b>, 797&#x2013;804 (1991).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawakami, T. et al. Mast cells in atopic dermatitis. <i>Curr. Opin. Immunol.</i><b>21</b>, 666&#x2013;678 (2009).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2839879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19828304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parrilla, M. et al. Wearable microneedle-based array patches for continuous electrochemical monitoring and drug delivery: toward a closed-loop system for methotrexate treatment. <i>ACS Sens.</i><b>8</b>, 4161&#x2013;4170 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37856156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi, Z. et al. Electro-responsive silk fibroin microneedles for controlled release of insulin. <i>Int. J. Biol. Macromol.</i><b>1</b>, 124684 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37148951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, J. et al. Masticatory system&#x2013;inspired microneedle theranostic platform for intelligent and precise diabetic management. <i>Sci. Adv.</i><b>8</b>, eabo6900 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9750147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36516258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gita, K. et al. A pH-mediated electronic wound dressing for controlled drug delivery. <i>Adv. Healthc. Mater.</i><b>7</b>, 1800396 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30073801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaap, M. J. et al. Skin surface protein detection by transdermal analysis patches in pediatric psoriasis. <i>Ski. Pharmacol. Physiol.</i><b>34</b>, 271&#x2013;280 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8491489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34015784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, X. et al. Epidermal impedance sensing sheets for precision hydration assessment and spatial mapping. <i>IEEE Trans. Biomed. Eng.</i><b>60</b>, 2848&#x2013;2857 (2013).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23739778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>