<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39330672</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2079-4991</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>18</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nanomaterials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nanomaterials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Foam Stabilization Process for Nano-Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> and Its Effect on Mechanical Properties of Foamed Concrete.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1516</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/nano14181516</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Foamed concrete is increasingly utilized in engineering due to its light weight, excellent thermal insulation, fire resistance, etc. However, its low strength has always been the most crucial factor limiting its large-scale application. This study introduced an innovative method to enhance the strength of foamed concrete by using nano-Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> (NA) as a foam stabilizer. NA was introduced into a foaming agent containing sodium dodecyl sulfate (SDS) and hydroxypropyl methylcellulose (HPMC) to prepare a highly stable foam. This approach significantly improved the foam stability and the strength of foamed concrete. Its drainage volume, settlement distance, microstructure, and stabilizing action were investigated, along with the strength, microstructure, and hydration products of foamed concrete. The presence of NA effectively reduced the drainage volume and settlement distance of the foam. NA is distributed at the gas-liquid interface and within the liquid film to play a hindering role, increasing the thickness of the liquid film, delaying the liquid discharge rate from the liquid film, and hindering bubble aggregation, thereby enhancing foam stability. Additionally, due to the stabilizing effect of NA on the foam, the precast foam forms a fine and uniform pore structure in the hardened foamed concrete. At 28 d, the compressive strength of FC0 (0% NAs in foam) is 2.18 MPa, while that of FC3 (0.18% NAs in foam) is 3.90 MPa, increased by 79%. The reason for this is that NA promotes the formation of AFt, and its secondary hydration leads to the continuous consumption of Ca(OH)<sub>2</sub>, resulting in a more complete hydration reaction. This study presents a novel method for significantly improving the performance of foamed concrete by incorporating NA.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Haibao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Chang'an University, Xi'an 710061, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xi'an Sipai New Materials Technology Co., Ltd., Xi'an 710061, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zhenjun</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Chang'an University, Xi'an 710061, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shaanxi Union Research Center of University and Enterprise for Advanced Transportation Infrastructure Materials, Xi'an 710061, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Ting</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Chang'an University, Xi'an 710061, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zhaorui</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Chang'an University, Xi'an 710061, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024GX-YBXM-377</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Development Project of Shaanxi Province, China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>21-53K</GrantID><Agency>Shaanxi Transportation Technology Project, China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>23KGDW0035-2023</GrantID><Agency>Xi'an Science and Technology Plan Project, China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023JH-GXRC-0059</GrantID><Agency>Xi'an Science and Technology Bureau Project, China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Nanomaterials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101610216</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2079-4991</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">foam stability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">foamed concrete</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mechanical property</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microstructure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nano-Al2O3</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Author Haibao Zhang was employed by the company Xi&#x2019;an Sipai New Materials Technology Co., Ltd. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39330672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11434740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nano14181516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">nano14181516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kugler S., Ossowicz P., Malarczyk-Matusiak K., Wierzbicka E. Advances in Rosin-Based Chemicals: The Latest Recipes, Applications and Future Trends. Molecules. 2019;24:1651. doi: 10.3390/molecules24091651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules24091651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6539233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31035500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang L., Wang Z., Gao X., Cui M., Yang Q., Qin J. Effect of nanoparticles and surfactants on properties and microstructures of foam and foamed concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;411:134444. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Q., Chen S., Yang R., Wang Z., Zhao Y. Temperature affected cement foaming and foams. Cem. Concr. Res. 2024;181:107532. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2024.107532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2024.107532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G., Tan H., He X., Zhang J., Deng X., Zheng Z. Research on the properties of wet-ground waste limestone powder as foam stabilizer in foamed concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2022;329:127203. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.127203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.127203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou L., Li J., Lu Z., Niu Y. Influence of foaming agent on cement and foam concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;280:122399. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Lu X., Wang J., Deng X., Li M., Lv X., Zhu C., Tan H. Modification of super-sulfated cement based foamed concrete with nano-ettringite. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;417:135200. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar N.V., Arunkumar C., Senthil S.S. Experimental Study on Mechanical and Thermal Behavior of Foamed Concrete. Mater. Today Proc. 2018;5:8753&#x2013;8760. doi: 10.1016/j.matpr.2017.12.302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2017.12.302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feneuil B., Aimedieu P., Scheel M., Perrin J., Roussel N., Pitois O. Stability criterion for fresh cement foams. Cem. Concr. Res. 2019;125:105865. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang G., Liu T., Li H., Dong B., Shi T. A novel synthesis of lightweight and high-strength green geopolymer foamed material by rice husk ash and ground-granulated blast-furnace slag. Resour. Conserv. Recycl. 2022;176:105922. doi: 10.1016/j.resconrec.2021.105922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resconrec.2021.105922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu Y., Wang X., Wang L., Li Y. Foam Concrete: A State-of-the-Art and State-of-the-Practice Review. Adv. Mater. Sci. Eng. 2020;2020:1&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1155/2020/6153602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/6153602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones M.R., Ozlutas K., Zheng L. Stability and instability of foamed concrete. Mag. Concr. Res. 2016;68:542&#x2013;549. doi: 10.1680/macr.15.00097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1680/macr.15.00097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh V., Tyagi R. Investigations of mixed surfactant systems of lauryl alcohol-based bissulfosuccinate anionic gemini surfactants with conventional surfactants: A fluorometric study. J. Taibah Univ. Sci. 2018;9:477&#x2013;489. doi: 10.1016/j.jtusci.2015.01.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtusci.2015.01.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Z., Zeng J., Chu S., Zhou W., Mu Y., Ye G. Effect of different foam stabilizers on the setting behavior and pore characteristics of CAC-bonded Al2O3 foamed ceramics. Ceram. Int. 2023;49:10574&#x2013;10579. doi: 10.1016/j.ceramint.2022.11.244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceramint.2022.11.244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He J., Gao Q., Song X., Bu X., He J. Effect of foaming agent on physical and mechanical properties of alkali-activated slag foamed concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;226:280&#x2013;287. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.07.302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.07.302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu H., Chen L., Xu J., Han Q. Experimental study on performance improvement of anionic surfactant foaming agent by xanthan gum. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;230:116993. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.116993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.116993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu X., Jiang N., Miao X., Zong R., Sheng Y., Li C., Lu S. Formation of stable aqueous foams on the ethanol layer: Synergistic stabilization of fluorosurfactant and polymers. Colloids Surf. A Physicochem. Eng. Asp. 2020;591:124545. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2020.124545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2020.124545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C., Wang D., Wang H., Hu J., Zhu X., Zhang Y. Effect of partially hydrolyzed polyacrylamide on the solution and foam properties of sodium alcohol ether sulfate. Colloids Surf. A Physicochem. Eng. Asp. 2018;556:51&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2018.08.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2018.08.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu G., Zhu Q., Yuan C., Wang H., Li C., Sun S., Hu S. Molecular dynamics simulation of the influence of polyacrylamide on the stability of sodium dodecyl sulfate foam. Chem. Eng. Sci. 2017;166:313&#x2013;319. doi: 10.1016/j.ces.2017.03.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ces.2017.03.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derkach S.R. Interfacial layers of complex-forming ionic surfactants with gelatin. Adv. Colloid. Interface Sci. 2015;222:172&#x2013;198. doi: 10.1016/j.cis.2014.05.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cis.2014.05.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24970019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahu S.S., Gandhi I.S.R. Studies on influence of characteristics of surfactant and foam on foam concrete behaviour. J. Build. Eng. 2021;40:102333. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2021.102333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2021.102333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., Yang F., Lv Y., Wu P., Zeng W., Xu G. Research progress on foam stabilization method and mechanism of foamed concrete. J. Chin. Ceram. Soc. 2021;49:2266&#x2013;2275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C., Fan D., Lu J.-X., Pang C., Poon C.S. Ultra-stable foam enabled by nano silica engineering for foam concrete improvement. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2024;150:105575. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2024.105575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2024.105575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo S., Wang W., Jia Z., Qi X., Zhu H., Liu X. Nanoparticle-stabilized foam with controllable structure for enhanced foamed concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;362:129723. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Y., Zhu Y., Chen C., Zhang Y. Effect of nano-alumina modified foaming agents on properties of foamed concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;267:121045. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G., Tan H., He X., Zhang J., Deng X., Zheng Z., Guo Y. The influence of wet ground fly ash on the performance of foamed concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;304:124676. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruglyakov P.M., Elaneva S.I., Vilkova N.G. About mechanism of foam stabilization by solid particles. Adv. Colloid. Interface Sci. 2011;165:108&#x2013;116. doi: 10.1016/j.cis.2011.02.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cis.2011.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21382608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou L., Li J., Lu Z., Niu Y., Jiang J., Li T. Effect of nanoparticles on foaming agent and the foamed concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;227:116698. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.116698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.116698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Common Portland Cement. Standardization Administration of China; Beijing, China: 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Technical Specification for Application of Foamed Concrete. Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development; Beijing, China: 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foaming Agents for Foamed Concrete. Ministry of Industry and Information Technology; Beijing, China: 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu J., Xie J., Jiang X., Li Q., Wang X., Zhang L., Yin L., Deng L. Improving oxidation resistance of ZrB2-based ceramics by LaF3 doping via oxidation-induced self-healing mechanism. Ceram. Int. 2021;47:9504&#x2013;9512. doi: 10.1016/j.ceramint.2020.12.084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceramint.2020.12.084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma G., Li G., Mu X., Hou W., Ren Y., Yang M. Effect of raindrop splashes on topsoil structure and infiltration characteristics. Catena. 2022;212:106040. doi: 10.1016/j.catena.2022.106040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.catena.2022.106040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foamed Concrete. Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development; Beijing, China: 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desbordes L., Grandjean A., Frances F., Lorcet H., Faure S. Critical bubble diameters and Plateau border dimensions for drainage in aqueous xanthan foams. Colloids Surf. A Physicochem. Eng. Asp. 2021;612:125682. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2020.125682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2020.125682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruglyakov P.M., Nushtayeva A.V. Phase inversion in emulsions stabilised by solid particles. Adv. Colloid. Interface Sci. 2004;108&#x2013;109:151&#x2013;158. doi: 10.1016/j.cis.2003.10.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cis.2003.10.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15072938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Nguyen A.V., Farrokhpay S. A critical review of the growth, drainage and collapse of foams. Adv. Colloid. Interface Sci. 2016;228:55&#x2013;70. doi: 10.1016/j.cis.2015.11.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cis.2015.11.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26718078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rio E., Biance A.L. Thermodynamic and mechanical timescales involved in foam film rupture and liquid foam coalescence. Chemphyschem. 2014;15:3692&#x2013;3707. doi: 10.1002/cphc.201402195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cphc.201402195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25257045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickinson E., Ettelaie R., Kostakis T., Murray B.S. Factors controlling the formation and stability of air bubbles stabilized by partially hydrophobic silica nanoparticles. Langmuir. 2004;20:8517&#x2013;8525. doi: 10.1021/la048913k.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la048913k</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15379469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y., Chen X., Chen B., Wen R., Wu P. Analysis of foamed concrete pore structure of railway roadbed based on X-ray computed tomography. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;273:121773. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T., Ma B., Jiang D., Jiang Q., Jin Z. Comparative research on the effect of various mineral admixtures on the early hydration process of cement. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;301:124372. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang A., Ge Y., Du S., Wang G., Chen X., Liu X., Li H. Durability effect of nano-SiO2/Al2O3 on cement mortar subjected to sulfate attack under different environments. J. Build. Eng. 2023;64:105642. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2022.105642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.105642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Ma B., Tan H., Li H., Mei J., Zhang T., Chen P., Gu B. Chloride immobilization of cement-based material containing nano-Al2O3. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;220:43&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.05.148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.05.148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C., Cao Y., Li G., Liang Q., Wu X., Wu G., Wang F., Du Q., Wang Y., Qi S., et al. Modified cementitious materials incorporating Al2O3 and SiO2 nanoparticle reinforcements: An experimental investigation. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2023;19:e02542. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dadsetan S., Bai J. Mechanical and microstructural properties of self-compacting concrete blended with metakaolin, ground granulated blast-furnace slag and fly ash. Constr. Build. Mater. 2017;146:658&#x2013;667. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.04.158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.04.158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>