<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40480251</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1361-6560</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>70</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physics in medicine and biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Phys Med Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hydrated electron yield dependence on instantaneous dose rates with electron ultra-high dose rate (UHDR) irradiation.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1088/1361-6560/ade223</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><i>Objective.</i>The aim of this study was to quantify the characteristic transient production yield of hydrated electrons (<i>G</i>-value) in water under ultra-high dose rates (UHDR) with electron irradiation. Changes in this yield with UHDR irradiation may provide insights into the radiation chemistry origins of the normal tissue-sparing effect observed in FLASH therapy.<i>Approach.</i>A multi-pass transmission measurement technique was used to detect and quantify hydrated electrons based on its near-infrared absorption. Transient absorbance profiles of hydrated electrons were used to estimate the<i>G</i>-value as a function of variation in pulse width, source-to-surface distance and pulse frequency, to assess dependence upon instantaneous and average dose rates.<i>Main results.</i>The study confirmed a linear relationship between total radiation dose and production of hydrated electrons, giving a stable<i>G</i>-value for a fixed dose rate. However, the measured<i>G</i>-value increased with increasing instantaneous dose rates (0.18-0.33 MGy s<sup>-1</sup>), ranging from 35 up to 48 nM Gy<sup>-1</sup>. However, the<i>G</i>-value did not change appreciably when varying the pulse frequency and pulse width, which varies the average dose rate.<i>Significance.</i>The instantaneous dose rate of UHDR directly influenced the generation yield of hydrated electrons during UHDR water radiolysis. Further research is needed to solidify this connection and to better understand the role of hydrated electrons in the observed sparing effect of FLASH radiotherapy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Creative Commons Attribution license.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Xu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8749-1716</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Physics, School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI 53705, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Science and Technology, Xidian University, Xi'an, Shaanxi, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parks</LastName><ForeName>Aubrey</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Physics, School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI 53705, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thomas</LastName><ForeName>William</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Physics, School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI 53705, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reed</LastName><ForeName>Matthew S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Physics, School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI 53705, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Culberson</LastName><ForeName>Wesley S</ForeName><Initials>WS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4573-4406</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Physics, School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI 53705, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pogue</LastName><ForeName>Brian W</ForeName><Initials>BW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9887-670X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Physics, School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI 53705, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P30 CA014520</GrantID><Acronym>CA</Acronym><Agency>NCI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 CA271330</GrantID><Acronym>CA</Acronym><Agency>NCI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U01 CA260446</GrantID><Acronym>CA</Acronym><Agency>NCI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Phys Med Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0401220</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0031-9155</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004583" MajorTopicYN="Y">Electrons</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="Y">Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011829" MajorTopicYN="Y">Radiation Dosage</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004307" MajorTopicYN="N">Dose-Response Relationship, Radiation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FLASH therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydrated electron</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ultra-high dose rate</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40480251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2115557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12662644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1361-6560/ade223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Alanazi A, Meesungnoen J and Jay-Gerin J-P 2021a. A computer modeling study of water radiolysis at high dose rates. Relevance to FLASH radiotherapy Radiation research 195 149&#x2013;62</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33300999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alanazi A, Meesungnoen J and Jay-Gerin JP 2021b. A Computer Modeling Study of Water Radiolysis at High Dose Rates. Relevance to FLASH Radiotherapy Radiation Research 195 149&#x2013;62</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33300999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexandre J, Batteux F, Nicco C, Ch&#xe9;reau C, Laurent A, Guillevin L, Weill B and Goldwasser F 2006. Accumulation of hydrogen peroxide is an early and crucial step for paclitaxel-induced cancer cell death both in vitro and in vivo International journal of cancer 119 41&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16450384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almeida A, Togno M, Ballesteros-Zebadua P, Franco-Perez J, Geyer R, Schaefer R, Petit B, Grilj V, Meer D and Safai S 2024. Dosimetric and biologic intercomparison between electron and proton FLASH beams Radiotherapy and oncology 190 109953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37839557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blain G, Vandenborre J, Villoing D, Fiegel V, Fois GR, Haddad F, Koumeir C, Maigne L, M&#xe9;tivier V and Poirier F 2022. Proton irradiations at ultra-high dose rate vs. conventional dose rate: Strong impact on hydrogen peroxide yield Radiation Research 198 318&#x2013;24</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35675499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boscolo D, Scifoni E, Durante M, Kramer M and Fuss MC 2021. May oxygen depletion explain the FLASH effect? A chemical track structure analysis Radiother Oncol 162 68&#x2013;75</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34214612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourhis J, Sozzi WJ, Jorge PG, Gaide O, Bailat C, Duclos F, Patin D, Ozsahin M, Bochud F and Germond J-F 2019. Treatment of a first patient with FLASH-radiotherapy Radiotherapy and oncology 139 18&#x2013;22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31303340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao X, Zhang R, Esipova TV, Allu SR, Ashraf R, Rahman M, Gunn JR, Bruza P, Gladstone DJ, Williams BB, Swartz HM, Hoopes PJ, Vinogradov SA and Pogue BW 2021. Quantification of Oxygen Depletion During FLASH Irradiation In Vitro and In Vivo Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys 111 240&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8338745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33845146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D-Kondo JN, Garcia-Garcia OR, LaVerne JA, Faddegon B, Schuemann J, Shin W-G and Ramos-M&#xe9;ndez J 2023. An integrated Monte Carlo track-structure simulation framework for modeling inter and intra-track effects on homogenous chemistry Physics in Medicine &amp; Biology 68 125008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10355172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37201533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Khatib M, Van Slyke A L, Velalopoulou A, Kim MM, Shoniyozov K, Allu SR, Diffenderfer EE, Busch TM, Wiersma RD, Koch CJ and Vinogradov SA 2022. Ultrafast Tracking of Oxygen Dynamics During Proton FLASH Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys 113 624&#x2013;34</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9250619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35314293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favaudon V, Caplier L, Monceau V, Pouzoulet F, Sayarath M, Fouillade C, Poupon MF, Brito I, Hupe P, Bourhis J, Hall J, Fontaine JJ and Vozenin MC 2014. Ultrahigh dose-rate FLASH irradiation increases the differential response between normal and tumor tissue in mice Sci Transl Med 6 245ra93</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25031268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ha B, Liang K, Liu C, Melemenidis S, Manjappa R, Viswanathan V, Das N, Ashraf R, Lau B, Soto L, Graves EE, Rao J, Loo BW Jr. and Pratx G 2022. Real-time optical oximetry during FLASH radiotherapy using a phosphorescent nanoprobe Radiother Oncol 176 239&#x2013;43</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11277691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35964762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Held KD, McNamara AL, Daartz J, Bhagwat MS, Rothwell B and Schuemann J 2024. Dose Rate Effects from the 1950s through to the Era of FLASH Radiation Research 202 161&#x2013;76</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11426361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38954556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiroki A, Pimblott SM and LaVerne JA 2002. Hydrogen peroxide production in the radiolysis of water with high radical scavenger concentrations The Journal of Physical Chemistry A 106 9352&#x2013;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horst F, Sch&#xfc;ller A, Kapsch R, Hackel T and Pawelke J 2024. PP13. 07 STUDY ON THE DOSE RATE DEPENDENCE OF EBT3 FILMS Physica Medica 125 103901</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin J-Y, Gu A, Wang W, Oleinick NL and Machtay M 2020. Ultra-high dose rate effect on circulating immune cells: A potential mechanism for FLASH effect? Radiotherapy and Oncology 149 55&#x2013;62</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7442672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32387486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karsch L, Beyreuther E, Burris-Mog T, Kraft S, Richter C, Zeil K and Pawelke J 2012. Dose rate dependence for different dosimeters and detectors: TLD, OSL, EBT films, and diamond detectors Medical physics 39 2447&#x2013;55</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22559615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch CJ, Kim MM and Wiersma RD 2023. Radiation-Chemical Oxygen Depletion Depends on Chemical Environment and Dose Rate: Implications for the FLASH Effect Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys 117 214&#x2013;22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11044555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37059234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristensen L, Rohrer S, Hoffmann L, Pr&#xe6;stegaard LH, Ankj&#xe6;rgaard C, Andersen CE, Kanouta E, Johansen JG, Sahlertz M and Nijkamp J 2025. Electron vs proton FLASH radiation on murine skin toxicity Radiotherapy and Oncology 110796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39983873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kusumoto T, Danvin A, Mamiya T, Arnone A, Chefson S, Galindo C, Peaupardin P, Raffy Q, Kamiguchi N and Amano D 2024. Dose Rate Effects on Hydrated Electrons, Hydrogen Peroxide, and a OH Radical Molecular Probe Under Clinical Energy Protons Radiation Research 201 287&#x2013;93</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38407439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K, Waldrop T, Aguilar E, Mims N, Neill D, Delahoussaye A, Li Z, Swanson D, Lin SH and Koong AC 2025. Redefining FLASH radiation therapy: The impact of mean dose rate and dose per pulse in the gastrointestinal tract International Journal of Radiation Oncology* Biology* Physics 121 1063&#x2013;76</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39424078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mari&#x107; D and Burrows J 1996. Application of a Gaussian distribution function to describe molecular UV&#x2013; visible absorption continua. 1. Theory The Journal of Physical Chemistry 100 8645&#x2013;59</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKeague A, Wilson D and Nelson J 2003. Staurosporine-induced apoptosis and hydrogen peroxide-induced necrosis in two human breast cell lines British journal of cancer 88 125&#x2013;31</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2376787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12556971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe9;grour&#xe8;che J, Bekerat H, Bian J, Bui A, Sankey J, Childress L and Enger SA 2023. Development of a hydrated electron dosimeter for radiotherapy applications: a proof of concept Medical Physics 50 7245&#x2013;51</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37334736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montay-Gruel P, Acharya MM, Petersson K, Alikhani L, Yakkala C, Allen BD, Ollivier J, Petit B, Jorge PG, Syage AR, Nguyen TA, Baddour AD, Lu C, Singh P, Moeckli R, Bochud F, Germond JF, Froidevaux P, Bailat C, Bourhis J, Vozenin MC and Limoli CL 2020. Long-term neurocognitive benefits of FLASH radiotherapy driven by reduced reactive oxygen species (vol 116, pg 10943, 2019) P Natl Acad Sci USA 117 25946&#x2013;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6561167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31097580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montay-Gruel P, Bouchet A, Jaccard M, Patin D, Serduc R, Aim W, Petersson K, Petit B, Bailat C and Bourhis J 2018. X-rays can trigger the FLASH effect: Ultra-high dose-rate synchrotron light source prevents normal brain injury after whole brain irradiation in mice Radiotherapy and Oncology 129 582&#x2013;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30177374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montay-Gruel P, Petersson K, Jaccard M, Boivin G, Germond J-F, Petit B, Doenlen R, Favaudon V, Bochud F and Bailat C 2017. Irradiation in a flash: Unique sparing of memory in mice after whole brain irradiation with dose rates above 100 Gy/s Radiotherapy and Oncology 124 365&#x2013;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28545957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersson K, Adrian G, Butterworth K and McMahon SJ 2020. A Quantitative Analysis of the Role of Oxygen Tension in FLASH Radiation Therapy Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys 107 539&#x2013;47</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32145319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothwell BC, Kirkby NF, Merchant MJ, Chadwick AL, Lowe M, Mackay RI, Hendry JH and Kirkby KJ 2021. Determining the parameter space for effective oxygen depletion for FLASH radiation therapy Phys Med Biol 66</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8208623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33535191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruan J-L, Lee C, Wouters S, Tullis ID, Verslegers M, Mysara M, Then CK, Smart SC, Hill MA and Muschel RJ 2021. Irradiation at ultra-high (FLASH) dose rates reduces acute normal tissue toxicity in the mouse gastrointestinal system International Journal of Radiation Oncology* Biology* Physics 111 1250&#x2013;61</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7612009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34400268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sehested K, Rasmussen OL and Fricke H 1968. Rate constants of OH with HO2, O2-, and H2O2+ from hydrogen peroxide formation in pulse-irradiated oxygenated water The Journal of Physical Chemistry 72 626&#x2013;31</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin W-G, D-Kondo JN, Ramos-M&#xe9;ndez J, LaVerne JA, Rothwell B, Bertolet A, McNamara A, Faddegon B, Paganetti H and Schuemann J 2024. Investigation of hydrogen peroxide yields and oxygen consumption in high dose rate irradiation: a TOPAS-nBio Monte Carlo study Physics in Medicine &amp; Biology 70 015012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12184618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39657326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sunnerberg JP, Zhang R, Gladstone DJ, Swartz HM, Gui J and Pogue BW 2023. Mean dose rate in ultra-high dose rate electron irradiation is a significant predictor for O2 consumption and H2O2 yield Physics in Medicine &amp; Biology 68 165014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10405361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37463588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas W, Sunnerberg J, Reed M, Gladstone DJ, Zhang R, Harms J, Swartz HM and Pogue BW 2024. Proton and electron ultrahigh-dose-rate isodose irradiations produce differences in reactive oxygen species yields International Journal of Radiation Oncology* Biology* Physics 118 262&#x2013;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10843497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37558097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torche F and Marignier J-L 2016. Direct evaluation of the molar absorption coefficient of hydrated electron by the isosbestic point method The Journal of Physical Chemistry B 120 7201&#x2013;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27362328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Slyke AL, El Khatib M, Velalopoulou A, Diffenderfer E, Shoniyozov K, Kim MM, Karagounis IV, Busch TM, Vinogradov SA and Koch CJ 2022. Oxygen monitoring in model solutions and in vivo in mice during proton irradiation at conventional and FLASH dose rates Radiation research 198 181&#x2013;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10176203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35640166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velalopoulou A, Karagounis IV, Cramer GM, Kim MM, Skoufos G, Goia D, Hagan S, Verginadis II, Shoniyozov K and Chiango J 2021. FLASH proton radiotherapy spares normal epithelial and mesenchymal tissues while preserving sarcoma response Cancer research 81 4808&#x2013;21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8715480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34321243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villoing D, Koumeir C, Bongrand A, Guertin A, Haddad F, M&#xe9;tivier V, Poirier F, Potiron V, Servagent N and Supiot S
2022. 
Proton beam dosimetry at ultra-high dose rates (FLASH): Evaluation of GAFchromic<sup>&#x2122;</sup>(EBT3, EBT-XD) and OrthoChromic (OC-1) film performances
Medical Physics
49
2732&#x2013;45
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35179234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vozenin M 2020. Towards clinical implementation of FLASH radiotherapy Radiotherapy and Oncology 152 S414&#x2013;S</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C-R, Nguyen J and Lu Q-B 2009. Bond breaks of nucleotides by dissociative electron transfer of nonequilibrium prehydrated electrons: a new molecular mechanism for reductive DNA damage Journal of the American Chemical Society 131 11320&#x2013;2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19634911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Wang Z and Chao X 2021. Gaussian process regression for direct laser absorption spectroscopy in complex combustion environments Optics Express 29 17926&#x2013;39</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34154064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T, Stengl C, Derksen L, Palskis K, Koritsidis K, Zink K, Adeberg S, Major G, Weishaar D and Thei&#xdf; U 2024a. Analysis of hydrogen peroxide production in pure water: Ultrahigh versus conventional dose-rate irradiation and mechanistic insights Medical physics 51 7439&#x2013;52</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39092902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T, Stengl C, Derksen L, Palskis K, Koritsidis K, Zink K, Adeberg S, Major G, Weishaar D, Theiss U, Jin J, Spadea MF, Theodoridou E, Hesser J, Baumann KS and Seco J 2024b. Analysis of hydrogen peroxide production in pure water: Ultrahigh versus conventional dose-rate irradiation and mechanistic insights Med Phys</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39092902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou G 2020. Mechanisms underlying FLASH radiotherapy, a novel way to enlarge the differential responses to ionizing radiation between normal and tumor tissues Radiation Medicine and Protection 1 35&#x2013;40</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>