<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41085096</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-4095</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advanced materials (Deerfield Beach, Fla.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Mater</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Crystalline Confinement of Dynamic Room-Temperature Phosphorescent Hydrogels: A New Paradigm for Synergistic Enhancement between Lifetime and Flexibility.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e14693</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e14693</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/adma.202514693</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Dynamic room-temperature phosphorescence (RTP) materials present promising applications in optoelectronic fields.&#xa0; However, conventional dynamic RTP hydrogels typically suffer from an inherent performance trade-off, where enhancement of flexibility comes at the expense of phosphorescence lifetime and vice versa. Herein, a universal crystalline confinement strategy is reported to overcome this fundamental limitation by employing ionic comonomers to regulate crystalline domains. By incorporating ionic comonomers such as 3-sulfopropyl methacrylate potassium salt (SPM), the hydration competition and disruption of crystalline packing enable precise control over crystal dimensions, yielding hydrogels with exceptional stretchability (634%) and toughness (12 MJ&#xa0;m<sup>-3</sup>, 107-fold improvement). The ionic comonomers also serve as electrostatic anchoring sites for chromophores, stabilizing triplet excitons and significantly prolonging the phosphorescence lifetime to 598.79 ms. This approach overcomes traditional trade-offs between flexibility and phosphorescence lifetime, demonstrating broad applicability across various ionic comonomers with &#x2248;100-fold toughness enhancements and prolonged phosphorescence lifetime. These results establish a generalizable framework linking crystalline domain dynamics with photophysical properties in dynamic hydrogels. The design opens avenues for advanced dynamic RTP materials in stretchable optoelectronics, dynamic encryption, smart sensors, and reagent thermal history monitoring.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Wiley&#x2010;VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deng</LastName><ForeName>Yifan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Natural Product Chemistry, Lanzhou Magnetic Resonance Center, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, 730000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Panyi</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Natural Product Chemistry, Lanzhou Magnetic Resonance Center, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, 730000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Xipeng</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Natural Product Chemistry, Lanzhou Magnetic Resonance Center, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, 730000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Ningyan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Natural Product Chemistry, Lanzhou Magnetic Resonance Center, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, 730000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Song</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Natural Product Chemistry, Lanzhou Magnetic Resonance Center, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, 730000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Zehua</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Natural Product Chemistry, Lanzhou Magnetic Resonance Center, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, 730000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>L&#xfc;</LastName><ForeName>Shaoyu</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0171-6601</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Natural Product Chemistry, Lanzhou Magnetic Resonance Center, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, 730000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>lzujbky-2024-it11</GrantID><Agency>Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>25JRRA745</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Gansu Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>21875094</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Mater</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9885358</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0935-9648</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dynamic hydrogel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">flexibility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">room&#x2010;temperature phosphorescence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tunable crystalline domains</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41085096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202514693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>A. Kishimura, T. Yamashita, K. Yamaguchi, T. Aida, Nat. Mater. 2005, 4, 546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Dai, X. Niu, X. Wu, Y. Ren, Y. Zhang, G. Li, H. Su, Y. Lei, J. Xiao, J. Shi, B. Tong, Z. Cai, Y. Dong, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2022, 61, 202200236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Huang, B. Chen, X. Zhang, C. O. Trindle, F. Liao, Y. Wang, H. Miao, Y. Luo, G. Zhang, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2018, 57, 16046.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Tao, C. Liu, Y. Xiang, Z. Wang, X. Xue, P. Li, H. Li, G. Xie, W. Huang, R. Chen, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2022, 144, 6946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Wang, H. Wu, W. Hu, J. F. Stoddart, Adv. Mater. 2022, 34, 2105405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Li, X. Liu, G. Wang, B. Li, H. Chen, H. Li, Y. Zhao, Nat. Commun. 2021, 12, 1363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Yang, A. Li, Y. Yang, J. Wang, Y. Chen, K. Yang, B. Z. Tang, Z. Li, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2023, 62, 202308848.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Ma, T.&#x2010;J. Ye, H.&#x2010;J. Yang, G.&#x2010;K. Ling, D. Wang, J.&#x2010;S. Li, P. Gu, L.&#x2010;J. Xu, T.&#x2010;L. Sheng, F.&#x2010;R. Lin, R.&#x2010;F. Shen, Q. Zhang, Aggregate 2024, 5, 579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Gao, M. Shi, Z. L&#xfc;, Q. Zhao, G. Chen, J. Bian, H. Qi, J. Ren, B. L&#xfc;, F. Peng, Adv. Mater. 2023, 35, 2305126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Guo, H. Li, Y. Yan, W. Zhao, Z. Gao, H. Cao, X. Yan, H. Li, G. Xie, R. Chen, Y. Tao, W. Huang, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2412100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Xu, W. Chen, K. Chen, S. Lin, Z. Wu, G. Deng, J. Chen, M. Tayyab, Y. Xiong, M.&#x2010;D. Li, D. Wang, Z. An, B. Z. Tang, Adv. Mater. 2025, 37, 2418778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Guo, Y. Chen, C. Li, X. Wang, Q. Li, M. He, H. Hou, C. Yang, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025, 35, 2416465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Li, K. Chen, J. Wei, Y. Ma, R. Zhou, S. Liu, Q. Zhao, W.&#x2010;Y. Wong, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2021, 143, 18317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Xie, Z. Mao, H. Wang, Y. Xiao, X. Zhang, T. Yu, Z. An, W. Huang, Light Sci. Appl. 2024, 13, 85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Chen, F. Lin, D. Guo, T. Tang, Y. Miao, Y. Wu, W. Zhai, H. Huang, Z. Chi, Y. Chen, Z. Yang, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2409642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhang, Y. Chen, J.&#x2010;Q. Li, S.&#x2010;E. Liu, Y. Liu, Adv. Sci. 2024, 11, 2307777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Man, Z. Lv, Y. Cao, Z. Xu, Q. Liao, J. Yao, F. Teng, A. Tang, H. Fu, Small 2024, 20, 2310226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhang, M. Gao, R. Wu, Y. Meng, N. Li, Z. Chen, M. Fang, J. Yang, Z. Li, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025, 35, 2502811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Li, X. Yang, B. Wang, P. Chen, Y. Ma, Q. Zhang, Y. Huang, Y. Zhang, S. L&#xfc;, Adv. Sci. 2024, 11, 2404698.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Duan, Q. Zheng, Y. Liang, T. Tu, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2409620.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Peng, X. Yao, X. Hu, B. Wu, X. Pei, Y. Yang, Z. Dong, Z. An, W. Huang, T. Cai, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2406618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Yang, Y. Liang, Y. Zheng, J.&#x2010;A. Li, S. Wu, H. Zhang, T. Huang, S. Luo, C. Liu, G. Shi, F. Sun, Z. Chi, B. Xu, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2022, 61, 202201820.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Zhou, C. Yang, Y. Zhao, Chem 2023, 9, 2446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H.&#x2010;J. Yu, Q. Zhou, X. Dai, F.&#x2010;F. Shen, Y.&#x2010;M. Zhang, X. Xu, Y. Liu, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2021, 143, 13887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Chen, Y. Zhang, J. Shan, M. Dong, Z. Qian, A. Lv, H.&#x2010;J. Qian, H. Ma, Z. An, L. Gu, W. Huang, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2025, 64, 202500610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Wei, C. Liu, J. Duan, A. Shao, J. Li, J. Li, W. Gu, Z. Li, S. Liu, Y. Ma, W. Huang, Q. Zhao, Nat. Commun. 2023, 14, 627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Gao, W. Yuan, Y. Li, A. Huang, Y. Fang, A. Li, K. Wang, B. Zou, Q. Li, Z. Li, Light Sci. Appl. 2025, 14, 99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Chen, X. Chen, D. Ma, Z. Mao, J. Zhao, Z. Chi, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2023, 145, 16748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Liu, B. Liang, Y. Dong, H. Wu, C. Zhang, H. Pei, M. Zuo, X. Yu, S. Zheng, S. Feng, W. Huang, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025, 35, 2419483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Ren, M. Gao, Z. Liu, Y. Yang, R. Wu, J. Liang, J. Yang, M. Fang, Z. Li, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 34, 2311659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Tu, Y. Chen, X. Song, W. Jiang, Y. Xie, Z. Li, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 63, 202402865.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Qi, J. Huang, J. Wei, J. Zhou, D. Liu, L. Li, W. Luo, G. Yin, T. Chen, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2025, 64, 202501054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Zhao, C. Wang, K. Huang, L. Li, W. Fan, Q. Zhu, H. Ma, X. Wang, Z. Wang, W. Huang, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2023, 145, 26532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Wang, Z. Yu, X. Sun, M. Panahi&#x2010;Sarmad, P. Yang, P. Zhu, Y. Zhu, H. Liu, F. Jiang, Adv. Mater. 2025, 37, 2416916.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Li, L. Liu, Y. Zhang, W. Zhao, X. Zhao, Y. Liu, B. Yu, S. Ma, F. Zhou, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2025, 64, 202424129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B.&#x2010;L. Zhang, L. Miao, W.&#x2010;T. Song, J.&#x2010;J. Zhang, J. Chen, T. Wang, W.&#x2010;Q. Zhang, J. Ni, Z. Zhao, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025, 35, 2415094.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Yang, A. Cholewinski, L. Yu, G. Rivers, B. Zhao, Nat. Mater. 2019, 18, 874.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Liu, Y. Fang, X. Xiong, W. Xu, J. Cui, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 63, 202320095.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. B. H. Schroeder, J. Aizenberg, Nat. Commun. 2022, 13, 259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Wei, G. Wei, Y. Shang, J. Zhou, C. Wu, Q. Wang, Adv. Mater. 2019, 31, 1900248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Kim, S. Hong, J. J. Park, Y. Jung, S. H. Choi, C. Cho, I. Ha, P. Won, C. Majidi, S. H. Ko, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2313344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. F. Green, J. Phys. Chem. 1908, 12, 655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Lizana, P. E. Sanchez&#x2010;Jimenez, R. Chacartegui, J. A. Becerra, L. A. Perez&#x2010;Maqueda, J. Energy Storage 2022, 55, 105584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Wei, R. Li, L. Li, W. Wang, T. Chen, Nano Micro Lett 2022, 14, 182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Yan, Y. Shi, C. Liu, J. Shao, N. Sun, B. Ma, Y. Li, J. Huang, S. Ge, ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2023, 15, 48632.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhao, Y. Chen, X. Song, Y. Li, L. Zhang, Y. Meng, X. Zhang, X. Qiu, J. Huang, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2023, 33, 2304439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. X. Hou, H. Ju, X. P. Hao, H. Zhang, L. Zhang, Z. He, J. Wang, Q. Zheng, Z. L. Wu, Adv. Mater. 2023, 35, 2300244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Chen, H. Qie, X. Yang, S. Ma, Z. Wang, N. Li, Y. Deng, F. Bian, S. L&#xfc;, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025, 35, 2416430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Lee, H. Kwak, Y. Eom, S.&#x2010;A. Park, T. Sakai, H. Jeon, J. M. Koo, D. Kim, C. Cha, S. Y. Hwang, J. Park, D. X. Oh, Nat. Mater. 2024, 23, 414.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Wang, L. Yu, S. Wang, L. Zhang, L. Chen, X. Xu, Z. Song, H. Liu, C. Chen, Nat. Commun. 2022, 13, 3408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Ye, H. Ma, H. Shi, H. Wang, A. Lv, L. Bian, M. Zhang, C. Ma, K. Ling, M. Gu, Y. Mao, X. Yao, C. Gao, K. Shen, W. Jia, J. Zhi, S. Cai, Z. Song, J. Li, Y. Zhang, S. Lu, K. Liu, C. Dong, Q. Wang, Y. Zhou, W. Yao, Y. Zhang, H. Zhang, Z. Zhang, X. Hang, et al., Nat. Mater. 2021, 20, 1539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Yang, N. Li, B. Wang, P. Chen, S. Ma, Y. Deng, S. L&#xfc;, Y. Tang, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2005, 64, 202419114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Zhang, F. Guo, H. Mi, Z.&#x2010;S. Wu, C. Ji, C. Yang, J. Qiu, Adv. Energy Mater. 2022, 12, 2202219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Tang, M. Li, Y. Yao, Y. Wang, Y. Zhang, G. Wang, J. Liu, L. Li, Energy Storage Mater. 2023, 55, 527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Wang, H. Su, T. Xu, H. Cui, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2023, 62, 202306652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. He, G. Fang, Z. Chang, Y. Zhang, S. Zhou, M. Zhou, S. Chai, Y. Zhong, G. Cao, S. Liang, A. Pan, Nano Micro Lett 2022, 14, 93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Jiang, D. Zhan, M. Zhang, Y. Zhu, H. Zhong, Y. Wu, Q. Tan, X. Dong, D. Zhang, N. Hadjichristidis, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2023, 62, 202310832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Chen, B. Liu, J. Ren, C. Zhang, Z. Ren, Z.&#x2010;H. Guan, Adv. Mater. 2025, 37, 2504825.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Yang, C. Wang, Q. Yu, P. Ma, Q. Zhao, Y. Wu, K. Ma, S. Tan, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 63, 202406407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Duan, J. Ding, D. Wang, X. Zhu, J. Chen, G. Zhu, C. Chen, Y. Yu, H. Liao, Z. Li, C.&#x2010;a. Di, W. Yue, Adv. Sci. 2023, 10, 2204872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Zhang, B. Wu, S. Sun, P. Wu, Nat. Commun. 2021, 12, 4082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Meng, L. Wang, G. Zhao, J. Diao, Z. Qi, M. Yu, Z. Li, Y. Niu, G. He, X. Jiang, ACS Nano 2024, 18, 13794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Li, K. Qi, Z. Qin, X. Ding, Y. Zhu, Z. Hou, Y. Qian, ACS Nano 2024, 18, 27016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Pizzirusso, F. Peyronel, E. D. Co, A. G. Marangoni, G. Milano, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2018, 140, 12405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Meng, Y. Su, H. Zhu, J. Zhang, T. Cai, Adv. Sci. 2025, 12, 2502692.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>