<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40021819</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Feasibility evaluation of mechanical and environmental properties for red mud based rapid setting filling support material.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>7255</StartPage><MedlinePgn>7255</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">7255</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-90570-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Red mud (RM), a solid waste byproduct of the alumina industry, has accumulated in significant global stockpiles. Currently, the primary application of RM involves magnetic separation to recover iron oxides, while the residual RM is predominantly landfilled. Due to its strong alkalinity, RM can serve as a substitute for strong alkalis or sodium salts in the alkali activation of concrete, thereby accelerating setting time and improving early-age strength. Building on this property, this study designs and develops an RM based rapid setting filling support material, primarily composed of RM, which features rapid setting and high early strength. This material is intended as a substitute for high-water-content materials in gob-side entry retaining for coal mining. Experimental results demonstrate that when RM content reaches 70% and cement content is 10%, the Rapid-Setting Filling Support Material (RSM) achieves satisfactory compressive strength and initial setting time, coupled with excellent economic performance. The compressive strengths at 1&#xa0;day, 3&#xa0;days, 7&#xa0;days, and 28&#xa0;days are 6.12&#xa0;MPa, 8.97&#xa0;MPa, 11.25&#xa0;MPa, and 12.33&#xa0;MPa, respectively, meeting all requirements specified in the 'Technical Requirements for Roadside Bag Filling for Gob-side Entry Retaining with High-Water Material' (GB/T 39336-2020). The RSM also exhibits good durability, with primary hydration products including C-S-H gel, ettringite, and calcium carbonate, all of which contribute to strength development. Leaching tests reveal that heavy metal ion concentrations in the RSM leachate comply with integrated emission standards for Class III groundwater and wastewater, confirming its safe application. Considering the annual increase of approximately 13,000&#xa0;km in roadway length for coal mining in China, the demand for filling and support materials is substantial. Consequently, the findings of this study hold significant economic and environmental value, with the potential to promote green mining practices and the circular economy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Xiang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Materials and Metallurgy, Guizhou University, Guiyang, 550003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jiangang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Light Metal Materials Processing Technology of Guizhou Province, Guizhou Institute of Technology, Guiyang, 550003, China. zhangjg009@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Su</LastName><ForeName>Xiangdong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Materials and Metallurgy, Guizhou University, Guiyang, 550003, China. suxiangdong01@sina.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Zhiwei</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Materials and Metallurgy, Guizhou University, Guiyang, 550003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Haijia</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Materials and Metallurgy, Guizhou University, Guiyang, 550003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Qianke He Chenguo [2023] Major 009</GrantID><Agency>2023 Guizhou Provincial Key Scientific and Technological Achievements Transformation Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Qianke He Chenguo [2023] Major 009</GrantID><Agency>2023 Guizhou Provincial Key Scientific and Technological Achievements Transformation Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Zhuke Hetong [2022] No. 2-6</GrantID><Agency>2022 Guiyang Science and Technology Plan Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Zhuke Hetong [2022] No. 2-6</GrantID><Agency>2022 Guiyang Science and Technology Plan Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Qian Ke He Platform and talent [2016]5104</GrantID><Agency>Supported by Project of the Key Laboratory of Light Metal Materials Processing of Guizhou Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Qian Ke He Platform and talent [2016]5104</GrantID><Agency>Supported by Project of the Key Laboratory of Light Metal Materials Processing of Guizhou Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Environmental assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Filling material</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Leaching</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Red mud</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Waste utilization</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40021819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11871025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-90570-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-90570-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Z. Research and development of red mud resource utilization technology. <i>Guangzhou Chem.</i><b>41</b>(6), 29&#x2013;31 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, S., Jiang, S., Wang, W. Research progress on building materials resources of red mud in China. <i>Light Met.</i> (12), 1&#x2013;5 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pengfei, W. et al. Properties of red mud-filled and modified resin composites. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>409</b>, 133984 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emile, M. et al. Preparation and characterization of a red mud-based road base material: Strength formation mechanism and leaching characteristics. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>220</b>, 297&#x2013;307 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J. Z. et al. Environmental aspects and pavement properties of red mud waste as the replacement of mineral filler in asphalt mixture. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>178</b>, 288&#x2013;300 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, X. et al. Research and development of steel fiber reinforced concrete filling material and its application in gob-side entry retaining technology in deep mines. <i>Buildings</i><b>14</b>(3), 722 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J. et al. Resource utilization potential of red mud: A study on the micro-mechanism of the synergistic effect of multiple solid waste filling materials. <i>Sustainability</i><b>15</b>(21), 15532 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhen, L. et al. Layered re-breaking behavior of gangue backfilling materials and inspirations for protecting mined ecological environments. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>368</b>, 130477 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z. et al. Effect and mechanism of time-dependent and economical expansion materials in improving the active roof-contact for cemented paste backfill. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>439</b>, 137339 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, F. et al. Post-peak mechanical characteristics of the high-water material for backfilling the gob-side entry retaining: From experiment to field application. <i>Arab. J. Geosci.</i><b>13</b>(7), 183&#x2013;186 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiaoxuan, W. et al. Rheological and mechanical performance analysis and proportion optimization of cemented gangue backfill materials based on response surface methodology. <i>Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res. Int.</i><b>30</b>(58), 122482&#x2013;122496 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37971589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Q. et al. Recycling multisource industrial waste residues as green binder for cemented ultrafine tailings backfill: Hydration kinetics, mechanical properties, and solidification mechanism. <i>Powder Technol.</i><b>441</b>, 119799 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, L. R. et al. Multisolid waste collaborative production of aeolian sand-red mud-fly ash cemented paste backfill. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater.</i><b>20</b>, e02843 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zude, P. et al. Study on application and environmental effect of phosphogypsum-fly ash-red mud composite cemented paste backfill. <i>Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res. Int.</i><b>30</b>(50), 108832&#x2013;108845 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37755593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaohui, Z. &amp; Xiaolei, W. Modification test of high-water packing material and application in the gob-side entry retained engineering. <i>Arab. J. Geosci.</i><b>15</b>(7), 579 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiwei, B., Shuai, L. &amp; Qinli, Z. Experimental investigation on red mud from the bayer process for cemented paste backfill. <i>Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health</i><b>19</b>(19), 11926&#x2013;11926 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9565261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36231225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhaowen, D., Shouqian, S. &amp; Jiaxing, G. Effect of composite activators on mechanical properties, hydration activity and microstructure of red mud-based geopolymer. <i>J. Mater. Res. Technol.</i><b>24</b>, 8077&#x2013;8085 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shuai, L. et al. Feasibility of recycling bayer process red mud for the safety backfill mining of layered soft bauxite under coal seams. <i>Minerals</i><b>11</b>(7), 722&#x2013;722 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhikai, W. et al. Effective reuse of red mud as supplementary material in cemented paste backfill: Durability and environmental impact. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>328</b>, 127002 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. et al. Synergistic utilization, critical mechanisms, and environmental suitability of bauxite residue (red mud) based multi-solid wastes cementitious materials and special concrete. <i>J. Environ. Manag.</i><b>361</b>, 121255 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38815426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehdipour, I. &amp; Khayat, H. K. Effect of particle-size distribution and specific surface area of different binder systems on packing density and flow characteristics of cement paste. <i>Cem. Concr. Compos.</i><b>78</b>, 120&#x2013;131 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong, C. H. H. &amp; Kwan, H. K. A. Packing density of cementitious materials: part 1&#x2014;Measurement using a wet packing method. <i>Mater. Struct.</i><b>41</b>(4), 689&#x2013;701 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, J., Bai, B. &amp; Du, Q. Durability evaluation of a high-performance red mud-based composite material. <i>Mater. Today Commun.</i><b>39</b>, 108684 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, S., Kumar, A. &amp; Sitharam, T. G. Investigating the strength and durability properties of alkali activated red mud for tailings pond embankment material. <i>Geomech. Energy Environ.</i><b>36</b>, 100500 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, N. et al. Improved macro-microscopic characteristic of gypsum-slag based cementitious materials by incorporating red mud/carbide slag binary alkaline waste-derived activator. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>428</b>, 136425 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, W. et al. Current research status and emerging trends in utilization of red mud resources: A study based on bibliometric network analysis. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>442</b>, 137605 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, W. C., Wang, Z., Liu, Y. &amp; Cui, H. Z. Influence of red mud on fresh and hardened properties of self-compacting concrete. <i>Construct. Build. Mater.</i><b>178</b>, 288&#x2013;300 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence, P., Cyr, M. &amp; Ringot, E. Mineral admixtures in mortars&#x2014;Effect of inert materials on short-term hydration. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>33</b>(12), 1939&#x2013;1947 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xianhai, L. &amp; Qin, Z. Influence behavior of phosphorus slag and fly ash on the interface transition zone in concrete prepared by cement-red mud. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>49</b>, 104017 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, C. &amp; Jiusu, L. Effects of different silicon sources on the properties of geopolymer planting concrete mixed with red mud. <i>Sustainability</i><b>15</b>(5), 4427&#x2013;4427 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dongshuai, H. et al. Sustainable use of red mud in ultra-high performance concrete (UHPC): Design and performance evaluation. <i>Cem. Concr. Compos.</i><b>115</b>, 103862 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan, Z. et al. Hydration products of alkali-activated slag&#x2013;red mud cementitious material. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>32</b>(3), 357&#x2013;362 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing, W. et al. Alkali-activated red mud in stabilizing marine dredged clay with low amount of cement. <i>Eur. J. Environ. Civ. Eng.</i><b>27</b>(16), 4598&#x2013;4612 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mousa, I. M. et al. Self-curing concrete types: Water retention and durability. <i>Alex. Eng. J.</i><b>54</b>(3), 565&#x2013;575 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue, L. et al. Micro-chemomechanical properties of red mud binder and its effect on concrete. <i>Compos. Part B</i><b>258</b>, 110688 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, Z. et al. Solidification mechanism of bayer red mud under the action of calcium hydroxide. <i>Sustainability</i><b>16</b>(11), 4770 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong, L. et al. Preparation, characterization and application of red mud, fly ash and desulfurized gypsum based eco-friendly road base materials. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>284</b>, 124777 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, N. et al. Hydration characteristics and environmental friendly performance of a cementitious material composed of calcium silicate slag. <i>J. Hazard. Mater.</i><b>30</b>, 667&#x2013;676 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26691955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zajac, M. et al. Influence of limestone and anhydrite on the hydration of Portland cements. <i>Cement Concr. Compos.</i><b>46</b>, 99&#x2013;108 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, T. et al. The strength, reaction mechanism, sustainable potential of full solid waste alkali-activated cementitious materials using red mud and carbide slag. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>449</b>, 138454 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, Y. et al. Mechanical and microstructural characterization of one-part binder incorporated with alkali-thermal activated red mud. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater.</i><b>21</b>, e03634 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S., Zou, F. &amp; Luo, H. An all solid waste CO<sub>2</sub> sequestration material consist of multiple calcium silicate clinkers by carbide slag, copper tailing and red mud: Clinker crystal transformation and carbonation hardening properties. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>450</b>, 138534 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong, W. et al. Transferring red mud to efficient adsorbent for the adsorption and immobilization of Ni(II) from aqueous solution. <i>Colloids Surf. C Environ. Asp.</i><b>2</b>, 100045 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. et al. Preparation of road base material by utilizing electrolytic manganese residue based on Si-Al structure: Mechanical properties and Mn 2+ stabilization/solidification characterization. <i>J. Hazard. Mater.</i><b>390</b>, 122188 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32006843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, M. et al. Immobilization of Cr(VI) by hydrated Portland cement pastes with and without calcium sulfate. <i>J. Hazard. Mater.</i><b>342</b>, 242&#x2013;251 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28843168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, J. et al. Rapid wet grinding carbonation of sintering red mud for highly efficient CO2 sequestration and Cr solidification. <i>Chem. Eng. J.</i><b>488</b>, 151134 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. et al. Preparation of environmental-friendly cementitious material from red mud and waste glass sludge by mechanical activation. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>423</b>, 135861 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duo-Rui, Z. et al. Novel adsorbent synthesized from red mud and acid mine drainage for enhanced contaminant removal: Industrial waste transformation, adsorbent performance and metal(loid) removal mechanisms. <i>Chem. Eng. J.</i><b>465</b>, 142867 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J. et al. Effect of thermal pretreatment on the reactivity of red mud valorized as aluminosilicate precursor for geopolymer production. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>445</b>, 13794 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, L. et al. A comprehensive investigation of the adsorption behaviour and mechanism of industrial waste sintering and bayer red muds for heavy metals. <i>Environ. Geochem. Health</i><b>46</b>(11), 434 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39316166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, B. et al. Modeling of multilayer water adsorption and condensation in slits of cement minerals by molecule simulation and adsorption isotherm. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>421</b>, 135571 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jinbo, Y. et al. Effects of C&#x2013;S&#x2013;H gel surface structure on sodium chloride evaporation crystallization in C&#x2013;S&#x2013;H gel nanopores with molecular dynamics analysis. <i>Appl. Surf. Sci.</i><b>639</b>, 158159 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Q. et al. Immobilisation of heavy metal in cement-based solidification/stabilisation: A review. <i>Waste Manag.</i><b>29</b>(1), 390&#x2013;403 (2008).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18367391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng, D. et al. Effect of anionic charge quantity on adsorption properties of PCE molecules on ettringite surface: A molecular dynamic simulation method. <i>J. Nanopart. Res.</i><b>25</b>(8), 161 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chrysochoou, M. &amp; Dermatas, D. Evaluation of ettringite and hydrocalumite formation for heavy metal immobilization: Literature review and experimental study. <i>J. Hazard. Mater.</i><b>136</b>(1), 20&#x2013;33 (2005).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16343745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>