<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40777148</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2189-7255</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Fujita medical journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Fujita Med J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Concomitant use of sivelestat sodium hydrate and antithrombotic drugs worsens the treatment outcome of patients with acute respiratory distress syndrome and suppression of fibrinolysis: a single-center, retrospective study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>129</StartPage><EndPage>134</EndPage><MedlinePgn>129-134</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.20407/fmj.2024-026</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Sivelestat sodium hydrate (SSH) may be effective in the early stage of acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) before the neutrophil extracellular trap scaffold structure is complete. Therefore, patients with suppression of fibrinolysis (SF) before the secondary fibrinolytic process might benefit from SSH administration. The primary aim of this study was to determine the effect of the SF state and combination therapy on the effect of SSH administration.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We retrospectively reviewed the data of patients diagnosed with ARDS at Fujita Health University Hospital between July 2005 and December 2016. Patients with ARDS were stratified into the SF and hyperfibrinolysis (HF) groups. Using the fibrin degradation product (FDP)/D-dimer ratio, cut-off values were set as follows: FDP/D-dimer &gt;2 for the HF group and FDP/D-dimer &#x2264;2 for the SF group. The 28-day mortality was the primary endpoint.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In total, 168 patients (71 in the HF group and 97 in the SF group) were included in the analysis. The mortality within 28 days was not different based on SSH administration in either group (HF group: <i>p</i>=0.956, SF group: <i>p</i>=0.957). In the SF group, the mortality rate within 28 days in SSH-treated patients who received antithrombotic drugs was significantly higher than that in patients who received SSH only (<i>p</i>&lt;0.05). However, this finding was not present in the HF group (<i>p</i>=0.786).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Concomitant use of SSH and antithrombotic drugs might worsen the treatment outcome of patients with ADRS in the SF state.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kato</LastName><ForeName>Takahiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacotherapeutics and Informatics, Fujita Health University, School of Medicine, Toyoake, Aichi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mizuno</LastName><ForeName>Tomohiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacotherapeutics and Informatics, Fujita Health University, School of Medicine, Toyoake, Aichi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koseki</LastName><ForeName>Takenao</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacotherapeutics and Informatics, Fujita Health University, School of Medicine, Toyoake, Aichi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takahashi</LastName><ForeName>Kazuo</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Molecular Sciences, Fujita Health University, School of Medicine, Toyoake, Aichi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamada</LastName><ForeName>Shigeki</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacotherapeutics and Informatics, Fujita Health University, School of Medicine, Toyoake, Aichi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Imaizumi</LastName><ForeName>Kazuyoshi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Fujita Health University, School of Medicine, Toyoake, Aichi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsuboi</LastName><ForeName>Naotake</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Fujita Health University, School of Medicine, Toyoake, Aichi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hashimoto</LastName><ForeName>Naozumi</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Fujita Health University, School of Medicine, Toyoake, Aichi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>Fujita Med J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101745077</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2189-7247</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acute respiratory distress syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antithrombotic drug</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fibrinolysis suppression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sivelestat sodium hydrate</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>SY, KI, and NT are editorial board members of Fujita Medical Journal. The other authors declare no conflict of interest regarding this study.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40777148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12327214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20407/fmj.2024-026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bos LDJ, Ware LB. Acute respiratory distress syndrome: causes, pathophysiology, and phenotypes. Lancet 2022; 400: 1145&#x2013;1156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36070787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellani G, Laffey JG, Pham T, et al. Epidemiology, Patterns of Care, and Mortality for Patients With Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome in Intensive Care Units in 50 Countries. JAMA 2016; 315: 788&#x2013;800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26903337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer NJ, Gattinoni L, Calfee CS. Acute respiratory distress syndrome. Lancet 2021; 398: 622&#x2013;637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8248927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34217425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moss M, Huang DT, Brower RG, et al. Early Neuromuscular Blockade in the Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome. N Engl J Med 2019; 380: 1997&#x2013;2008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6741345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31112383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X, Jin J, Lv T, Song Y. A nNarrative Review: The Role of NETs in Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome/Acute Lung Injury. Int J Mol Sci 2024; 25: 1464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10855305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38338744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papayannopoulos V. Neutrophil extracellular traps in immunity and disease. Nat Rev Immunol 2018; 18: 134&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28990587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cesta MC, Zippoli M, Marsiglia C, Gavioli EM, Mantelli F, Allegretti M, Balk RA. The role of interleukin-8 in lung inflammation and injury: Implications for the management of covid-19 and hyperinflammatory acute respiratory distress syndrome. Front Pharmacol 2022; 12: 808797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8790527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35095519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swaroopa D, Bhaskar K, Mahathi T, Katkam S, Raju YS, Chandra N, Kutala VK. Association of serum interleukin-6, interleukin-8, and acute physiology and chronic health evaluation ii score with clinical outcome in patients with acute respiratory distress syndrome. Indian J Crit Care Med 2016; 20: 518&#x2013;525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5027744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27688627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urban CF, Ermert D, Schmid M, Abu-Abed U, Goosmann C, Nacken W, Brinkmann V, Jungblut PR, Zychlinsky A. Neutrophil extracellular traps contain calprotectin, a cytosolic protein complex involved in host defense against Candida albicans. PLoS Pathog 2009; 5: e1000639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2763347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19876394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moraes TJ, Chow CW, Downey GP. Proteases and lung injury. Crit Care Med 2003; 31(4 Suppl): S189&#x2013;S194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12682439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraham E. Neutrophils and acute lung injury. Crit Care Med 2003; 31(4 Suppl): S195&#x2013;S199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12682440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamakuma S, Ogawa M, Aikawa N, Kubota T, Hirasawa H, Ishizaka A, Taenaka N, Hamada C, Matsuoka S, Abiru T. Relationship between neutrophil elastase and acute lung injury in humans. Pulm Pharmacol Ther 2004; 17: 271&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15477122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aikawa N, Ishizaka A, Hirasawa H, Shimazaki S, Yamamoto Y, Sugimoto H, Shinozaki M, Taenaka N, Endo S, Ikeda T, Kawasaki Y. Reevaluation of the efficacy and safety of the neutrophil elastase inhibitor, Sivelestat, for the treatment of acute lung injury associated with systemic inflammatory response syndrome; a phase IV study. Pulm Pharmacol Ther 2011; 24: 549&#x2013;554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21540122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayakawa M, Katabami K, Wada T, Sugano M, Hoshino H, Sawamura A, Gando S. Sivelestat (selective neutrophil elastase inhibitor) improves the mortality rate of sepsis associated with both acute respiratory distress syndrome and disseminated intravascular coagulation patients. Shock 2010; 33: 14&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19487982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Q, Wang Y, Yang C, Tuerxun D, Yu X. Effect of Sivelestat in the Treatment of Acute Lung Injury and Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Intensive Care Res 2023: 1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10233530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37360308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeiher BG, Artigas A, Vincent JL, Dmitrienko A, Jackson K, Thompson BT, Bernard G. Neutrophil elastase inhibition in acute lung injury: results of the STRIVE study. Crit Care Med 2004; 32: 1695&#x2013;1702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15286546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tasaka S, Ohshimo S, Takeuchi M, et al. ARDS clinical practice guideline 2021. Respir Investig 2022; 60: 446&#x2013;495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35753956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whyte CS, Morrow GB, Mitchell JL, Chowdary P, Mutch NJ. Fibrinolytic abnormalities in acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) and versatility of thrombolytic drugs to treat COVID-19. J Thromb Haemost 2020; 18: 1548&#x2013;1555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7264738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32329246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark SR, Ma AC, Tavener SA, et al. Platelet tlr4 activates neutrophil extracellular traps to ensnare bacteria in septic blood. Nat Med 2007; 13: 463&#x2013;469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17384648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao W, Chen J, Wu S, Han X, Guan J, Yuan D, Cai J, Hei Z. ONO-5046 suppresses reactive oxidative species-associated formation of neutrophil extracellular traps. Life Sci 2018; 210: 243&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30195031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawamura A, Hayakawa M, Gando S, Kubota N, Sugano M, Wada T, Katabami K. Disseminated intravascular coagulation with a fibrinolytic phenotype at an early phase of trauma predicts mortality. Thromb Res 2009; 124: 608&#x2013;613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19660788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wada T, Gando S, Ono Y, Maekawa K, Katabami K, Hayakawa M, Sawamura A. Disseminated intravascular coagulation with the fibrinolytic phenotype predicts the outcome of patients with out-of-hospital cardiac arrest. Thromb J 2016; 14: 43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5030731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27679536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada S, Asakura H. Therapeutic Strategies for Disseminated Intravascular Coagulation Associated with Aortic Aneurysm. Int J Mol Sci 2022; 23: 1296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8836167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35163216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wada T, Gando S. Phenotypes of Disseminated Intravascular Coagulation. Thromb Haemost 2024; 124: 181&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10890912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37657485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernard GR, Artigas A, Brigham KL, Carlet J, Falke K, Hudson L, Lamy M, LeGall JR, Morris A, Spragg R. Report of the American-European consensus conference on ARDS: definitions, mechanisms, relevant outcomes and clinical trial coordination. The Consensus Committee. Intensive Care Med 1994; 20: 225&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8014293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson ND, Fan E, Camporota L, et al. The Berlin definition of ARDS: an expanded rationale, justification, and supplementary material. Intensive Care Med 2012; 38: 1573&#x2013;1582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22926653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Chest Physicians/Society of Critical Care Medicine Consensus Conference: definitions for sepsis and organ failure and guidelines for the use of innovative therapies in sepsis. Crit Care Med 1992; 20: 864&#x2013;874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1597042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asakura H. Classifying types of disseminated intravascular coagulation: clinical and animal models. J Intensive Care 2014; 2: 20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4267600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25520834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrams ST, Su D, Sahraoui Y, Lin Z, Cheng Z, Nesbitt K, Alhamdi Y, Harrasser M, Du M, Foley JH, Lillicrap D, Wang G, Toh CH. Assembly of alternative prothrombinase by extracellular histones initiates and disseminates intravascular coagulation. Blood 2021; 137: 103&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33410894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Br&#xfc;hl ML, Stark K, Steinhart A, et al. Monocytes, neutrophils, and platelets cooperate to initiate and propagate venous thrombosis in mice in vivo. J Exp Med 2012; 209: 819&#x2013;835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3328366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22451716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massberg S, Grahl L, von Bruehl ML, et al. Reciprocal coupling of coagulation and innate immunity via neutrophil serine proteases. Nat Med 2010; 16: 887&#x2013;896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20676107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranieri VM, Rubenfeld GD, Thompson BT, Ferguson ND, Caldwell E, Fan E, Camporota L, Slutsky AS. Acute respiratory distress syndrome: the Berlin Definition. JAMA 2012; 307: 2526&#x2013;2533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22797452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira JD, Vieira-Damiani G, da Silva LQ, Leonardi GR, Vaz CO, Jacintho-Robison BC, Mazetto BM, de Paula EV, Monica FZ, Orsi FA. Impact of antiplatelets, anticoagulants and cyclic nucleotide stimulators on neutrophil extracellular traps (nets) and inflammatory markers during covid-19. J Thromb Thrombolysis 2024 (epub ahead of print).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39546241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>