<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41572875</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1520-5827</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Langmuir : the ACS journal of surfaces and colloids</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Langmuir</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Smart Nanofluidic Transistors for High-Efficiency Blue Energy Harvesting: The Hidden Role of Ion Hydration.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3656</StartPage><EndPage>3671</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3656-3671</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c06294</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Osmotic energy harvesting from salinity gradients has emerged as a promising route for sustainable power generation; however, achieving high power output and efficiency remains limited by ionic selectivity and internal resistance in conventional membranes. In this work, we investigate osmotic energy conversion in polymer-coated ionic nanotransistors under high salinity gradients using a coupled Poisson-Nernst-Planck and Navier-Stokes numerical framework. The influence of cation type in three monovalent electrolytes (NaCl, KCl, and LiCl) is systematically examined for two soft-gated nanotransistor configurations (NPN and PNP). A key innovation of this study is the identification of a configuration-dependent inversion in electrolyte performance, arising from the interplay between ion hydration, diffusivity, and electrostatic partitioning within the soft polyelectrolyte layer. Under a concentration ratio of 1000 and a polyelectrolyte charge density of 100 mol m<sup>-3</sup>, the NPN configuration exhibits the highest power output with KCl (5.27 pW; &#x223c;186 W/m<sup>2</sup>), which is approximately three times higher than NaCl (1.75 pW; &#x223c;61.7 W/m<sup>2</sup>) and over ten times higher than LiCl (0.51 pW; &#x223c;18 W/m<sup>2</sup>). In contrast, the PNP configuration demonstrates a markedly enhanced maximum power output with LiCl, reaching 9.78 pW (&#x223c;345 Wm<sup>2</sup>), which is &#x223c;36% higher than NaCl (7.19 pW; &#x223c;254 W/m<sup>2</sup>) and nearly 2.6 times higher than KCl (3.81 pW; &#x223c;134 W/m<sup>2</sup>). This performance inversion originates from stronger electrostatic coupling and larger hydration radius of Li<sup>+</sup> in the PNP configuration, which enhance ionic selectivity and suppress co-ion leakage, whereas the higher mobility of K<sup>+</sup> benefits the conductance-dominated NPN system. Furthermore, the peak energy conversion efficiency approaches &#x223c;50% in the PNP-LiCl system, highlighting the high thermodynamic favorability of salinity-gradient-driven nanofluidic power generation. These findings provide mechanistic insight and quantitative design guidance for optimizing electrolyte selection and surface-charge architectures in next-generation nanofluidic osmotic energy-harvesting devices.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dolatshahi</LastName><ForeName>Reza</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Lab for Advanced Separation Processes, Department of Chemical Engineering, Iran University of Science and Technology, Narmak, Tehran 16846-13114, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khatibi</LastName><ForeName>Mahdi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Lab for Advanced Separation Processes, Department of Chemical Engineering, Iran University of Science and Technology, Narmak, Tehran 16846-13114, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ashrafizadeh</LastName><ForeName>Seyed Nezameddin</ForeName><Initials>SN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9584-2037</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Lab for Advanced Separation Processes, Department of Chemical Engineering, Iran University of Science and Technology, Narmak, Tehran 16846-13114, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Langmuir</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9882736</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0743-7463</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41572875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c06294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>