<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41246742</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Profound Hypomagnesemia Due to Proton Pump Inhibitor Use-Associated Wernicke's Encephalopathy: A Case Report on Excitotoxicity.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e94687</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e94687</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e94687</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.94687</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hypomagnesemia is a frequently underdiagnosed condition. Its clinical consequences can be serious, with a wide variety of clinical presentations. Magnesium deficiency is often multifactorial, and this insufficiency can exacerbate or delay the recovery of other conditions. Magnesium is increasingly studied in the central nervous system for its regulation of excitotoxicity and its anti-apoptotic role. We describe the clinical case of a 50-year-old woman who presented to the emergency department with neurological symptoms characterized by dysarthria, headaches, photophobia, paresthesias, vertigo, multidirectional nystagmus, and gait instability. Her hospitalization revealed profound multifactorial hypomagnesemia (&lt; 0.10 mmol/L). This condition results from&#xa0;diarrhea, chronic use of a proton pump inhibitor, alcohol consumption, and malnutrition. These electrolyte imbalances, along with the clinical presentation of Wernicke's encephalopathy, led to her admission to the intensive care unit. Her overall condition and neurological symptoms improved following the correction of her biochemical abnormalities, intravenous hydration, and thiamine supplementation. The patient was discharged from the hospital eight days later. In conclusion, hypomagnesemia is an electrolyte disorder whose neurological presentations remain rare but severe. Hypomagnesemia is a rare and insidious consequence of proton pump inhibitors and should be monitored frequently. The action of magnesium in the central nervous system is neuroprotective; it reduces&#xa0;inflammation and decreases excitotoxicity, a mechanism also involved in the pathophysiology of Wernicke's syndrome. This association is even more pertinent considering magnesium is necessary for the conversion of thiamine into its active form. Hypomagnesemia should be investigated more systematically and actively monitored, as the replenishment of the body's reserves can be time-consuming.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Delforge et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Delforge</LastName><ForeName>Benoit</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anesthesiology and Reanimation, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire (CHU) Universit&#xe9; Catholique de Louvain (UCLouvain), Mont-Godinne, BEL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Volon</LastName><ForeName>Brieuc</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Critical Care, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire (CHU) Hospital of Nivelles (HELORA), Nivelles, BEL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Laurent</LastName><ForeName>Yves</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Critical Care, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire (CHU) Hospital of Nivelles (HELORA), Nivelles, BEL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Steinier</LastName><ForeName>Charlotte</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency Medicine, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire (CHU) Hospital of Nivelles (HELORA), Jolimont, BEL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">excitotoxicity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">magnesium deficiency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurologic manifestations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">proton pump inhibitors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wernicke's encephalopathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wernicke&#x2019;s encephalopathy (we)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41246742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12618944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.94687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Severe hypomagnesemia induced by taking a proton pump inhibitor: report of 2 cases and review of the literature (Article in French) Apraxine M, Levecque P, Druez P, Dahan K, Cambier J-F, Lengel&#xe9; J-P. https://www.louvainmedical.be/article/260 Louvain M&#xe9;dical. 2019:446&#x2013;451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnesium in prevention and therapy. Gr&#xf6;ber U, Schmidt J, Kisters K. Nutrients. 2015;7:8199&#x2013;8226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4586582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26404370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hypomagnesemia and hypermagnesemia. Van Laecke S. Acta Clin Belg. 2019;74:41&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30220246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>How to treat abnormalities in magnesium levels (Article in French) Guillaume T, Krzesinski JM. https://hdl.handle.net/2268/6042. Rev M&#xe9;d Li&#xe8;ge. 2003;58:465&#x2013;467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14579608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnesium in daily clinical practice (Article in French) Minetto D, Serratrice J, Stirnemann J. Rev M&#xe9;d Suisse. 2016;12:1761&#x2013;1765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28692217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The role of magnesium in neurological disorders. Kirkland AE, Sarlo GL, Holton KF. Nutrients. 2018;10:730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6024559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29882776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggravation of thiamine deficiency by magnesium depletion. A case report. Dyckner T, Ek B, Nyhlin H, Wester PO. Acta Med Scand. 1985;218:129&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4050546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnesium deficiency: a possible cause of thiamine refractoriness in Wernicke-Korsakoff encephalopathy. Traviesa DC. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1974;37:959&#x2013;962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC494812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4420329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernicke's encephalopathy induced by magnesium depletion. McLean J, Manchip S. Lancet. 1999;353:1768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10348000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnesium imbalances (Article in French) Folefack FK, Stoermann Chopard C. Rev M&#xe9;d Suisse. 2007;3:605&#x2013;611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17436799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rude RK. Principles of Bone Biology (Second Edition) London, UK: Academic Press; 2002. Chapter 21 - magnesium homeostasis; pp. 339&#x2013;358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnesium intake and incidence of stroke: meta-analysis of cohort studies. Nie ZL, Wang ZM, Zhou B, Tang ZP, Wang SK. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2013;23:169&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22789806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mechanism of hypokalemia in magnesium deficiency. Huang CL, Kuo E. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2007;18:2649&#x2013;2652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17804670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Complications of proton pump inhibitor therapy. Vaezi MF, Yang YX, Howden CW. Gastroenterology. 2017;153:35&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28528705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The association between the use of proton pump inhibitors and the risk of hypomagnesemia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Park CH, Kim EH, Roh YH, Kim HY, Lee SK. PLoS One. 2014;9:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4230950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25394217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hypomagnesemia and proton pump inhibitors. Meier P, Schmidtko J. Rev Med Suisse. 2012;8:806&#x2013;810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22574415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houillier P, Prot-Bertoye C. D&#xe9;sordres Hydro&#xe9;lectolytiques. 4th Edition (Book in French) Brussels: De Boeck; 2015. Magnesium homeostasis and abnormalities of magnesium levels; p. 124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proton-pump inhibitors do not influence serum magnesium levels in renal transplant recipients. Van Ende C, Van Laecke S, Marechal C, et al. J Nephrol. 2014;27:707&#x2013;711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24816563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnesium and the brain: a focus on neuroinflammation and neurodegeneration. Maier JA, Locatelli L, Fedele G, Cazzaniga A, Mazur A. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;24:223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9820677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36613667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuroprotective effects of magnesium: implications for neuroinflammation and cognitive decline. Patel V, Akimbekov NS, Grant WB, Dean C, Fang X, Razzaque MS. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2024;15:1406455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11461281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39387051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnesium and depression: a systematic review. Derom ML, Say&#xf3;n-Orea C, Mart&#xed;nez-Ortega JM, Mart&#xed;nez-Gonz&#xe1;lez MA. Nutr Neurosci. 2013;16:191&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23321048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnesium in migraine prophylaxis-is there an evidence-based rationale? A systematic review. von Luckner A, Riederer F. Headache. 2018;58:199&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29131326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A double-blinded randomised controlled study of the value of sequential intravenous and oral magnesium therapy in patients with chronic low back pain with a neuropathic component. Yousef AA, Al-deeb AE. Anaesthesia. 2013;68:260&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23384256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seizures related to hypomagnesemia: a case series and review of the literature. Chen BB, Prasad C, Kobrzynski M, Campbell C, Filler G. Child Neurol Open. 2016;3:2329048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5417264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28503619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oxidative stress, mitochondrial function, and acute glutamate excitotoxicity in cultured cerebellar granule cells. Castilho RF, Ward MW, Nicholls DG. J Neurochem. 1999;72:1394&#x2013;1401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10098841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietary magnesium intake and risk of stroke: a meta-analysis of prospective studies. Larsson SC, Orsini N, Wolk A. Am J Clin Nutr. 2012;95:362&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22205313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molecular mechanisms of ischemia and glutamate excitotoxicity. Neves D, Salazar IL, Almeida RD, Silva RM. Life Sci. 2023;328:121814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37236602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiamine in the treatment of Wernicke encephalopathy in patients with alcohol use disorders. Latt N, Dore G. Intern Med J. 2014;44:911&#x2013;915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25201422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>From thiamine deficiency to Gayet-Wernicke encephalopathy, a little-known pathology (Article in French) Farquet V. Alvarez V, Biselx S, Coutaz M. Revue M&#xe9;di Suisse. 2017;13:382&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28708361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Update of cell damage mechanisms in thiamine deficiency: focus on oxidative stress, excitotoxicity and inflammation. Hazell AS, Butterworth RF. Alcohol Alcohol. 2009;44:141&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19151161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Learning and behavioral-long-term potentiation: importance of controlling for motor activity. Hargreaves EL, Cain DP, Vanderwolf CH. J Neurosci. 1990;10:1472&#x2013;1478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6570083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2332791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiamine deficiency and delirium. Osiezagha K, Ali S, Freeman C, et al.  https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC3659035/ Innov Clin Neurosci. 2013;10:26&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3659035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23696956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiamine refractory Wernickes encephalopathy reversed with magnesium therapy. Coughlan JJ, Mross T, Wafer M, Liston R. BMJ Case Rep. 2016;2016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5093844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27797884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>