<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39495040</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1524-4040</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>96</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurosurgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurosurgery</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical Benefits of Photodynamic Therapy Using Talaporfin Sodium in Patients With Isocitrate Dehydrogenase -Wildtype Diagnosed Glioblastoma: A Retrospective Study of 100 Cases.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1374</StartPage><EndPage>1385</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1374-1385</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1227/neu.0000000000003247</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Photodynamic therapy (PDT) with talaporfin sodium is an intraoperative local therapy administered after the surgical removal of malignant gliomas. However, its clinical efficacy in a large patient population has not been determined. To analyze the clinical outcomes and prognosis in isocitrate dehydrogenase (IDH) -wildtype glioblastoma patients treated with PDT.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This retrospective study included patients with newly diagnosed IDH -wildtype glioblastoma treated at Kobe University Hospital between January 2013 and December 2022. PDT involves irradiation of the resection cavity with a 664-nm semiconductor laser after an intravenous infusion of talaporfin sodium. The main outcome measures were the recurrence patterns and survival times, which were compared between the PDT and non-PDT groups. Univariate and multivariate analyses were used to determine the prognostic factors. In addition, adverse events and prognostic factors in the PDT group were analyzed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 44 and 56 patients were included in the PDT and non-PDT groups, respectively. The local recurrence rate was significantly lower in the PDT group than in the non-PDT group (51.3% vs 83.9%), whereas the distant recurrence and dissemination rates were significantly higher in the PDT group than in the non-PDT group (48.7% vs 16.1%). Two grade 3 adverse events were observed in the PDT group. The median progression-free survival and overall survival times were significantly longer in the PDT group than in the non-PDT group (progression-free survival: 10.8 vs 9.3 months, respectively, and overall survival: 24.6 vs 17.6 months, respectively). Multivariate analysis of the PDT groups revealed that younger age was an independent prognostic factor.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">PDT with talaporfin sodium provided effective local control with minimal adverse effects. The survival time of the patients treated with PDT was significantly longer than that of the patients who did not receive PDT. Therefore, a randomized controlled clinical trial on PDT is warranted.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; Congress of Neurological Surgeons 2024. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fujimoto</LastName><ForeName>Yosuke</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Kobe University Graduate School of Medicine, Kobe , Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fujita</LastName><ForeName>Yuichi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Kobe University Graduate School of Medicine, Kobe , Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tanaka</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiro</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Kobe University Graduate School of Medicine, Kobe , Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nagashima</LastName><ForeName>Hiroaki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Kobe University Graduate School of Medicine, Kobe , Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamanishi</LastName><ForeName>Shunsuke</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Kobe University Graduate School of Medicine, Kobe , Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ikeuchi</LastName><ForeName>Yusuke</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Kobe University Graduate School of Medicine, Kobe , Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iwahashi</LastName><ForeName>Hirofumi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Kobe University Graduate School of Medicine, Kobe , Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sanada</LastName><ForeName>Shoji</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical and Translational Research Center, Kobe University Hospital, Kobe , Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muragaki</LastName><ForeName>Yoshihiro</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Advanced Medical Engineering Research and Development, Kobe University, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sasayama</LastName><ForeName>Takashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5593-9045</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Kobe University Graduate School of Medicine, Kobe , Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>20K09369</GrantID><Agency>the Japanese Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science, and Technology.</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neurosurgery</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7802914</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-396X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 1.1.1.41</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007521">Isocitrate Dehydrogenase</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>P4ROX5ELT2</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C053434">Talaporfin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017319">Photosensitizing Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011166">Porphyrins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010778" MajorTopicYN="Y">Photochemotherapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005909" MajorTopicYN="Y">Glioblastoma</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001932" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brain Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007521" MajorTopicYN="Y">Isocitrate Dehydrogenase</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017319" MajorTopicYN="Y">Photosensitizing Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011166" MajorTopicYN="Y">Porphyrins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009364" MajorTopicYN="N">Neoplasm Recurrence, Local</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adverse events</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glioblastoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Photodynamic therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Recurrence pattern</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39495040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1227/neu.0000000000003247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006123-202506000-00023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Stupp R, Taillibert S, Kanner A, et al. Effect of tumor-treating fields plus maintenance temozolomide vs maintenance temozolomide alone on survival in patients with glioblastoma: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2017;318(23):2306-2316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellingson BM, Abrey LE, Nelson SJ, et al. Validation of postoperative residual contrast-enhancing tumor volume as an independent prognostic factor for overall survival in newly diagnosed glioblastoma. Neuro Oncol. 2018;20(9):1240-1250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanai N, Polley MY, McDermott MW, Parsa AT, Berger MS. An extent of resection threshold for newly diagnosed glioblastomas. J Neurosurg. 2011;115(1):3-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molinaro AM, Hervey-Jumper S, Morshed RA, et al. Association of maximal extent of resection of contrast-enhanced and non-contrast-enhanced tumor with survival within molecular subgroups of patients with newly diagnosed glioblastoma. JAMA Oncol. 2020;6(4):495-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stupp R, Mason WP, van den Bent MJ, et al. Radiotherapy plus concomitant and adjuvant temozolomide for glioblastoma. N Engl J Med. 2005;352(10):987-996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinot OL, Wick W, Mason W, et al. Bevacizumab plus radiotherapy-temozolomide for newly diagnosed glioblastoma. N Engl J Med. 2014;370(8):709-722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert MR, Dignam JJ, Armstrong TS, et al. A randomized trial of bevacizumab for newly diagnosed glioblastoma. N Engl J Med. 2014;370(8):699-708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akimoto J. Photodynamic therapy for malignant brain tumors. Neurol Med Chir (Tokyo) 2016;56(4):151-157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akimoto J, Haraoka J, Aizawa K. Preliminary clinical report on safety and efficacy of photodynamic therapy using talaporfin sodium for malignant gliomas. Photodiagnosis Photodyn Ther. 2012;9(2):91-99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsutsumi M, Miki Y, Akimoto J, et al. Photodynamic therapy with talaporfin sodium induces dose-dependent apoptotic cell death in human glioma cell lines. Photodiagnosis Photodyn Ther. 2013;10(2):103-110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miki Y, Akimoto J, Hiranuma M, Fujiwara Y. Effect of talaporfin sodium-mediated photodynamic therapy on cell death modalities in human glioblastoma T98G cells. J Toxicol Sci. 2014;39(6):821-827.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muragaki Y, Akimoto J, Maruyama T, et al. Phase II clinical study on intraoperative photodynamic therapy with talaporfin sodium and semiconductor laser in patients with malignant brain tumors. J Neurosurg. 2013;119(4):845-852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nitta M, Muragaki Y, Maruyama T, et al. Role of photodynamic therapy using talaporfin sodium and a semiconductor laser in patients with newly diagnosed glioblastoma. J Neurosurg. 2018;131(5):1361-1368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiba K, Aihara Y, Oda Y, et al. Photodynamic therapy for malignant brain tumors in children and young adolescents. Front Oncol. 2022;12:957267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karschnia P, Young JS, Dono A, et al. Prognostic validation of a new classification system for extent of resection in glioblastoma: a report of the RANO resect group. Neuro Oncol. 2023;25(5):940-954.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen PY, van den Bent M, Youssef G, et al. Rano 2.0: update to the response assessment in neuro-oncology criteria for high- and low-grade gliomas in adults. J Clin Oncol. 2023;41(33):5187-5199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pope WB, Xia Q, Paton VE, et al. Patterns of progression in patients with recurrent glioblastoma treated with bevacizumab. Neurology. 2011;76(5):432-437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cachia D, Elshafeey NA, Kamiya-Matsuoka C, et al. Radiographic patterns of progression with associated outcomes after bevacizumab therapy in glioblastoma patients. J Neurooncol. 2017;135(1):75-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Louis DN, Perry A, Wesseling P, et al. The 2021 WHO classification of tumors of the central nervous system: a summary. Neuro Oncol. 2021;23(8):1231-1251.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwiatkowski S, Knap B, Przystupski D, et al. Photodynamic therapy&#x2014;mechanisms, photosensitizers and combinations. Biomed Pharmacother. 2018;106:1098-1107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y, Jia H, Liu Y, Zhang L, Feng G, Tang BZ. Recent progress in Type I aggregation-induced emission photosensitizers for photodynamic therapy. Molecules. 2022;28(1):332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castano AP, Mroz P, Hamblin MR. Photodynamic therapy and anti-tumour immunity. Nat Rev Cancer. 2006;6(7):535-545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolmans DE, Fukumura D, Jain RK. Photodynamic therapy for cancer. Nat Rev Cancer. 2003;3(5):380-387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stylli SS, Kaye AH. Photodynamic therapy of cerebral glioma&#x2014;a review Part I&#x2014;a biological basis. J Clin Neurosci. 2006;13(6):615-625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoudi K, Garvey KL, Bouras A, et al. 5-Aminolevulinic acid photodynamic therapy for the treatment of high-grade gliomas. J Neurooncol. 2019;141(3):595-607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenthal MA, Kavar B, Hill JS, et al. Phase I and pharmacokinetic study of photodynamic therapy for high-grade gliomas using a novel boronated porphyrin. J Clin Oncol. 2001;19(2):519-524.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannino S, Molinari A, Sabatino G, et al. Intratumoral vs systemic administration of meta-tetrahydroxyphenylchlorin for photodynamic therapy of malignant gliomas: assessment of uptake and spatial distribution in C6 rat glioma model. Int J Immunopathol Pharmacol. 2008;21(1):227-231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita Y, Nagashima H, Tanaka K, Hashiguchi M, Itoh T, Sasayama T. Hyperintense signal on diffusion-weighted imaging for monitoring the acute response and local recurrence after photodynamic therapy in malignant gliomas. J Neurooncol. 2021;155(1):81-92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita Y, Sasayama T, Tanaka K, et al. DWI for monitoring the acute response of malignant gliomas to photodynamic therapy. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2019;40(12):2045-2051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usuda J, Ichinose S, Ishizumi T, et al. Outcome of photodynamic therapy using NPe6 for bronchogenic carcinomas in central airways &gt;1.0 cm in diameter. Clin Cancer Res. 2010;16(7):2198-2204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yano T, Kasai H, Horimatsu T, et al. A multicenter phase II study of salvage photodynamic therapy using talaporfin sodium (ME2906) and a diode laser (PNL6405EPG) for local failure after chemoradiotherapy or radiotherapy for esophageal cancer. Oncotarget. 2017;8(13):22135-22144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iuchi T, Sakaida T, Sugiyama T, et al. Patterns of failure after photodynamic therapy of newly diagnosed glioblastoma patients. J Jpn Soc Laser Surg Med. 2023;44(2):109-116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz CRA, Tonn J-C, Kreth S, Kreth F-W. Interstitial photodynamic therapy of de-novo glioblastoma multiforme WHO IV. Neuro Oncol. 2015;17:v219.215-v220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peciu-Florianu I, Vannod-Michel Q, Vauleon E, Bonneterre ME, Reyns N. Long term follow-up of patients with newly diagnosed glioblastoma treated by intraoperative photodynamic therapy: an update from the INDYGO trial (NCT03048240). J Neurooncol. 2024;168(3):495-505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng X, Jiang F, Katakowski M, et al. Sensitization of cerebral tissue in nude mice with photodynamic therapy induces ADAM17/TACE and promotes glioma cell invasion. Cancer Lett. 2008;265(2):177-187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mossakowska BJ, Fabisiewicz A, Tudek B, Siedlecki JA. Possible mechanisms of resistance development to photodynamic therapy (PDT) in vulvar cancer cells. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23(23):14689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weijer R, Broekgaarden M, Kos M, et al. Enhancing photodynamic therapy of refractory solid cancers: combining second-generation photosensitizers with multi-targeted liposomal delivery. J Photochem Photobiol C Photochem Rev. 2015;23:103-131.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>