<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40428993</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Influence of Ion Chelating Agents with Different Chelating Abilities on the Properties and Microstructure of Cement-Based Materials.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2256</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma18102256</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Concrete structures are prone to cracking and seepage issues due to material degradation during long-term service. Ionic chelating agents (ICAs) can significantly enhance the durability and extend the service life of concrete structures by chelating metal ions in the cement matrix and promoting the formation of crystalline products within pores. The study selected commonly used ICAs, including sodium gluconate, sodium maleate, and sodium citrate, as well as a self-made high-efficiency ICA, to compare their chelating abilities for metal ions (such as Al<sup>3+</sup>, Mg<sup>2+</sup>, Fe<sup>3+</sup>, and Ca<sup>2+</sup>). Their effects on the performance and microstructure of cement-based materials were evaluated through tests on hydration heat, mechanical strength, the chloride ion diffusion coefficient, pore size distribution, and microstructural analysis. The results showed that the stronger the chelating ability of the ICA, the more significant its improvement on the performance and microstructure of cement-based materials. Cement paste incorporating the high-efficiency ICA exhibited significantly accelerated hydration kinetics, with the hydration rate markedly increasing and the peak heat release rising from 0.0012 W/g to 0.0016 W/g, thereby effectively enhancing the early-age properties of the cement-based materials. After 28 days, compared to ordinary mortar, the flexural and compressive strengths of mortar containing the high-efficiency ICA increased by 17.1% and 11.6%, respectively, while the chloride ion diffusion coefficient decreased by 37.4%. Pore size distribution and microstructural analyses indicated that mortar incorporating the high-efficiency ICA exhibited the most compact internal structure, with abundant crystalline products such as CaSiO<sub>3</sub> and 3CaO&#xb7;Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>&#xb7;3CaSO<sub>4</sub>&#xb7;32H<sub>2</sub>O (AFt) forming within the pores. These findings suggest that optimizing the ion-chelating capacity of ICA provides a feasible strategy to enhance the compactness, durability, and mechanical performance of cement-based materials in practical engineering applications.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Ke</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Chang'an University, Xi'an 710061, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ruiyang</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Chang'an University, Xi'an 710061, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Jianying</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Silicate Materials for Architectures, Wuhan University of Technology, Wuhan 430070, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Quantao</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Silicate Materials for Architectures, Wuhan University of Technology, Wuhan 430070, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zha</LastName><ForeName>Yagang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Silicate Materials for Architectures, Wuhan University of Technology, Wuhan 430070, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023-JC-QN-0435</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Basic Research Program of Shaanxi</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>SYSJJ2023-01</GrantID><Agency>State Key Laboratory of Silicate Materials for Architectures (Wuhan University of Technology)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chelation ability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">impermeability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ion-chelating agent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microstructure of cement-based materials</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40428993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12113519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma18102256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma18102256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shao R.Z., Wu C.Q., Li J. A comprehensive review on dry concrete: Application, raw material, preparation, mechanical, smart and durability performance. J. Build. Eng. 2022;55:104696. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He H.J., Qiao H.X., Sun T.Y., Yang H., He C. Research progress in mechanisms, influence factors and improvement routes of chloride binding for cement composites. J. Build. Eng. 2024;86:108978. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.108978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.108978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Ba M.F., Yi B., Liu J. Experimental and numerical investigation on the effect of cracks on chloride diffusion and steel corrosion in concrete. J. Build. Eng. 2024;86:108521. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.108521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.108521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao R.Q., Li C.F., Guan X.M. Advances in modeling surface chloride concentrations in concrete serving in the marine environment: A mini review. Buildings. 2024;14:1879. doi: 10.3390/buildings14061879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings14061879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belie N.D., Gruyaert E., Al-Tabbaa A., Antonaci P., Baera C., Bajare D., Darquennes A., Davies R., Ferrara L., Jefferson T., et al. A review of self-healing concrete for damage management of structures. Adv. Mater. Interfaces. 2018;5:1800074. doi: 10.1002/admi.201800074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/admi.201800074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao C.Y., Lei M.F., Jia C.J., Wu C., Yang Z., Shi Y. Influence mechanism of initial mechanical damage on concrete permeability and tunnel lining leakage. Eng. Fract. Mech. 2024;310:110531. doi: 10.1016/j.engfracmech.2024.110531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfracmech.2024.110531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dousti A., Moradian M., Taheri S.R., Rashetnia R., Shekarchi M. Corrosion assessment of RC deck in a jetty structure damaged by chloride attack. J. Perform. Constr. Facil. 2013;27:519&#x2013;528. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)CF.1943-5509.0000348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)CF.1943-5509.0000348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z.G., Qu X.L., Li J.H. Application of polymer modified cementitious coatings (PCCs) for impermeability enhancement of concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;249:118769. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo S.Y., Luo H.H., Tan Z., Chen J.Z., Zhang L., Ren J. Impermeability and interfacial bonding strength of TiO2-graphene modified epoxy resin coated OPC concrete. Prog. Org. Coat. 2021;151:106029. doi: 10.1016/j.porgcoat.2020.106029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.porgcoat.2020.106029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao H.G., Liu R., Zhang F.L., Liu M., Li H. Role of nano-SiO2 in improving the microstructure and impermeability of concrete with different aggregate gradations. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;188:537&#x2013;545. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.08.148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.08.148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuenca E., Tejedor A., Ferrara L. A methodology to assess crack sealing effectiveness of crystalline admixtures under repeated cracking-healing cycles. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;179:619&#x2013;632. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.05.261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.05.261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Rashed R., Al-Jabari M. Multi-crystallization enhancer for concrete waterproofing by pore blocking. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;272:121668. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira A.D.S., Gomes O.D.F.M., Ferrara L., Fairbairn E.D.M.R., Toledo Filho R.D. An overview of a twofold effect of crystalline admixtures in cement-based materials: From permeability reducers to self-healing stimulators. J. Build. Eng. 2021;41:102400. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2021.102400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2021.102400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong L., Zhao J.Y., Geng S., Qiu X., Jiang P., Zhou J., Jia S., Yao Z. Exploring the effects of cementitious capillary crystalline waterproof material on the properties of cement with/without mineral admixture: A comparison of rheology, hydration process, and self-healing behavior. Constr. Build. Mater. 2025;470:140546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azarsa P., Gupta R., Biparva A. Assessment of self-healing and durability parameters of concretes incorporating crystalline admixtures and Portland limestone cement. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2019;99:17&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2019.02.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2019.02.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park B., Choi Y.C. Self-healing capability of cementitious materials with crystalline admixtures and super absorbent polymers (SAPs) Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;189:1054&#x2013;1066. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.09.061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.09.061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C.C., Lu R.W., Li Y.Z., Guan X. Effect of crystalline admixtures on mechanical, self-healing and transport properties of engineered cementitious composite. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2021;124:104256. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2021.104256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2021.104256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R.Y., Yu J.Y., Gu S.J., He P., Han X., Liu Q. Investigation of self-healing capability on surface and internal cracks of cement mortar with ion chelator. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;236:117598. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira A.D.S., Filho R.D.T., Fairbairn E.D.M.R., de Oliveira L.F.C., Gomes O.D.F.M. Microstructural characterization of self-healing products in cementitious systems containing crystalline admixture in the short- and long-term. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2021;126:104369. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2021.104369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2021.104369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg R.P., Cuenca E., Brac E.M.G., Ferrara L. Crack sealing capacity in chloride-rich environments of mortars containing different cement substitutes and crystalline admixtures. J. Sustain. Cem. Based Mater. 2018;7:141&#x2013;159. doi: 10.1080/21650373.2017.1411297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21650373.2017.1411297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He P., Yu J.Y., Xue L.H., Han X. Influence of ion chelator on pore structure, water transport and crack-healing properties of cement pastes incorporating high-volume fly ash and blast-furnace slag. J. Build. Eng. 2022;55:104696. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R.Y., Yu J.Y., Liu Q.T. Influence of inorganic compounds on self-repairing capability and frost resistance of concrete incorporating ion chelating agent. J. Build. Eng. 2024;91:109754. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He C.F., Ye J.T., Gao Y., Liu C., Pan X. Comparative analysis of calcium chelation mechanism and chelating ability about sodium tripolyphosphate and citric acid sodium. J. Mol. Sci. 2015;31:198&#x2013;202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J.Y., Zha Y.G., Wang R.Y., He P., Li Y., Xie J., Wu S.P. A Concrete Self-Healing Additive and Its Preparation Method. 201711094897.9. China Patent. 2017 November 3;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R.Y., Yu J.Y., Gu S.J., He P., Han X., Liu Q. Investigation of migration and self-healing ability of ion chelator in cement-based materials by a novel method. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;262:120917. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidone R.E., Gaona X., Winnefeld F., Altmaier M., Geckeis H., Lothenbach B. Citrate sorption on cement hydrates. Cem. Concr. Res. 2024;178:107404. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2023.107404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2023.107404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Test Method of Cement Mortar Strength (ISO Method) China Building Industry Press; Beijing, China: 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard for Test Methods of Long-Term Performance and Durability of Ordinary Concrete. National Standard of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China; Beijing, China: 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rong Z.D., Yang H.L., Gao Y., Chen H. The Pore Structure Characteristics of Mortar and Its Application in the Study of Chloride Ion Transport Performance. Buildings. 2025;15:383. doi: 10.3390/buildings15030383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings15030383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X.H., Qi C.C., Aretxabaleta X.M., Ma C., Spagnoli D., Manzano H. The initial stages of cement hydration at the molecular level. Nat. Commun. 2024;15:2731. doi: 10.1038/s41467-024-46962-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-024-46962-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10980771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38553480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y., Ning L., Bi J., Wang C., Zhang Y., Zhao Y., Deng X., Shen M., Li Y. Advances in understanding hydration of Portland cement. J. Build. Eng. 2025;108:112866. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2025.112866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2025.112866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren B., Bai E.L., Luo X., Wang T., Wang Z. Impact mechanical properties and pore structure of graphene oxide concrete at high temperature. J. Build. Eng. 2024;85:108593. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.108593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.108593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K., Zhou J., Yin Z.G. Experimental study on mechanical properties and pore structure deterioration of concrete under freeze&#x2013;thaw cycles. Materials. 2021;14:6568. doi: 10.3390/ma14216568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma14216568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8585203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34772090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>