<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41819386</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-3476</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>695</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of pharmaceutics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Pharm</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pig skin-derived reconstituted lipid nanoparticles loaded sodium alginate hydrogel for wound healing.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>126763</StartPage><MedlinePgn>126763</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2026.126763</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0378-5173(26)00211-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Chronic non-healing wounds pose a clinical burden, necessitating advanced dressings that modulate the healing microenvironment and accelerate tissue regeneration. Herein, we developed a hydrogel-based dressing by integrating pig skin-derived reconstituted lipid nanoparticles (PS-rLNPs) with FDA-approved sodium alginate (SA), termed PS-rLNPs-SA. PS-rLNPs were fabricated via a solvent injection method with lipids from fresh pig skin, which were characterized by dynamic light scattering (DLS), transmission electron microscopy (TEM), and liquid chromatography-mass spectrometry (LC-MS). PS-rLNPs exhibited uniform spherical morphology with hydrated particle size of 91.3&#xa0;nm, excellent colloidal stability in physiological environments, and were mainly composed of triglycerides (77.9%) and phosphatidylcholine (11.6%)-lipids that synergistically support cell metabolism and membrane interaction. In vitro, PS-rLNPs promoted proliferation and migration of 3&#xa0;T3 and L929 fibroblasts in a concentration-dependent manner (optimal at 300&#xa0;&#x3bc;g/mL) without cytotoxicity, primarily via clathrin-mediated endocytosis and lysosomal escape. PS-rLNPs-SA hydrogel, prepared via in-situ calcium crosslinking, displayed shear-thinning behavior, injectability, and biocompatibility, enabling sustained release of PS-rLNPs at the wound site. In murine full-thickness skin defect model, PS-rLNPs-SA significantly accelerated wound closure (healing rate of 93.26% on Day 10), outperforming free PS-rLNPs and blank SA hydrogel. Histopathological and immunohistochemical analyses showed PS-rLNPs-SA enhanced regeneration, reduced inflammatory infiltration, promoted collagen deposition, and increased neovascularization (CD31<sup>+</sup> vessels) and cell proliferation (Ki-67<sup>+</sup> cells). Furthermore, in vitro hemolysis assays and in vivo major organ histology verified the biosafety of PS-rLNPs-SA. This work introduces promising natural lipid-based nanoplatform for wound repair, offering a novel strategy for developing clinically translatable wound dressings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liao</LastName><ForeName>Xiangyan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Pharmacy, Changzhou University, Changzhou 213164, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fu</LastName><ForeName>Xuanqi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, Jiangsu Normal University, Xuzhou 221116, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Shuping</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, Nanshan District Maternity and Child Healthcare Hospital of Shenzhen, Shenzhen 518067, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Rongjing</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hua Lookeng Honors College, Changzhou University, Changzhou 213164, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Yun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital, Affiliated Hospital of Medical School, Nanjing University, Nanjing 210008, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Fangying</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Ultrasound in Medicine, Sir Run Run Shaw Hospital, School of Medicine, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310016, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Cheng</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Pharmacy, Changzhou University, Changzhou 213164, Jiangsu, China. Electronic address: wangc90@cczu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jianhao</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Pharmacy, Changzhou University, Changzhou 213164, Jiangsu, China. Electronic address: minuswan@cczu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Pharm</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7804127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0378-5173</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biocompatibility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fibroblasts</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lipid nanoparticles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Natural lipids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wound healing</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41819386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2026.126763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0378-5173(26)00211-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>