<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41335616</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Moisture dynamics and ageing in clarinet reeds by neutron radiography.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0334660</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0334660</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0334660</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0334660</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The vibrational behavior of reeds in wind instruments is highly sensitive to their moisture content, yet the underlying hydration dynamics and their relationship to ageing remain poorly understood. In this study, we employ in situ neutron radiography to visualize and quantify internal water distribution in clarinet reeds at three stages of use: pristine, broken-in, and aged. Reeds were subjected to controlled wetting durations followed by drying under ambient conditions to enable time-resolved analysis of moisture uptake and retention. Neutron imaging revealed that water preferentially accumulates in the vamp region due to longitudinally exposed vascular structures, while the stock remains largely dry. Ageing significantly reduces both water uptake and retention capacity. Pristine reeds absorbed water rapidly and uniformly, whereas aged reeds exhibited faster drying; asymmetric moisture distribution; and non-uniform swelling and shrinkage, consistent with structural fatigue. These results demonstrate how repeated use alters hydration behavior and underscore the governing role of anatomical features, such as exposed vascular bundles and parenchyma cells. This study presents the first application of neutron imaging to clarinet reeds, providing spatially resolved insight into internal moisture dynamics. The findings establish a scientific basis for understanding reed break-in and ageing, with implications for performance optimization, reed design, and maintenance practices. Moreover, this work pioneers a novel application of neutron imaging in the study of woodwind instruments, where moisture control critically influences playability and longevity.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Lee et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Jongmin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9751-0186</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PSI Center for Neutron and Muon Sciences, Villigen PSI, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PSI Center for Energy and Environmental Sciences, Villigen PSI, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhan</LastName><ForeName>Qianru</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PSI Center for Neutron and Muon Sciences, Villigen PSI, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trtik</LastName><ForeName>Pavel</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PSI Center for Neutron and Muon Sciences, Villigen PSI, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mannes</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PSI Center for Neutron and Muon Sciences, Villigen PSI, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="Y">Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009502" MajorTopicYN="N">Neutrons</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011859" MajorTopicYN="N">Radiography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>NO authors have competing interests Enter: The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41335616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12674550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0334660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-29891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rice AR. The Baroque Clarinet. USA: Oxford University Press; 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Backus J. Vibrations of the reed and the air column in the clarinet. The Journal of the Acoustical Society of America. 1961;33(6):806&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1121/1.1908803</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1121/1.1908803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scavone GP. An acoustic analysis of single-reed woodwind instruments with an emphasis on design and performance issues and digital waveguide modeling techniques. Ph.D., Stanford University. Available from: https://www.proquest.com/docview/304371570/abstract/6E6FFAA3BA67408CPQ/1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Backus J. Small-Vibration Theory of the Clarinet. The Journal of the Acoustical Society of America. 1963;35(3):305&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1121/1.1918458</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1121/1.1918458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen EA, Guillemain P, Jousserand M. The dual influence of the reed resonance frequency and tonehole lattice cutoff frequency on sound production and radiation of a clarinet-like instrument. J Acoust Soc Am. 2022;151(6):3780. doi: 10.1121/10.0011467</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1121/10.0011467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35778204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Bhogal N. H&#xf6;gskolan f&#xf6;r scen och Musik, University of Gothenburg; p. 115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>KOLESIK P. Anatomical Characteristics Affecting the Musical Performance of Clarinet Reeds Made fromArundo donaxL. (Gramineae). Annals of Botany. 1998;81(1):151&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1006/anbo.1997.0548</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/anbo.1997.0548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucur V. Manufacturing of the Reeds for Reed Driven Instruments. In: Bucur V, editor. Handbook of Materials for Wind Musical Instruments. Cham: Springer International Publishing; 2019. pp. 559&#x2013;577. doi:10.1007/978-3-030-19175-7_14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-19175-7_14</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conte P, Fiore V, Valenza A. Structural and Mechanical Modification Induced by Water Content in Giant Wild Reed (A. donax L.). ACS Omega. 2018;3(12):18510&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.8b02649</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.8b02649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducasse &#xc9;. Mod&#xe9;lisation et simulation dans le domaine temporel d&#x2019;instruments &#xe0; vent &#xe0; anche simple en situation de jeu: m&#xe9;thodes et mod&#xe8;les. These de doctorat, Le Mans. 2001. Available from: https://theses.fr/2001LEMA1013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taillard PA, Lalo&#xeb; F, Gross M, Dalmont JP, Kergomard J. Measurements of resonance frequencies of clarinet reeds and simulations. 34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Facchinetti ML, Boutillon X, Constantinescu A. Numerical and experimental modal analysis of the reed and pipe of a clarinet. J Acoust Soc Am. 2003;113(5):2874&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1121/1.1560212</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1121/1.1560212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12765403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taillard P-A. Theoretical and experimental study of the role of the reed in clarinet playing. phdthesis, Le Mans Universit&#xe9;. 2018. Available from: https://theses.hal.science/tel-01858244</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaillard A, Koehl V, Gazengel B. Theoretical and experimental studies about single cane reeds: a review. Acta Acust. 2024;8:63. doi: 10.1051/aacus/2024050</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1051/aacus/2024050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christ S. Natural Reed Enhancement: Establishing the First Universal Reed Break-In Process Through Hydro-Stabilization. Theses and Dissertations. 2020. Available from: https://scholarcommons.sc.edu/etd/5927</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez-Bhogal N. Breaking in Clarinet Reeds - Techniques and their Effectiveness. 2019 [cited 25 Mar 2025]. Available from: https://gupea.ub.gu.se/handle/2077/61985</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casadonte DJ. The Clarinet Reed: An Introduction to its Biology, Chemistry, and Physics. The Ohio State University. 1995. Available from: https://etd.ohiolink.edu/apexprod/rws_etd/send_file/send?accession=osu1210865836&amp;disposition=inline</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucur V. Traditional and new materials for the reeds of woodwind musical instruments. Wood Sci Technol. 2019;53(5):1157&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1007/s00226-019-01117-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00226-019-01117-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strobl M, Lehmann E. Neutron Imaging: From applied materials science to
industry. IOP Publishing; 2024. Available from: https://iopscience.iop.org/book/edit/978-0-7503-3495-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehmann EH, L&#xe4;mmlein S, Mannes D. Neutron imaging as tool for investigations on historical musical instruments. Journal of Archaeological Science: Reports. 2018;20:239&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1016/j.jasrep.2018.05.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jasrep.2018.05.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Untersuchungen von historischen Blechblasinstrumenten mittels Neutronen-Imaging. [cited 25 Mar 2025]. Available from: https://arbor.bfh.ch/entities/publication/5d9aa98e-8aa5-452d-97d3-926e99e1d8ba</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>New Insights into the Conservation of Brass Instruments: Brass Instruments between Preventive Conservation and Use in Historically Informed Performance. [cited 25 Mar 2025]. Available from: https://arbor.bfh.ch/entities/publication/f10a2964-c93b-43c0-93fe-0871fee068a0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xe4;mmlein SL, Mannes D, Van Damme B, Schwarze FWMR, Burgert I. The influence of multi-layered varnishes on moisture protection and vibrational properties of violin wood. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):18611. doi: 10.1038/s41598-019-54991-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-54991-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6901594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31819087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehmann EH, Vontobel P, Wiezel L. Properties of the radiography facility neutra at sinq and its potential for use as european reference facility. Nondestructive Testing and Evaluation. 2001;16(2&#x2013;6):191&#x2013;202. doi: 10.1080/10589750108953075</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10589750108953075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blau B, Clausen KN, Gvasaliya S, Janoschek M, Janssen S, Keller L, et al. The Swiss Spallation Neutron Source SINQ at Paul Scherrer Institut. Neutron News. 2009;20(3):5&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1080/10448630903120387</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10448630903120387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Carreon Ruiz ER, Kaestner A, Trtik P, Strobl M, Boillat P. Framework for processing operando neutron radiography of energy devices. Sci Rep. 2025;15(1):25835. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-09425-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-09425-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12267630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40670489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boillat P. Advanced characterization of polymer electrolyte fuel cells using high resolution neutron imaging. ETH Zurich. 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider CA, Rasband WS, Eliceiri KW. NIH Image to ImageJ: 25 years of image analysis. Nat Methods. 2012;9(7):671&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1038/nmeth.2089</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nmeth.2089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5554542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22930834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virtanen P, Gommers R, Oliphant TE, Haberland M, Reddy T, Cournapeau D, et al. SciPy 1.0: fundamental algorithms for scientific computing in Python. Nat Methods. 2020;17(3):261&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1038/s41592-019-0686-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41592-019-0686-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7056644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32015543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawasaki M, Nobuchi T, Nakafushi Y, Nose M, Shibata M, Li P, et al. Structural observations and biomechanical measurements of clarinet reeds made from Arundo donax. Microsc Res Tech. 2017;80(8):959&#x2013;68. doi: 10.1002/jemt.22889</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jemt.22889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28485485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemp C, Scavone G. Mechanical, anatomical and modeling techniques for alto saxophone reed evaluation and classification. Wood Sci Technol. 2020;54(6):1677&#x2013;704. doi: 10.1007/s00226-020-01224-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00226-020-01224-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgano M, Trtik P, Meyer M, Lehmann EH, Hovind J, Strobl M. Unlocking high spatial resolution in neutron imaging through an add-on fibre optics taper. Opt Express. 2018;26(2):1809&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1364/OE.26.001809</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1364/OE.26.001809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29402049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehmann EH, Frei G, K&#xfc;hne G, Boillat P. The micro-setup for neutron imaging: A major step forward to improve the spatial resolution. Nuclear Instruments and Methods in Physics Research Section A: Accelerators, Spectrometers, Detectors and Associated Equipment. 2007;576(2&#x2013;3):389&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1016/j.nima.2007.03.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nima.2007.03.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watts DA, Moore GW. Water-Use Dynamics of an Invasive Reed, Arundo donax, from Leaf to Stand. Wetlands. 2011;31(4):725&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1007/s13157-011-0188-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13157-011-0188-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Water Uptake and Transport in Vascular Plants | Learn Science at Scitable. [cited 8 Apr 2025]. Available from: https://www.nature.com/scitable/knowledge/library/water-uptake-and-transport-in-vascular-plants-103016037/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngernsaengsaruay C, Puangsin B, Leksungnoen N, Khantayanuwong S, Chanton P, Thaepthup T, et al. Morphology, Taxonomy, Culm Internode and Leaf Anatomy, and Palynology of the Giant Reed (Arundo donax L.), Poaceae, Growing in Thailand. Plants (Basel). 2023;12(9):1850. doi: 10.3390/plants12091850</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/plants12091850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10181382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37176909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Secchi F, Pagliarani C, Zwieniecki MA. The functional role of xylem parenchyma cells and aquaporins during recovery from severe water stress. Plant Cell Environ. 2017;40(6):858&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1111/pce.12831</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pce.12831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27628165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo W, Tong L, Yang L, Zhao S, Yin S, Liu C, et al. A thick-layer drying kinetic model and drying characteristics of moisture-containing porous materials. International Communications in Heat and Mass Transfer. 2023;149:107133. doi: 10.1016/j.icheatmasstransfer.2023.107133</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.icheatmasstransfer.2023.107133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solbrig K, Fr&#xfc;hwald K, Ressel JB, Mannes D, Schillinger B, Schulz M. Radiometric Investigation of Water Vapour Movement in Wood-based Composites by Means of Cold and Thermal Neutrons. Physics Procedia. 2015;69:583&#x2013;92. doi: 10.1016/j.phpro.2015.07.083</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phpro.2015.07.083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannes D, Sonderegger W, Hering S, Lehmann E, Niemz P. Non-destructive determination and quantification of diffusion processes in wood by means of neutron imaging. hfsg. 2009;63(5):589&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1515/hf.2009.100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/hf.2009.100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonderegger W, Hering S, Mannes D, Vontobel P, Lehmann E, Niemz P. Quantitative determination of bound water diffusion in multilayer boards by means of neutron imaging. Eur J Wood Prod. 2010;68(3):341&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1007/s00107-010-0463-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00107-010-0463-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gezici-Ko&#xe7; &#xd6;, Erich SJF, Huinink HP, van der Ven LGJ, Adan OCG. Bound and free water distribution in wood during water uptake and drying as measured by 1D magnetic resonance imaging. Cellulose. 2016;24(2):535&#x2013;53. doi: 10.1007/s10570-016-1173-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10570-016-1173-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obataya E, Norimoto M. Mechanical relaxation processes due to sugars in cane (Arundo donax L.). J Wood Sci. 1999;45(5):378&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1007/bf01177909</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/bf01177909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xfc;ggeberg M, Burgert I, Speck T. Structural and mechanical design of tissue interfaces in the giant reed Arundo donax. J R Soc Interface. 2010;7(44):499&#x2013;506. doi: 10.1098/rsif.2009.0273</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rsif.2009.0273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2842797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19726440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemp C. Characterisation of woodwind instrument reed (Arundo donax L) degradation and mechanical behaviour. Journal of Materials Science. 2023;45:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemp C, Scavone G. Microstructure contributions to vibrational damping and identification of damage mechanisms in arundo Donax L: Reed Cane for Woodwind Instruments. MRS Advances. 2017;2(35&#x2013;36):1869&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1557/adv.2017.223</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1557/adv.2017.223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Zhu L, Gu X, Xu J, Dong L, Qiu J. Reed microstructure detection by optical coherence tomography, an efficient and non-invasive method. Appl Opt, AO. 2023;62: 3874&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1364/AO.483991</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1364/AO.483991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37706696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a Esteban L, Gril J, de Palacios de Palacios P, Guindeo Casas&#xfa;s A. Reduction of wood hygroscopicity and associated dimensional response by repeated humidity cycles. Ann For Sci. 2005;62(3):275&#x2013;84. doi: 10.1051/forest:2005020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1051/forest:2005020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popineau V, C&#xe9;lino A, P&#xe9;ron M, Baley C, Le Duigou A. Understanding the effect of hygroscopic cycling on the internal stress and stiffness of natural fibre biocomposites. Composites Part A: Applied Science and Manufacturing. 2022;158:106995. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesa.2022.106995</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesa.2022.106995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar M, Shakher C. Experimental characterization of the hygroscopic properties of wood during convective drying using digital holographic interferometry. Appl Opt. 2016;55(5):960&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1364/AO.55.000960</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1364/AO.55.000960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26906359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang YF, Li DY, Yu JX, He HT. On the thickness and nanomechanical properties of salivary pellicle formed on tooth enamel. J Dent. 2016;55:99&#x2013;104. doi: 10.1016/j.jdent.2016.10.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jdent.2016.10.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27771252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer NG, Aparicio C. The salivary pellicle on dental biomaterials. Colloids Surf B Biointerfaces. 2021;200:111570. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfb.2021.111570</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfb.2021.111570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33460965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grado&#x144; L. Blockage of porous structures caused by the deposition of aerosol particles. Journal of Aerosol Science. 1984;15(4):503&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1016/0021-8502(84)90046-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0021-8502(84)90046-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papp EA, Csiha C. Contact angle as function of surface roughness of different wood species. Surfaces and Interfaces. 2017;8:54&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.surfin.2017.04.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.surfin.2017.04.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>How to Deal With Clarinet Reeds. In: Alexandra Doyle [Internet]. [cited 9 Apr 2025]. Available from: https://www.alexdoyleclarinet.com/blog/how-to-deal-with-clarinet-reeds</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adjusting Reeds for the Beginner to Advanced &#x2013; International Clarinet Association. [cited 9 Apr 2025]. Available from: https://clarinet.org/adjusting-reeds-for-the-beginner-to-advanced/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Clarinet BBoard. [cited 9 Apr 2025]. Available from: http://test.woodwind.org/oboe/BBoard/read.html?f=1&amp;i=374292&amp;t=374292</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer P. Peter Spitzer Music Blog: Why Good Reeds Go Bad. In: Peter Spitzer Music Blog [Internet]. 17 Jan 2013 [cited 9 Apr 2025]. Available: https://peterspitzer.blogspot.com/2013/01/why-good-reeds-go-bad.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatziioannou V, P&#xe0;mies-Vil&#xe0; M. Analyzing the single-reed excitation mechanism. J Acoust Soc Am. 2022;152(2):R3. doi: 10.1121/10.0012989</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1121/10.0012989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36050164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cipriano Almeida Barros L, Longui EL, Muszynski L. A quest for a sustainable alternative wood species to produce world class clarinets. BioRes. 2021;16(3):6292&#x2013;312. doi: 10.15376/biores.16.3.6292-6312</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15376/biores.16.3.6292-6312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>