<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39640943</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2589-5370</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>78</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>EClinicalMedicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>EClinicalMedicine</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The global, regional, and national burden of urolithiasis in 204 countries and territories, 2000-2021: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>102924</StartPage><MedlinePgn>102924</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">102924</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.eclinm.2024.102924</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Urolithiasis is a common urological problem that is associated with high morbidity. A comprehensive assessment of the non-fatal and fatal health trends of urolithiasis by age, sex, and geography over time is necessary to inform policy to control this surgically managed non-communicable disease.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study was conducted using the standard GBD methodology and analytic tools. Cause-specific mortality rate (CSMR) was estimated using vital registration and verbal autopsy data and the Cause of Death Ensemble model (CODEm) modelling tool. CSMR estimates and incidence data from medical insurance claims and hospital discharges were analysed using a Bayesian meta-regression modelling tool, DisMod-MR 2.1, to estimate age-, sex-, and location-specific incidence of urolithiasis between 2000 and 2021. Disability-adjusted life-years (DALYs) were the sum of years of life lost (YLL) and years lived with disability (YLDs). YLLs due to urolithiasis were calculated by multiplying the estimated number of deaths by the standard life expectancy at the age of death. YLDs were estimated by multiplying the disability weight by the symptomatic proportion of urolithiasis cases. The Global Burden of Diseases study used de-identified data, approved by the University of Washington IRB (Study Number 9060).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">There were 106 million (95% UI 88.3-129.0) incident cases of urolithiasis in 2021, of which 67% were in men (71.1 million [59.4-86.2)]). The global number of incident cases, deaths, and DALYs increased by 26.7% (23.8-29.8), 60.3% (41.5-84.7), and 34.5% (24.6-47.3), respectively, between 2000 and 2021. The global age-standardised incidence rate of urolithiasis experienced a significant decrease of 17.5% (14.7-20.0), while the age-standardised DALYs rate saw a reduction of 15.1% (6.8-21.3). Twelve GBD regions showed declining trends in the age-standardised incidence rate of urolithiasis between 2000 and 2021, and the remaining nine GBD regions had an increasing trend of age-standardised rates of urolithiasis. A significant increase in the age-standardised incidence rate of urolithiasis was observed in Central America, Tropical Latin America, and the Caribbean regions, whereas notable decline was observed in east Asia, eastern Europe, central Europe, and high-income North America. It was observed that the global age-standardised death rate was less than 0.5 per 100,000 across all GBD regions and less than 1 per 100,000 across all SDI quintiles, with fairly stable global age-standardised death rates of urolithiasis between 2000 and 2021. The age-standardised incidence rate of urolithiasis was 837 (688-1034) in low SDI regions and 1443 (12,108-1734) in high-middle SDI regions. Furthermore, the age-standardised DALY rate showed a decreasing trend across all SDI quintiles over the same period: high-middle SDI (-28.9% [-34.4 to&#xa0;-23.0]), middle SDI (-22.6% [-30.5 to&#xa0;-10.9]), and low-middle SDI (-2.9% [-15.8 to 12.9]).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Global urolithiasis incidence and DALY rates have decreased, while the death rate has stabilised worldwide, showing significant variability among regions, SDI levels, and countries. This could be due to effective preventive measures c on urolithiasis risk factors, effective public health education, lifestyle changes, and early interventions and improved health care access at the global level. This analysis offers relevant insights into global, regional, and country-specific urolithiasis trends.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUNDING" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>GBD 2021 Urolithiasis Collaborators</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>EClinicalMedicine</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101733727</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2589-5370</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Disability adjusted life loss</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Global burden of disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nephrolithiasis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Urolithiasis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>S Bhaskar reports grants or contracts from the Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS), Japanese Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science, and Technology (MEXT) and JSPS and the Australian Academy of Science; leadership or fiduciary roles in board, society, committee or advocacy groups, paid or unpaid, with Rotary District 9675, Sydney, Australia; Global Health &amp; Migration Hub Community, Global Health Hub Germany, Berlin, Germany; PLOS One, BMC Neurology, Frontiers in Neurology, Frontiers in Stroke, Frontiers in Public Health, Journal of Aging Research, and BMC Medical Research Methodology; College of Reviewers, Canadian Institutes of Health Research, Government of Canada; World Headache Society, Bengaluru India; Cariplo Foundation, Milan, Italy; National Cerebral and Cardiovascular Center, Department of Neurology, Suita, Osaka, Japan; Cardiff University Biobank, Cardiff, UK, all outside the submitted work. B Bikbov reports grants or contracts from the European Commission, University of Rome, and Politecnico di Milano; supporting for attending meetings and/or travel from the European Renal Association; leadership or fiduciary roles in board, society, committee or advocacy groups, unpaid, with the International Society of Nephrology and the Western Europe Regional Board, International Society of Nephrology; and other support from Scientific-Tools.org, all outside the submitted work. I Ilic report support for the present manuscript from the Ministry of Education, Science, and Technological Development, Republic of Serbia (Project No. 175042, 2011&#x2013;2023). M Ilic reports support for the present manuscript from the Ministry of Science, Technological Development, and Innovation, Republic of Serbia (Project No. 451-03-47/2023-01/200111). A-F A Mentis reports grants or contracts from &#x2018;MilkSafe: A novel pipeline to enrich formula milk using omics technologies', a research co financed by the European Regional Development Fund of the European Union and Greek national funds through the Operational Program Competitiveness, Entrepreneurship and Innovation, under the call RESEARCH&#x2013;CREATE&#x2013;INNOVATE (project code: T2EDK-02222), as well as from ELIDEK (Hellenic Foundation for Research and Innovation, MIMS-860) (both outside of the present manuscript); payment or expert testimony as a peer-reviewer for FONDAZIONE CARIPLO, ITALY; Participation on a Data Safety Monitoring Board or Advisory Board as Editorial Board Member for &#x201c;Systematic Reviews&#x201d; journal, for &#x201c;Annals of Epidemiology&#x201d; journal, and as Associate Editor for &#x201c;Translational Psychiatry&#x201d;; stock or stock options on a family winery; other financial interests as a scientific officer as part of the BGI Group; outside the submitted work. A Ortiz reports grants to their institute from Sanofi and Catedra Mundipharma-UAM of diabetic kidney disease and the Catedra Astrazeneca-UAM of chronic kidney disease and electrolytes; consultancy or speaker fees Advicciene, Astellas, Astrazeneca, Amicus, Amgen, Fresenius Medical Care, GSK, Bayer, Sanofi-Genzyme, Menarini, Kyowa Kirin, Alexion, Idorsia, Chiesi, Otsuka, Novo-Nordisk and Vifor Fresenius Medical Care Renal Pharma; travel support from Advicciene, Astellas, Astrazeneca, Fresenius Medical Care, Boehringer-Ingelheim Bayer, Sanofi-Genzyme, Menarini, Chiesi, Otsuka, Sysmex; leadership or fiduciary role, unpaid, with Council ERA. SOMANE; all outside the submitted work. J A Singh reports consulting fees from ROMTech, Atheneum, Clearview healthcare partners, American College of Rheumatology, Yale, Hulio, Horizon Pharmaceuticals, DINORA, Frictionless Solutions, Schipher, Crealta/Horizon, Medisys, Fidia, PK Med, Two labs Inc., Adept Field Solutions, Clinical Care options, Putnam associates, Focus forward, Navigant consulting, Spherix, MedIQ, Jupiter Life Science, UBM LLC, Trio Health, Medscape, WebMD, and Practice Point communications; and the National Institutes of Health; Payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers bureaus, manuscript writing or educational events on the speakers bureau of Simply Speaking; Support for attending meetings and/or travel from OMERACT as a steering committee member; Participation on a Data Safety Monitoring Board or Advisory Board with the FDA Arthritis Advisory Committee; Leadership or fiduciary role in other board, society, committee or advocacy group, paid as a past steering committee member of the OMERACT, an international organization that develops measures for clinical trials and receives arm's length funding from 12 pharmaceutical companies, unpaid as Chair of the Veterans Affairs Rheumatology Field Advisory Committee, and unpaid as the Editor and Director of the UAB Cochrane Musculoskeletal Group Satellite Center on Network Meta-analysis; Stock or stock options in Atai life sciences, Kintara therapeutics, Intelligent Biosolutions, Acumen pharmaceutical, TPT Global Tech, Vaxart pharmaceuticals, Atyu biopharma, Adaptimmune Therapeutics, GeoVax Labs, Pieris Pharmaceuticals, Enzolytics Inc., Seres Therapeutics, Tonix Pharmaceuticals Holding Corp., Aebona Pharmaceuticals, and Charlotte's Web Holdings, Inc. and previously owned stock options in Amarin, Viking, and Moderna Pharmaceuticals; all outside the submitted work. A Zumla reports support for the present manuscript the Pan-African Network for Rapid Research, Response, Relief and Preparedness for Infectious Disease Epidemics (PANDORA-ID-NET) funded by the EDCTP&#x2013;the EU Horizon 2020 Framework Programme, and is a recipient of the UK NIHR Senior Investigator Award, Mahathir Science Award, and EU-EDCTP Pascoal Mocumbi Prize Laureate.</CoiStatement><InvestigatorList><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Awedew</LastName><ForeName>Atalel Fentahun</ForeName><Initials>AF</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Hannah</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berice</LastName><ForeName>B&#xe9;tyna N</ForeName><Initials>BN</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dodge</LastName><ForeName>Maxwell</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schneider</LastName><ForeName>Rachel D</ForeName><Initials>RD</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abbasi-Kangevari</LastName><ForeName>Mohsen</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Aly</LastName><ForeName>Ziyad</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almidani</LastName><ForeName>Omar</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alvand</LastName><ForeName>Saba</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arabloo</LastName><ForeName>Jalal</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aravkin</LastName><ForeName>Aleksandr Y</ForeName><Initials>AY</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ayana</LastName><ForeName>Tegegn Mulatu</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhardwaj</LastName><ForeName>Nikha</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhardwaj</LastName><ForeName>Pankaj</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhaskar</LastName><ForeName>Sonu</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bikbov</LastName><ForeName>Boris</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caetano Dos Santos</LastName><ForeName>Florentino Luciano</ForeName><Initials>FL</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Charan</LastName><ForeName>Jaykaran</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cruz-Martins</LastName><ForeName>Natalia</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dadras</LastName><ForeName>Omid</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dai</LastName><ForeName>Xiaochen</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Digesa</LastName><ForeName>Lankamo Ena</ForeName><Initials>LE</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elhadi</LastName><ForeName>Muhammed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elmonem</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Esezobor</LastName><ForeName>Christopher Imokhuede</ForeName><Initials>CI</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fatehizadeh</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gebremeskel</LastName><ForeName>Teferi Gebru</ForeName><Initials>TG</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Getachew</LastName><ForeName>Motuma Erena</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghamari</LastName><ForeName>Seyyed-Hadi</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hay</LastName><ForeName>Simon I</ForeName><Initials>SI</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ilic</LastName><ForeName>Irena M</ForeName><Initials>IM</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ilic</LastName><ForeName>Milena D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jayarajah</LastName><ForeName>Umesh</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jazayeri</LastName><ForeName>Seyed Behzad</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Min Seo</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Sang-Woong</ForeName><Initials>SW</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Shaun Wen Huey</ForeName><Initials>SWH</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lim</LastName><ForeName>Stephen S</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahmoud</LastName><ForeName>Mansour Adam</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malik</LastName><ForeName>Ahmad Azam</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mentis</LastName><ForeName>Alexios-Fotios A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mestrovic</LastName><ForeName>Tomislav</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Michalek</LastName><ForeName>Irmina Maria</ForeName><Initials>IM</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mihrtie</LastName><ForeName>Gedefaye Nibret</ForeName><Initials>GN</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mirrakhimov</LastName><ForeName>Erkin M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mokdad</LastName><ForeName>Ali H</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moni</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad Ali</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moradi</LastName><ForeName>Maryam</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murray</LastName><ForeName>Christopher Jl</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ortiz</LastName><ForeName>Alberto</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pawar</LastName><ForeName>Shrikant</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perico</LastName><ForeName>Norberto</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rashidi</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad-Mahdi</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rawassizadeh</LastName><ForeName>Reza</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Remuzzi</LastName><ForeName>Giuseppe</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schumacher</LastName><ForeName>Austin E</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Jasvinder A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Skryabin</LastName><ForeName>Valentin Yurievich</ForeName><Initials>VY</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Skryabina</LastName><ForeName>Anna Aleksandrovna</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Ker-Kan</ForeName><Initials>KK</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tolani</LastName><ForeName>Musliu Adetola</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Valadan Tahbaz</LastName><ForeName>Sahel</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Valizadeh</LastName><ForeName>Rohollah</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vo</LastName><ForeName>Bay</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wolde</LastName><ForeName>Asrat Arja</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yahyazadeh Jabbari</LastName><ForeName>Seyed Hossein</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yazdanpanah</LastName><ForeName>Fereshteh</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yi&#x11f;it</LastName><ForeName>Arzu</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yi&#x11f;it</LastName><ForeName>Vahit</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zahir</LastName><ForeName>Mazyar</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zastrozhin</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Zhi-Jiang</ForeName><Initials>ZJ</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zumla</LastName><ForeName>Alimuddin</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Misganaw</LastName><ForeName>Awoke</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dirac</LastName><ForeName>M Ashworth</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials></Investigator></InvestigatorList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39640943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11618031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2024.102924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2589-5370(24)00503-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pearle M.S., Jodi A., Antonelli J.A., Lotan Y. In: Campbell-Walsh Urology. 11th ed. Wein A.J., Kavoussi L.R., Partin A.W., Peters C.A., editors. Elsevier; Philadelphia: 2016. Urinary Lithiasis: etiology, epidemiology, and pathogenesis; pp. 1170&#x2013;1291. 1600 John F. Kennedy Blvd.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung M.J. Urolithiasis and nephrolithiasis. JAAPA. 2017;30(9):49&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28858017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakore P., Liang T.H.  StatPearls. StatPearls Publishing; Treasure Island (FL): 2022. Urolithiasis.https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK559101/ [Updated 2021 Jun 18] Available from:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorokin I., Mamoulakis C., Miyazawa K., Rodgers A., Talati J., Lotan Y. Epidemiology of stone disease across the world. World J Urol. 2017;35(9):1301&#x2013;1320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28213860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyams E.S., Matlaga B.R. Economic impact of urinary stones. Transl Androl Urol. 2014;3(3):278&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4708578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26816777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakore P., Liang T.H. StatPearls. StatPearls Publishing; Treasure Island (FL): 2022. Urolithiasis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli J.A., Maalouf N.M., Pearle M.S., Lotan Y. Use of the national health and nutrition examination survey to calculate the impact of obesity and diabetes on cost and prevalence of urolithiasis in 2030. Eur Urol. 2014;66(4):724&#x2013;729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4227394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25015037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raheem O.A., Khandwala Y.S., Sur R.L., Ghani K.R., Denstedt J.D. Burden of urolithiasis: trends in prevalence, treatments, and costs. Eur Urol Focus. 2017;3(1):18&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28720363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knoll T. Epidemiology, pathogenesis, and pathophysiology of urolithiasis. Eur Urol Suppl. 2010;9(12):802&#x2013;806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thongprayoon C., Krambeck A.E., Rule A.D. Determining the true burden of kidney stone disease. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2020;16(12):736&#x2013;746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32753740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scales C.D., Jr., Curtis L.H., Norris R.D., et al. Changing gender prevalence of stone disease. J&#xa0;Urol. 2007;177(3):979&#x2013;982.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17296391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearle M.S., Calhoun E.A., Curhan G.C., Urologic Diseases of America Project Urologic diseases in America project: urolithiasis. J&#xa0;Urol. 2005;173(3):848&#x2013;857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15711292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brikowski T.H., Lotan Y., Pearle M.S. Climate-related increase in the prevalence of urolithiasis in the United States. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2008;105(28):9841&#x2013;9846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2474527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18626008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin S., Srivastava A., Alli N.A., Bandyopadhyay B.C. Confounding risk factors and preventative measures driving nephrolithiasis global makeup. World J Nephrol. 2018;7(7):129&#x2013;142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6259033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30510912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor E.N., Stampfer M.J., Curhan G.C. Obesity, weight gain, and the risk of kidney stones. JAMA. 2005;293(4):455&#x2013;462. doi: 10.1001/jama.293.4.455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.293.4.455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15671430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pak C.Y.C. Etiology and treatment of urolithiasis. Am J Kidney Dis. 1991;18(6):624&#x2013;637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1962646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alelign T., Petros B. Kidney stone disease: an update on current concepts. Adv Urol. 2018;2018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5817324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29515627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trinchieri A., Maletta A., Simonelli G., Boeri L., De Lorenzis E., Montanari E. Time changes in the spectrum of urinary stone composition: a role for climate variations? BMC Nephrol. 2020;21(1):535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7726867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33297997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coe F.L., Evan A., Worcester E. Kidney stone disease. J&#xa0;Clin Invest. 2005;115(10):2598&#x2013;2608. doi: 10.1172/JCI26662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI26662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1236703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16200192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero V., Akpinar H., Assimos D.G. Kidney stones: a global picture of prevalence, incidence, and associated risk factors. Rev Urol. 2010;12(2-3):e86&#x2013;e96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2931286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20811557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abufaraj M., Xu T., Cao C., et al. Prevalence and trends in kidney stone among adults in the USA: analyses of national health and nutrition examination survey 2007-2018 data. Eur Urol Focus. 2021;7(6):1468&#x2013;1475. doi: 10.1016/j.euf.2020.08.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.euf.2020.08.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32900675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z., Prosperi M., Bird V.Y. Prevalence of kidney stones in the USA: the National Health and Nutrition Evaluation Survey. J&#xa0;Clin Urol. 2019;12(4):296&#x2013;302. doi: 10.1177/2051415818813820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2051415818813820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masterson J.H., Phillips C.J., Crum-Cianflone N.F., Krause R.J., Sur R.L., L'Esperance J.O. A&#xa0;10-year retrospective review of nephrolithiasis in the navy and navy pilots. J&#xa0;Urol. 2017;198(2):394&#x2013;400. doi: 10.1016/j.juro.2017.02.074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.juro.2017.02.074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28235550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillams K., Julieb&#xf8;-Jones P., Julieb&#xf8; S.&#xd8;., Somani B.K. Gender differences in kidney stone disease (KSD): findings from a systematic review. Curr Urol Rep. 2021;22(10):50. doi: 10.1007/s11934-021-01066-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11934-021-01066-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8497339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34622358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu C., Wang D.Q., Zi H., et al. Epidemiological trends of urinary tract infections, urolithiasis and benign prostatic hyperplasia in 203 countries and territories from 1990 to 2019. Mil Med Res. 2021;8(1):64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8656041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34879880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S., Huang X., Liu J., et al. Trends in the incidence and DALYs of urolithiasis from 1990 to 2019: results from the global burden of disease study 2019. Front Public Health. 2022;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8931285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35309229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang J., Narendrula A., El-Zawahry A., Sindhwani P., Ekwenna O. Global trends in incidence and burden of urolithiasis from 1990 to 2019: an analysis of global burden of disease study data. Eur Urol Open Sci. 2022;35:37&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8738898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35024630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2019 Diseases and Injuries Collaborators Global burden of 369 diseases and injuries in 204 countries and territories, 1990-2019: a systematic analysis for the global burden of disease study 2019. Lancet. 2020;396(10258):1204&#x2013;1222. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30925-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30925-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7567026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33069326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens G.A., Alkema L., Black R.E., et al. Guidelines for accurate and transparent health estimates reporting: the GATHER statement. Lancet. 2016;388(10062):e19&#x2013;e23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27371184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens G.A., Alkema L., Black R.E., et al. Guidelines for accurate and transparent health estimates reporting: the GATHER statement. PLoS Med. 2016;13(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4924581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27351744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krawczyk P., &#x15a;wi&#x119;cicki &#x141;. ICD-11 vs. ICD-10 - a review of updates and novelties introduced in the latest version of the WHO International Classification of Diseases. Psychiatr Pol. 2020;54(1):7&#x2013;20. doi: 10.12740/PP/103876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12740/PP/103876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32447353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2016 Causes of Death Collaborators Global, regional, and national age-sex specific mortality for 264 causes of death, 1980-2016: a systematic analysis for the global burden of disease study 2016. Lancet. 2017;390(10100):1151&#x2013;1210. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(17)32152-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(17)32152-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5605883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28919116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2021 Demographics Collaborators Global age-sex-specific mortality, life expectancy, and population estimates in 204 countries and territories and 811 subnational locations, 1950-2021, and the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic: a comprehensive demographic analysis for the global burden of disease study 2021. Lancet. 2024;403(10440):1989&#x2013;2056. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(24)00476-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(24)00476-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11126395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38484753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foreman K.J., Lozano R., Lopez A.D., Murray C.J. Modeling causes of death: an integrated approach using CODEm. Popul Health Metr. 2012;10:1. doi: 10.1186/1478-7954-10-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1478-7954-10-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3315398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22226226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieto-Barajas L.E. Bayesian regression with spatiotemporal varying coefficients. Biom J. 2020;62(5):1245&#x2013;1263. doi: 10.1002/bimj.201900098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bimj.201900098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32048325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vos T., Lim S.S., Abbafati C., et al. Global burden of 369 diseases and injuries in 204 countries and territories, 1990&#x2013;2019: a systematic analysis for the global burden of disease study 2019. Lancet. 2020;396:1204&#x2013;1222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7567026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33069326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flaxman A.D., Vos T., Murray C.J.L.  1st ed. University of Washington Press; 2015. An integrative Metaregression Framework for Descriptive Epidemiology; p. 250.https://uwapress.uw.edu/book/9780295991849/an-integrative-metaregression-framework-for-descriptive-epidemiology [cited 2021 Feb 3]. (Publications on Global Health, Institute for Health Metrics and Evaluation). Available from:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality  MEPS-HC panel design and collection process. 2019. https://meps.ahrq.gov/mepsweb/survey_comp/hc_data_collection.jsp [cited 2019 Apr 23]. Available from:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salomon J.A., Haagsma J.A., Davis A., et al. Disability weights for the global burden of disease 2013 study. Lancet Global Health. 2015;3(11):e712&#x2013;e723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26475018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salomon J.A., Vos T., Hogan D.R., et al. Common values in assessing health outcomes from disease and injury: disability weights measurement study for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2010. Lancet. 2012;380(9859):2129&#x2013;2143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10782811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23245605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haagsma J.A., Maertens de Noordhout C., Polinder S., et al. Assessing disability weights based on the responses of 30,660 people from four European countries. Popul Health Metr. 2015;13:10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4715333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26778920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2019 Demographics Collaborators Global age-sex-specific fertility, mortality, healthy life expectancy (HALE), and population estimates in 204 countries and territories, 1950-2019: a comprehensive demographic analysis for the global burden of disease study 2019. Lancet. 2020;396(10258):1160&#x2013;1203. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30977-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30977-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7566045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33069325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieske J.C., Pena de la Vega L.S., Slezak J.M., et al. Renal stone epidemiology in Rochester, Minnesota: an update. Kidney Int. 2006;69(4):760&#x2013;764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16518332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziemba J.B., Matlaga B.R. Epidemiology and economics of nephrolithiasis. Investig Clin Urol. 2017;58(5):299&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5577325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28868500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curhan G.C. Epidemiology of stone disease. Urol Clin North Am. 2007;34(3):287&#x2013;293. doi: 10.1016/j.ucl.2007.04.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ucl.2007.04.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2693870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17678980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chewcharat A., Curhan G. Trends in the prevalence of kidney stones in the United States from 2007 to 2016. Urolithiasis. 2021;49(1):27&#x2013;39. doi: 10.1007/s00240-020-01210-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00240-020-01210-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32870387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skolarikos A., Neisius A., Petrik A., et al. European Association of Urology (EAU)   2022. EAU Guidelines on Urolithiasis.https://uroweborg/guidelines/urolithiasis [cited 25 November, 2022]. Available from: [Google Scholar]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assimos D., Krambeck A., Miller N.L., et al. Surgical management of stones: American urological association/endourological society guideline, part II. J&#xa0;Urol. 2016;196:1161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27238615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhojani N., Bjazevic J., Wallace B., et al. Update - Canadian urological association guideline: evaluation and medical management of kidney stones. Can Urol Assoc J. 2022;16(6):175&#x2013;188. doi: 10.5489/cuaj.7872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5489/cuaj.7872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9245965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35623003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng D.M., Haleem M., Mamuchashvili A., et al. Medical evaluation and pharmacotherapeutical strategies in management of urolithiasis. Ther Adv Urol. 2021;13 doi: 10.1177/1756287221993300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1756287221993300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7907714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33708261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuvanc E., Yilmaz E., Tuglu D., Batislam E. Medical and alternative therapies in urinary tract stone disease. World J Nephrol. 2015;4(5):492&#x2013;499. doi: 10.5527/wjn.v4.i5.492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5527/wjn.v4.i5.492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4635369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26558186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borumandnia N., Fattahi P., Talebi A., et al. Longitudinal trend of urolithiasis incidence rates among world countries during past decades. BMC Urol. 2023;23(1):166. doi: 10.1186/s12894-023-01336-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12894-023-01336-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10577967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37845667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah S., Calle J.C. Dietary and medical management of recurrent nephrolithiasis. Cleve Clin J Med. 2016;83(6):463&#x2013;471. doi: 10.3949/ccjm.83a.15089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3949/ccjm.83a.15089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27281259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scales C.D., Jr., Smith A.C., Hanley J.M., Saigal C.S., Urologic Diseases in America P Prevalence of kidney stones in the United States. Eur Urol. 2012;62(1):160&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3362665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22498635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraro P.M., Bargagli M., Trinchieri A., Gambaro G. Risk of kidney stones: influence of dietary factors, dietary patterns, and vegetarian-vegan diets. Nutrients. 2020;12(3):779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7146511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32183500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alatab S., Pourmand G., El Howairis Mel F., et al. National profiles of urinary calculi: a comparison between developing and developed worlds. Iran J Kidney Dis. 2016;10(2):51&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26921745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson R.J., Sanchez-Lozada L.G., Newman L.S., et al. Climate change and the kidney. Ann Nutr Metab. 2019;74(Suppl 3):38&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31203298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Meteorological Organization (WMO)  State of the climate in Latin America and the Caribbean 2023. 2024. https://library.wmo.int/records/item/68891-state-of-the-climate-in-latin-america-and-the-caribbean-2023 Geneva.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson W.G. Stone formation in the Middle Eastern Gulf states: a review. Arab J Urol. 2012;10(3):265&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4442957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26558035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaee M.E., Ward C.E., Pollock M., Shetty S.D. Association between multiple chronic conditions and urolithiasis. Int Urol Nephrol. 2017;49(8):1361&#x2013;1367. doi: 10.1007/s11255-017-1611-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11255-017-1611-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28477302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q., Wang Y., Yang C., et al. Trends of urolithiasis in China: a national study based on hospitalized patients from 2013 to 2018. Kidney Dis. 2022;9(1):49&#x2013;57. doi: 10.1159/000527967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000527967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9900463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36756086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omran A.R. The epidemiologic transition. A theory of the epidemiology of population change. Milbank Mem Fund Q. 1971;49(4):509&#x2013;538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5155251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knoll T., Schubert A.B., Fahlenkamp D., Leusmann D.B., Wendt-Nordahl G., Schubert G. Urolithiasis through the ages: data on more than 200,000 urinary stone analyses. J&#xa0;Urol. 2011;185(4):1304&#x2013;1311. doi: 10.1016/j.juro.2010.11.073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.juro.2010.11.073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21334658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker V., Stansbridge E.M., Griffin D.G. Demography and biochemistry of 2800 patients from a renal stones clinic. Ann Clin Biochem. 2013;50(Pt 2):127&#x2013;139. doi: 10.1258/acb.2012.012122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1258/acb.2012.012122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23431484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strope S.A., Wolf J.S., Jr., Hollenbeck B.K. Changes in gender distribution of urinary stone disease. Urology. 2010;75(3):543&#x2013;546.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3410535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19854493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson C.M., Wilson D.M., O'Fallon W.M., Malek R.S., Kurland L.T. Renal stone epidemiology: a 25-year study in Rochester, Minnesota. Kidney Int. 1979;16(5):624&#x2013;631. doi: 10.1038/ki.1979.173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ki.1979.173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">548606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>