<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41548033</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>&#x200b;&#x200b;Influence of coir and flax fiber lengths on fracture toughness of fly ash, slag, and silica fume-based geopolymer concrete.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5596</StartPage><MedlinePgn>5596</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5596</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-35731-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Geopolymer concrete (GC), which is produced from industrial by-products rich in aluminosilicates such as fly ash, ground granulated blast furnace slag, and silica fume, serves as an environmentally sustainable substitute for conventional Portland cement-based concrete. Fracture toughness is vital for GC, as its brittle matrix is prone to crack initiation and propagation, affecting structural safety. Enhancing fracture resistance ensures reliable performance under various loading modes. Coir and flax fibers were chosen for their availability, sustainability, and ability to bridge cracks and improve post-crack energy absorption, providing insights for optimizing natural fiber reinforcement. Researchers have turned to natural fibers such as coir and flax to overcome the limited ductility and mechanical shortcomings typical of geopolymer composites. These fibers were specifically chosen for their potential to enhance both toughness and post-cracking energy absorption in the matrix. This investigation focused on how different aspect ratios of coir and flax fibers affected the fracture properties of GC when exposed to various loading modes: Mode I, Mode III, and their combination. To ensure a controlled comparison, GC specimens were cast with fiber lengths set at 20&#xa0;mm, 40&#xa0;mm, and 60&#xa0;mm, while maintaining a fixed fiber volume fraction of 0.5%. Additionally, the microstructure of the geopolymer composite was characterized using scanning electron microscopy, X-ray Diffraction, thermogravimetric analysis, and fourier transform infrared spectroscopy analyses. The results demonstrated that the incorporation of 40&#xa0;mm coir and flax fibres enhanced the fracture toughness of the GC by up to 20.65% under mixed-mode loading (loading angle&#x2009;=&#x2009;20&#xb0;), 18.96% under Mode I, and 9.70% under Mode III. In contrast, extending the fibre length to 60&#xa0;mm led to a deterioration in performance, with FRTS values falling by as much as 2.64% below those of the control composite, a decline attributable to fibre agglomeration and the consequent disruption of effective stress transfer. Microstructural analyses reveal that a dense, continuous sodium aluminosilicate hydrate gel network augmented by residual crystalline phases such as quartz and mullite substantially reinforces the geopolymer matrix. Coir fibres exhibit superior interfacial bonding and more stable debonding characteristics than flax fibres, thereby promoting more effective crack bridging and yielding greater fracture toughness. Complementary thermal and chemical characterisation further indicates enhanced matrix stability, reduced porosity, and improved load-transfer efficiency, with partial carbonation imparting additional microstructural densification.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bazarkhankyzy</LastName><ForeName>Aidana</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Faculty of Natural Sciences, L.N. Gumilyov Eurasian National University, Satpayev str., 2, 010000, Astana, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General and Biological Chemistry, Astana Medical University, Beibitshilik str., 49a, 010000, Astana, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aibuldinov&#x144;ska</LastName><ForeName>Yelaman</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of New Chemical Technologies, L.N. Gumilyov Eurasian National University, Satpayev str., 2, 010000, Astana, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>K. Kulazhanov Kazakh University of Technology and Business, Kaiym Mukhamedkhanov str, 37 A, 010000, Astana, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iskakova</LastName><ForeName>Zhanar</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of New Chemical Technologies, L.N. Gumilyov Eurasian National University, Satpayev str., 2, 010000, Astana, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kurpi&#x144;ska</LastName><ForeName>Marzena</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Civil and Environmental Engineering, Gdansk University of Technology, Gda&#x144;sk, Poland. marzena.kurpinska@pg.edu.pl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdelgader</LastName><ForeName>Hakim S</ForeName><Initials>HS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Civil and Environmental Engineering, Gdansk University of Technology, Gda&#x144;sk, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Engineering, Civil Engineering Department, University of Tripoli, Tripoli, Libya.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Avudaiappan</LastName><ForeName>Siva</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de Ciencias de la Construcci&#xf3;n, Facultad de ciencias de la construccion y ordenamiento territorial, Universidad Tecnol&#xf3;gica Metropolitana, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Flores</LastName><ForeName>Erick Saavedra</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departamento de Ingenier&#xed;a en Obras Civiles, Universidad de Santiago de Chile, Av. Ecuador 3659, Estaci&#xf3;n Central, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murali</LastName><ForeName>G</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Promotion of Research, Graphic Era (Deemed to be University), Clement town, Dehradun, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coir fiber</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Flax fiber</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fracture toughness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Geopolymer concrete</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Modes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Declaration of generative AI and AI-assisted technologies in the writing process: During the preparation of this work, the authors used Chat GTP AI in order to enhance readability and language quality. After using this tool, the authors reviewed and edited the content as needed and take responsibility for the content of the publication.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41548033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12890962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-35731-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-35731-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kishore, K., Sheikh, M. N. &amp; Hadi, M. N. S. Functionalization of carbon nanotubes for enhanced dispersion and improved properties of geopolymer concrete: A review. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>111</b>, (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanagaraj, B., Anand, N., Samuvel Raj, R. &amp; Lubloy, E. Techno-socio-economic aspects of Portland cement, geopolymer, and limestone calcined clay cement (LC3) composite systems: A-state-of-art-review. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>398</b>, (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbhuiya, S., Bhusan Das, B. &amp; Adak, D. Roadmap to a net-zero carbon cement sector: Strategies, innovations and policy imperatives. <i>J. Environ. Manag.</i><b>359</b>, (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38704956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ter&#xe1;n-Cuadrado, G., Tahir, F., Nurdiawati, A., Almarshoud, M. A. &amp; Al-Ghamdi, S. G. Current and potential materials for the low-carbon cement production: life cycle assessment perspective. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>96</b>, (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H Kumar, M. et al. Mechanical behaviour of high strength concrete modified with triple blend of fly ash, silica fume and steel fibers. <i>Mater. Today Proc.</i><b>65</b>, 933&#x2013;942 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2022.03.528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, M. H., Mohanta, N. R., Patel, N., Samantaray, S. &amp; Reddy, S. V. B. Impact of fly Ash and metakaoline on the crack resistance and shrinkage of concrete. <i>Iran. J. Sci. Technol. Trans. Civ. Eng.</i><b>46</b>, 2011&#x2013;2026 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40996-021-00748-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohanta, N. R. &amp; Samantaray, S. Study of combined effect of metakaolin and steel fiber on mechanical properties of concrete. <i>Pertanika J. Sci. Technol.</i><b>27</b>, 1381&#x2013;1396 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karthik, S., Raja Mohan, S., Murali, K. &amp; Ravindran, G. G. Research on pure modes i and II and mixed-mode (I/II) fracture toughness of geopolymer fiber-reinforced concrete. <i>Adv. Civ. Eng.</i><b>2023</b>. (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H. et al. Determination of fracture toughness of concrete based on actual critical crack length: theoretical model and experimental validation. <i>Eng. Fract. Mech.</i><b>318</b>, (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, H. et al. Effect of strain rate on crack propagation and fracture toughness of the concrete at mode I and mixed mode I/II. <i>Theor. Appl. Fract. Mech.</i><b>140</b>, (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aghdam, A. A. &amp; Niaki, M. H. Influence of high temperatures on modes I and II fracture toughness and energy of nanoclay-reinforced polymer concrete. <i>Mag. Concr. Res.</i><b>76</b>, 591&#x2013;599 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1680/jmacr.23.00163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakhshizadeh, M., Pirmohammad, S., Karimi, H. R. &amp; Aliha, M. R. M. Effect of support friction on pure mode I, II, and III fracture toughness of cement concrete tested with edge-notched disc Bend specimen. <i>Theor. Appl. Fract. Mech.</i><b>129</b>, (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samadi, M. et al. Fracture toughness enhancement of Preplaced aggregate geopolymer concrete under mode I, III, and I/III loading: role of 5D steel fibers and steel wire mesh. <i>Theor. Appl. Fract. Mech.</i><b>139</b>, (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghodratnama, M. et al. Enhancing the fracture toughness of eco-friendly self-compacting concrete with waste glass coarse aggregates and steel fibers: A mixed-mode I/II fracture analysis using SCB specimens. <i>Theor. Appl. Fract. Mech.</i><b>138</b>, (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haeri, H. et al. Surgical face masks as reinforcement to improve the tensile mode fracture toughness of reinforced concrete under three-point bending tests. <i>Eng. Fract. Mech.</i><b>314</b>, (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai, R., Mao, J., Qi, H., Qu, J. &amp; Guo, Q. Experimental study of the quasi-static and dynamic fracture toughness of Notched and repaired concrete using semi-circular Bend method. <i>Theor. Appl. Fract. Mech.</i><b>128</b>, (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motamedi, H., Fazaeli, H., Aliha, M. R. M. &amp; Reza Amiri, H. Evaluation of temperature and loading rate effect on fracture toughness of fiber reinforced asphalt mixture using edge Notched disc Bend (ENDB) specimen. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>234</b>, (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qing, L., Dong, M. &amp; Guan, J. Determining initial fracture toughness of concrete for split-tension specimens based on the extreme theory. <i>Eng. Fract. Mech.</i><b>189</b>, 427&#x2013;438 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfracmech.2017.11.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan, J. F., Hu, X. Z., Xie, C. P., Li, Q. B. &amp; Wu, Z. M. Wedge-splitting tests for tensile strength and fracture toughness of concrete. <i>Theor. Appl. Fract. Mech.</i><b>93</b>, 263&#x2013;275 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tafmec.2017.09.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murali, G. Recent research in mechanical properties of geopolymer-based ultra-high-performance concrete: A review. <i>Def. Technol.</i><b>32</b>, 67&#x2013;88 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dt.2023.07.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mani, S., Partheeban, P. &amp; Gifta, C. C. A comprehensive review on multilayered natural-fibre composite reinforcement in geopolymer concrete. <i>Clean Mater.</i><b>16</b>, (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, Z. Utilisation of steel fibres to reinforce waste glass concrete: Alkali&#x2013;silica reaction, engineering properties, and 3D mesoscale modelling. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater.</i><b>17</b>, (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, Z., Zhang, S. &amp; Deng, Z. PVA fiber-reinforced geopolymer mortar made with hybrid recycled aggregates: toward thermal insulation, lightweight and improved durability. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>426</b>, (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, Z. et al. Advantages and disadvantages of PVA-fibre-reinforced slag- and fly ash-blended geopolymer composites: engineering properties and microstructure. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>349</b>, 128690 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.128690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanagaraj, B. et al. Natural and synthetic fiber reinforced recycled aggregate concrete subjected to standard fire temperature. <i>Heliyon.</i><b>10</b>, (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11539323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39512461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wongsa, A., Kunthawatwong, R., Naenudon, S., Sata, V. &amp; Chindaprasirt, P. Natural fiber reinforced high calcium fly Ash geopolymer mortar. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>241</b>, (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korniejenko, K., Fr&#x105;czek, E., Pytlak, E. &amp; Adamski, M. Mechanical properties of geopolymer composites reinforced with natural fibers. <i>Proc. Eng.</i><b>151</b>, 388&#x2013;393 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.proeng.2016.07.395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noor Abbas, A. G., Aziz, N. A. A., Abdan, F. &amp; Azline Mohd Nasir, K. N. &amp; Fahim Huseien, G. Experimental evaluation and statistical modeling of Kenaf fiber-reinforced geopolymer concrete. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>367</b>, (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed, A. D. A. A., Ronghui, W. &amp; Huseien, G. F. Mechanical properties of natural jute Fiber-Reinforced geopolymer concrete: effects of various lengths and volume fractions. <i>J. Compos. Sci.</i><b>8</b>, (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazarkhankyzy, A. et al. Comprehensive evaluation of impact strength and microstructural characteristics of geopolymer concrete reinforced with four types of natural fibers of varying lengths. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12343770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40797089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guruswamy, K. P. et al. Coir fibre-reinforced concrete for enhanced compressive strength and sustainability in construction applications. <i>Heliyon.</i><b>10</b>, (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11567113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39553567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firas, A. B. M., Aziz, F. N. A. A., Abbas, A. G. N., Nasir, N. A. M. &amp; Safiee, N. A. Thermal performance of natural fiber-reinforced geopolymer concrete. <i>Lect. Notes Civ. Eng.</i><b>385</b>, 151&#x2013;162 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-99-6018-7_11</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajendran, M., Bakthavatchalam, K. &amp; Leela Bharathi, S. M. Review on the hybridized application of natural fiber in the development of geopolymer concrete. <i>J. Nat. Fibers</i><b>20</b>, (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbasi Zargaleh, M. R., Mazloom, M., Samimi, M. J. &amp; Ramesht, M. H. The effect of replacing fly Ash with GGBFS on the fracture parameters of geopolymer concrete. <i>Mater. Lett.</i><b>390</b>, (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y., Hu, S. &amp; Sun, X. Experimental investigation on the elastic modulus and fracture properties of basalt fiber&#x2013;reinforced fly Ash geopolymer concrete. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>338</b>, (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghasemzadeh Mousavinejad, S. H. &amp; Gashti, M. F. Effects of alkaline solution to binder ratio on fracture parameters of steel fiber reinforced heavyweight geopolymer concrete. <i>Theor. Appl. Fract. Mech.</i><b>113</b>, (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H., Jin, P., Yan, C., Zhang, N. &amp; Li, L. Impact of polyethylene fiber and Microsilica on fracture properties of high strength high toughness geopolymer concrete (HSHTGC). <i>Dev. Built Environ.</i><b>18</b>, (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., Shi, C., Zhang, Z., Li, N. &amp; Shi, D. Mechanical and fracture properties of ultra-high performance geopolymer concrete: effects of steel fiber and silica fume. <i>Cem. Concr. Compos.</i><b>112</b>, 103665 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2020.103665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karthik, S., Raja Mohan, S., Murali, K., Abid, G. &amp; Dixit, S. S. R. Impact of various fibers on mode I, III and I/III fracture toughness in slag, fly Ash, and silica fume-based geopolymer concrete using edge-notched disc Bend specimen. <i>Theor. Appl. Fract. Mech.</i><b>134</b>, (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation><i>IS 383:2016 Coarse and Fine Aggregate for Concrete-Specification (Third Revision)</i>. <i>Buria of Indian Standard</i>, vol. third edit (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM C-535. C131/C131M-14 standard test method for resistance to degradation of small-size coarse aggregate by abrasion and impact in the Los Angeles machine. In <i>Annual Book of American Society for Testing materials ASTM Standards, West Conshohocken, USA</i>, vol. 03, 1&#x2013;3 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>British Standards Institution. Part 112: methods for determination of aggregate impact value (AIV). (1990).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliha, M. R. M., Bahmani, A. &amp; Akhondi, S. Determination of mode III fracture toughness for different materials using a new designed test configuration. <i>Mater. Des.</i><b>86</b>, 863&#x2013;871 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2015.08.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pirmohammad, S. &amp; Bayat, A. Finite element analysis of a new specimen for conduct- Ing fracture tests under mixed mode I / III loading. <i>J. Stress Anal.</i><b>1</b>, 33&#x2013;41 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z., Ma, C. &amp; Wei, X. Assessment of mode I/III fracture toughness of bi-material rock-like ENDB and ENDC specimens. <i>Theor. Appl. Fract. Mech</i><b>129</b>, (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mousavi, S. R., Afshoon, I., Bayatpour, M. A., Davarpanah, T. Q. &amp; Miri, M. A. Effect of waste glass and curing aging on fracture toughness of self-compacting mortars using ENDB specimen. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>282</b>, (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pirmohammad, S. &amp; Bayat, A. Characterizing mixed mode I/III fracture toughness of asphalt concrete using asymmetric disc Bend (ADB) specimen. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>120</b>, 571&#x2013;580 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.05.137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Y. et al. Evaluating fracture resistance of basalt fiber reinforced mortar to mode I/III load using edge Notched disc Bend (ENDB) specimen: insights from acoustic emission and morphological analysis. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>411</b>, (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliha, M. R. M., Fazaeli, H. &amp; Aghajani, S. Moghadas Nejad, F. Effect of temperature and air void on mixed mode fracture toughness of modified asphalt mixtures. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>95</b>, 545&#x2013;555 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.07.165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliha, M. R. M., Bahmani, A. &amp; Akhondi, S. A novel test specimen for investigating the mixed mode I&#x2009;+&#x2009;III fracture toughness of hot mix asphalt composites&#x2014;Experimental and theoretical study. <i>Int. J. Solids Struct.</i><b>90</b>, 167&#x2013;177 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijsolstr.2016.03.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoseini, S. O., Sohrabi, M. R., Mousavi, S. R. &amp; Ghasemi, M. Effects of coarse aggregate and wavy steel fiber volumes on the critical stress intensity factors of modes I and III cracks in self-compacting concrete using ENDB specimens. <i>Theor. Appl. Fract. Mech.</i><b>121</b>, (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan, Z. et al. Experimental investigation on mixed mode I-III fracture behaviors and degradation mechanism of sandstone under thermal-chemical stimulation. <i>Theor. Appl. Fract. Mech.</i><b>129</b>, (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansourian, A., Hashemi, S. &amp; Aliha, M. R. M. Evaluation of pure and mixed modes (I/III) fracture toughness of Portland cement concrete mixtures containing reclaimed asphalt pavement. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>178</b>, 10&#x2013;18 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.05.130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murali, G. et al. Pure and mixed-mode (I/III) fracture toughness of preplaced aggregate fibrous concrete and slurry infiltrated fibre concrete and hybrid combination comprising nano carbon tubes. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>362</b>, (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kathirvel, P. &amp; Murali, G. Effect of using available GGBFS, silica fume, quartz powder and steel fibres on the fracture behavior of sustainable reactive powder concrete. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>375</b>, 130997 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.130997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliha, M. R. M., Sarbijan, M. J. &amp; Bahmani, A. Fracture toughness determination of modified HMA mixtures with two novel disc shape configurations. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>155</b>, 789&#x2013;799 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.08.093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khelifi, H., Lecompte, T., Perrot, A. &amp; Ausias, G. Mechanical enhancement of cement-stabilized soil by flax fibre reinforcement and extrusion processing. <i>Mater. Struct. Constr.</i><b>49</b>, 1143&#x2013;1156 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1617/s11527-015-0564-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page, J., Khadraoui, F., Boutouil, M. &amp; Gomina, M. Multi-physical properties of a structural concrete incorporating short flax fibers. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>140</b>, 344&#x2013;353 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.02.124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandrasekaran, R. G. &amp; Gudimella, R. Mechanical properties and durability analysis of coir fibre reinforced composites&#x2014;state of art report. <i>AIP Conf. Proc.</i> 2766, (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, W. et al. Effect of coconut fiber length and content on properties of high strength concrete. <i>Materials (Basel)</i><b>13</b>, (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7084858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32121125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baskar, P., Annadurai, S., Sekar, K. &amp; Prabakaran, M. A. Review on fresh, hardened, and microstructural properties of fibre-reinforced geopolymer concrete. <i>Polymers (Basel)</i><b>15</b>, (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10051752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36987261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walter Otunyo, A. Dan Nyechieo, N. Mechanical properties and fracture behaviour of coconut fibre reinforced concrete (CFRC). <i>Am. J. Civ. Eng. Archit.</i><b>5</b>, 208&#x2013;216 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamada, H. M., Al-Attar, A., Askar, M. K., Beddu, S. &amp; Majdi, A. Advancing the sustainability of fiber-reinforced geopolymer concrete using natural plant fibers: A comprehensive review of properties and impacts. <i>Structures</i><b>77</b>, (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdalla, J. A. et al. A comprehensive review on the use of natural fibers in cement/geopolymer concrete: A step towards sustainability. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater</i><b>19</b>, (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayeni, I. S., Lim, N. H. A. S. &amp; Samad, M. Engineering properties of natural fibre-reinforced one-part geopolymer concrete. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>456</b>, (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huseien, G. F., Ismail, M., Khalid, N. H. A., Hussin, M. W. &amp; Mirza, J. Compressive strength and microstructure of assorted wastes incorporated geopolymer mortars: effect of solution molarity. <i>Alex. Eng. J.</i><b>57</b>, 3375&#x2013;3386 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aej.2018.07.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Riessen, A., Jamieson, E., Gildenhuys, H., Skane, R. &amp; Allery, J. Using XRD to assess the strength of fly-ash- and metakaolin-based geopolymers. <i>Materials (Basel)</i><b>18</b>, (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12072858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40363595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z. &amp; Ikeda, K. Compositions and microstructures of carbonated geopolymers with different precursors. <i>Materials (Basel)</i><b>17</b>, (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11012618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38612006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, Y., Klima, K. M., Melzer, S., Brouwers, H. J. H. &amp; Yu, Q. Uncover the thermal behavior of geopolymer: insights from in-situ high temperature exposure. <i>Cem. Concr. Compos.</i><b>164</b>, (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, R., Dai, N. &amp; Wang, Z. Thermal and mechanical properties of geopolymers exposed to high temperature: a literature review. <i>Adv. Civ. Eng.</i><b>2020</b>. (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, B., Li, Y. &amp; Li, P. Synergistic effect of blended precursors and silica fume on strength and high temperature resistance of geopolymer. <i>Materials (Basel)</i><b>17</b>, (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11206042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38930345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuaiter, M. et al. Effect of blending GGBS and silica fume on the mechanical properties of geopolymer concrete. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11914085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40097572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukhametkaliyev, T., Ali, M. H., Kutugin, V., Savinova, O. &amp; Vereschagin, V. Influence of mixing order on the synthesis of geopolymer concrete. <i>Polymers (Basel)</i><b>14</b>, (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9656506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36365778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., Zhu, W. &amp; Yang, E. H. Alkali-activated ground granulated blast-furnace slag incorporating incinerator fly Ash as a potential binder. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>112</b>, 1005&#x2013;1012 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.02.153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbas, R., Abdelzaher, M. A., Shehata, N. &amp; Tantawy, M. A. Production, characterization and performance of green geopolymer modified with industrial by-products. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>14</b>, (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10907711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38429487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, B. et al. Effect of geopolymerization reaction on the flexural strength of Kaolin-Based systems. <i>Materials (Basel)</i>. <b>17</b>, (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11122983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38793290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>