<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41650338</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1524-4725</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Dermatologic surgery : official publication for American Society for Dermatologic Surgery [et al.]</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Dermatol Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy and Safety of Sodium Hyaluronate Gel for Facial Skin Rejuvenation.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/DSS.0000000000005042</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Hyaluronic acid (HA) is a cornerstone of aesthetic skin treatments due to its vital role in skin hydration and combating aging signs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This trial evaluated the efficacy and safety of a novel non-cross-linked HA gel for improving skin quality in a Chinese population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this multicenter, randomized, controlled trial, 420 subjects were enrolled (2:1, treatment: control). The treatment group received three full-face intradermal injections of the HA gel at 3-week intervals, whereas the control group received no intervention. Primary end points were blinded evaluations of the Global Aesthetic Improvement Scale and a composite improvement rate for skin dryness/dullness.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The treatment group showed significantly higher Global Aesthetic Improvement Scale improvement (90.63% vs 3.65%) and composite improvement rates (83.20% vs 3.65%) than control group (p &lt; .0001), with effects sustained for 6 months. Skin hydration and elasticity significantly increased from baseline (p &lt; .05). Peak efficacy rates for fine lines and roughness reached 51.59% and 50.00%, respectively. Adverse events were mild and transient, with decreasing incidence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This non-cross-linked HA gel effectively enhances skin hydration, elasticity, and texture with sustained 6-month benefits and a favorable safety profile, supporting its use for facial rejuvenation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 by the American Society for Dermatologic Surgery, Inc. Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liao</LastName><ForeName>Zhifeng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, The Affiliated Guangdong Second Provincial General Hospital of Jinan University, Guangzhou City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hong</LastName><ForeName>Weijin</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, The Affiliated Guangdong Second Provincial General Hospital of Jinan University, Guangzhou City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Shiliang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hyamed Biotechnology (Zhuhai) Co., Ltd., Zhuhai City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hou</LastName><ForeName>Yuxin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hyamed Biotechnology (Zhuhai) Co., Ltd., Zhuhai City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Sha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Sun Yat-sen Memorial Hospital, Sun Yat-sen University, Guangzhou City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Rixin</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Nanyang First People's Hospital, Nanyang City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yingbo</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, The Third Hospital of Changsha, Changsha City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Department of Cosmetic and Plastic Surgery, First Affiliated Hospital of Hunan University of Chinese Medicine, Changsha City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yaling</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology and Plastic Surgery, Third Hospital of Hebei Medical University, Shijiazhuang City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Shengkang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, The Affiliated Guangdong Second Provincial General Hospital of Jinan University, Guangzhou City, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Dermatol Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9504371</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1076-0512</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41650338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/DSS.0000000000005042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00042728-990000000-01557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fink B, Grammer K, Thornhill R. Human (Homo sapiens) facial attractiveness in relation to skin texture and color. J Comp Psychol 2001;115:92&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones AL, Kramer RS, Ward R. Signals of personality and health: the contributions of facial shape, skin texture, and viewing angle. J Exp Psychol Hum Percept Perform 2012;38:1353&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai M, Oru&#xe7; I, Barton JJS. The role of skin texture and facial shape in representations of age and identity. Cortex 2013;49:252&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsankova E, Kappas AJ. Facial skin smoothness as an indicator of perceived trustworthiness and related traits. Perception 2016;45:400&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher GJ, Varani J, Voorhees JJ. Looking older: fibroblast collapse and therapeutic implications. Arch Dermatol 2008;144:666&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trojahn C, Dobos G, Lichterfeld A, Blume-Peytavi U, et al. Characterizing facial skin ageing in humans: disentangling extrinsic from intrinsic biological phenomena. Biomed Res Int 2015;2015:318586.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher GJ, Wang Z, Datta SC, Varani J, et al. Pathophysiology of premature skin aging induced by ultraviolet light. N Engl J Med 1997;337:1419&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callaghan T, Wilhelm KP. A review of ageing and an examination of clinical methods in the assessment of ageing skin. Part 2: clinical perspectives and clinical methods in the evaluation of ageing skin. Int J Cosmet Sci 2008;30:323&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bukhari SN, Roswandi NL, Waqas M, Habib H, et al. Hyaluronic acid, a promising skin rejuvenating biomedicine: A review of recent updates and pre-clinical and clinical investigations on cosmetic and nutricosmetic effects. Int J Biol Macromol 2018;120:1682&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sales AF, Pandolfo IL, de Almeida Cruz M, Parisi JR, et al. Intense pulsed light on skin rejuvenation: a systematic review. Arch Dermatol Res 2021;314:823&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AlKhawam L, Alam M. Dermabrasion and microdermabrasion. Facial Plast Surg 2009;25:301&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alster TS, Graham PM. Microneedling: a review and practical guide. Dermatol Surg 2017;44:397&#x2013;404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connor AA, Lowe PM, Shumack S, Lim AC. Chemical peels: a review of current practice. Australas J Dermatol 2017;59:171&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu WTL. Microbotox of the lower face and neck: evolution of a personal technique and its clinical effects. Plast Reconstr Surg 2015;136:92S&#x2013;100S.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landau M, Fagien S. Science of hyaluronic acid beyond filling: fibroblasts and their response to the extracellular matrix. Plast Reconstr Surg 2015;136:188S&#x2013;95S.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakai S, Yasuda R, Sayo T, Ishikawa O, et al. Hyaluronan exists in the normal stratum corneum. J Invest Dermatol 2000;114:1184&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weindl G, Schaller M, Sch&#xe4;fer-Korting M, Korting HC. Hyaluronic acid in the treatment and prevention of skin diseases: molecular biological, pharmaceutical and clinical aspects. Skin Pharmacol Physiol 2004;17:207&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duranti F, Salti G, Bovani B, Calandra M, et al. Injectable hyaluronic acid gel for soft tissue augmentation. A clinical and histological study. Dermatol Surg 1998;24:1317&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao Z, Ma J, Bu X, Zhang Y, et al. Effectiveness and safety of a hyaluronic acid filler for Chin augmentation and correction of Chin retrusion: a multi-center, prospective. Aesthetic Plast Surg 2025;49:1046&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao Z-F, Yang W, Lin F-C, Wang S-W, et al. A case study: comprehensive approach for treating horizontal neck wrinkles using hyaluronic acid injections and thread-lifting. Aesthetic Plast Surg 2023;47:765&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerscher M, Bayrhammer J, Reuther T. Rejuvenating influence of a stabilized hyaluronic acid&#x2013;based gel of nonanimal origin on facial skin aging. Dermatol Surg 2008;34:720&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Streker M, Reuther T, Krueger N, Kerscher M. Stabilized hyaluronic acid-based gel of non-animal origin for skin rejuvenation: face. J Drugs Dermatol 2013;12:990&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee BM, Han DG, Choi WS. Rejuvenating effects of facial hydrofilling using restylane vital. Arch Plast Surg 2015;42:282&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roh NK, Kim MJ, Lee YW, Choe YB, et al. A split-face study of the effects of a stabilized hyaluronic acid-based gel of nonanimal origin for facial skin rejuvenation using a stamp-type multineedle injector: a randomized clinical trial. Plast Reconstr Surg 2016;137:809&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seok J, Hong JY, Choi SY, Park KY, et al. A potential relationship between skin hydration and stamp-type microneedle intradermal hyaluronic acid injection in middle-aged male face. J Cosmet Dermatol 2016;15:578&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi SY, Ko EJ, Yoo KH, Han HS, et al. Effects of hyaluronic acid injected using the mesogun injector with stamp-type microneedle on skin hydration. Dermatol Ther 2020;33:e13963.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baspeyras M, Rouvrais C, Li&#xe9;gard L, Delalleau A, et al. Clinical and biometrological efficacy of a hyaluronic acid-based mesotherapy product: a randomised controlled study. Arch Dermatol Res 2013;305:673&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niforos F, Ogilvie P, Cavallini M, Leys C, et al. VYC-12 injectable gel is safe and effective for improvement of facial skin topography: a prospective study. Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol 2019;12:791&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanian F, Deutsch J-J, Bousquet MT, Boisnic S, et al. A hyaluronic acid-based micro-filler improves superficial wrinkles and skin quality: a randomized prospective controlled multicenter study. J Dermatolog Treat 2023;34:2216323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iranmanesh B, Khalili M, Mohammadi S, Amiri R, et al. Employing hyaluronic acid-based mesotherapy for facial rejuvenation. J Cosmet Dermatol 2022;21:6605&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Tian Y, Xu J, Zhong S, et al. A randomized study showing improved skin quality and aesthetic appearance of dorsal hands after hyaluronic acid gel treatment in a Chinese population. J Cosmet Dermatol 2020;19:1627&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Aloiso CM, Senzolo M. Efficacy of dermal redensification in chronoaged face: quantitative volumetric assessment. J Cosmet Dermatol 2020;19:199&#x2013;204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Wit A, Siebenga PS, Wijdeveld RW, Koopmans PC. A split-face comparative performance evaluation of injectable hyaluronic acid-based preparations HCC and CPM-HA20G in healthy females. J Cosmet Dermatol 2022;21:5576&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerscher M, Prager W, Fischer TC, Gauglitz GG, et al. Facial skin revitalization with cohesive polydensified Matrix-HA20G: results from a randomized multicenter clinical study. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open 2021;9:e3973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hertz-Kleptow D, Hanschmann A, Hofmann M, Reuther T, et al. Facial skin revitalization with CPM&#xae;-HA20G: an effective and safe early intervention treatment. Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol 2019;12:563&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng H-Y, Chen Y-X, Wang M-F, Zhao J-Y, et al. Evaluation of changes in skin biophysical parameters and appearance after pneumatic injections of non-cross-linked hyaluronic acid in the face. J Cosmet Laser Ther 2018;20:454&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trong HN, Phuong TVT, Van TN, Thai HV, et al. The efficacy and safety of hyaluronic acid microinjection for skin rejuvenation in Vietnam. Open Access Maced J Med Sci 2019;7:234&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cesare B, Roberto C, Giuseppe N, Luca G, et al. Face rejuvenation: a new combinated protocol for biorevitalization. Acta Biomed 2018;89:400&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao Z-F, Yang W, Li X, Wang S-W, et al. Infraorbital rejuvenation combined with thread-lifting and non-cross-linked hyaluronic acid injection: a retrospective, case-series study. Aesthetic Plast Surg 2024;48:1589&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou R, Yu M. The effect of local hyaluronic acid injection on skin aging: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Cosmet Dermatol 2025;24:e16760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryu HS, Joo YH, Kim SO, Park KC, et al. Influence of age and regional differences on skin elasticity as measured by the Cutometer. Skin Res Technol 2008;14:354&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J. Effects of injection depth and volume of stabilized hyaluronic acid in human dermis on skin texture, hydration, and thickness. Arch Aesthetic Plast Surg 2014;20:97&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F, Garza LA, Kang S, Varani J, et al. In vivo stimulation of de novo collagen production caused by cross-linked hyaluronic acid dermal filler injections in photodamaged human skin. Arch Dermatol 2007;143:155&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carruthers J, Donofrio L, Hardas B, Murphy DK, et al. Development and validation of a photonumeric scale for evaluation of facial fine lines. Dermatol Surg 2016;42(Suppl 1):S227&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donofrio L, Carruthers A, Hardas B, Murphy DK, et al. Development and validation of a photonumeric scale for evaluation of facial skin texture. Dermatol Surg 2016;42(Suppl 1):S219&#x2013;S226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raspaldo H, Chantrey J, Belhaouari L, Saleh R, et al. Juv&#xe9;derm volbella with lidocaine for lip and perioral enhancement: a prospective, randomized, controlled trial. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open 2015;3:e321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor SC, Downie JB, Shamban A, Few J, et al. Lip and perioral enhancement with hyaluronic acid dermal fillers in individuals with skin of color. Dermatol Surg 2019;45:959&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>