<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40731015</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1746-6148</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC veterinary research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Vet Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluation of water treadmill training, lunging and treadmill training in the rehabilitation of horses with back pain.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>495</StartPage><MedlinePgn>495</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">495</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12917-025-04950-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Data about efficacy of different training modalities during rehabilitation of horses with back pain is scarce. The aim of this study was to analyze the effect of water treadmill training, lunging and dry treadmill training in horses with back pain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Eighteen warmblood riding horses referred with confirmed clinical signs of back pain including abnormal responses to passive mobilisation were randomized into three groups to participate in a 6-week water treadmill training, lunging or dry treadmill program under otherwise identical conditions. Two clinicians, one blinded to the program, performed a structured clinical examination of the back at three time-points (baseline, week 3, week 6). Mechanical nociceptive thresholds were determined with pressure algometry.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Visual muscle development scores for the lumbar region (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.001) and palpation sensitivity scores along the thoracic and lumbar region significantly improved at week 6, compared to baseline (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001). No differences in mechanical nociceptive thresholds were detected between water treadmill training, lunging and dry treadmill training at any time-point (p&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05). At week 3 and 6 of all programs mechanical nociceptive thresholds significantly increased at the level of the 10th to 18th thoracic (T18) and 3rd lumbar vertebra (L3) compared to baseline.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION/MAIN LIMITATIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Small group size, lack of control group with ridden rehabilitation exercise.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Different training programs without a rider could be beneficial for horses with back pain. Water treadmill training seems equivalent to dry treadmill training and lunging to increase mechanical nociceptive thresholds in the region with main saddle contact.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geiger</LastName><ForeName>Tobias</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinic for Horses, University of Veterinary Medicine Hanover, B&#xfc;nteweg 9, Hannover, 30559, Germany. tobias.geiger@tiho-hannover.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lindenhahn</LastName><ForeName>Liesa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinic for Horses, University of Veterinary Medicine Hanover, B&#xfc;nteweg 9, Hannover, 30559, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tieraerztliche Klinik F&#xfc;r Pferde Wolfesing, Wolfesing, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Delarocque</LastName><ForeName>Julien</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinic for Horses, University of Veterinary Medicine Hanover, B&#xfc;nteweg 9, Hannover, 30559, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geburek</LastName><ForeName>Florian</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinic for Horses, University of Veterinary Medicine Hanover, B&#xfc;nteweg 9, Hannover, 30559, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Vet Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101249759</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1746-6148</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006736" MajorTopicYN="N">Horses</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006734" MajorTopicYN="Y">Horse Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001416" MajorTopicYN="Y">Back Pain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000662" MajorTopicYN="N">veterinary</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010805" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Conditioning, Animal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000662" MajorTopicYN="N">veterinary</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="N">Water</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005080" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Test</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000662" MajorTopicYN="N">veterinary</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Back pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Equine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lunging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pressure algometry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Treadmill training</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study was approved by the ethics committee of the responsible German federal state authority (State Office for Nature-, Environment- and Consumer Protection North Rhine Westphalia, AZ: 81&#x2013;04.13). Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40731015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12305931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12917-025-04950-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12917-025-04950-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Haussler KK. Chiropractic evaluation and management. Veterinary Clinics of North America: Equine Practice. 1999;15(1):195&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10218250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerman M, Dyson S, Murray R. Close, impinging and overriding spinous processes in the thoracolumbar spine: The relationship between radiological and scintigraphic findings and clinical signs. Equine Vet J. 2012;44(2):178&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21880062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen AK, et al. How to diagnose and treat back pain in the horse. AAEP Proceedings. 2010;56:384&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riccio B, Fraschetto C, Villanueva J, Cantatore F, Bertuglia A. Two multicenter surveys on equine back-pain 10 years a part. Frontiers in veterinary science. 2018;5:195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6115529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30191152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall-Gibson ME, Durham MG, Seabaugh KA, Moorman VJ, Ferris DJ. Survey of equine veterinarians regarding primary equine back pain in the United States. Frontiers in Veterinary Science. 2023;10:1224605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10411723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37565081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krabak B, Kennedy DJ. Functional rehabilitation of lumbar spine injuries in the athlete. Sports Med Arthrosc Rev. 2008;16(1):47&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18277262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGill SM. Low back exercises: evidence for improving exercise regimens. Phys Ther. 1998;78(7):754&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9672547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nankervis KJ, Launder EJ, Murray RC. The use of treadmills within the rehabilitation of horses. J Equine Vet. 2017;53:108&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cottriall S, Ritruechai P, Wakeling JM. The effects of training aids on the longissimus dorsi in the equine back. Comparative Exercise Physiology. 2008;5(3&#x2013;4):111&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siqueira R, Teixeira M, Perez F, Gulart L. Effect of lunging exercise program with Pessoa training aid on cardiac physical conditioning predictors in adult horses. Arquivo Brasileiro de Medicina Veterin&#xe1;ria e Zootecnia. 2023;75:545&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfau T, Simons V, Rombach N, Stubbs N, Weller R. Effect of a 4-week elastic resistance band training regimen on back kinematics in horses trotting in-hand and on the lunge. Equine Vet J. 2017;49(6):829&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28432739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw K, Ursini T, Levine D, Richards J, Adair S. The effect of ground poles and elastic resistance bands on longissimus dorsi and rectus abdominus muscle activity during equine walk and trot. J Equine Vet. 2021;107: 103772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34802619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown S, Tabor G, Williams J. The effect of trot pole exercise on rectus abdominus activity in the horse. Journal of Veterinary Behavior. 2019;29:155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker VA, Tranquillle CA, MacKechnie-Guire R, Spear J, Newton R, Murray RC. Effect of ground and raised Poles on kinematics of the walk. J Equine Vet. 2022;115: 104005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35533803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daglish J, Mama KR. Pain: its diagnosis and management in the rehabilitation of horses. Veterinary Clinics: Equine Practice. 2016;32(1):13&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27012506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabor G, Nankervis K, Fernandes J, Williams J. Generation of domains for the equine musculoskeletal rehabilitation outcome score: Development by expert consensus. Animals. 2020;10(2):203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7070405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31991716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakeling JM, Ritruechai P, Dalton S, Nankervis K. Segmental variation in the activity and function of the equine longissimus dorsi muscle during walk and trot. Equine and Comparative Exercise Physiology. 2007;4(2):95&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mooij M, Jans W, Den Heijer G, De Pater M, Back W. Biomechanical responses of the back of riding horses to water treadmill exercise. Vet J. 2013;198:e120&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24360735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray RC, Hopkins E, Tracey JB, Nankervis K, Deckers I, Mackechnie-Guire R et al.. Change in muscle development of horses undergoing 20 weeks of water treadmill exercise compared with control horses. 2020. Abstract from British Equine Veterinary Association Congress 2020. 10.1111/evj.09_13365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nankervis K, Tranquille C, McCrae P, York J, Lashley M, Baumann M, et al. Consensus for the general use of equine water treadmills for healthy horses. Animals. 2021;11(2):305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7912478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33530300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tranquille C, Tacey J, Walker V, Mackechnie-Guire R, Ellis J, Nankervis K, et al. Effect of Water Depth on Limb and Back Kinematics in Horses Walking on a Water Treadmill. J Equine Vet. 2022;115: 104025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35649493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nankervis K, Tranquille C, Tacey J, Deckers I, MacKechnie-Guire R, Walker V, et al. Kinematic Responses to Water Treadmill Exercise When Used Regularly within a Sport Horse Training Programme: A Longitudinal, Observational Study. Animals. 2024;14(16):2393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11350662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39199927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfau T, Stubbs NC, Kaiser LJ, Brown LE, Clayton HM. Effect of trotting speed and circle radius on movement symmetry in horses during lunging on a soft surface. Am J Vet Res. 2012;73(12):1890&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23176414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabor G. Veterinary physiotherapy for back pain in the horse. UK-Vet Equine. 2022;6(4):168&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starke SD, Witte TH, May SA, Pfau T. Accuracy and precision of hind limb foot contact timings of horses determined using a pelvis-mounted inertial measurement unit. J Biomech. 2012;45(8):1522&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22483227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clayton HM. Core training and rehabilitation in horses. Veterinary Clinics: Equine Practice. 2016;32(1):49&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27012507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown S, Stubbs N, Kaiser L, Lavagnino M, Clayton H. Swing phase kinematics of horses trotting over poles. Equine Vet J. 2015;47(1):107&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24593249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacKechnie-Guire R, Pfau T. Differential rotational movement and symmetry values of the thoracolumbosacral region in high-level dressage horses when trotting. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(5): e0251144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8101941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33956858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaneps AJ. Practical rehabilitation and physical therapy for the general equine practitioner. Veterinary Clinics: Equine Practice. 2016;32(1):167&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26898959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabor G, Williams J. Equine rehabilitation: a review of trunk and hind limb muscle activity and exercise selection. J Equine Vet. 2018;60(97&#x2013;103): e3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Mee&#xfb;s DC, Boshuizen B, Oosterlinck M, van de Winkel D, De Spiegelaere W, de Bruijn CM, et al. Flexibility of equine bioenergetics and muscle plasticity in response to different types of training: An integrative approach, questioning existing paradigms. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(4): e0249922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8043414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33848308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindner A, W&#xe4;schle S, Sasse H. Physiological and blood biochemical variables in horses exercising on a treadmill submerged in water. J Anim Physiol Anim Nutr. 2012;96(4):563&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21692872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott R, Nankervis K, Stringer C, Westcott K, Marlin D. The effect of water height on stride frequency, stride length and heart rate during water treadmill exercise. Equine Vet J. 2010;42:662&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21059077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnicoat F, Wills A. Effect of water depth on limb kinematics of the domestic dog (Canis lupus familiaris) during underwater treadmill exercise. Comparative Exercise Physiology. 2016;12(4):199&#x2013;207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkinson S, Wills A, Tabor G, Williams J. Effect of water depth on muscle activity of dogs when walking on a water treadmill. Comparative Exercise Physiology. 2018;14(2):79&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkurdi W, Paul DR, Sadowski K, Dolny DG. The effect of water depth on energy expenditure and perception of effort in female subjects while walking. International Journal of Aquatic Research and Education. 2010;4(1):7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrae P, Bradley M, Rolian C, L&#xe9;guillette R. Water height modifies forelimb kinematics of horses during water treadmill exercise. Comparative Exercise Physiology. 2021;17(1):91&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendez-Angulo JL, Firshman AM, Groschen DM, Kieffer PJ, Trumble TN. Effect of water depth on amount of flexion and extension of joints of the distal aspects of the limbs in healthy horses walking on an underwater treadmill. Am J Vet Res. 2013;74(4):557&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23531063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nankervis K, Finney P, Launder L. Water depth modifies back kinematics of horses during water treadmill exercise. Equine Vet J. 2016;48(6):732&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26502104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King MR, Haussler KK, Kawcak CE, McIlwraith CW, Reiser RF II. Effect of underwater treadmill exercise on postural sway in horses with experimentally induced carpal joint osteoarthritis. Am J Vet Res. 2013;74(7):971&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23802668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prins J, Cutner D. Aquatic therapy in the rehabilitation of athletic injuries. Clin Sports Med. 1999;18(2):447&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10230578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng MS, Wang R, Wang YZ, Chen CC, Wang J, Liu XC, et al. Efficacy of therapeutic aquatic exercise vs physical therapy modalities for patients with chronic low back pain: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Network Open. 2022;5(1):e2142069-e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8742191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34994794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dundar U, Solak O, Yigit I, Evcik D, Kavuncu V. Clinical effectiveness of aquatic exercise to treat chronic low back pain: a randomized controlled trial. Spine&#xa0;(Phila Pa 1976). 2009;34(14):1436&#x2013;40. 10.1097/BRS.0b013e3181a79618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19525833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edinger J, Wissdorf H, Gerhards H, Huskamp B, Deegen E. Orthop&#xe4;dische Untersuchung der Gliedma&#xdf;en und der Wirbels&#xe4;ule. Praxisorientierte Anatomie und Prop&#xe4;deutik des Pferdes Hannover: M u H Schaper. 2010;890:926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvarez CG, Rhodin M, Bobbert MF, Meyer H, Weishaupt MA, Johnston C, et al. The effect of head and neck position on the thoracolumbar kinematics in the unridden horse. Equine Vet J. 2006;38(S36):445&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17402464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeffcott L. (2) The Diagnosis of Diseases of the Horse&#x2019;s Back. Equine Vet J. 1975;7(2):69&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">124654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keegan K, editor The Lameness Locator (wireless inertial sensors for detection of lameness in horses). Proceedings of the Congress of the European Society of Veterinary Orthopaedics and Traumatology, Bologna, Italy. 2010;215-217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haussler K, Erb H. Pressure algometry for the detection of induced back pain in horses: a preliminary study. Equine Vet J. 2006;38(1):76&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16411591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varcoe-Cocks K, Sagar K, Jeffcott L, McGowan C. Pressure algometry to quantify muscle pain in racehorses with suspected sacroiliac dysfunction. Equine Vet J. 2006;38(6):558&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17124847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing, Vienna. 2022; https://www.R-project.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen R. Regression Models for Ordinal Data. https://github.com/runehaubo/ordinal2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singmann, H., Bolker, B. and Westfall, J. Afex: Analysis of Factorial Experiments. R Package Version 0.15-2. 2015. http://CRAN.R-project.org/package=afex.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenth, R.V. Emmeans: Estimated Marginal Means, Aka Least-Squares Means. 2021. https://cran.r-project.org/package=emmeans.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendall MG. The treatment of ties in ranking problems. Biometrika. 1945;33(3):239&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21006841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulekas R, Haussler KK. Principles and practice of therapeutic exercise for horses. J Equine Vet. 2009;29(12):870&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denoix J, Pailloux J. Anatomy and basic biomechanical concepts. Physical Therapy and Massage for the Horse, 2nd ed; Trafalgar Square Publishing: North Pomfret, VT, USA. 2001:19&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robert C, Audigi&#xe9; F, Valette J, Pourcelot P, Denoix JM. Effects of treadmill speed on the mechanics of the back in the trotting saddlehorse. Equine Vet J. 2001;33(S33):154&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11721558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolschrijn C, Audigi&#xe9; F, Wijnberg ID, Johnston C, Denoix J-M. The neck and back. Equine locomotion. 2013; 2nd Edition: 216-23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fair N, Blake S, Blake R. Four Weeks of Incline Water Treadmill Exercise Can Contribute to Increase Epaxial Muscle Profile in Horses. Vet Med Int. 2023;2023:9090406. 10.1155/2023/9090406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10645497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38023427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ursini T, Shaw K, Levine D, Richards J, Adair HS. Electromyography of the multifidus muscle in horses trotting during therapeutic exercises. Frontiers in Veterinary Science. 2022;9: 844776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9184818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35692292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller-Quirin J, Dittmann MT, Roepstorff C, Arpagaus S, Latif SN, Weishaupt MA. Riding soundness&#x2014;comparison of subjective with objective lameness assessments of owner-sound horses at trot on a treadmill. J Equine Vet. 2020;95: 103314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33276930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller-Quirin J, Latif S. &#xa0;Sattelpassform zwischen Wissenschaft und &#xdc;berlieferung. pferde spiegel. 2020;23(01):3&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin P, Cheze L, Pourcelot P, Desquilbet L, Duray L, Chateau H. Effect of the rider position during rising trot on the horse&#x5f3; s biomechanics (back and trunk kinematics and pressure under the saddle). J Biomech. 2016;49(7):1027&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26947029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wennerstrand J, Johnston C, Roethlisberger-Holm K, Erichsen C, Eksell P, Drevemo S. Kinematic evaluation of the back in the sport horse with back pain. Equine Vet J. 2004;36(8):707&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15656501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haussler KK. Pressure algometry for the detection of mechanical nociceptive thresholds in horses. Animals. 2020;10(12):2195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7760268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33255216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyson S, Berger J, Ellis AD, Mullard J. Development of an ethogram for a pain scoring system in ridden horses and its application to determine the presence of musculoskeletal pain. Journal of Veterinary Behavior. 2018;23:47&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleerup KB, Forkman B, Lindegaard C, Andersen PH. An equine pain face. Veterinary Anaesth Analg. 2015;42(1):103&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4312484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25082060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvarez CG, Bobbert M, Lamers L, Johnston C, Back W, Van Weeren P. The effect of induced hindlimb lameness on thoracolumbar kinematics during treadmill locomotion. Equine Vet J. 2008;40(2):147&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18089465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kallerud AS, Marques-Smith P, Bendiksen HK, Fjordbakk CT. Objective movement asymmetry in horses is comparable between markerless technology and sensor-based systems. Equine Vet J. 2025;57(1):115&#x2013;25. 10.1111/evj.14089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11616950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38566453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawin FJ, Bystr&#xf6;m A, Roepstorff C, Rhodin M, Alml&#xf6;f M, Silva M, et al. Is Markerless More or Less? Comparing a Smartphone Computer Vision Method for Equine Lameness Assessment to Multi-Camera Motion Capture. Animals. 2023;13(3):390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9913208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36766279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heim C, Pfau T, Gerber V, Schweizer C, Doherr M, Sch&#xfc;pbach-Regula G, et al. Determination of vertebral range of motion using inertial measurement units in 27 Franches-Montagnes stallions and comparison between conditions and with a mixed population. Equine Vet J. 2016;48(4):509&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25919410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardeman A, Bystr&#xf6;m A, Roepstorff L, Swagemakers J, Van Weeren P, Serra BF. Range of motion and between-measurement variation of spinal kinematics in sound horses at trot on the straight line and on the lunge. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(2): e0222822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7041811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32097432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>