<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40151753</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ventricular Arrhythmias Caused by Left Main Coronary Artery Vasospasm: A Diagnostic Challenge in a Cardiac Arrest Victim.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e79554</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e79554</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e79554</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.79554</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sudden cardiac death (SCD) is a common cause of&#xa0;cardiovascular deaths. It may be caused by primary electrical diseases, cardiomyopathies, myocarditis, valvular heart diseases, or coronary artery disease (including acute coronary syndrome). Coronary artery vasospasm is defined as a transient total or subtotal coronary artery obstruction, associated with angina symptoms and ischemic findings on electrocardiogram (ECG). It is a cause of myocardial infarction, life-threatening arrhythmias, atrioventricular block, and SCD. A 55-year-old man presented to the hospital after an out-of-hospital cardiac arrest (OHCA). He had a previous history of cardiovascular risk factors, excessive alcohol intake,&#xa0;non-obstructive coronary artery disease, and paroxysmic atrial fibrillation. On the day of the OHCA, he had a sudden collapse while exercising, with ventricular fibrillation&#xa0;and return of spontaneous circulation (ROSC) after advanced life support (ALS). No ECG or echocardiographic anomalies were identified on hospital admission. The patient suffered three more episodes of cardiac arrest during the hospital stay, with atypical arrhythmic presentations.&#xa0;No ECG or echocardiographic abnormalities were observed after ROSC. The fourth cardiac arrest had concomitant segmental ST changes and de novoechocardiographic segmental motility abnormalities suggestive of left main coronary artery occlusion. These findings were transient, with a normal ECG and echocardiogram obtained one hour after ROSC. No electrolyte abnormalities or other causes of cardiac arrest were identified. The hypothesis of left main coronary vasospasm was raised as the likely diagnosis. Coronary artery vasospasm is a possible cause of major cardiac events. Diagnosis can be challenging due to the transient findings and varied manifestations, often in patients with normal coronary arteries. The correct diagnosis and treatment of coronary artery vasospasm can have a determinant effect on prognosis and mortality, as appropriate treatment&#xa0;can lead to prolonged event-free survival. Provocative coronary vasospasm tests performed in patients with atypical cardiovascular manifestations can allow for the timely diagnosis of vasospasm and avoid critical events. The authors aim to raise awareness of the different clinical presentations of coronary artery vasospasm and its consequences. The performance of provocative tests in selected patients should be considered to promote early diagnosis and potentially avoid major events.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Carqueja et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carqueja</LastName><ForeName>In&#xea;s</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Intensive Care Unit, Hospital Pedro Hispano, Matosinhos, PRT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Montenegro S&#xe1;</LastName><ForeName>Fernando</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology Service, Department of Medicine, Hospital Pedro Hispano, Matosinhos, PRT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Monteiro</LastName><ForeName>Sofia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Intensive Care Unit, Hospital Pedro Hispano, Matosinhos, PRT.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiac dysrhythmia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">coronary artery vasospasm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">out-of-hospital cardiac arrest</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-resuscitation care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sudden cardiac death (scd)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: Fernando Montenegro S&#xe1; declare(s) personal fees from Medtronic. He is an undisclosed consultant. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40151753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11947499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.79554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Public health burden of sudden cardiac death in the United States. Stecker EC, Reinier K, Marijon E, et al. Circ Arrhythm Electrophysiol. 2014;7:212&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4041478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24610738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudden cardiac death caused by coronary heart disease. Myerburg RJ, Junttila MJ. Circulation. 2012;125:1043&#x2013;1052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22371442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2022 ESC guidelines for the management of patients with ventricular arrhythmias and the prevention of sudden cardiac death. Zeppenfeld K, Tfelt-Hansen J, de Riva M, et al. Eur Heart J. 2022;43:3997&#x2013;4126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36477551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Temporal trends in coronary heart disease mortality and sudden cardiac death from 1950 to 1999: the Framingham Heart Study. Fox CS, Evans JC, Larson MG, Kannel WB, Levy D. Circulation. 2004;110:522&#x2013;527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15262842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemiology of sudden cardiac death: global and regional perspectives. Wong CX, Brown A, Lau DH, Chugh SS, Albert CM, Kalman JM, Sanders P. Heart Lung Circ. 2019;28:6&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30482683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International standardization of diagnostic criteria for vasospastic angina. Beltrame JF, Crea F, Kaski JC, et al. Eur Heart J. 2017;38:2565&#x2013;2568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26245334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angina pectoris I. A variant form of angina pectoris. Prinzmetal M, Kennamer R, Merliss R, Wada T, Bor N. Am J Med. 1959;27:375&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14434946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasospastic angina: a literature review of current evidence. Picard F, Sayah N, Spagnoli V, Adjedj J, Varenne O. Arch Cardiovasc Dis. 2019;112:44&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30197243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Variant angina and coronary artery spasm: the clinical spectrum, pathophysiology, and management. Kusama Y, Kodani E, Nakagomi A, Otsuka T, Atarashi H, Kishida H, Mizuno K. J Nippon Med Sch. 2011;78:4&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21389642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Left main coronary spasm: an extremely rare entity with possible life-threatening complications. Al Emam A, Sricharoen N. Int J Angiol. 2016;25:0&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5186305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28031683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overview of the pharmacological spasm provocation test: comparisons between acetylcholine and ergonovine. Sueda S, Kohno H, Ochi T, Uraoka T, Tsunemitsu K. J Cardiol. 2017;69:57&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27856130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coronary vasospasm-related sudden cardiac arrest in the community. Waldmann V, Bougouin W, Karam N, et al. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2018;72:814&#x2013;815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30092958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Resuscitation Council and European Society of Intensive Care Medicine guidelines 2021: post-resuscitation care. Nolan JP, Sandroni C, B&#xf6;ttiger BW, et al. Intensive Care Med. 2021;47:369&#x2013;421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7993077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33765189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Left main coronary artery spasm. Rumoroso JR, Inguanzo R, Cembellin JC, Bodegas A, Barrenetxea JI. Int J Cardiol. 1995;51:202&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8522418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coronary vasospasm presenting in a catastrophic way. Wong KT, Tam CF, Chung TS, Lau TA, Wong SF. JACC Case Rep. 2024;29:102554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11442284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39359978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinus node dysfunction during coronary vasospastic angina. Bashour TT, Kabbani SS, Brewster HP, Wald SH, Hanna ES, Cheng TO. Am Heart J. 1984;108:1056&#x2013;1059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6485993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exertional syncope caused by left main coronary artery spasm. Havranek EP, Dunbar DN. Am Heart J. 1992;123:792&#x2013;794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1539534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atrio-ventricular block and ventricular tacchycardia induced by severe coronary spasm. Dawson D, Wistow TE. Int J Cardiol. 2004;97:319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15458705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical characteristics and long-term prognosis of vasospastic angina patients who survived out-of-hospital cardiac arrest: multicenter registry study of the Japanese Coronary Spasm Association. Takagi Y, Yasuda S, Tsunoda R, et al. Circ Arrhythm Electrophysiol. 2011;4:295&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21406685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>