<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39927814</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-5598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of hypertension</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hypertens</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy and safety of sacubitril-valsartan in hypertension patients with end-stage kidney disease on maintenance dialysis: a meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>557</StartPage><EndPage>567</EndPage><MedlinePgn>557-567</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/HJH.0000000000003972</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The aim of this meta-analysis was to assess the efficacy and safety of sacubitril-valsartan in hypertension patients with end-stage kidney disease (ESKD) undergoing dialysis. We searched the Medline, Cochrane, Embase, Web of Science, and ClinicalTrials.gov databases for studies reporting outcomes after SV treatment. All analyses were performed utilizing the random effects models. Nineteen studies comprising 1597 patients with concomitant hypertension and ESKD undergoing dialysis were included. After sacubitril-valsartan treatment, significant reductions in both SBP and DBP were observed (mean change in SBP: -11.09&#x200a;mmHg [95% confidence interval, 95% CI: -14.51,-7.66] and DBP: -4.37&#x200a;mmHg [-6.36,-2.38]). Compared to conventional treatment, patients treated with sacubitril-valsartan had a lower risk of cardiovascular hospitalization (risk ratio: 0.63 [0.44,0.90]). Sacubitril-valsartan treatment showed a trend toward reducing the risk of all-cause mortality, although this was not statistically significant (risk ratio: 0.66 [0.27,1.60]). Evaluation of echocardiographic parameters among studies including hypertension patients with heart failure indicated that SV improved LVEF (mean change: +7.04%[+3.19, +10.90]), however this effect was more pronounced in the HFrEF patients ( Pinteraction =0.0003). Sacubitril-valsartan also reduced LVSd, LVDd, LAD, and E/e' ratio ( P &#x200a;&lt;&#x200a;0.05). The risks of severe hyperkalemia and symptomatic hypotension were comparable between sacubitril-valsartan treatment and conventional treatment ( P &#x200a;&gt;&#x200a;0.05). The present study revealed that sacubitril-valsartan treatment is well tolerated and could have potential benefits in hypertension patients with ESKD on dialysis by effectively controlling blood pressure, improving LVEF, reversing cardiac remodeling, and reducing the risk of cardiovascular hospitalization.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nguyen</LastName><ForeName>Dung Viet</ForeName><Initials>DV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, VNU University of Medicine and Pharmacy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pham</LastName><ForeName>Giang Thai</ForeName><Initials>GT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, 108 Military Central Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pham</LastName><ForeName>Son Nguyen</ForeName><Initials>SN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, 108 Military Central Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nguyen</LastName><ForeName>Hoai Thi Thu</ForeName><Initials>HTT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, VNU University of Medicine and Pharmacy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vietnam National Heart Institute, Bach Mai Hospital, Hanoi, Vietnam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>J Hypertens</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8306882</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0263-6352</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000613">Aminobutyrates</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>WB8FT61183</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C549068">sacubitril and valsartan sodium hydrate drug combination</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001713">Biphenyl Compounds</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004338">Drug Combinations</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>80M03YXJ7I</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000068756">Valsartan</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013777">Tetrazoles</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D057911">Angiotensin Receptor Antagonists</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000613" MajorTopicYN="Y">Aminobutyrates</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001713" MajorTopicYN="N">Biphenyl Compounds</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004338" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Combinations</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006973" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hypertension</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007676" MajorTopicYN="Y">Kidney Failure, Chronic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068756" MajorTopicYN="N">Valsartan</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006435" MajorTopicYN="Y">Renal Dialysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013777" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tetrazoles</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057911" MajorTopicYN="Y">Angiotensin Receptor Antagonists</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39927814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HJH.0000000000003972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00004872-990000000-00619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Thurlow JS, Joshi M, Yan G, Norris KC, Agodoa LY, Yuan CM, et al. Global epidemiology of end-stage kidney disease and disparities in kidney replacement therapy. Am J Nephrol 2021; 52:98&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B, Wang GH, Ding XX, Tang HX, Zheng J, Liu BC, et al. Effects of Sacubitril/Valsartan on resistant hypertension and myocardial work in hemodialysis patients. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 2022; 24:300&#x2013;308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgianos PI, Agarwal R. Resistant hypertension in dialysis: epidemiology, diagnosis, and management. J Am Soc Nephrol 2024; 35:505&#x2013;514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwashima Y, Fukushima H, Horio T, Rai T, Ishimitsu T. Efficacy and safety of sacubitril/valsartan after switching from azilsartan in hemodialysis patients with hypertension. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 2023; 25:304&#x2013;308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan MS, Ahmed A, Greene SJ, Fiuzat M, Kittleson MM, Butler J, et al. Managing heart failure in patients on dialysis: state-of-the-art review. J Card Fail 2023; 29:87&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Izzo JL Jr, Zappe DH, Jia Y, Hafeez K, Zhang J. Efficacy and safety of crystalline valsartan/sacubitril (LCZ696) compared with placebo and combinations of free valsartan and sacubitril in patients with systolic hypertension: the RATIO Study. J Cardiovasc Pharmacol 2017; 69:374&#x2013;381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Supasyndh O, Sun N, Kario K, Hafeez K, Zhang J. Long-term (52-week) safety and efficacy of Sacubitril/valsartan in Asian patients with hypertension. Hypertens Res 2017; 40:472&#x2013;476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rakugi H, Kario K, Yamaguchi M, Sasajima T, Gotou H, Zhang J. Efficacy of sacubitril/valsartan versus olmesartan in Japanese patients with essential hypertension: a randomized, double-blind, multicenter study. Hypertens Res 2022; 45:824&#x2013;833.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho IJ, Kang SM. Angiotensin receptor-neprilysin inhibitor in patients with heart failure and chronic kidney disease. Kidney Res Clin Pract 2021; 40:555&#x2013;565.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stroup DF, Berlin JA, Morton SC, Olkin I, Williamson GD, Rennie D, et al. Meta-analysis of observational studies in epidemiology: a proposal for reporting. JAMA 2000; 283:2008&#x2013;2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liberati A, Altman DG, Tetzlaff J, Mulrow C, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Ioannidis JPA, et al. The PRISMA statement for reporting systematic reviews and meta-analyses of studies that evaluate healthcare interventions: explanation and elaboration. BMJ 2009; 339:b2700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JAC, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Blencowe NS, Boutron I, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ 2019; 366:l4898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Hern&#xe1;n MA, Reeves BC, Savovi&#x107; J, Berkman ND, Viswanathan M, et al. ROBINS-I: a tool for assessing risk of bias in nonrandomised studies of interventions. BMJ 2016; 355:i4919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT TJ, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA, editors. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. Chichester (UK): John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ 2003; 327:557&#x2013;560.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duval S, Tweedie R. Trim and fill: a simple funnel-plot&#x2013;based method of testing and adjusting for publication bias in meta-analysis. Biometrics 2000; 56:455&#x2013;463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen N, Li X, Lin L. Effects of sacubitril/valsartan on hypertension in patients with CKD Stage 5D: PUB368. J Am Soc Nephrol 2022; 33:986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabido R, Cesar SR, Gerardo BE, Lucio SJP. Efficacy and safety of sacubitril-valsartan in heart failure with reduced ejection fraction in end-stage renal patients. Heart Failure Congress 2023 Prague, Czech Republic: Heart Failure Association of the ESC 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mario Galvan Ruiz M, Fernandez De Sanmamed Giron M, Lopez Perez M, Groba Marco M, Singh M, Martin Bou E, et al. Experience of using sacubitril-valsartan in dialysis patients. Eur J Heart Fail 2021; 23:119&#x2013;120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santhakumari SY. Effectiveness of sacubitril-valsartan in the treatment of heart failure in ESKD patients on maintenance hemodialysis. J Am Soc Nephrol 2019; 30:1098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu CY, Yang SF, Ou SM, Wu CH, Huang PH, Hung CL, et al. Sacubitril/valsartan in patients with heart failure and concomitant end-stage kidney disease. J Am Heart Assoc 2022; 11:e026407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y, Ren M, Wang T, Wang Y, Pu T, Li X, et al. Effects of sacubitril/valsartan in ESRD patients undergoing hemodialysis with HFpEF. Front Cardiovasc Med 2022; 9:955780.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F, Zhang T, Yang S, Wang D, Zhuo Q, Qin X, et al. Sacubitril-valsartan increases ultrafiltration in patients undergoing peritoneal dialysis: a short-term retrospective self-controlled study. Front Med (Lausanne) 2022; 9:831541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao C, Guo Y, Wang Y, Wang L, Yu L, Liang Y, et al. The efficacy and safety of Sacubitril/Valsartan on pulmonary hypertension in hemodialysis patients. Front Med (Lausanne) 2022; 9:1055330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y, Wan L, Zhang ZC, Yang QH, Ding JX, Qu Z, et al. Effects of sacubitril-valsartan in patients undergoing maintenance dialysis. Ren Fail 2023; 45:2222841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Y, Jin Y, Xue H, Liu R, Zhang M, Liao R, et al. Pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of sacubitril/valsartan in peritoneal dialysis patients. Nephrol Dial Transplant 2023; 38:1880&#x2013;1889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishikawa R, Ishiyama K, Yabana I, Hirose T, Sato T, Matsumoto K, et al. Antihypertensive effect of angiontensin receptor-neprilysin inhibition in peritoneal dialysis patients. J Hypertens 2023; 41:e354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuwae N. Functional changes in the heart after sacubitril/valsartan use in 5 hemodialysis patients with hypertension. Case report. CEN Case Rep 2023; 13:233&#x2013;239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Huang L, Tse G, Liu T, Che J. Effects of sacubitril-valsartan in the treatment of chronic heart failure patients with end-stage renal disease undergoing dialysis. Clin Cardiol 2023; 46:930&#x2013;936.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu N, Lv N, Chen Y. Treatment with sacubitril/valsartan effectively manages hypertension and ameliorates left ventricular hypertrophy in hemodialysis patients. Blood Purif 2024; 53:657&#x2013;664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang XM, Li JJ, Yin W, Fu HL, Yu F, Gu LQ, et al. Effect of sacubitril valsartan on heart failure with mid-range or preserved ejection fraction in patients on maintenance hemodialysis: real-world experience in a single-center, prospective study. BMC Cardiovasc Disord 2024; 24:79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mima A, Gotoda H, Lee S, Lee R, Murakami A, Akai R, et al. Effect of sacubitril/valsartan on patients having heart failure with preserved left ventricular ejection fraction undergoing hemodialysis: a long-term observational study. In Vivo 2024; 38:1266&#x2013;1270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao Z, Wang P, Fu Q, Song Q, Liu A, Li H, et al. Efficacy and safety of sacubitril/valsartan in hemodialysis patients with chronic heart failure: a retrospective study at a single center. Med Sci Monit 2024; 30:e943529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMurray JJ, Packer M, Desai AS, Gong J, Lefkowitz MP, Rizkala AR, et al. Angiotensin-neprilysin inhibition versus enalapril in heart failure. N Engl J Med 2014; 371:993&#x2013;1004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velazquez EJ, Morrow DA, DeVore AD, Duffy CI, Ambrosy AP, McCague K, et al. Angiotensin-neprilysin inhibition in acute decompensated heart failure. N Engl J Med 2019; 380:539&#x2013;548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonagh TA, Metra M, Adamo M, Gardner RS, Baumbach A, B&#xf6;hm M, et al. 2021 ESC Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure. Eur Heart J 2021; 42:3599&#x2013;3726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heidenreich PA, Bozkurt B, Aguilar D, Allen LA, Byun JJ, Colvin MM, et al. 2022&#x200a;AHA/ACC/HFSA Guideline for the Management of Heart Failure: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Circulation 2022; 145:e895&#x2013;e1032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson AM, Jhund PS, Anand IS, D&#xfc;ngen HD, Lam CSP, Lefkowitz MP, et al. Sacubitril-valsartan as a treatment for apparent resistant hypertension in patients with heart failure and preserved ejection fraction. Eur Heart J 2021; 42:3741&#x2013;3752.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng Y, Ma X, Liu Y, Yang X, Sun F. Study on the efficacy of Sacubitril/Valsartan in patients with heart failure with preserved ejection fraction undergoing peritoneal dialysis. Cardiology 2023; 148:385&#x2013;394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le D, Grams ME, Coresh J, Shin JI. Sacubitril-valsartan in patients requiring hemodialysis. JAMA Netw Open 2024; 7:e2429237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucharles SGE, Wallbach KKS, Moraes TP, Pecoits-Filho R. Hypertension in patients on dialysis: diagnosis, mechanisms, and management. J Bras Nefrol 2019; 41:400&#x2013;411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rangaswami J, McCullough PA. Heart failure in end-stage kidney disease: pathophysiology, diagnosis, and therapeutic strategies. Semin Nephrol 2018; 38:600&#x2013;617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Oh J, Kim H, Ha J, Chun KH, Lee CJ, et al. Sacubitril/valsartan in patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction with end-stage of renal disease. ESC Heart Fail 2020; 7:1125&#x2013;1129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lihua W, Cheng L, Chen H, Wei F, Jiang A. Use of angiotensin receptor neprilysin inhibitor in patients on maintenance hemodialysis with reduced cardiac ejection fraction, real-world experience from a single center. Iran J Kidney Dis 2021; 15:288&#x2013;299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang HY, Lin CC, Chao CJ, Lin YC, Wang YC, Liao CT, et al. Real-world experience of angiotensin receptor-neprilysin inhibition in reduced ejection fraction heart failure patients with advanced kidney disease. Mayo Clin Proc 2023; 98:88&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin WY, Shao YJ, Chiang AF, Huang CC, Chiang KF, Chan CS, et al. Long-term outcomes of sacubitril/valsartan in heart failure with reduced ejection fraction and coexisting end-stage renal disease. Clin Pharmacol Ther 2024; 116:471&#x2013;477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma JW, Ren LL, Huang JC, Bao SZ, Dai LL, Ying J, et al. [Efficacy of sacubitril/valsartan in peritoneal dialysis patients with HFpEF and its effect on residual renal function]. Zhonghua Yi Xue Za Zhi 2023; 103:117&#x2013;124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bavishi C, Messerli FH, Kadosh B, Ruilope LM, Kario K. Role of neprilysin inhibitor combinations in hypertension: insights from hypertension and heart failure trials. Eur Heart J 2015; 36:1967&#x2013;1973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadic M, Cuspidi C. Sacubitril/valsartan in the treatment of resistant hypertension: raising star or illusion? J Clin Med 2022; 11:3081.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Judge PK, Herrington WG, Haynes R. Sacubitril/valsartan in peritoneal dialysis-lessons from a pharmacokinetic study. Nephrol Dial Transplant 2023; 38:1780&#x2013;1781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayalasomayajula S, Langenickel T, Pal P, Boggarapu S, Sunkara G. Clinical pharmacokinetics of Sacubitril/Valsartan (LCZ696): a novel angiotensin receptor-neprilysin inhibitor. Clin Pharmacokinet 2017; 56:1461&#x2013;1478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirata S, Kadowaki D. Appropriate drug dosing in patients receiving peritoneal dialysis. Contrib Nephrol 2012; 177:30&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Z, Wang X, Zhang L, Apaer R, Xu L, Ma J, et al. Pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of Sacubitril/Valsartan in maintenance hemodialysis patients with heart failure. Blood Purif 2022; 51:270&#x2013;279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan L, Lyu X, Yang X, Zhao Z, Tang Y, Chen Y, et al. Application of angiotensin receptor-neprilysin inhibitor in chronic kidney disease patients: Chinese Expert Consensus. Front Med (Lausanne) 2022; 9:877237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haynes R, Judge PK, Staplin N, Herrington WG, Storey BC, Bethel A, et al. Effects of Sacubitril/Valsartan versus irbesartan in patients with chronic kidney disease. Circulation 2018; 138:1505&#x2013;1514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Ma F, Wang Y, Zhao H, Gao J. Incidence of hyperkalemia in anuric hemodialysis patients treated with sacubitril/valsartan. Hemodial Int 2024; 28:336&#x2013;342.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>