<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41020563</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-7347</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Knee surgery, sports traumatology, arthroscopy : official journal of the ESSKA</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Anticoagulant and anti-inflammatory effects of fondaparinux sodium during anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction in high risk VTE patients: A randomised controlled, triple blinded, prospective study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ksa.70081</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to evaluate the anticoagulant and anti-inflammatory effects of fondaparinux sodium in patients at high risk of venous thromboembolism (VTE) undergoing anterior cruciate ligament (ACL) reconstruction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A single-centre, triple-blinded, randomised, controlled study enroled high-risk VTE patients (Caprini score&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;5) undergoing ACL reconstruction. Patients were randomised to receive either fondaparinux sodium (2.5&#x2009;mg daily for 14 days) or enoxaparin sodium (4000 AxaIU daily for 14 days). Coagulation parameters, inflammatory markers, thromboelastography (TEG) and duplex ultrasound of the lower limbs were assessed at predefined time points.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 72 patients were included. Baseline demographic characteristics, including age, gender and preoperative health status, were similar between the two groups. No cases of deep vein thrombosis (DVT) or pulmonary embolism (PE) were reported in either group. Group A showed significantly lower D-dimer levels on postoperative days 3, 7, and 13 and higher activated partial thromboplastin time (APTT) on Day 7 (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). TEG showed that reaction time (R) was longer in Group A, and maximum amplitude (MA) increased postoperatively (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). Inflammatory markers (ESR, CRP and IL-6) were significantly lower in Group A at multiple time points (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). Knee circumference also decreased significantly in Group A on Days 3 and 7 (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05). No significant differences were found between the groups regarding pain, blood loss or postoperative complications (p&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In high-risk VTE patients undergoing ACL reconstruction, fondaparinux sodium exhibited superior anticoagulant and anti-inflammatory effects compared to enoxaparin sodium, with reduced knee swelling. No significant differences were observed in major postoperative VTE events or bleeding risks, suggesting fondaparinux sodium may be a preferable option for postoperative thromboprophylaxis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level I.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 European Society of Sports Traumatology, Knee Surgery and Arthroscopy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Pai</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-6711-1912</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital of Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Che</LastName><ForeName>Guangwei</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital of Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xueer</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital of Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>You</LastName><ForeName>Haoming</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital of Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Jiayuan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital of Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital of Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Lihan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-5125-5543</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital of Chengdu University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2021HR08</GrantID><Agency>Scientific Research Special Funding of Sichuan Medical Association</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9314730</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0942-2056</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fondaparinux sodium</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postoperative anticoagulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postoperative anti&#x2010;inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">venous thromboembolism</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41020563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ksa.70081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Talwar A, Farley JF, Muzumdar J, Schommer JC, Balkrishnan R, et al. Fondaparinux sodium compared with low&#x2010;molecular&#x2010;weight heparins for perioperative surgical thromboprophylaxis: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. J Am Heart Assoc. 2019;8:e012184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onishi A, St Ange K, Dordick JS, Linhardt RJ. Heparin and anticoagulation. Front Biosci. 2016;21:1372&#x2013;1392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsheikh K, Hilabi A, Aleid A, Alharbi KG, Alangari HS, Alkhamis M, et al. Efficacy and safety of thromboprophylaxis post&#x2010;orthopedic surgery. Cureus. 2021;13(11):e19691.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds AW, Garay M, Lynch S, Black KP, Gallo RA. Incidence of venous thromboembolism following knee arthroscopy: effectiveness of a risk&#x2010;based stratified chemoprophylaxis protocol. J Knee Surg. 2022;35:443&#x2013;448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B C, Zc L, M G, Jp M. Utility of D&#x2010;dimer in total joint arthroplasty. World J Orthop. 2023;14(3):90&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauersachs RM. Fondaparinux sodium: recent advances in the management of thrombosis. J Cardiovasc Pharmacol Ther. 2023;28:10742484221145010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayle&#x2010;Iniguez X, Cassard X, Vinciguerra B, Murgier J. Postoperative thromboprophylaxis does not reduce the incidence of thromboembolic events after ACL reconstruction. Orthop Traumatol: Surg Res. 2021;107(4):102904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradsell HL, Lencioni A, Frank RM. Incidence and prevention of thromboembolic complications for sports and arthroscopic&#x2010;related surgery: evidence&#x2010;based recommendations. Sports Med Arthrosc. 2022;30(1):24&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandao GM, Junqueira DR, Rollo HA, Sobreira ML. Pentasaccharides for the treatment of deep vein thrombosis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;12(12):CD011782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryll J, P&#x142;omi&#x144;ski J. Venous thromboembolism prophylaxis in arthroscopic surgery. Ortop Traumatol Rehabil. 2013;15(6):517&#x2013;529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardillo G, Viggiano GV, Russo V, Mangiacapra S, Cavalli A, Castaldo G, et al. Fondenoxavid Study Group. Antithrombotic and anti&#x2010;inflammatory effects of fondaparinux and enoxaparin in hospitalized COVID&#x2010;19 patients: The FONDENOXAVID study. J Blood Med. 2021;12:69&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chechik O, Amar E, Khashan M, Lador R, Eyal G, Gold A. An international survey on anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction practices. Int Orthop. 2013;37(2):201&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P, Wang J, Wang L, Xiong S, Wang C, Yang X, et al. Study on the safety and effectiveness of low&#x2010;dose vs. regular&#x2010;dose fondaparinux in preventing venous thromboembolism prophylaxis following total knee arthroplasty. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2023;10:1195322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cullison TR, Muldoon MP, Gorman JD, Goff WB. The incidence of deep venous thrombosis in anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Arthroscopy. 1996;12(6):657&#x2013;659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delis KT, Hunt N, Strachan RK, Nicolaides AN. Incidence, natural history and risk factors of deep vein thrombosis in elective knee arthroscopy. Thromb Haemost. 2001;86(3):817&#x2013;821.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y, Han B, Yuan B, Nie M, Liu R, Zhao M, et al. Occurrence rates and risk factors of in&#x2010;hospital venous thromboembolism, major bleeding, and death in patients receiving fondaparinux after orthopedic surgery or trauma surgery. Irish J Med Sci. 2023;192(6):2973&#x2013;2979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu D, Li L, Li Y, Liu X, Chen H, Wu N, et al. Fondaparinux sodium and low molecular weight heparin for venous thromboembolism prophylaxis in Chinese patients with major orthopedic surgery or trauma: a real&#x2010;world study. BMC Surg. 2022;22(1):243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao X, Jin X, Huang R, Li Z, Zhang H, Fan P. Comparison of efficacy of nadroparin and fondaparinux sodium for prevention of deep vein thromboembolism in lower extremities after total hip arthroplasty and total knee arthroplasty: a retrospective study of 592 patients. BMC Surg. 2024;24(1):162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geerts WH, Pineo GF, Heit JA, Bergqvist D, Lassen MR, Colwell CW, et al. Prevention of venous thromboembolism. Chest. 2004;126(3 Suppl):338S&#x2013;400S.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto Y, Komiya E, Nishino K, Nishida Y, Masuda A, Nakamura H. Postoperative D&#x2010;dimer levels predict venous thromboembolisms detected with contrast&#x2010;enhanced computerized tomography in patients undergoing anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2023;24:95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Healey F, Gower J, Roberts L, Arya R, Beresford M, Fowler A, et al. Who dies from venous thromboembolism after hospitalisation for other reasons in England?: a national retrospective cohort study. BMJ Open. 2024;14(5):e082951.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holler JT, Salesky M, Halvorson RT, Zhang AL, Ma CB, Feeley BT, et al. Perioperative thromboprophylaxis is associated with lower risk of venous thromboembolism after knee arthroscopy. Arthroscopy. 2022;38(12):3184&#x2013;3191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huo MH, Spyropoulos AC. The eighth American college of chest physicians guidelines on venous thromboembolism prevention: implications for hospital prophylaxis strategies. J Thromb Thrombolysis. 2011;31(2):196&#x2013;208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iba T, Aihara K, Watanabe S, Yanagawa Y, Yamada A, Koichiro N, et al. Factor Xa inhibitor attenuates leukocyte adhesion and thrombus formation in an experimental mouse model of the metabolic syndrome. Cardiovasc Ther. 2013;31(5):280&#x2013;284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones A, Al&#x2010;Horani RA. Venous thromboembolism prophylaxis in major orthopedic surgeries and factor XIa inhibitors. Med Sci. 2023;11(3):49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalina R, Fidler E, B&#xe9;re&#x161; M, Zeman P, Sigmund M, Gallo J. Effect of a single dose of tranexamic acid administered during anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction using hamstrings: a randomized clinical study. Acta Chir Orthop Traumatol Cech. 2021;88(3):184&#x2013;190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller RA, Moutzouros V, Dines JS, Bush&#x2010;Joseph CA, Limpisvasti O. Deep venous thrombosis prophylaxis in anterior cruciate ligament reconstructive surgery: what is the current state of practice? Sports Health. 2018;10(2):156&#x2013;159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ld Z, Hb L, Yn L, Hm M, Yb L, My W. Correlation analysis between plasma D&#x2010;dimer levels and orthopedic trauma severity. Chin Med J. 2012;125(17):3133&#x2013;3136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee K&#x2010;H, Chen K&#x2010;H, Ma H&#x2010;H, Huang T&#x2010;J, Ma H&#x2010;L, Chiang E&#x2010;R. Effects of intra&#x2010;articular tranexamic acid injection with different acting times after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a cohort study with historical controls. J Orthop Traumatol. 2025;26(1):15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H&#x2010;M, Huang L, Fu J, Tong Z, Wei W, Teng C. The efficacy and safety of low&#x2010;molecular&#x2010;weight heparin in patients undergoing knee arthroscopic surgery and anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Heliyon. 2023;9(9):e19696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linnemann B, Beyer&#x2010;Westendorf J, Espinola&#x2010;Klein C, M&#xfc;hlberg KS, M&#xfc;ller OJ, Klamroth R. Management of deep vein thrombosis: an update based on the revised AWMF S2k guideline. Hamostaseologie. 2024;44(2):097&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M C, N D, Es K, A S, N W, M D, et al. Completion of the Updated Caprini Risk Assessment Model (2013 Version). Clin Appl Thromb/Hemost. 2019;25:1076029619838052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma R, Wu M, Li Y, Wang J, Wang W, Yang P, et al. The comparative efficacies of intravenous administration and intra&#x2010;articular injection of tranexamic acid during anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction for reducing postoperative hemarthrosis: a prospective randomized study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2021;22(1):114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Migliorini F, Maffulli N, Velaj E, Bell A, K&#xe4;mmer D, Hildebrand F, et al. Antithrombotic prophylaxis following total hip arthroplasty: a level I Bayesian network meta&#x2010;analysis. J Orthop Traumatol. 2024;25(1):1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harkey MS, Luc BA, Golightly YM, Thomas AC, Driban JB, Hackney AC, et al. Osteoarthritis&#x2010;related biomarkers following anterior cruciate ligament injury and reconstruction: a systematic review. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2015;23:1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu&#xf1;oa L, Gonz&#xe1;lez AB, D&#xed;az de Rada P, Valent&#xed; A, Valent&#xed; JR. Rivaroxaban is as efficient and safe as bemiparin as thromboprophylaxis in knee arthroscopy. Musculoskeletal Surgery. 2014;98(1):21&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy RF, Heyworth B, Kramer D, Naqvi M, Miller PE, Yen Y&#x2010;M, et al. Symptomatic venous thromboembolism after adolescent knee arthroscopy. J Pediatr Orthop. 2019;39(3):125&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang L, Li P, Li H, Tang X, Zhu J. Does anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction increase venous thromboembolism risk compared with knee meniscectomy under arthroscopy? BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2022;23(1):268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrotta C, Chahla J, Badariotti G, Ramos J. Interventions for preventing venous thromboembolism in adults undergoing knee arthroscopy. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2022;8(8):CD005259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramanujam V, DiMaria S, Varma V. Thromboelastography in the perioperative period: a literature review. Cureus. 2023;15(5):e39407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reale D, Andriolo L, Gursoy S, Bozkurt M, Filardo G, Zaffagnini S. Complications of tranexamic acid in orthopedic lower limb surgery: a meta&#x2010;analysis of randomized controlled trials. BioMed Res Int. 2021;2021:6961540.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'toole RV, Stein DM, Frey KP, O'hara NN, Scharfstein DO, Slobogean GP, et al. PREVENTion of CLots in Orthopaedic Trauma (PREVENT CLOT): a randomised pragmatic trial protocol comparing aspirin versus low&#x2010;molecular&#x2010;weight heparin for blood clot prevention in orthopaedic trauma patients. BMJ open. 2021;11:041845.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsson S, Struglics A, Lohmander LS, Frobell R. Surgical reconstruction of ruptured anterior cruciate ligament prolongs trauma&#x2010;induced increase of inflammatory cytokines in synovial fluid: an exploratory analysis in the KANON trial. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2017;25:1443&#x2013;1451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Screpis D, De Berardinis L, Qordja F, Piovan G, Giannini E, Gigante AP, et al. Comparison of autograft and allograft outcomes in adolescent ACL reconstruction: a propensity score analysis. Eur J Orthop Surg Traumatol. 2025;35(1):149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melillo SN, Scanlon JV, Exter BP, Steinberg M, Jarvis CI. Rivaroxaban for thromboprophylaxis in patients undergoing major orthopedic surgery. Annal Pharmacother. 2010;44:1061&#x2013;1071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wills JH, Gaski GE. Update on venous thromboembolism in orthopaedic trauma surgery. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2024;32:e961&#x2013;e969.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Y, Li X, Lei G, Zeng C, Wei J, Ding X, et al. Anterior cruciate ligament tear increases the risk of venous thromboembolism: a population&#x2010;based cohort study. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2023;31(5):1805&#x2013;1814.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y J, J L, Y L, Yc L, Wg Z. Risk factors for deep vein thrombosis after orthopedic surgery and the diagnostic value of D&#x2010;dimer. Ann Vasc Surg. 2015;29(4):675&#x2013;681.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X, Li N, Guo T, Guan X, Tan J, Gao X, et al. Comparison of the effects of low&#x2010;molecular&#x2010;weight heparin and fondaparinux on liver function in patients with pulmonary embolism. J Clin Pharmacol. 2020;60(12):1671&#x2013;1678.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zhang M, Tan L, Pan N, Zhang L. The clinical use of Fondaparinux: a synthetic heparin pentasaccharide. Prog Mol Biol Transl Sci. 2019;163:41&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziyadeh F, Mauer Y. Management of lower&#x2010;extremity venous thromboembolism: an updated review. Cleve Clin J Med. 2024;91(4):229&#x2013;235.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>