<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40141504</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Basic Research on the Preparation of Electrolytic Manganese Residue-Red Mud-Ground Granulated Blast Furnace Slag-Calcium Hydroxide Composite Cementitious Material and Its Mechanical Properties.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1218</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma18061218</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>A novel composite cementitious material was constructed by synergistically utilizing multiple industrial solid wastes, including electrolytic manganese residue (EMR), red mud (RM), and ground granulated blast furnace slag (GGBS), with calcium hydroxide [Ca(OH)<sub>2</sub>] as an alkaline activator. In addition, the mechanical properties of the composite cementitious materials were systematically analyzed under different raw material ratios, alkali activator dosages, and water-binder ratios. To further investigate the hydration products and mechanisms of the composite cementitious material, characterization methods, for instance, XRD, FT-IR, SEM-EDS, and TG-DTG, were employed to characterize the materials. To ensure that the composite cementitious material does not cause additional environmental pressure, it was analyzed for toxic leaching. The relevant experimental results indicate that the optimal ratio of the EMR-RM-GGBS-Ca(OH)<sub>2</sub> components of the composite cementitious material is EMR content of 20%, RM content of 15%, GGBS content of 52%, calcium hydroxide as alkali activator content of 13%, and water-binder ratio of 0.5. Under the optimal ratio, the composite cementitious material at 28 days exhibited a compressive strength of 27.9 MPa, as well as a flexural strength of 7.5 MPa. The hydration products in the as-synthesized composite cementitious material system primarily encompassed ettringite (AFt) and hydrated calcium silicate (C-S-H), and their tight bonding in the middle and later curing stages was the main source of engineering mechanical strength. The heavy metal concentrations in the 28-day leaching solution of the EMR-RM-GGBS-Ca(OH)<sub>2</sub> composite cementitious material fall within the limits prescribed by the drinking water hygiene standard (GB5749-2022), indicating that this composite material exhibits satisfactory safety performance. To sum up, it is elucidated that the novel process involved in this research provide useful references for the pollution-free treatment and resource utilization of solid wastes such as red mud and electrolytic manganese residue in the future.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Biao</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Materials Science and Engineering, Guilin University of Technology, Guilin 541004, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Lusen</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Materials Science and Engineering, Guilin University of Technology, Guilin 541004, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zhonglin</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-1591-2290</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Materials Science and Engineering, Guilin University of Technology, Guilin 541004, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Ye</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Materials Science and Engineering, Guilin University of Technology, Guilin 541004, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Weiguang</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Materials Science and Engineering, Guilin University of Technology, Guilin 541004, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yibing</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Materials Science and Engineering, Guilin University of Technology, Guilin 541004, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electrolytic manganese residue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">green cementitious material</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ground granulated blast furnace slag</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">red mud</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40141504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11943943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma18061218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma18061218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Davis S.J., Caldeira K., Matth H.D. Future CO2 Emissions and Climate Change from Existing Energy Infrastructure. Science. 2010;329:1330&#x2013;1333. doi: 10.1126/science.1188566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1188566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20829483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan J., Zhang S., Mei T., Dong Y., Hou H. Mechanochemical modification of electrolytic manganese residue: Ammonium nitrogen recycling, heavy metal solidification, and baking-free brick preparation. J. Clean. Prod. 2021;329:129727. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.129727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.129727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Ren Y., Zhang Z., Liu X., Wang Y. Harmless treatment of electrolytic manganese residue: Ammonia nitrogen recovery, preparation of struvite and nonsintered bricks. Chem. Eng. J. 2022;455:140739. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2022.140739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2022.140739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu R., Poon C.S. Utilization of red mud derived from bauxite in self-compacting concrete. J. Clean. Prod. 2016;112:384&#x2013;391. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2015.09.049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2015.09.049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Power G., Gr&#xe4;fe M., Klauber C. Bauxite residue issues: I. Current management, disposal and storage practices. Hydrometallurgy. 2011;108:33&#x2013;45. doi: 10.1016/j.hydromet.2011.02.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.hydromet.2011.02.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Liu Z., Liu H., Peng B. Clean strengthening reduction of lead and zinc from smelting waste slag by iron oxide. J. Clean. Prod. 2017;143:311&#x2013;318. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2016.12.108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2016.12.108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanvar H., Mishra B. Comprehensive utilization of bauxite residue for simultaneous recovery of base metals and critical elements. Sustain. Mater. Technol. 2022;33:466. doi: 10.1016/j.susmat.2022.e00466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.susmat.2022.e00466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vilarinho I.S., Dias A.C., Carneiro J., Pinto C., Labrincha J.A., Seabra M.P. Red mud valorization in stoneware pastes: Technical and environmental assessment. Sustain. Mater. Technol. 2023;38:762. doi: 10.1016/j.susmat.2023.e00762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.susmat.2023.e00762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei M., Wang B., Wu P., Zhang X., Chen M., Wang S. Electrolytic manganese residue-biochar composite for simultaneous removal of antimony and arsenic from water: Adsorption performance and mechanisms. J. Clean. Prod. 2024;437:140623. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.140623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.140623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K., Dou Z., Liu Y., Li X., Lv G., Zhang T.A. Summary of research progress on separation and extraction of valuable metals from Bayer red mud. Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res. 2022;29:89834&#x2013;89852. doi: 10.1007/s11356-022-23837-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-022-23837-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36357761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Georgiades M., Shah I.H., Steubing B., Cheeseman C., Myers R.J. Prospective life cycle assessment of European cement production. Resour. Conserv. Recycl. 2023;194:106998. doi: 10.1016/j.resconrec.2023.106998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resconrec.2023.106998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng X., Long D., Zhang C., Gao X., Yu Y., Mei K., Zhang C., Guo X., Chen Z. Utilization of red mud, slag and waste drilling fluid for the synthesis of slag-red mud cementitious material. J. Clean. Prod. 2019;238:117902. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2019.117902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2019.117902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozden B., Brennan C., Landsberger S. Investigation of bauxite residue (red mud) in terms of its environmental risk. J. Radioanal. Nucl. Chem. 2019;319:339&#x2013;346. doi: 10.1007/s10967-018-6355-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10967-018-6355-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koshy N., Dondrob K., Hu L., Wen Q., Meegoda J.N. Mechanical Properties of Geopolymers Synthesized from Fly Ash and Red Mud under Ambient Conditions. Crystals. 2019;9:572. doi: 10.3390/cryst9110572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cryst9110572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu P., Liu X., Zhang Z., Wei C., Wang J., Gu J. The harmless and value-added utilization of red mud: Recovering iron from red mud by pyrometallurgy and preparing cementitious materials with its tailings. J. Ind. Eng. Chem. 2024;132:50&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1016/j.jiec.2023.11.038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jiec.2023.11.038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Luo Y., Zhou H., Zhong X., Zhou Z., Li J., Hou H. Preparation of environmental-friendly cementitious material from red mud and waste glass sludge by mechanical activation. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;423:135861. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui W., Liu J., Duan W., Xie M., Li X., Dong X. Study on the synergistic effects and eco-friendly performance of red mud-based quaternary cementitious materials. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;428:136352. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Peng B., Chai L., Zhang Q., Liu Q. Preparation of electrolytic manganese residue&#x2013;ground granulated blastfurnace slag cement. Powder Technol. 2013;241:12&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1016/j.powtec.2013.03.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.powtec.2013.03.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Z., Zhang H., Pu S., Cai G., Duan W., Song H., Zeng C., Yang Y. Synergistic preparation of geopolymer using electrolytic manganese residue, coal slag and granulated blast furnace slag. J. Build. Eng. 2024;91:109609. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Sun P., Li J., Lv Y., Ye H., Shao L., Du D. Synthesis of electrolytic manganese residue-fly ash based geopolymers with high compressive strength. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;248:118489. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He D., Chen M., Liu H., Wang J. Preparation of activated electrolytic manganese residue-slag-cement ternary blended cementitious material: Hydration characteristics and carbon reduction potential. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;425:135990. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juenger M.C.G., Snellings R., Bernal S.A. Supplementary cementitious materials: New sources, characterization, and performance insights. Cem. Concr. Res. 2019;122:257&#x2013;273. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.05.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.05.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y., Lu B., Bai T., Wang H., Du F., Zhang Y., Cai L., Jiang C., Wang W. Geopolymer, green alkali activated cementitious material: Synthesis, applications and challenges. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;224:930&#x2013;949. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.07.112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.07.112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lingyu T., Dongpo H., Jianing Z., Hongguang W. Durability of geopolymers and geopolymer concretes: A review. Rev. Adv. Mater. Sci. 2021;60:1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1515/rams-2021-0002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/rams-2021-0002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang N., Li H., Liu X. Hydration mechanism and leaching behavior of bauxite-calcination-method red mud-coal gangue based cementitious materials. J. Hazard. Mater. 2016;314:172&#x2013;180. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2016.04.040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2016.04.040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27131457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y.C., Min X.B., Ke Y., Chai L.Y., Shi M.Q., Tang C.J., Wang Q.W., Liang Y.J., Lei J., Liu D.G. Utilization of red mud and Pb/Zn smelter waste for the synthesis of a red mud-based cementitious material. J. Hazard. Mater. 2018;344:343&#x2013;349. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2017.10.046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2017.10.046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29080487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma F., Chen L., Lin Z., Liu Z., Zhang W., Guo R. Microstructure and Key Properties of Phosphogypsum-Red Mud-Slag Composite Cementitious Materials. Materials. 2022;15:6096. doi: 10.3390/ma15176096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15176096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9458091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36079477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Test Methods for Cement Mortar Strength (ISO Method) Standardization Administration of China; Beijing, China: 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Min X., Ke Y., Liu D., Tang C. Preparation of red mud-based geopolymer materials from MSWI fly ash and red mud by mechanical activation. Waste Manag. 2019;83:202&#x2013;208. doi: 10.1016/j.wasman.2018.11.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wasman.2018.11.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30514467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M.Z., Zhao Y.X., Chen B. Efflorescence mitigation in fly ash/slag-based geopolymers: The role of precursor composition and proportions, and admixtures. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;438:137216. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie Q., Hu W., Ai T., Huang B., Shu X., He Q. Strength properties of geopolymers derived from original and desulfurized red mud cured at ambient temperature. Constr. Build. Mater. 2016;125:905&#x2013;911. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.08.144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.08.144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhary H.K., Anupama A.V., Kumar R., Panzi M.E., Matteppanavar S., Sherikar B.N., Sahoo B. Observation of phase transformations in cement during hydration. Constr. Build. Mater. 2015;101:122&#x2013;129. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.10.027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.10.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei X., Ni W., Zhang S., Wang X., Li J., Du H. Influence of the key factors on the performance of steel slag-desulphurisation gypsum-based hydration-carbonation materials. J. Build. Eng. 2022;45:103591. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Ni W., Li J., Zhang S., Hitch M., Pascual R. Carbonation of steel slag and gypsum for building materials and associated reaction mechanisms. Cem. Concr. Res. 2019;125:105893. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao C., Suraneni P., Ying T.N.W., Choudhary A., Weiss J. Chloride binding of cement pastes with fly ash exposed to CaCl2 solutions at 5 and 23 &#xb0;C. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2019;97:43&#x2013;53. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2018.12.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2018.12.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Lyu X., Wang L., Cao X., Liu Q., Zang H. Influence of the combination of calcium oxide and sodium carbonate on the hydration reactivity of alkali-activated slag binders. J. Clean. Prod. 2018;171:622&#x2013;629. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2017.10.077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2017.10.077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuri J.C., Nuruzzaman M., Sarker P.K. Sodium sulphate resistance of geopolymer mortar produced using ground ferronickel slag with fly ash. Ceram. Int. 2023;49:2765&#x2013;2773. doi: 10.1016/j.ceramint.2022.09.258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceramint.2022.09.258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng C., Mao Z., Chen L., Qian H., Wang J. Development of a novel rapid repairing agent for concrete based on GFRP waste powder/GGBS geopolymer mortars. J. Build. Eng. 2023;71:106542. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou D., Wu D., Wang X., Gao S., Yu R., Li M., Wang P., Wang Y. Sustainable use of red mud in ultra-high performance concrete (UHPC): Design and performance evaluation. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2021;115:103862. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2020.103862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2020.103862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Li S., Li Z., Liu C., Gao Y., Qi Y. Properties of red mud blended with magnesium phosphate cement paste: Feasibility of grouting material preparation. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;260:119704. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solid Waste&#x2014;Extraction Procedure for Leaching Toxicity&#x2014;Sulphuric Acid and Nitric Acid Method. Standardization Administration of China; Beijing, China: 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standards for Drinking Water Quality. Standardization Administration of China; Beijing, China: 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan J., Yan J., Zhou M., Xu Y., Lu Y., Duan P., Zhu Y., Zhang Z., Li W., Wang A., et al. Heavy metals immobilization of ternary geopolymer based on nickel slag, lithium slag and metakaolin. J. Hazard. Mater. 2023;453:131380. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2023.131380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2023.131380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37043859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>