<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40197010</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1936-086X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>15</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS nano</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Nano</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Unidirectional Ion Sieve Enabling High-Flux and Reversible Zinc Anodes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>14987</StartPage><EndPage>15001</EndPage><MedlinePgn>14987-15001</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsnano.5c01103</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The longevity of aqueous batteries after scaling up is largely restricted by metal anodes (Zn, Al, and Mg). Parasitic reactions and uncontrolled dendrites dominate failure modes, especially at high current densities. To fully improve its reversibility, tailored surface chemistry and well-designed ion transport channels are simultaneously demanded. Here, inspired by the reticulated structure of the sea urchin shell, an aligned porous coating assembled from graphene oxide and sodium alginate is anchored on zinc anodes, termed a unidirectional ion sieve. As revealed by multiscale modeling and tests, this biomimetic layer produces a high surface area, creating low-tortuosity channels that greatly enhance transport kinetics and uniform distribution of ions. The introduction of an ion-conductive natural polymer enables a well-tuned hydration structure and ion selectivity, greatly alleviating aqueous side reactions. With the structural-functional integrity design, the decorated symmetrical cell presents reversible cycling for 1600 h, with a greatly reduced nucleation potential of 21 mV and high Coulombic efficiency. Aided by the Distribution of Relaxation Time tool, different electrochemical processes are deconvoluted to understand respective mechanisms, thereby providing a referable strategy for product scaling. In the end, a 7Ah Zn||VO<sub>2</sub> pouch cell demonstrates stable cycling for over 500 cycles at 1 A&#xb7;g<sup>-1</sup>, with the capacity retention over 90%.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zhiyuan</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science and Engineering, the University of Nottingham Ningbo China, Ningbo 315100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Yifan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science and Engineering, the University of Nottingham Ningbo China, Ningbo 315100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Energy Storage Center, Shanghai Advanced Research Institute, Chinese Academy of Sciences, 99 Haike Road, Shanghai 201210, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Ping</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science and Engineering, the University of Nottingham Ningbo China, Ningbo 315100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Jiayan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Superhard Materials, College of Physics, Jilin University, Changchun, Jilin 130012, PR China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Xuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1706-3801</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Christopher Ingold Laboratory, Department of Chemistry, University College London, 20 Gordon Street, London WC1H 0AJ, U.K.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Thom Building, Department of Engineering Science, University of Oxford, 17 Parks Road, Oxford OX1 3PJ, U.K.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Guanjie</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7365-9645</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Christopher Ingold Laboratory, Department of Chemistry, University College London, 20 Gordon Street, London WC1H 0AJ, U.K.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yi</LastName><ForeName>Xiaosu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science and Engineering, the University of Nottingham Ningbo China, Ningbo 315100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Nano</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101313589</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1936-0851</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aligned coating</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomimetic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">composites</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">zinc anode</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">zinc-ion batteries</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors
declare no competing financial interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40197010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12020423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsnano.5c01103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yang Y.; Qin L.; He Q.; Yin C.; Lei Y.; Liang S.; Fang G. Electrochemically and chemically in-situ interfacial protection layers towards stable and reversible Zn anodes. Sci. Bull. 2024, 70, 104&#x2013;124. 10.1016/j.scib.2024.10.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scib.2024.10.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39477784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong H.; Li J.; Guo J.; Lai F.; Zhao F.; Jiao Y.; Brett D. J.; Liu T.; He G.; Parkin I. P. Insights on flexible zinc-ion batteries from lab research to commercialization. Adv. Mater. 2021, 33 (20), 2007548. 10.1002/adma.202007548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202007548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33797810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yufit V.; Tariq F.; Eastwood D. S.; Biton M.; Wu B.; Lee P. D.; Brandon N. P. Operando visualization and multi-scale tomography studies of dendrite formation and dissolution in zinc batteries. Joule 2019, 3 (2), 485&#x2013;502. 10.1016/j.joule.2018.11.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2018.11.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y.; Huang Z.; Zheng M.; Chen H.; Qian S.; Sun C.; Tian Y.; Wu Z.; Lai C.; Zhang S.; et al. Scalable Construction of Multifunctional Protection Layer with Low-Cost Water Glass for Robust and High-Performance Zinc Anode. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 34 (3), 2306085. 10.1002/adfm.202306085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202306085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bie Z.; Yang Q.; Cai X.; Chen Z.; Jiao Z.; Zhu J.; Li Z.; Liu J.; Song W.; Zhi C. One-step construction of a polyporous and zincophilic interface for stable zinc metal anodes. Adv. Energy Mater. 2022, 12 (44), 2202683. 10.1002/aenm.202202683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202202683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng X.; Liu Z.; Sun J.; Luo R.; Xu K.; Si M.; Kang J.; Yuan Y.; Liu S.; Ahmad T.; et al. Constructing robust heterostructured interface for anode-free zinc batteries with ultrahigh capacities. Nat. Commun. 2023, 14 (1), 76. 10.1038/s41467-022-35630-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-022-35630-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9816316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36604413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai X.; Wang X.; Bie Z.; Jiao Z.; Li Y.; Yan W.; Fan H. J.; Song W. A Layer-by-Layer Self-Assembled Bio-Macromolecule Film for Stable Zinc Anode. Adv. Mater. 2024, 36 (3), 2306734. 10.1002/adma.202306734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202306734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37843433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y.; Chen Z.; Gao X.; Dong H.; Zhao X.; He G.; Yang H. In-Situ Self-respiratory Solid-to-hydrogel Electrolyte Interface Evoked Well-Distributed Deposition on Zinc Anode for Highly Reversible Zinc-ion Batteries. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2025, 64, e202415251 10.1002/anie.202415251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202415251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39383296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren B.; Hu S.; Chen A.; Zhang X.; Wei H.; Jiang J.; Chen G.; Zhi C.; Li H.; Liu Z. Inhibiting Dendrite Formation and Electrode Corrosion via a Scalable Self-Assembled Mercaptan Layer for Stable Aqueous Zinc Batteries. Adv. Energy Mater. 2024, 14 (3), 2302970. 10.1002/aenm.202302970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202302970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K.; Sun M.; Yang S.; Gan G.; Bu S.; Zhu A.; Lin D.; Zhang T.; Luan C.; Zhi C.; et al. Multifunctional Nanodiamond Interfacial Layer for Ultra-Stable Zinc-Metal Anodes. Adv. Energy Mater. 2024, 14, 2401479. 10.1002/aenm.202401479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202401479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Z.; Zhong X.; Zhang Q.; Zhang M.; Dai L.; Xiao X.; Xu J.; Jiao M.; Wang B.; Li H.; et al. An extended substrate screening strategy enabling a low lattice mismatch for highly reversible zinc anodes. Nat. Commun. 2024, 15 (1), 753. 10.1038/s41467-024-44893-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-024-44893-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10810881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38272872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Z.; Fan L.; Zhao C.; Chen A.; Liu N.; Zhang Y.; Zhang N. A dynamic and self-adapting interface coating for stable Zn-metal anodes. Adv. Mater. 2022, 34 (2), 2105133. 10.1002/adma.202105133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202105133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34676914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao Z.; Zhang H.; Song B.; Xiong D.; Tao S.; Deng W.; Hu J.; Hou H.; Zou G.; Ji X. Angstrom-Level Ionic Sieve 2D-MOF Membrane for High Power Aqueous Zinc Anode. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2023, 33 (28), 2300339. 10.1002/adfm.202300339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202300339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z.; Yang X.; Li P.; Wang Y.; Zhao X.; Safaei J.; Tian H.; Zhou D.; Li B.; Kang F.; et al. Biomimetic Dendrite-Free Multivalent Metal Batteries. Adv. Mater. 2022, 34 (47), 2206970. 10.1002/adma.202206970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202206970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36124867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng X.; Song Z.; Zhang D.; Du W.; Miao L.; Lv Y.; Gan L.; Liu M. Biomimetic Quasi-Skin-Capillary Structure Engineering of Ionic-Electronic Conducting Full-Chain Networks for Stable Zinc Powder Anodes. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 35, 2413990. 10.1002/adfm.202413990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202413990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M.; Emre A.; Tung S.; Gerber A.; Wang D.; Huang Y.; Cecen V.; Kotov N. A.
Biomimetic solid-state
Zn<sup>2+</sup> electrolyte for corrugated structural batteries. ACS Nano
2019, 13 (2), 1107&#x2013;1115. 10.1021/acsnano.8b05068.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsnano.8b05068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30608112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang T.; Xu K.; Jia N.; Yang L.; Liu H.; Zhu J.; Yan Q. Intrinsic interfacial dynamic engineering of zincophilic microbrushes via regulating Zn deposition for highly reversible aqueous zinc ion battery. Adv. Mater. 2023, 35 (5), 2205206. 10.1002/adma.202205206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202205206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36453716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X.; Ma Q.; Wang J.; Han Q.; Liu C. A biomimetic polymer-based composite coating inhibits zinc dendrite growth for high-performance zinc-ion batteries. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2022, 14 (8), 10384&#x2013;10393. 10.1021/acsami.1c23422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.1c23422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35170300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X.; Ju Z.; Zhu Y.; Takeuchi K. J.; Takeuchi E. S.; Marschilok A. C.; Yu G. Multiscale understanding and architecture design of high energy/power lithium-ion battery electrodes. Adv. Energy Mater. 2021, 11 (2), 2000808. 10.1002/aenm.202000808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202000808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao J. J.; Lv W.; Yang Q. H. Self-assembly of graphene oxide at interfaces. Adv. Mater. 2014, 26 (32), 5586&#x2013;5612. 10.1002/adma.201400267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.201400267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24852899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du H.; Liang R.; Ji X.; Li J.; Liu C.; Cheng S. Fabrication of Self-Assembled Graphene Oxide Film and Its Application in Aqueous Zinc Metal Batteries. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2024, 16, 55502&#x2013;55510. 10.1021/acsami.4c12672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.4c12672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39353177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng J.; Zhao Q.; Tang T.; Yin J.; Quilty C. D.; Renderos G. D.; Liu X.; Deng Y.; Wang L.; Bock D. C.; et al. Reversible epitaxial electrodeposition of metals in battery anodes. Science 2019, 366 (6465), 645&#x2013;648. 10.1126/science.aax6873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aax6873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31672899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong H.; Hu X.; Liu R.; Ouyang M.; He H.; Wang T.; Gao X.; Dai Y.; Zhang W.; Liu Y.; et al. Bio-inspired polyanionic electrolytes for highly stable zinc-ion batteries. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2023, 62, e202311268 10.1002/anie.202311268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202311268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10962557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37615518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabater i Serra R.; Molina-Mateo J.; Torregrosa-Cabanilles C.; Andrio-Balado A.; Meseguer Duenas J. M.; Serrano-Aroca A. &#xb4;. Bio-nanocomposite hydrogel based on zinc alginate/graphene oxide: morphology, structural conformation, thermal behavior/degradation, and dielectric properties. Polymers 2020, 12 (3), 702. 10.3390/polym12030702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym12030702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7183265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32235735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>graphicsrf . Urchin Free Vector; Vecteezy, 2024. https://www.vecteezy.com/vector-art/372378-urchin (accessed 2024 10.10).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klang K.; Nickel K. G. The plant-like structure of lance sea urchin spines as biomimetic concept generator for freeze-casted structural graded ceramics. Biomimetics 2021, 6 (2), 36. 10.3390/biomimetics6020036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomimetics6020036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8261639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34072652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu H.; Hu J.; Zhang Y.; Zhang K.; Yan X.; Li H.; Li J.; Li Y.; Zhao J.; Xu B. 3D Cold-Trap Environment Printing for Long-Cycle Aqueous Zn-Ion Batteries. Adv. Mater. 2023, 35 (9), 2209886. 10.1002/adma.202209886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202209886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36515180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu C.; Zhai X.; Liu L.; Zhao Y.; Jiang L.; Qu L. Spontaneous reduction and assembly of graphene oxide into three-dimensional graphene network on arbitrary conductive substrates. Sci. Rep. 2013, 3 (1), 2065. 10.1038/srep02065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep02065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3691888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23799368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia A.; Pu X.; Tao Y.; Liu H.; Wang Y. Graphene oxide spontaneous reduction and self-assembly on the zinc metal surface enabling a dendrite-free anode for long-life zinc rechargeable aqueous batteries. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2019, 481, 852&#x2013;859. 10.1016/j.apsusc.2019.03.197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2019.03.197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jabbar A. A.; Hussain D. H.; Latif K. H.; Albukhaty S.; Jasim A. K.; Sulaiman G. M.; Abomughaid M. M. RETRACTED ARTICLE: Extremely efficient aerogels of graphene oxide/graphene oxide nanoribbons/sodium alginate for uranium removal from wastewater solution. Sci. Rep. 2024, 14 (1), 1285. 10.1038/s41598-024-52043-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-52043-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10787740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38218971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruan J.; Ma D.; Ouyang K.; Shen S.; Yang M.; Wang Y.; Zhao J.; Mi H.; Zhang P. 3D artificial array interface engineering enabling dendrite-free stable Zn metal anode. Nanomicro Lett. 2023, 15 (1), 37. 10.1007/s40820-022-01007-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-022-01007-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9845508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36648582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y.; Deng Z.; Sun Y.; Li Y.; Zhang H.; Li G.; Zeng H.; Wang X. Ultrathin Zincophilic Interphase Regulated Electric Double Layer Enabling Highly Stable Aqueous Zinc-Ion Batteries. Nanomicro Lett. 2024, 16 (1), 96. 10.1007/s40820-023-01312-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-023-01312-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10810772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38270675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen A.; Zhao C.; Gao J.; Guo Z.; Lu X.; Zhang J.; Liu Z.; Wang M.; Liu N.; Fan L.; et al. Multifunctional SEI-like structure coating stabilizing Zn anodes at a large current and capacity. Energy Environ. Sci. 2023, 16 (1), 275&#x2013;284. 10.1039/d2ee02931f.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d2ee02931f</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moats M.; Hymer T.. To Polarize or Not to Polarize: Practical Advice on How to Control Zinc Electrodeposition. In PbZn 2020: 9th International Symposium on Lead and Zinc Processing; Springer, 2020, pp 111&#x2013;122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X.; Xu Y.; Zhang J.; Zhong Y.; Li Z.; Qiu H.; Wu H. B.; Wang J.; Wang X.; Gu C.; et al. Quasi-solid electrolyte interphase boosting charge and mass transfer for dendrite-free zinc battery. Nanomicro Lett. 2023, 15 (1), 56. 10.1007/s40820-023-01031-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-023-01031-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9975136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36853520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo J.; Xu L.; Yang Y.; Huang S.; Zhou Y.; Shao Y.; Wang T.; Tian J.; Guo S.; Zhao J.; et al. Stable zinc anode solid electrolyte interphase via inner Helmholtz plane engineering. Nat. Commun. 2024, 15 (1), 6471. 10.1038/s41467-024-50890-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-024-50890-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11291733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39085235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao M.; Rong J.; Huo F.; Lv Y.; Yue B.; Xiao Y.; Chen Y.; Hou G.; Qiu J.; Chen S. Semi-Immobilized Ionic Liquid Regulator with Fast Kinetics toward Highly Stable Zinc Anode under&#x2013; 35 to 60&#xb0; C. Adv. Mater. 2022, 34 (32), 2203153. 10.1002/adma.202203153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202203153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35635220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q.; Luan J.; Tang Y.; Ji X.; Wang H. Interfacial design of dendrite-free zinc anodes for aqueous zinc-ion batteries. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2020, 59 (32), 13180&#x2013;13191. 10.1002/anie.202000162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202000162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32124537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park S.; Lee K. S.; Bozoklu G.; Cai W.; Nguyen S. T.; Ruoff R. S. Graphene oxide papers modified by divalent ions-enhancing mechanical properties via chemical cross-linking. ACS Nano. 2008, 2, 572&#x2013;578. 10.1021/nn700349a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/nn700349a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19206584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu S.; Zhu Y.; Xiong D.; Wang L.; Yang P.; Chu P. K. Zinc Electrodeposition on Polycrystalline Copper: Electrochemical Study of Early-Stage Growth Mechanism. J. Phys. Chem. C 2017, 121, 3938&#x2013;3946. 10.1021/acs.jpcc.6b12036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.6b12036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou L.; Wang F.; Yang F.; Liu X.; Yu Y.; Zheng D.; Lu X. Unshared Pair Electrons of Zincophilic Lewis Base Enable Long-life Zn Anodes under &#x201c;Three High&#x201d; Conditions. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2022, 61 (40), e202208051 10.1002/anie.202208051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202208051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35971572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H.; Xu Z.; Cao B.; Xin Z.; Lai H.; Gao S.; Xu B.; Yang J. L.; Xiao T.; Zhang B.; et al. Marangoni-Driven Self-Assembly MXene As Functional Membrane Enables Dendrite-Free and Flexible Zinc&#x2013;Iodine Pouch Cells. Adv. Energy Mater. 2024, 14, 2400318. 10.1002/aenm.202400318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202400318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L.; Wang X.; Hu Z.; Wang X.; Zheng Q.; Han C.; Xu J.; Xu X.; Liu H. K.; Dou S. X.; et al. Electric Double Layer Regulator Design through a Functional Group Assembly Strategy towards Long-Lasting Zinc Metal Batteries. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 63 (30), e202405209 10.1002/anie.202405209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202405209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38712643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S.; Zhang Z.; Lan M.; Yang S.; Cheng J.; Cai J.; Shen J.; Zhu Y.; Zhang K.; Zhang W. Lithiophilic Cu-CuO-Ni hybrid structure: advanced current collectors toward stable lithium metal anodes. Adv. Mater. 2018, 30 (9), 1705830. 10.1002/adma.201705830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.201705830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29327388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper E. R.; Li M.; Gentle I.; Xia Q.; Knibbe R. A deeper understanding of metal nucleation and growth in rechargeable metal batteries through theory and experiment. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2023, 62 (51), e202309247 10.1002/anie.202309247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202309247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37735095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Q.; Fang G.; Chang Z.; Zhang Y.; Zhou S.; Zhou M.; Chai S.; Zhong Y.; Cao G.; Liang S.; et al. Building ultra-stable and low-polarization composite Zn anode interface via hydrated polyzwitterionic electrolyte construction. Nanomicro Lett. 2022, 14 (1), 93. 10.1007/s40820-022-00835-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-022-00835-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8986915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35384517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng J.; Zhang B.; Chen X.; Hao W.; Yao J.; Li J.; Gan Y.; Wang X.; Liu X.; Wu Z.; et al. Critical solvation structures arrested active molecules for reversible Zn electrochemistry. Nanomicro Lett. 2024, 16 (1), 145. 10.1007/s40820-024-01361-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40820-024-01361-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10914662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38441811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G.; Zhao Z.; Zhang S.; Sun L.; Li M.; Yuwono J. A.; Mao J.; Hao J.; Vongsvivut J.; Xing L.; et al. A biocompatible electrolyte enables highly reversible Zn anode for zinc ion battery. Nat. Commun. 2023, 14 (1), 6526. 10.1038/s41467-023-42333-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-023-42333-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10579325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37845239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao R.; Wang H.; Du H.; Yang Y.; Gao Z.; Qie L.; Huang Y. Lanthanum nitrate as aqueous electrolyte additive for favourable zinc metal electrodeposition. Nat. Commun. 2022, 13 (1), 3252. 10.1038/s41467-022-30939-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-022-30939-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9170708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35668132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo S.; Qin L.; Wu J.; Liu Z.; Huang Y.; Xie Y.; Fang G.; Liang S. Conversion-type anode chemistry with interfacial compatibility toward Ah-level near-neutral high-voltage zinc ion batteries. Natl. Sci. Rev. 2024, 11 (7), nwae181. 10.1093/nsr/nwae181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nsr/nwae181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11193386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38912515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han M. C.; Zhang J. H.; Yu C. Y.; Yu J. C.; Wang Y. X.; Jiang Z. G.; Yao M.; Xie G.; Yu Z. Z.; Qu J. Constructing Dynamic Anode/Electrolyte Interfaces Coupled with Regulated Solvation Structures for Long-Term and Highly Reversible Zinc Metal Anodes. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2024, 63 (22), e202403695 10.1002/anie.202403695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202403695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38436549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan T. H.; Saccoccio M.; Chen C.; Ciucci F. Influence of the discretization methods on the distribution of relaxation times deconvolution: implementing radial basis functions with DRTtools. Electrochim. Acta 2015, 184, 483&#x2013;499. 10.1016/j.electacta.2015.09.097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2015.09.097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y.; Zhao C.-Z.; Huang J.-Q.; Zhang Q. The timescale identification decoupling complicated kinetic processes in lithium batteries. Joule 2022, 6 (6), 1172&#x2013;1198. 10.1016/j.joule.2022.05.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2022.05.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z.; Lv C.; Li W.; Wu T.; Zhang Q.; Tang Y.; Shao M.; Wang H. Revealing the Two-Dimensional Surface Diffusion Mechanism for Zinc Dendrite Formation on Zinc Anode. Small 2022, 18 (43), 2104148. 10.1002/smll.202104148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202104148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34766709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan M.; Xu C.; Sun Y.; Pan H.; Li H. Manipulating Zn anode reactions through salt anion involving hydrogen bonding network in aqueous electrolytes with PEO additive. Nano Energy 2021, 82, 105739. 10.1016/j.nanoen.2020.105739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2020.105739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y.; Wang T.; Mao Y.; Li Z.; Yu H.; Su M.; Ye K.; Cao D.; Zhu K. Reversible Protonated Electrolyte Additive Enabling Dendrites-Free Zn Metal Anode with High Depth of Discharge. Adv. Energy Mater. 2024, 14, 2400353. 10.1002/aenm.202400353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202400353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q.; Chen A.; Wang D.; Pei Z.; Zhi C. &#x201c;Soft shorts&#x201d; hidden in zinc metal anode research. Joule 2022, 6 (2), 273&#x2013;279. 10.1016/j.joule.2021.12.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2021.12.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown D. E.; McShane E. J.; Konz Z. M.; Knudsen K. B.; McCloskey B. D. Detecting onset of lithium plating during fast charging of Li-ion batteries using operando electrochemical impedance spectroscopy. Cell Rep. Phys. Sci. 2021, 2 (10), 100589. 10.1016/j.xcrp.2021.100589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xcrp.2021.100589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Y.; Yang Y.; Tao Y.; Huang D.; Huang B.; Chen H. Directing the preferred crystal orientation by a cellulose acetate/graphene oxide composite separator for dendrite-free Zn-metal anodes. ACS Appl. Energy Mater. 2021, 4 (12), 14599&#x2013;14607. 10.1021/acsaem.1c03223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsaem.1c03223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao J.; Zhang D.; Gu C.; Wang X.; Wang S.; Zhang X.; Qin J.; Wu Z. S. Manipulating crystallographic orientation of zinc deposition for dendrite-free zinc ion batteries. Adv. Energy Mater. 2021, 11 (29), 2101299. 10.1002/aenm.202101299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202101299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J.; Zhao W.; Jiang J.; Zhao X.; Zheng S.; Pan Z.; Yang X. Challenges and perspectives of hydrogen evolution-free aqueous Zn-Ion batteries. Energy Storage Mater. 2023, 59, 102767. 10.1016/j.ensm.2023.04.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ensm.2023.04.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H.; Ren Y.; Zhu Y.; Tian J.; Sun X.; Sheng C.; He P.; Guo S.; Zhou H. A Bio-Inspired Trehalose Additive for Reversible Zinc Anodes with Improved Stability and Kinetics. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2023, 135 (41), e202310143 10.1002/anie.202310143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202310143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37578683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X.; Hu J. P.; Fu N.; Zhou W. B.; Liu B.; Deng Q.; Wu X. W. Comprehensive review on zinc-ion battery anode: challenges and strategies. InfoMat 2022, 4 (7), e12306 10.1002/inf2.12306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/inf2.12306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma L.; Schroeder M. A.; Borodin O.; Pollard T. P.; Ding M. S.; Wang C.; Xu K. Realizing high zinc reversibility in rechargeable batteries. Nat. Energy 2020, 5 (10), 743&#x2013;749. 10.1038/s41560-020-0674-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41560-020-0674-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang G.; Tang Z.; Han B.; Zhu J.; Chen A.; Li Q.; Chen Z.; Huang Z.; Li X.; Yang Q.; et al. Regulating inorganic and organic components to build amorphous-ZnFx enriched solid-electrolyte interphase for highly reversible Zn metal chemistry. Adv. Mater. 2023, 35 (20), 2210051. 10.1002/adma.202210051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202210051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36840372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J.; Quattrocchi E.; Ciucci F.; Chen Y. Charging processes in lithium-oxygen batteries unraveled through the lens of the distribution of relaxation times. Chem. 2023, 9 (8), 2267&#x2013;2281. 10.1016/j.chempr.2023.04.022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chempr.2023.04.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q.; Luan J.; Huang X.; Wang Q.; Sun D.; Tang Y.; Ji X.; Wang H. Revealing the role of crystal orientation of protective layers for stable zinc anode. Nat. Commun. 2020, 11 (1), 3961. 10.1038/s41467-020-17752-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-020-17752-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7415142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32770066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu J.; Tao Y.; Chen H.; Cao Z.; Zhang Y.; Du Z.; Cui Y.; Yang S. Stress-release functional liquid metal-mxene layers toward dendrite-free zinc metal anodes. Adv. Energy Mater. 2022, 12 (16), 2200115. 10.1002/aenm.202200115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.202200115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang N.; Huang S.; Yuan Z.; Zhu J.; Zhao Z.; Niu Z. Direct self-assembly of MXene on Zn anodes for dendrite-free aqueous zinc-ion batteries. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2021, 60 (6), 2861&#x2013;2865. 10.1002/anie.202012322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202012322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33090646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou J.; Xie M.; Wu F.; Mei Y.; Hao Y.; Huang R.; Wei G.; Liu A.; Li L.; Chen R. Ultrathin surface coating of nitrogen-doped graphene enables stable zinc anodes for aqueous zinc-ion batteries. Adv. Mater. 2021, 33 (33), 2101649. 10.1002/adma.202101649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202101649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34240487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z.; Wu L.; Dong S.; Xu T.; Li S.; An Y.; Jiang J.; Zhang X. Pencil drawing stable interface for reversible and durable aqueous zinc-ion batteries. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2021, 31 (4), 2006495. 10.1002/adfm.202006495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202006495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H.; Guo R.; Li S.; Liu C.; Li H.; Zou G.; Hu J.; Hou H.; Ji X. Graphene quantum dots enable dendrite-free zinc ion battery. Nano Energy 2022, 92, 106752. 10.1016/j.nanoen.2021.106752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2021.106752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y.; Fan Q.; Liu L.; Chen X.; Huang S.; Xu J. A Protective Layer of UIO-66/Reduced Graphene Oxide to Stabilize Zinc-Metal Anodes toward High-Performance Aqueous Zinc-Ion Batteries. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2024, 16, 34020&#x2013;34029. 10.1021/acsami.4c02912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.4c02912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38961571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Y.; Zhang X.; Qin R.; Liu X.; Fang P.; Zheng D.; Tong Y.; Lu X. Dendrite-free zinc deposition induced by multifunctional CNT frameworks for stable flexible Zn-ion batteries. Adv. Mater. 2019, 31 (36), 1903675. 10.1002/adma.201903675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.201903675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31342572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R.; Zhou M.; Xiang Y.; Yang J.; Xu C.; Li X. Dendrite-free zinc anodes via self-assembly of graphene nanoribbon for long-life aqueous zinc-ion batteries. J. Power Sources 2023, 582, 233504. 10.1016/j.jpowsour.2023.233504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2023.233504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng J.; Gu M.; Xiao J.; Zuo P.; Wang C.; Zhang J.-G. Corrosion/fragmentation of layered composite cathode and related capacity/voltage fading during cycling process. Nano Lett. 2013, 13 (8), 3824&#x2013;3830. 10.1021/nl401849t.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/nl401849t</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23802657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>