<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40978368</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-1343</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>36</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS omega</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Omega</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Understanding Ion Intercalation Characteristics of Layered Materials in Superconcentrated Electrolytes: Effects of Concentration, Temperature, and Anion Identity.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>41938</StartPage><EndPage>41947</EndPage><MedlinePgn>41938-41947</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsomega.5c06741</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) are promising layered materials for energy storage applications, due to their ability to host ions within their interlayer galleries. Reducing the hydration shell of aqueous ions, which can be achieved through high-concentration electrolytes, enhances ion intercalation, with some systems reaching the "water-in-salt" regime. Understanding the interplay among ion identity, concentration, and interlayer electrochemistry is thus essential for advancing high-performance energy storage devices. In this study, exfoliated molybdenum disulfide (MoS<sub>2</sub>) was employed as a model TMD electrode to investigate these effects. A systematic evaluation was conducted using lithium-based electrolytes (LiTFSI, LiNO<sub>3</sub>, Li<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub>, and LiCl) across a wide concentration range, from conventional "salt-in-water" to superconcentrated "water-in-salt" conditions. Electrochemical performance was further analyzed under various temperatures (-5 to 60 &#xb0;C). The 5 m LiTFSI system demonstrated the highest specific capacitance (205 F g<sup>-1</sup> at 5 mV s<sup>-1</sup>) and optimal ion mobility under ambient conditions. Temperature-dependent behavior revealed distinct operational windows for each concentration, with the 5 m electrolyte excelling at low-to-moderate temperatures and the 20 m system becoming favorable at elevated temperatures due to enhanced ion dynamics. Among the salts, LiTFSI provided the widest electrochemical stability window and fastest relaxation behavior, while LiNO<sub>3</sub> emerged as a cost-effective alternative with comparable performance. These findings highlight the importance of tuning the electrolyte concentration, composition, and thermal compatibility to optimize the intercalation behavior of layered materials in supercapacitor systems.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arayawate</LastName><ForeName>Sirintra</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Bio-Chemical Engineering and Technology, Sirindhorn International Institute of Technology, Thammasat University, Khlong Nueng 12120, Thailand.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">37698</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit in Sustainable Electrochemical Intelligent, Thammasat University, Khlong Nueng 12120, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kareeklin</LastName><ForeName>Napaporn</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Bio-Chemical Engineering and Technology, Sirindhorn International Institute of Technology, Thammasat University, Khlong Nueng 12120, Thailand.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">37698</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit in Sustainable Electrochemical Intelligent, Thammasat University, Khlong Nueng 12120, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saisopa</LastName><ForeName>Thanit</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Applied Physics, Faculty of Sciences and Liberal Arts, Rajamangala University of Technology Isan, Nakhon Ratchasima, 30000, Thailand.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">202946</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Songsiriritthigul</LastName><ForeName>Prayoon</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Physics, Suranaree University of Technology, Nakhon Ratchasima, 30000, Thailand.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">65162</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iamprasertkun</LastName><ForeName>Pawin</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8950-3330</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Bio-Chemical Engineering and Technology, Sirindhorn International Institute of Technology, Thammasat University, Khlong Nueng 12120, Thailand.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">37698</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit in Sustainable Electrochemical Intelligent, Thammasat University, Khlong Nueng 12120, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Omega</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101691658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-1343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40978368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12444522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.5c06741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Liang H., Ma Z., Wang Y., Zhao F., Cao Z., Cavallo L., Li Q., Ming J.. Solvent-Solvent Interaction Mediated Lithium-Ion (De)&#xad;intercalation Chemistry in Propylene Carbonate Based Electrolytes for Lithium-Sulfur Batteries. ACS Nano. 2023;17(18):18062&#x2013;18073. doi: 10.1021/acsnano.3c04790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsnano.3c04790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37703060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakshmi K. C. S., Vedhanarayanan B.. High-Performance Supercapacitors: A Comprehensive Review on Paradigm Shift of Conventional Energy Storage Devices. Batteries. 2023;9:202. doi: 10.3390/batteries9040202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/batteries9040202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S., Chand P.. Supercapacitor and Electrochemical Techniques: A Brief Review. Results Chem. 2023;5:100885. doi: 10.1016/j.rechem.2023.100885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rechem.2023.100885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chavalekvirat P., Hirunpinyopas W., Deshsorn K., Jitapunkul K., Iamprasertkun P.. Liquid Phase Exfoliation of 2D Materials and Its Electrochemical Applications in the Data-Driven Future. Precis. Chem. 2024;2:300. doi: 10.1021/prechem.3c00119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/prechem.3c00119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11504616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39473901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esfandiar A., Radha B., Wang F. C., Yang Q., Hu S., Garaj S., Nair R. R., Geim A. K., Gopinadhan K.. Size Effect in Ion Transport through Angstrom-Scale Slits. Science (80-.). 2017;358(6362):511&#x2013;513. doi: 10.1126/science.aan5275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aan5275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29074772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naguib M., Kurtoglu M., Presser V., Lu J., Niu J., Heon M., Hultman L., Gogotsi Y., Barsoum M. W.. Two-Dimensional Nanocrystals Produced by Exfoliation of Ti3AlC2 . Adv. Mater. 2011;23(37):4248&#x2013;4253. doi: 10.1002/adma.201102306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.201102306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21861270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M., Afzal A. M., Iqbal M. W., Mumtaz S., Imran M., Ashraf F., Ur Rehman A., Muhammad F.. 2D-TMDs Based Electrode Material for Supercapacitor Applications. Int. J. Energy Res. 2022;46:22336&#x2013;22364. doi: 10.1002/er.8698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/er.8698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q.-Z., Zhang D., Miao Z.-C., Zhang X.-L., Chou S.-L.. Research Progress in MnO2-Carbon Based Supercapacitor Electrode Materials. Small. 2018;14(24):1702883. doi: 10.1002/smll.201702883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.201702883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29707887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramanian V., Zhu H., Wei B.. Nanostructured MnO2: Hydrothermal Synthesis and Electrochemical Properties as a Supercapacitor Electrode Material. J. Power Sources. 2006;159(1):361&#x2013;364. doi: 10.1016/j.jpowsour.2006.04.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2006.04.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Li G., Lv Y., Wang L., Zhang A., Song Y., Huang B.. Electrochemical Investigation of MnO2 Electrode Material for Supercapacitors. Int. J. Hydrogen Energy. 2011;36(18):11760&#x2013;11766. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2011.06.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2011.06.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chavalekvirat P., Saisopa T., Sornnoei N., Hirunpinyopas W., Sirisaksoontorn W., Busayaporn W., Iamprasertkun P.. Tunable Properties of WSe2 Nanosheets and Nano-Dispersion via Energy Dependent Exfoliation. Mater. Reports Energy. 2025;5:100326. doi: 10.1016/j.matre.2025.100326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matre.2025.100326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamila S., Kandasamy M., Chakraborty B., Jena B. K.. Recent Development on Engineered TMDs for Charge Storage Performance: Experimental and Theoretical Investigations. J. Energy Storage. 2024;89:111614. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2024.111614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2024.111614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan X., Zhang H.. Introduction: Two-Dimensional Layered Transition Metal Dichalcogenides. Chem. Rev. 2024;124(19):10619&#x2013;10622. doi: 10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39380397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eng A. Y. S., Ambrosi A., Sofer Z., &#x160;imek P., Pumera M.. Electrochemistry of Transition Metal Dichalcogenides: Strong Dependence on the Metal-to-Chalcogen Composition and Exfoliation Method. ACS Nano. 2014;8(12):12185&#x2013;12198. doi: 10.1021/nn503832j.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/nn503832j</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25453501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iamprasertkun P., Hirunpinyopas W., Deerattrakul V., Sawangphruk M., Nualchimplee C.. Controlling the Flake Size of Bifunctional 2D WSe2 Nanosheets as Flexible Binders and Supercapacitor Materials. Nanoscale Adv. 2021;3:653&#x2013;660. doi: 10.1039/D0NA00592D.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D0NA00592D</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9418638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36133846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y., Sun P.. Electrochemical Performance of Interspace-Expanded Molybdenum Disulfide Few-Layer. J. Nanoparticle Res. 2018;20(7):183. doi: 10.1007/s11051-018-4284-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11051-018-4284-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bissett M. A., Kinloch I. A., Dryfe R. A. W.. Characterization of MoS2-Graphene Composites for High-Performance Coin Cell Supercapacitors. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2015;7:17388&#x2013;17398. doi: 10.1021/acsami.5b04672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.5b04672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26196223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bissett M. A., Worrall S. D., Kinloch I. A., Dryfe R. A. W.. Comparison of Two-Dimensional Transition Metal Dichalcogenides for Electrochemical Supercapacitors. Electrochim. Acta. 2016;201:30&#x2013;37. doi: 10.1016/j.electacta.2016.03.190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2016.03.190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook J. B., Kim H. S., Yan Y., Ko J. S., Robbennolt S., Dunn B., Tolbert S. H.. Mesoporous MoS2 as a Transition Metal Dichalcogenide Exhibiting Pseudocapacitive Li and Na-Ion Charge Storage. Adv. Energy Mater. 2016;6:1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1002/aenm.201501937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.201501937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo H. D., Li Y., Liang Y., Lan Y., Wang F., Yao Y.. Intercalation Pseudocapacitance of Exfoliated Molybdenum Disulfide for Ultrafast Energy Storage. ChemNanoMat. 2016;2(7):688&#x2013;691. doi: 10.1002/cnma.201600117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cnma.201600117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suo L., Borodin O., Gao T., Olguin M., Ho J., Fan X., Luo C., Wang C., Xu K.. &#x201c;Water-in-Salt&#x201d; Electrolyte Enables High-Voltage Aqueous Lithium-Ion Chemistries. Science (80-.). 2015;350(6263):938. doi: 10.1126/science.aab1595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aab1595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26586759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coustan L., Shul G., B&#xe9;langer D.. Electrochemical Behavior of Platinum, Gold and Glassy Carbon Electrodes in Water-in-Salt Electrolyte. Electrochem. commun. 2017;77:89&#x2013;92. doi: 10.1016/j.elecom.2017.03.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.elecom.2017.03.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambou-Bosca A., B&#xe9;langer D.. Electrochemical Characterization of MnO2-Based Composite in the Presence of Salt-in-Water and Water-in-Salt Electrolytes as Electrode for Electrochemical Capacitors. J. Power Sources. 2016;326:595&#x2013;603. doi: 10.1016/j.jpowsour.2016.04.088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpowsour.2016.04.088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunpheng A., Chavalekvirat P., Tangthana-umrung K., Deerattrakul V., Nueangnoraj K., Hirunpinyopas W., Iamprasertkun P.. A Comprehensive Study of Affordable &#x201c;Water-in-Salt&#x201d; Electrolytes and Their Properties. Green Chem. Eng. 2025;6:126. doi: 10.1016/j.gce.2024.06.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gce.2024.06.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayah S., Ghosh A., Baazizi M., Amine R., Dahbi M., Amine Y., Ghamouss F., Amine K.. How Do Super Concentrated Electrolytes Push the Li-Ion Batteries and Supercapacitors beyond Their Thermodynamic and Electrochemical Limits? Nano Energy. 2022;98:107336. doi: 10.1016/j.nanoen.2022.107336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2022.107336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y., Yang W., Yang H., Zhou H.. Electrolyte Design Principles for Low-Temperature Lithium-Ion Batteries. eScience. 2023;3(6):100170. doi: 10.1016/j.esci.2023.100170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.esci.2023.100170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tulaphon P., Tantitumrongwut P., Ditkanaruxkul T., Bunpheng A., Tangthana-umrung K., Chomkhuntod P., Iamprasertkun P.. High Voltage Aqueous Based Energy Storage with &#x201c;Water-in-LiNO3&#x201d; Electrolyte. Chem. Eng. J. Adv. 2023;16:100553. doi: 10.1016/j.ceja.2023.100553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceja.2023.100553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunpheng A., Sakulaue P., Hirunpinyopas W., Nueangnoraj K., Luanwuthi S., Iamprasertkun P.. Revisiting the Properties of Lithium Chloride as &#x201c;Water-in-Salt&#x201d; Electrolyte for Pouch Cell Electrochemical Capacitors. J. Electroanal. Chem. 2023;944:117645. doi: 10.1016/j.jelechem.2023.117645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jelechem.2023.117645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., He T., Liu G., Zu L., Yang J.. One-Pot Mass Preparation of MoS2/C Aerogels for High-Performance Supercapacitors and Lithium-Ion Batteries. Nanoscale. 2017;9(28):10059&#x2013;10066. doi: 10.1039/C7NR03187D.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C7NR03187D</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28686263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang H., Kim H., Cho J.. MoS2 Nanoplates Consisting of Disordered Graphene-like Layers for High Rate Lithium Battery Anode Materials. Nano Lett. 2011;11:4826&#x2013;4830. doi: 10.1021/nl202675f.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/nl202675f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21958327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thangappan R., Kalaiselvam S., Elayaperumal A., Jayavel R., Arivanandhan M., Karthikeyan R., Hayakawa Y.. Graphene Decorated with MoS2 Nanosheets: A Synergetic Energy Storage Composite Electrode for Supercapacitor Applications. Dalt. Trans. 2016;45(6):2637&#x2013;2646. doi: 10.1039/C5DT04832J.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C5DT04832J</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26732466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohan M., Shetti N. P., Aminabhavi T. M.. Phase Dependent Performance of MoS2 for Supercapacitor Applications. J. Energy Storage. 2023;58:106321. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2022.106321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2022.106321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrivastav V., Mansi, Dubey P., Shrivastav V., Kaur A., Ho&#x142;dy&#x144;ski M., Krawczy&#x144;ska A., Tiwari U. K., Deep A., Nogala W., Sundriyal S.. Diffusion Controlled Electrochemical Analysis of MoS2 and MOF Derived Metal Oxide-Carbon Hybrids for High Performance Supercapacitors. Sci. Rep. 2023;13(1):20675. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-47730-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-47730-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10674017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38001163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasamani K. D., Alimohammadi F., Sun Y.. Interlayer-Expanded MoS2 . Mater. Today. 2017;20(2):83&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1016/j.mattod.2016.10.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mattod.2016.10.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janisch C., Song H., Zhou C., Lin Z., El&#xed;as A. L., Ji D., Terrones M., Gan Q., Liu Z.. MoS2 Monolayers on Nanocavities: Enhancement in Light-Matter Interaction. 2D Mater. 2016;3(2):25017. doi: 10.1088/2053-1583/3/2/025017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2053-1583/3/2/025017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu B., Sun Y., Liu L., Li C., Yu C., Zhang X., Chen Y.. Ultrasmall Fe2O3 Nanoparticles/MoS2 Nanosheets Composite as High-Performance Anode Material for Lithium Ion Batteries. Sci. Rep. 2017;7:42772. doi: 10.1038/srep42772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep42772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5316998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28218313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H., Zhu C., Zhang K., Chen Y., Li C., Gao P., Yang P., Ouyang Q.. Three-Dimensional Hierarchical MoS2 Nanoflake Array/Carbon Cloth as High-Performance Flexible Lithium-Ion Battery Anodes. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2014;2(13):4551&#x2013;4557. doi: 10.1039/C3TA14744D.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C3TA14744D</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasi S., Giofr&#xe8; S. V., Perathoner S., Mallamace D., Abate S., Wanderlingh U.. X-Ray Characterizations of Exfoliated MoS2 Produced by Microwave-Assisted Liquid-Phase Exfoliation. Materials (Basel). 2024;17:3887. doi: 10.3390/ma17163887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17163887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11355266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39203065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marinov A. D., Bravo Priegue L., Shah A. R., Miller T. S., Howard C. A., Hinds G., Shearing P. R., Cullen P. L., Brett D. J. L.. Ex Situ Characterization of 1T/2H MoS2 and Their Carbon Composites for Energy Applications, a Review. ACS Nano. 2023;17(6):5163&#x2013;5186. doi: 10.1021/acsnano.2c08913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsnano.2c08913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10062033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36926849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishna D. N. G., Philip J.. Review on Surface-Characterization Applications of X-Ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy (XPS): Recent Developments and Challenges. Appl. Surf. Sci. Adv. 2022;12:100332. doi: 10.1016/j.apsadv.2022.100332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsadv.2022.100332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambrosi A., Pumera M.. Electrochemical Exfoliation of MoS2 Crystal for Hydrogen Electrogeneration. Chem. - A Eur. J. 2018;24:18551&#x2013;18555. doi: 10.1002/chem.201804821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/chem.201804821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30462872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondekar N. P., Boebinger M. G., Woods E. V., McDowell M. T.. In Situ XPS Investigation of Transformations at Crystallographically Oriented MoS2 Interfaces. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2017;9(37):32394&#x2013;32404. doi: 10.1021/acsami.7b10230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.7b10230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28846377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker M. A., Gilmore R., Lenardi C., Gissler W.. XPS Investigation of Preferential Sputtering of S from MoS2 and Determination of MoSx Stoichiometry from Mo and S Peak Positions. Appl. Surf. Sci. 1999;150(1):255&#x2013;262. doi: 10.1016/S0169-4332(99)00253-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0169-4332(99)00253-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown N. M. D., Cui N., McKinley A.. An XPS Study of the Surface Modification of Natural MoS 2 Following Treatment in an RF-Oxygen Plasma. Appl. Surf. Sci. 1998;134:11&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1016/S0169-4332(98)00252-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0169-4332(98)00252-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma H., Ben S., Shen Z., Zhang X., Wu C., Liao S., An F.. Investigating the Exfoliation Behavior of MoS2 and Graphite in Water: A Comparative Study. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2020;512:145588. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2020.145588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2020.145588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adilbekova B., Lin Y., Yengel E., Faber H., Harrison G., Firdaus Y., El-Labban A., Anjum D. H., Tung V., Anthopoulos T. D.. Liquid Phase Exfoliation of MoS2 and WS2 in Aqueous Ammonia and Their Application in Highly Efficient Organic Solar Cells. J. Mater. Chem. C. 2020;8:5259&#x2013;5264. doi: 10.1039/D0TC00659A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D0TC00659A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma H., Shen Z., Ben S.. Understanding the Exfoliation and Dispersion of MoS2 Nanosheets in Pure Water. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2018;517:204&#x2013;212. doi: 10.1016/j.jcis.2017.11.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2017.11.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29427886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H., Wu J., Yin Z., Zhang H.. Preparation and Applications of Mechanically Exfoliated Single-Layer and Multilayer MoS2 and WSe2 Nanosheets. Acc. Chem. Res. 2014;47(4):1067&#x2013;1075. doi: 10.1021/ar4002312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ar4002312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24697842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manyepedza T., Courtney J. M., Snowden A., Jones C. R., Rees N. V.. Impact Electrochemistry of MoS2: Electrocatalysis and Hydrogen Generation at Low Overpotentials. J. Phys. Chem. C. 2022;126(42):17942&#x2013;17951. doi: 10.1021/acs.jpcc.2c06055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.2c06055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9619928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36330166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu J., Wang Z. C., Dai H., Wang Q., Yang R., Yu H., Liao M., Zhang J., Chen W., Wei Z., Li N., Du L., Shi D., Wang W., Zhang L., Jiang Y., Zhang G.. Boundary Activated Hydrogen Evolution Reaction on Monolayer MoS2 . Nat. Commun. 2019;10:1348. doi: 10.1038/s41467-019-09269-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-019-09269-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6430794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30902982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pesci F. M., Sokolikova M. S., Grotta C., Sherrell P. C., Reale F., Sharda K., Ni N., Palczynski P., Mattevi C.. MoS2/WS2 Heterojunction for Photoelectrochemical Water Oxidation. ACS Catal. 2017;7:4990&#x2013;4998. doi: 10.1021/acscatal.7b01517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acscatal.7b01517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Fevre L. W., Ejigu A., Todd R., Forsyth A. J., Dryfe R. A. W.. High Temperature Supercapacitors Using Water-in-Salt Electrolytes: Stability above 100 &#xb0;C. Chem. Commun. 2021;57:5294&#x2013;5297. doi: 10.1039/D1CC01087E.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D1CC01087E</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33942833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang C., Papadantonakis K. M., Lewis N. S.. Principles and Implementations of Electrolysis Systems for Water Splitting. Mater. Horizons. 2016;3(3):169&#x2013;173. doi: 10.1039/C6MH00016A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C6MH00016A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai T.-H., Lin H.-C., Lin M.-Y., Tsai T.-T.. The Analysis of Energy Efficiency of Water Electrolysis. Int. J. Eng. Sci. 2018;7(5):1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maeda T., Nagata Y., Endo N., Ishida M.. Effect of Water Electrolysis Temperature of Hydrogen Production System Using Direct Coupling Photovoltaic and Water Electrolyzer. J. Int. Counc. Electr. Eng. 2016;6:78&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1080/22348972.2016.1173783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/22348972.2016.1173783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu X., Shi R., Liu Y., He X., Li Q., Zhang Y., Zhao Y., Jiao S.. Expanding the Temperature Range of Stable Aqueous Batteries: Strategies, Mechanisms and Perspectives. Energy Environ. Sci. 2025;18(5):2165&#x2013;2215. doi: 10.1039/D4EE05304D.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D4EE05304D</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q., Xu S., Wang Y., Dou Q., Sun Y., Yan X.. Temperature-Dependent Structure and Performance Evolution of &#x201c;Water-in-Salt&#x201d; Electrolyte for Supercapacitor. Energy Storage Mater. 2023;55:205&#x2013;213. doi: 10.1016/j.ensm.2022.11.056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ensm.2022.11.056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang J., Liu B., Liu G., Qian D., Yang C., Li J.. A Systematically Comparative Study on LiNO3 and Li2SO4 Aqueous Electrolytes for Electrochemical Double-Layer Capacitors. Electrochim. Acta. 2018;274:121&#x2013;130. doi: 10.1016/j.electacta.2018.04.097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2018.04.097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;tz R., Carlen M.. Principles and Applications of Electrochemical Capacitors. Electrochim. Acta. 2000;45:2483&#x2013;2498. doi: 10.1016/S0013-4686(00)00354-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0013-4686(00)00354-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G., Xu Y., Yang T., Jiang L.. Recent Advances in Electrocatalysts for Seawater Splitting. Nano Mater. Sci. 2023;5(1):101&#x2013;116. doi: 10.1016/j.nanoms.2020.12.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoms.2020.12.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orazem, M. E. ; Tribollet, B. . Electrohydrodynamic Impedance. In Electrochemical Impedance Spectroscopy; John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd, 2017; pp 443&#x2013;464.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>