<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40911613</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-0573</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>2025</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Endocrinology, diabetes &amp; metabolism case reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Endocrinol Diabetes Metab Case Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A potential association between tirzepatide and hypercalcemia in the setting of chronic hydrochlorothiazide use.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e250067</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1530/EDM-25-0067</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Hypercalcemia is a prevalent electrolyte disturbance commonly associated with primary hyperparathyroidism, cancer, or medication adverse effects. Thiazide diuretics reduce urinary calcium excretion, increasing calcium reabsorption and hypercalcemia. Tirzepatide, a dual GIP and GLP-1 receptor agonist, is increasingly used for type 2 diabetes and obesity. While GIP/GLP-1 agonists typically have negligible effects on calcium homeostasis, the interaction between tirzepatide and thiazides remains unstudied. We report a 65-year-old female with obesity, hypertension, CKD3, and T2DM on chronic HCTZ who developed symptomatic hypercalcemia (corrected calcium: 4.58 mmol/L; normal range: 2.12-2.62 mmol/L), resulting in altered mental status days after initiating tirzepatide. PTH and vitamin D levels were low, and imaging ruled out malignancy. Discontinuation of tirzepatide/HCTZ, IV hydration, and calcitonin normalized her calcium by hospital day 4. This case highlights a potential association between HCTZ and tirzepatide in causing severe hypercalcemia. No prior reports link tirzepatide (or its combination with thiazides) to hypercalcemia. The mechanism likely involves thiazide-induced calcium reabsorption and tirzepatide's effects on bone turnover. As the use of tirzepatide and other GLP-1/GIP agonists becomes more prevalent, clinicians need to closely monitor calcium levels in thiazide-treated individuals, particularly those with CKD. Additional research is also needed to elucidate the drug's interaction with calcium metabolism.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEARNING POINTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Clinicians should be aware of the potential for severe hypercalcemia when tirzepatide is co-administered with chronic thiazide diuretics, particularly hydrochlorothiazide (HCTZ), in patients with pre-existing CKD. Tirzepatide, a dual GIP and GLP-1 receptor agonist, may influence calcium metabolism through mechanisms including increased osteoblastic activity and altered PTH regulation, especially in individuals with impaired renal clearance. Baseline and follow-up serum calcium monitoring is strongly recommended within 1-2 weeks of initiating tirzepatide in patients receiving thiazide diuretics or those with CKD. This case suggests a possible drug-drug interaction between tirzepatide and HCTZ leading to symptomatic hypercalcemia, highlighting the need for pharmacovigilance as newer agents are integrated into routine diabetes care. Severe hypercalcemia can present with nonspecific symptoms such as altered mental status, fatigue, constipation, and polyuria; clinicians should maintain a high index of suspicion in susceptible populations. Prompt cessation of the suspected offending agents, hydration, and short-term use of calcitonin can result in rapid and sustained normalization of calcium levels without the need for bisphosphonates.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nduma</LastName><ForeName>Basil</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Medical City Arlington, Arlington, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malapati</LastName><ForeName>Sai Nikhitha</ForeName><Initials>SN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-6256-3833</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Kamineni Academy of Medical Sciences and Research Center, Hyderabad, Telangana, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vibhuti</LastName><ForeName>Veeranna</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Medical City Arlington, Arlington, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Endocrinol Diabetes Metab Case Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101618943</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-0573</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic kidney disease (CKD)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydrochlorothiazide (HCTZ)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypercalcemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tirzepatide</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that there is no conflict of interest that could be perceived as prejudicing the impartiality of the work reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40911613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12423746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1530/EDM-25-0067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">e250067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mifsud S, Montanaro G, Craus S, et al. Thiazide diuretics and primary hyperparathyroidism. Br J Hosp Med 2023. 84 1&#x2013;8. ( 10.12968/hmed.2023.0228)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12968/hmed.2023.0228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38153014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinawi M. Disorders of calcium metabolism: hypocalcemia and hypercalcemia. Cureus 2021. 13 e12420. ( 10.7759/cureus.12420)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.12420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7849212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33542868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Seaghdha CM, Yang Q, Glazer NL, et al. Common variants in the calcium-sensing receptor gene are associated with total serum calcium levels. Hum Mol Genet 2010. 19 4296&#x2013;4303. ( 10.1093/hmg/ddq342)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/hmg/ddq342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2951868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20705733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alenezi BT, Elfezzani N, Uddin R, et al. Beyond glycemic control: GLP-1 receptor agonists and their impact on calcium homeostasis in real-world patients. J Clin Med 2024. 13 4896. ( 10.3390/jcm13164896)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm13164896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11355112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39201039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiellerup SP, Skov-Jeppesen K, Windel&#xf8;v JA, et al. Gut hormones and their effect on bone metabolism. Potential drug therapies in future osteoporosis treatment. Front Endocrinol 2019. 10 75. ( 10.3389/fendo.2019.00075)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2019.00075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6399108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30863364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skov-Jeppesen K, Christiansen CB, Hansen LS, et al. Effects of exogenous GIP and GLP-2 on bone turnover in individuals with type 2 diabetes. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2024. 109 1773&#x2013;1780. ( 10.1210/clinem/dgae022)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/clinem/dgae022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11180509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38217866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Xiao H, Lin S, et al. Effect of gut hormones on bone metabolism and their possible mechanisms in the treatment of osteoporosis. Front Pharmacol 2024. 15 1372399. ( 10.3389/fphar.2024.1372399)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2024.1372399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11079205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38725663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson TA, Incze MA &amp; Silverstein WK. Heightened vigilance needed when patients are prescribed GLP-1 and GIP agonists. JAMA Intern Med 2024. 184 1158&#x2013;1159. ( 10.1001/jamainternmed.2024.3732)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2024.3732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39102248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teles F, Pe&#xe7;anha de Miranda Coelho JA, Albino RM, et al. Effectiveness of thiazide and thiazide-like diuretics in advanced chronic kidney disease: a systematic review and meta analysis. Ren Fail 2023. 45 2163903. ( 10.1080/0886022X.2022.2163903)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0886022X.2022.2163903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9848247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36637019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MD Anderson Cancer Center . Hypercalcemia clinical management algorithm. MD Anderson Cancer Center, May, 2024. (https://www.mdanderson.org/content/dam/mdanderson/documents/forphysicians/algorithms/clinical-management/clin-management-hypercalcemia-web-algorithm.pdf)</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>