<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40942279</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2073-4360</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>17</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Polymers</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Polymers (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Poly(ethylene oxide) on the Foam Properties of Anionic Surfactants: Experiment and Molecular Dynamics Simulation.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2361</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/polym17172361</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Water-soluble polymers are often used as additives to adjust the foam properties of surfactant. In this study, the effects of water-soluble polymer poly(ethylene oxide) (PEO) on foam properties of two anionic surfactants, i.e., ammonium lauryl ether sulfate (ALES) and sodium dodecyl sulfate (SDS), were investigated by experimental and molecular dynamics simulation methods. Experimental results show that the addition of PEO can reduce the foaming ability of the two surfactants, but the inhibitory effect of PEO on the foaming ability is weakened at high surfactant concentration. Compared with ALES, PEO has a more significant inhibitory effect on the foaming ability of SDS. With the increase in PEO concentration, the half-life time of foam drainage in surfactant/water-soluble polymer composite systems gradually increases. The synergistic effect between PEO and ALES is stronger than that between PEO and SDS, resulting in a longer half-life time of foam drainage in ALES/PEO composite system. Molecular dynamics simulation results indicate that the addition of PEO can decline the air-water interface thickness of bubble films and the tail tilt angle of surfactant molecules at the air-water interface. The reduction in tail tilt angle means that the surfactant molecules are more vertical to the air-water interface and the hydrophobic interaction between adjacent tail chains of surfactants is weakened, which is unfavorable to the formation of bubble films, thus decreasing the foaming ability of surfactants. Because the ALES/PEO system has larger air-water interface thickness and surfactant tail tilt angle than the SDS/PEO system, the inhibitory effect of PEO on the foaming ability of ALES is weaker than that of SDS. Adding PEO can lower the peak position of the first hydration layer of surfactant head groups, increase the number of hydrogen bonds, and reduce the diffusion coefficient of water molecules, so that the surfactant/water-soluble polymer system has longer half-life time of foam drainage than the pure surfactant system. Due to the synergistic effect between ALES and PEO, the ALES/PEO system has a higher peak value of the first hydration layer of surfactant head groups, more hydrogen bonds, and lower diffusion coefficient of water molecules than the SDS/PEO system. Therefore, the half-life time of foam drainage in the ALES/PEO system is longer than that in the SDS/PEO system.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Chaohang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Safety Science and Emergency Management, Wuhan University of Technology, Wuhan 430070, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bi</LastName><ForeName>Ran</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Safety Science and Emergency Management, Wuhan University of Technology, Wuhan 430070, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Sijing</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Safety Science and Emergency Management, Wuhan University of Technology, Wuhan 430070, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaojun</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Safety Science and Emergency Management, Wuhan University of Technology, Wuhan 430070, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaolong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7350-2592</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Safety Engineering, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou 221116, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Guochun</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Grid Shandong Electric Power Research Institute, Jinan 250000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong Smart Grid Technology Innovation Center, Jinan 250002, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023YFC3008804</GrantID><Agency>National Key R&amp;D Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Polymers (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101545357</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2073-4360</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anionic surfactant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">foam drainage half-life time</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">foaming ability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">molecular dynamics simulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">poly(ethylene oxide)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Author Guochun Li was employed by the company State Grid Shandong Electric Power Research Institute. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40942279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12431101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym17172361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">polym17172361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sheng Y., Zhang S., Ma W., Peng Y., Ma L., Wang Q., Hu D. Tuning stability, rheology, and fire-extinguishing performance of advanced firefighting foam material by inorganic nanoparticle flame retardants. J. Colloid Interf. Sci. 2025;677:378&#x2013;389. doi: 10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39096706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Q., Fan L., Wang H., Han H., Zhu Z., Zhao X., Wang Y. A review of physical and chemical methods to improve the performance of water for dust reduction. Process Saf. Environ. Protec. 2022;166:86&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1016/j.psep.2022.07.065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2022.07.065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang L., Li H., Wang X., Liu N. Experimental study and field demonstration of air-foam flooding for heavy oil EOR. J. Petrol. Sci. Eng. 2020;185:106659. doi: 10.1016/j.petrol.2019.106659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2019.106659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui H., Cao G., Zhu S., Mu J., Liu X., Chou X. Foaming performance evaluation of frother emulsions in the slime flotation: Foamability, foam stability, and foam flow. Colloid. Surf. A-Physicochem. Eng. Asp. 2022;638:128310. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2022.128310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2022.128310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luengo G.S., Aubrun O., Restagno F. Foams in cosmetics: New trends in detergency, friction, coatings. Curr. Opin. Colloid Interface Sci. 2025;77:101906. doi: 10.1016/j.cocis.2025.101906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cocis.2025.101906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laporte M., Montillet A., Della Valle D., Loisel C., Riaublanc A. Characteristics of foams produced with viscous shear thinning fluids using microchannels at high throughput. J. Food Eng. 2016;173:25&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1016/j.jfoodeng.2015.10.032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfoodeng.2015.10.032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng Y., Zhang S., Hu D., Ma L., Li Y. Investigation on thermal stability of highly stable fluorine-free foam co-stabilized by silica nanoparticles and multi-component surfactants. J. Mol. Liq. 2023;382:122039. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2023.122039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2023.122039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bureko A., Trybala A., Kovalchuk N., Starov V. Current applications of foams formed from mixed surfactant-polymer solutions. Colloid Interface Sci. 2015;222:670&#x2013;677. doi: 10.1016/j.cis.2014.10.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cis.2014.10.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25455806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matouq M., Rafati R., Haddad A.S. Feasibility of using polymers to improve foam flow performance in vertical pipes: Application to liquid unloading in gas wells. Colloid. Surf. A-Physicochem. Eng. Asp. 2025;704:135545. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Momin S.A., Yeole P. Comparative study of effect of surfactant-polymer interactions on properties of alkyl polyglucosides and alpha olefin sulphonate. J. Surfactants. Deterg. 2012;15:291&#x2013;298. doi: 10.1007/s11743-011-1304-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11743-011-1304-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H., Wei X., Du Y., Wang D. Effect of water-soluble polymers on the performance of dust-suppression foams: Wettability, surface viscosity and stability. Colloid. Surf. A-Physicochem. Eng. Asp. 2019;568:92&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2019.01.062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2019.01.062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q., Qiu K., Li C., Li H., Zhang M., Liu H. Stability and rheological properties of firefighting foams with sodium carboxymethyl cellulose and hydrocarbon/silicone surfactants. Chem. Eng. Sci. 2024;288:119733. doi: 10.1016/j.ces.2024.119733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ces.2024.119733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueredo R.C.R., Sabadini E. Firefighting foam stability: The effect of the drag reducer poly(ethylene) oxide. Colloid. Surf. A-Physicochem. Eng. Asp. 2003;215:77&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1016/S0927-7757(02)00425-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0927-7757(02)00425-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C., Wu A., Zhao Z. Effect of sodium alginate and polyvinyl alcohol polymers on the foaming performance of dodecyl dimethyl betaine solutions. Colloid. Surf. A Physicochem. Eng. Asp. 2023;676:132151. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2023.132151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2023.132151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amankeldiyeva A., Kaumbekova S., Khalidulliyeva A., Salimova Z., Ibrayeva A., Cochennec M., Colombano S., Amanbek Y., Wang Y., Omirbekov S. Stability of colloidal gas aphrons based on polymer-surfactant formulations and molecular dynamics insights. Sci. Rep. 2025;15:23480. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-08100-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-08100-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12222480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40603561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu G., Zhu Q., Yuan C., Wang H., Li C., Sun S., Hu S. Molecular dynamics simulation of the influence of polyacrylamide on the stability of sodium dodecyl sulfate foam. Chem. Eng. Sci. 2017;166:313&#x2013;319. doi: 10.1016/j.ces.2017.03.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ces.2017.03.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C., Wang H., Wang D., Zhu X., Zhu Y., Bai X., Yang Q. Improvement of foaming ability of surfactant solutions by water-soluble polymers: Experiment and molecular dynamics simulation. Polymers. 2020;12:571. doi: 10.3390/polym12030571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym12030571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7182889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32143492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou J., Zhang C., Ranjith P.G. Highly stable polymer-enhanced pickering foams for hydraulic fracturing applications. Energy Fuels. 2023;37:9151&#x2013;9162. doi: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c01323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c01323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilmaz M., Yasin M., Mercimek O. Experimental study on out-of-plane behaviour of masonry walls strengthening with carbon fiber reinforced polymer sheets. Sci. Work. Azerbaijan Univ. Archit. Constr. 2023;2:58&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai C., Ding Q., Zhao M., Zhao J., Fang J., Li H. Construction and performance evaluation of a highly efficient mixed foaming system. RSC Adv. 2015;5:27978&#x2013;27985. doi: 10.1039/C5RA02166A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C5RA02166A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao T., Xu G., Yuan S., Chen Y., Yan H. Molecular dynamics study of alkyl benzene sulfonate at air/water interface: Effect of inorganic salts. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2010;114:5025&#x2013;5033. doi: 10.1021/jp907438x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp907438x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20353250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez L., Andrade R., Birgin E.G., Mart&#xed;nez J.M. Software news and update Packmol: A package for building initial configurations for molecular dynamics simulations. J. Comput. Chem. 2009;30:2157&#x2013;2164. doi: 10.1002/jcc.21224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcc.21224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19229944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berendsen H.J.C., van der Spoel D., van Drunen R. GROMACS: A message-passing parallel molecular dynamics implementation. Comput. Phys. Commun. 1995;91:43&#x2013;56. doi: 10.1016/0010-4655(95)00042-E.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0010-4655(95)00042-E</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorgensen W.L., Maxwell D.S., Tirado-Rives J. Development and testing of the OPLS all-atom force field on conformational energetics and properties of organic liquids. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 1996;118:11225&#x2013;11236. doi: 10.1021/ja9621760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ja9621760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hockney R.W. The potential calculation and some applications. Methods Comput. Phys. 1970;9:136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hess B., Bekker H., Berendsen H.J.C., Fraaije J.G.E.M. LINCS: A Linear Constraint Solver for Molecular Simulations. J. Comput. Chem. 1997;18:1463&#x2013;1472. doi: 10.1002/(SICI)1096-987X(199709)18:12&lt;1463::AID-JCC4&gt;3.0.CO;2-H.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1096-987X(199709)18:12&lt;1463::AID-JCC4&gt;3.0.CO;2-H</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Essmann U., Perera L., Berkowitz M.L. A smooth particle mesh Ewald method. J. Chem. Phys. 1995;103:8577&#x2013;8593. doi: 10.1063/1.470117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.470117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berendsen H.J.C., Grigera J.R., Straatsma T.P. The missing term in effective pair potentials. J. Phys. Chem. B. 1987;91:6269&#x2013;6271. doi: 10.1021/j100308a038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/j100308a038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans D.J., Holian B.L. The Nose-Hoover thermostat. J. Chem. Phys. 1985;83:4069&#x2013;4074. doi: 10.1063/1.449071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.449071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humphrey W., Dalke A., Schulten K. VMD: Visual Molecular Dynamics. J. Mol. Graph. 1996;14:33&#x2013;38. doi: 10.1016/0263-7855(96)00018-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0263-7855(96)00018-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8744570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao F., Liu G., Yuan S. The effect of betaine on the foam stability: Molecular simulation. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2017;407:156&#x2013;161. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2017.02.087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2017.02.087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>