<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41052644</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1546-170X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Lifetime benefits of comprehensive medical therapy in heart failure with mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>325</StartPage><EndPage>331</EndPage><MedlinePgn>325-331</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41591-025-04037-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitors (SGLT2i) and the nonsteroidal mineralocorticoid receptor antagonist (nsMRA) finerenone have each been shown to individually improve heart failure events among patients with heart failure and mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction (HFmrEF/HFpEF). Moreover, the angiotensin receptor neprilysin inhibitor (ARNI) sacubitril/valsartan has been shown to improve outcomes in patients with HFmrEF/HFpEF with a left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) below normal (&lt;60%). However, the expected benefits of the combined use of these agents with long-term administration are not well defined. Here, in this cross-trial analysis of DELIVER, FINEARTS-HF and PARAGON-HF, combined use of SGLT2i and nsMRA therapies was estimated to reduce the risk of cardiovascular death or first worsening heart failure event by 31% in the overall population (hazard ratio 0.69; 95% confidence interval 0.59-0.81), while combined use of SGLT2i, nsMRA and ARNI therapies was estimated to reduce risk by 39% in patients with HFmrEF/HFpEF and an LVEF &lt;60% (hazard ratio 0.61; 95% confidence interval 0.48-0.77). With long-term use, combined SGLT2i and nsMRA therapies in a 65-year-old patient with HFmrEF/HFpEF, or combined SGLT2i, nsMRA and ARNI therapies in a 65-year-old patient with an LVEF &lt;60%, were projected to afford 3.6 (2.0-5.2) or 4.9 (2.5-7.3) additional years free from cardiovascular death or a heart failure event, respectively. Combined therapy was estimated to result in meaningful gains in event-free survival across a broad age range, from 55 to 85&#x2009;years. Among patients with HFmrEF and HFpEF, the potential aggregated long-term treatment effects of early combination medical therapy with SGLT2i and nsMRA (and ARNI in selected individuals) are projected to be substantial.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vaduganathan</LastName><ForeName>Muthiah</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Claggett</LastName><ForeName>Brian L</ForeName><Initials>BL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chatur</LastName><ForeName>Safia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Desai</LastName><ForeName>Akshay S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1443-0701</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jhund</LastName><ForeName>Pardeep S</ForeName><Initials>PS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4306-5317</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>BHF Glasgow Cardiovascular Research Centre, School of Cardiovascular and Metabolic Medicine, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vardeny</LastName><ForeName>Orly</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6387-1351</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Chronic Disease Outcomes Research, Minneapolis VA Health Care System, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Merkely</LastName><ForeName>Bela</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6514-0723</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Semmelweis University, Heart and Vascular Centre, Budapest, Hungary.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Martinez</LastName><ForeName>Felipe</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidad Nacional de C&#xf3;rdoba, C&#xf3;rdoba, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Comin-Colet</LastName><ForeName>Josep</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8780-720X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bellvitge University Hospital (IDIBELL, CIBERCV), Universitat de Barcelona, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kerr Saraiva</LastName><ForeName>Jose F</ForeName><Initials>JF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pontifical Catholic University of Campinas, Campinas, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shah</LastName><ForeName>Sanjiv J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5655-8201</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lam</LastName><ForeName>Carolyn S P</ForeName><Initials>CSP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1903-0018</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Heart Centre Singapore, Duke-National University of Singapore, Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zannad</LastName><ForeName>Faiez</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7456-1570</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Lorraine, Nancy, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Docherty</LastName><ForeName>Kieran F</ForeName><Initials>KF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5446-9969</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>BHF Glasgow Cardiovascular Research Centre, School of Cardiovascular and Metabolic Medicine, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McMurray</LastName><ForeName>John J V</ForeName><Initials>JJV</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6317-3975</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>BHF Glasgow Cardiovascular Research Centre, School of Cardiovascular and Metabolic Medicine, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Solomon</LastName><ForeName>Scott D</ForeName><Initials>SD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3698-9597</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA. ssolomon@bwh.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9502015</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1078-8956</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000077203">Sodium-Glucose Transporter 2 Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001713">Biphenyl Compounds</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000451">Mineralocorticoid Receptor Antagonists</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000613">Aminobutyrates</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>80M03YXJ7I</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000068756">Valsartan</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C576501">finerenone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004338">Drug Combinations</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>WB8FT61183</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C549068">sacubitril and valsartan sodium hydrate drug combination</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013777">Tetrazoles</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D057911">Angiotensin Receptor Antagonists</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009287">Naphthyridines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006333" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heart Failure</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013318" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stroke Volume</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077203" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sodium-Glucose Transporter 2 Inhibitors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001713" MajorTopicYN="N">Biphenyl Compounds</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000451" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mineralocorticoid Receptor Antagonists</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000613" MajorTopicYN="N">Aminobutyrates</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068756" MajorTopicYN="N">Valsartan</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004338" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Combinations</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013777" MajorTopicYN="N">Tetrazoles</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057911" MajorTopicYN="N">Angiotensin Receptor Antagonists</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004359" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Therapy, Combination</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009287" MajorTopicYN="N">Naphthyridines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: M.V. has received research grant support, served on advisory boards or had speaker engagements with Alnylam Pharmaceuticals, American Regent, Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bayer AG, Baxter Healthcare, BMS, Boehringer Ingelheim, Chiesi, Cytokinetics, Esperion, Fresenius Medical Care, Idorsia Pharmaceuticals, Lexicon Pharmaceuticals, Merck, Milestone Pharmaceuticals, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Pharmacosmos, Recordati, Relypsa, Roche Diagnostics, Sanofi and Tricog Health, and participates on clinical trial committees for studies sponsored by Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bayer AG, Boehringer Ingelheim, Galmed, Impulse Dynamics, Novartis, Occlutech and Pharmacosmos. B.L.C. has received personal consulting fees from Alnylam, Bristol Myers Squibb, Cardior, Cardurion, Corvia, CVRx, Eli Lilly, Intellia and Rocket and has served on a DSMB for Novo Nordisk. S.C. is supported by the Canadian Child&#x2019;s Scholarship from the Libin Institute of Alberta/Cumming School of Medicine. A.S.D. has received institutional research grants (to Brigham and Women&#x2019;s Hospital) from Abbott, Alnylam, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Novartis and Pfizer as well as personal consulting fees from Abbott, Alnylam, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Biofourmis, Boston Scientific, Medpace, Medtronic, Merck, Novartis, Parexel, Porter Health, Regeneron, River2Renal, Roche, Veristat, Verily and Zydus. P.S.J. reports speakers&#x2019; fees from AstraZeneca, Novartis, Alkem Metabolics, ProAdWise Communications and Sun Pharmaceuticals; advisory board fees from AstraZeneca,Boehringer Ingelheim and Novartis; and research funding from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Analog Devices Inc and Roche Diagnostics. P.S.J.&#x2019;s employer, the University of Glasgow, has been remunerated for clinical trial work from AstraZeneca, Bayer AG, Novartis and Novo Nordisk. P.S.J. is also Director of GCTP Ltd. O.V. has received grants from AstraZeneca and Cardior, and institutional research support from Bayer and Cardurion. B.M. has received advisory board fees from Abbott, AstraZeneca, Biotronik, Boehringer Ingelheim, CSL Behring, Daiichi-Sankyo, Duke Clinical Institute, Medtronic and Novartis. B.M.&#x2019;s institution has received fees from Abbott, AstraZeneca, Biotronik, Boehringer Ingelheim, Boston Scientific, Bristol Myers Squibb, CSL Behring, Daiichi-Sankyo, Duke Clinical Institute, Eli Lilly, Medtronic, Novartis, Terumo and Vifor Pharma. F.M. has received consultation fees and research grants from AstraZeneca, Baliarda, Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Gador, Milestone, Novartis, Pfizer and St Lukes University. J.C.-C. has received grants from Novartis, Vifor Pharma, AstraZeneca and Orion Pharma and has received personal fees from Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Vifor Pharma, Novartis, AstraZeneca and Orion Pharma. J.F.K.S. has served on advisory boards for and received consulting fees and honoraria from Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Eli Lilly, Hypera, Medtronic, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Novartis, Novo Nordisk and Viatris. S.J.S. has received research grants from NIH (U54 HL160273, X01 HL169712, R01 HL140731 and R01 HL149423), AHA (24SFRNPCN1291224), AstraZeneca, Corvia, and Pfizer and consulting fees from Abbott, Alleviant, AstraZeneca, Amgen, Aria CV, Axon Therapies, Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Boston Scientific, Bristol Myers Squibb, Cyclerion, Cytokinetics, Edwards Lifesciences, Eidos, Imara, Impulse Dynamics, Intellia, Ionis, Lilly, Merck, MyoKardia, Novartis, Novo Nordisk,Pfizer, Prothena, Regeneron, Rivus, Sardocor, Shifamed, Tenax, Tenaya and Ultromics. C.S.P.L. has received research support from Novo Nordisk and Roche Diagnostics; has received consulting fees from Alleviant Medical, Allysta Pharma, AnaCardio AB, Applied Therapeutics, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Biopeutics, Boehringer Ingelheim, Boston Scientific, Bristol Myers Squibb, CardioRenal, CPC Clinical Research, Eli Lilly, Impulse Dynamics, Intellia Therapeutics, Ionis Pharmaceutical, Janssen Research &amp; Development LLC, Medscape/WebMD Global LLC, Merck, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Prosciento Inc, Quidel Corporation, Radcliffe Group Ltd., Recardio Inc, ReCor Medical, Roche Diagnostics, Sanofi, Siemens Healthcare Diagnostics and Us2.ai; and is a co-founder and non-executive director of Us2.ai. F.Z. reports personal fees from 89Bio, Abbott, Acceleron, Applied Therapeutics, Bayer, Betagenon, Boehringer, BMS, CVRx, Cambrian, Cardior, Cereno pharmaceutical, Cellprothera, CEVA, Inventiva, KBP, Merck, Novo Nordisk, Owkin, Otsuka, Roche Diagnostics, Northsea and Us2.ai, having stock options at G3Pharmaceutical and equities at Cereno, Cardiorenal and Eshmoun Clinical research and being the founder of Cardiovascular Clinical Trialists. K.F.D. reports that his employer, the University of Glasgow, has been remunerated by AstraZeneca for his work on clinical trials, and he has received speaker fees from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Pharmacosomos and Translational Medicine Academy; has served on advisory boards or performed consultancy for FIRE-1, Us2.ai and Bayer AG; holds stock in Us2.ai; has served on a Clinical Endpoint Committee for Bayer AG; and has received research grant support (paid to his institution) from AstraZeneca, Roche, Novartis and Boehringer Ingelheim. J.J.V.M. reports payments through Glasgow University from work on clinical trials, consulting and grants from Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Cardurion, Cytokinetics, GSK and Novartis; personal consultancy fees from Alnylam Pharmaceuticals,Amgen, AnaCardio, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Berlin Cures, BMS, Cardurion, Cytokinetics, IonisPharmaceuticals, Novartis, Regeneron Pharmaceuticals, River 2 Renal Corp., British Heart Foundation, National Institute for Health &#x2013; National Heart Lung and Blood Institute (NIH-NHLBI), Boehringer Ingelheim, SQ Innovations and Catalyze Group; and personal lecture fees from Abbott, Alkem Metabolics, AstraZeneca, Blue Ocean Scientific Solutions Ltd., Boehringer Ingelheim, Canadian Medical and Surgical Knowledge, Emcure Pharmaceuticals Ltd., Eris Lifesciences, European Academy of CME, Hikma Pharmaceuticals, Imagica Health, Intas Pharmaceuticals, J.B. Chemicals &amp; Pharmaceuticals Ltd., Lupin Pharmaceuticals, Medscape/Heart.Org., ProAdWise Communications, Radcliffe Cardiology, Sun Pharmaceuticals, The Corpus, Translation Research Group and Translational Medicine Academy. He serves on a DSMB for WIRB-CopernicusGroup Clinical Inc, and he is a director of Global Clinical Trial Partners Ltd. S.D.S. has received research grants from Alexion, Alnylam, AstraZeneca, Bellerophon, Bayer, BMS, Boston Scientific, Cytokinetics, Edgewise, Eidos, Gossamer, GSK, Ionis, Lilly, MyoKardia, NIH/NHLBI, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Respicardia, Sanofi Pasteur, Theracos and Us2.ai and has consulted for Abbott, Action, Akros, Alexion, Alnylam, Amgen, Arena, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, BMS, Cardior, Cardurion, Corvia, Cytokinetics, Daiichi-Sankyo, GSK, Lilly, Merck, Myokardia, Novartis, Roche, Theracos, Quantum Genomics, Janssen, CardiacDimensions, Tenaya, Sanofi Pasteur, Dinaqor, Tremeau, CellProThera, Moderna, American Regent, Sarepta, Lexicon, Anacardio, Akros and Valo.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41052644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12823412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-025-04037-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41591-025-04037-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shah, K. S. et al. Heart failure with preserved, borderline, and reduced ejection fraction: 5-year outcomes. <i>J. Am. Coll. Cardiol.</i><b>70</b>, 2476&#x2013;2486 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2017.08.074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29141781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anker, S. D. et al. Empagliflozin in heart failure with a preserved ejection fraction. <i>N. Engl. J. Med.</i><b>385</b>, 1451&#x2013;1461 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2107038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34449189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon, S. D. et al. Dapagliflozin in heart failure with mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction. <i>N. Engl. J. Med.</i><b>387</b>, 1089&#x2013;1098 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2206286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36027570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon, S. D. et al. Finerenone in heart failure with mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction. <i>N. Engl. J. Med.</i><b>391</b>, 1475&#x2013;1485 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2407107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39225278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon, S. D. et al. Angiotensin-neprilysin inhibition in heart failure with preserved ejection fraction. <i>N. Engl. J. Med.</i><b>381</b>, 1609&#x2013;1620 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1908655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31475794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon, S. D. et al. Sacubitril/valsartan across the spectrum of ejection fraction in heart failure. <i>Circulation</i><b>141</b>, 352&#x2013;361 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.119.044586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31736342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin, S. S. et al. 2025 heart disease and stroke statistics: a report of US and global data from the American Heart Association. <i>Circulation</i><b>151</b>, e41&#x2013;e660 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12256702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39866113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaduganathan, M. et al. Estimating lifetime benefits of comprehensive disease-modifying pharmacological therapies in patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction: a comparative analysis of three randomised controlled trials. <i>Lancet</i><b>396</b>, 121&#x2013;128 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30748-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32446323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonagh, T. A. et al. 2023 focused update of the 2021 ESC guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure. <i>Eur. Heart J.</i><b>44</b>, 3627&#x2013;3639 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehad195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37622666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heidenreich, P. A. et al. 2022 AHA/ACC/HFSA guideline for the management of heart failure: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines. <i>Circulation</i><b>145</b>, e895&#x2013;e1032 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35363499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell, P., Rutten, F. H., Lee, M. M., Hawkins, N. M. &amp; Petrie, M. C. Heart failure with preserved ejection fraction: everything the clinician needs to know. <i>Lancet</i><b>403</b>, 1083&#x2013;1092 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(23)02756-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38367642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaduganathan, M. et al. Estimating the benefits of combination medical therapy in heart failure with mildly reduced and preserved ejection fraction. <i>Circulation</i><b>145</b>, 1741&#x2013;1743 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.121.058929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35603667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, M. et al. Dapagliflozin in patients with heart failure with mildly reduced and preserved ejection fraction treated with a mineralocorticoid receptor antagonist or sacubitril/valsartan. <i>Eur. J. Heart Fail.</i><b>24</b>, 2307&#x2013;2319 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejhf.2722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11497302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36342375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaduganathan, M. et al. Effects of the nonsteroidal MRA finerenone with and without concomitant SGLT2 inhibitor use in heart failure. <i>Circulation</i><b>151</b>, 149&#x2013;158 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.072055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11732259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39340828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jering, K. S. et al. Cardiovascular and renal outcomes of mineralocorticoid receptor antagonist use in PARAGON-HF. <i>JACC Heart Fail.</i><b>9</b>, 13&#x2013;24 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jchf.2020.08.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33189633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira, J. P. et al. Sodium&#x2013;glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitor with and without an aldosterone antagonist for heart failure with preserved ejection fraction: the SOGALDI-PEF trial. <i>J. Am. Coll. Cardiol.</i><b>86</b>, 320&#x2013;333 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2025.05.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40738559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal, R. et al. Finerenone with empagliflozin in chronic kidney disease and type 2 diabetes. <i>N. Engl. J. Med</i>. 10.1056/NEJMoa2410659 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41160832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claggett, B. et al. Estimating the long-term treatment benefits of sacubitril&#x2013;valsartan. <i>N. Engl. J. Med.</i><b>373</b>, 2289&#x2013;2290 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMc1509753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26630151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira, J. P. et al. Within trial comparison of survival time projections from short-term follow-up with long-term follow-up findings. <i>ESC Heart Fail.</i><b>9</b>, 3655&#x2013;3658 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ehf2.13731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9715817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35799450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaduganathan, M. et al. Blinded withdrawal of finerenone after long-term treatment in the FINEARTS-HF trial. <i>J. Am. Coll. Cardiol.</i><b>86</b>, 396&#x2013;399 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2025.05.038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40738565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer, M. et al. Blinded withdrawal of long-term randomized treatment with empagliflozin or placebo in patients with heart failure. <i>Circulation</i><b>148</b>, 1011&#x2013;1022 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.123.065748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10516173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37621153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuen, B. L. et al. Sodium&#x2013;glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors and risk of hyperkalemia in people with type 2 diabetes: a meta-analysis of individual participant data from randomized, controlled trials. <i>Circulation</i><b>145</b>, 1460&#x2013;1470 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.121.057736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35394821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai, A. S. et al. Reduced risk of hyperkalemia during treatment of heart failure with mineralocorticoid receptor antagonists by use of sacubitril/valsartan compared with enalapril: a secondary analysis of the PARADIGM-HF trial. <i>JAMA Cardiol.</i><b>2</b>, 79&#x2013;85 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamacardio.2016.4733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27842179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mebazaa, A. et al. Safety, tolerability and efficacy of up-titration of guideline-directed medical therapies for acute heart failure (STRONG-HF): a multinational, open-label, randomised, trial. <i>Lancet</i><b>400</b>, 1938&#x2013;1952 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(22)02076-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36356631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer, M. et al. Tirzepatide for heart failure with preserved ejection fraction and obesity. <i>N. Engl. J. Med.</i><b>392</b>, 427&#x2013;437 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2410027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39555826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosiborod, M. N. et al. Semaglutide in patients with heart failure with preserved ejection fraction and obesity. <i>N. Engl. J. Med.</i><b>389</b>, 1069&#x2013;1084 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2306963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37622681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosiborod, M. N. et al. Semaglutide in patients with obesity-related heart failure and type 2 diabetes. <i>N. Engl. J. Med.</i><b>390</b>, 1394&#x2013;1407 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2313917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38587233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yusuf, S. et al. Effects of candesartan in patients with chronic heart failure and preserved left-ventricular ejection fraction: the CHARM-Preserved Trial. <i>Lancet</i><b>362</b>, 777&#x2013;781 (2003).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(03)14285-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13678871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massie, B. M. et al. Irbesartan in patients with heart failure and preserved ejection fraction. <i>N. Engl. J. Med.</i><b>359</b>, 2456&#x2013;2467 (2008).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa0805450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19001508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaduganathan, M. et al. A putative placebo analysis of the effects of sacubitril/valsartan in heart failure across the full range of ejection fraction. <i>Eur. Heart J.</i><b>41</b>, 2356&#x2013;2362 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7327532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32221596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peikert, A. et al. Efficacy and safety of dapagliflozin in heart failure with mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction according to age: the DELIVER trial. <i>Circ. Heart Fail.</i><b>15</b>, e010080 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCHEARTFAILURE.122.010080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36029467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaduganathan, M. et al. SGLT-2 inhibitors in patients with heart failure: a comprehensive meta-analysis of five randomised controlled trials. <i>Lancet</i><b>400</b>, 757&#x2013;767 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(22)01429-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36041474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jhund, P. S. et al. Mineralocorticoid receptor antagonists in heart failure: an individual patient level meta-analysis. <i>Lancet</i><b>404</b>, 1119&#x2013;1131 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(24)01733-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39232490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chimura, M. et al. Finerenone improves outcomes in patients with heart failure with mildly reduced or preserved ejection fraction irrespective of age: a prespecified analysis of FINEARTS-HF. <i>Circ. Heart Fail.</i><b>17</b>, e012437 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCHEARTFAILURE.124.012437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11573060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39342655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X. et al. Effect of sacubitril/valsartan in heart failure with preserved ejection fraction across the age spectrum in PARAGON-HF. <i>Eur. J. Heart Fail.</i><b>27</b>, 96&#x2013;106 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejhf.3535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39675788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>