<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39669713</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2325-9671</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Orthopaedic journal of sports medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Orthop J Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Identifying Hip Arthroscopy Trends in Turkey.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23259671241293741</StartPage><MedlinePgn>23259671241293741</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">23259671241293741</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/23259671241293741</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Hip arthroscopy (HA) procedures have continued to increase worldwide. However, no data are currently available regarding the increasing HA case volume and trends in Turkey.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To identify trends in postoperative care habits and incidence of HA in Turkey using data from the national Health Coding Reference Server (SKRS) database.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Cross-sectional study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Patients who underwent HA and were recorded in the SKRS database between 2016 and 2023 were identified and retrospectively analyzed. Age, sex, institution type, geographic zone, and number of procedures were determined. The incidence of HA, overall annual case volume, chemoprophylaxis prescriptions, and postoperative care habits were also evaluated. The International Classification of Diseases, 10th Revision codes for femoral neck fracture after the index procedure and total hip arthroplasty conversion rate were analyzed. The authors utilized Poisson regression to determine the ratios of before and after periods in comparison with the same periods. Statistical analysis was performed using the statistical package SPSS software.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In total, 1580 HA procedures were identified. The mean age of the included patients was 39.2 &#xb1; 11.0 years (range, 18-65 years). Throughout the research period, an 833% increase in the number of surgeries was observed, whereas the incidence increased from 0.37 to 2.86 per 100,000 cases (<i>P</i> = .001). A significant annual increase in incidence was noted from 2017, 2018 and 2021 compared with the respective prior year. Moreover, 56.1% of all HA cases were performed in the Marmara region, whereas 47.7% of the cases were treated in private hospitals. Femoral neck fractures were encountered in 2 (0.1%) cases throughout the study duration. Enoxaparin sodium was the most preferred chemoprophylactic drug (99.4%). The 2-year total hip arthroplasty conversion rate was 3.5%.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study describes the current trends in HA across Turkey and provides a perspective on physician preferences. Notably, HA procedure counts, the ratio between HA and other orthopaedic procedures, and the incidence of HA demonstrated an increasing trend, with enormous potential for further advancement. These findings highlight the need for the creation of a national registry capable of obtaining more specific and accurate data.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2024.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cirdi</LastName><ForeName>Yigit Umur</ForeName><Initials>YU</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4804-8823</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics and Traumatology, Acibadem Atasehir Hospital, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bingol</LastName><ForeName>Izzet</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics and Traumatology, Faculty of Medicine, Ankara Oncology Training and Research Hospital, Health Sciences University, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamac&#x131;</LastName><ForeName>Sayg&#x131;n</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8887-9333</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Hacettepe University, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bayram</LastName><ForeName>Sinem</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Directorate of Health Information Systems, Ministry of Health, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ata</LastName><ForeName>Naim</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Directorate of Health Information Systems, Ministry of Health, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ulgu</LastName><ForeName>M Mahir</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Directorate of Health Information Systems, Ministry of Health, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Birinci</LastName><ForeName>Suayip</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministry of Health, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kayaalp</LastName><ForeName>Asim</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Ankara Cankaya Hospital, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gursoy</LastName><ForeName>Safa</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics and Traumatology, Faculty of Medicine, Acibadem Mehmet Ali Aydinlar University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Orthop J Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101620522</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2325-9671</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hip arthroscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hip: femoroacetabular impingement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">replacement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sports medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">total hip arthroplasty</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared that they have no conflicts of interest in the authorship and publication of this contribution. AOSSM checks author disclosures against the Open Payments Database (OPD). AOSSM has not conducted an independent investigation on the OPD and disclaims any liability or responsibility relating thereto.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39669713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11635892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671241293741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_23259671241293741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aali Rezaie A, Azboy I, Parvizi J. Venous thromboembolism prophylaxis after hip preservation surgery: a review and presentation of institutional experience. J Hip Preserv Surg. 2018;5(3):181-189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6206688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30393544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayeni OR, Bedi A, Lorich DG, Kelly BT. Femoral neck fracture after arthroscopic management of femoroacetabular impingement: a case report. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2011;93(9):e47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21543668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beckmann JT, Wylie JD, Potter MQ, Maak TG, Greene TH, Aoki SK. Effect of naproxen prophylaxis on heterotopic ossification following hip arthroscopy: a double-blind randomized placebo-controlled trial. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2015;97(24):2032-2037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4673445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26677237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedi A, Zbeda RM, Bueno VF, Downie B, Dolan M, Kelly BT. The incidence of heterotopic ossification after hip arthroscopy. Am J Sports Med. 2012;40(4):854-863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22268230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhargava K, Bhandari F, Board T, et al. Effect of COVID-19 pandemic on hip preservation surgery&#x2014;a prospective surveillance from the UK Non-Arthroplasty Hip Registry. J Hip Preserv Surg. 2021;8(3):225-232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8689916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35411217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birinci &#x15e;. A digital opportunity for patients to manage their health: Turkey National Personal Health Record System (The e-Nab&#x131;z). Balkan Med J. 2023;40(3):215-221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10175887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37114621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolia IK, Fagotti L, McNamara S, Dornan G, Briggs KK, Philippon MJ. A systematic review-meta-analysis of venous thromboembolic events following primary hip arthroscopy for FAI: clinical and epidemiologic considerations. J Hip Preserv Surg. 2018;5(3):190-201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6206692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30393545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonazza NA, Homcha B, Liu G, Leslie DL, Dhawan A. Surgical trends in arthroscopic hip surgery using a large national database. Arthroscopy. 2018;34(6):1825-1830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29580743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozic KJ, Chan V, Valone FH, III, Feeley BT, Vail TP. Trends in hip arthroscopy utilization in the United States. J Arthroplasty. 2013;28(8 suppl):140-143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23916639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;chler L, Grob V, Anwander H, Lerch TD, Haefeli PC. Good outcome scores and low conversion rate to THA 10 years after hip arthroscopy for the treatment of femoroacetabular impingement. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2021;479(10):2256-2264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8445580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33929975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrd JWT. Femoroacetabular impingement in athletes: current concepts. Am J Sports Med. 2013;42(3):737-751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23982400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colvin AC, Harrast J, Harner C. Trends in hip arthroscopy. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2012;94(4):e23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22336982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cvetanovich GL, Chalmers PN, Levy DM, et al. Hip arthroscopy surgical volume trends and 30-day postoperative complications. Arthroscopy. 2016;32(7):1286-1292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27067059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de SA D, Phillips M, Philippon MJ, Letkemann S, Simunovic N, Ayeni OR. Ligamentum teres injuries of the hip: a systematic review examining surgical indications, treatment options, and outcomes. Arthroscopy. 2014;30(12):1634-1641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25125381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira GE, O&#x2019;Keeffe M, Maher CG, et al. The effectiveness of hip arthroscopic surgery for the treatment of femoroacetabular impingement syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sci Med Sport. 2021;24(1):21-29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32616421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganz R, Parvizi J, Beck M, et al. Femoroacetabular impingement: a cause for osteoarthritis of the hip. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2003;(417):112-120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14646708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatz M, Driessen A, Eschweiler J, Tingart M, Migliorini F. Arthroscopic surgery versus physiotherapy for femoroacetabular impingement: a meta-analysis study. Eur J Orthop Surg Traumatol. 2020;30(7):1151-1162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7505824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32382825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gedouin JE, May O, Bonin N, et al. Assessment of arthroscopic management of femoroacetabular impingement. A prospective multicenter study. Orthop Traumatol Surg Res. 2010;96(8 suppl):S59-S67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21035415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin DR, Dickenson EJ, Wall PDH, et al. Hip arthroscopy versus best conservative care for the treatment of femoroacetabular impingement syndrome (UK FASHIoN): a multicentre randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2018;391(10136):2225-2235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5988794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29893223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haldane CE, Ekhtiari S, de Sa D, et al. Venous thromboembolism events after hip arthroscopy: a systematic review. Arthroscopy. 2018;34(1):321-330.e321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28969946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris JD, McCormick FM, Abrams GD, et al. Complications and reoperations during and after hip arthroscopy: a systematic review of 92 studies and more than 6,000 patients. Arthroscopy. 2013;29(3):589-595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23544691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodakowski AJ, McCormick JR, Patel MS, et al. Social media in hip arthroscopy is an underused resource that enhances physician online reputation. Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil. 2022;4(2):e349-e357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9042750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35494268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoit G, Whelan DB, Ly P, Saskin R, Atrey A, Khoshbin A. Conversion to total hip arthroplasty after hip arthroscopy: a cohort-based survivorship study with a minimum of 2-year follow-up. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2021;29(20):885-893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33201044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holler JT, Halvorson RT, Salesky M, et al. Incidence of venous thromboembolism after hip arthroscopy is low with or without prophylaxis but risk factors include oral contraceptive use, obesity, and malignancy. Arthroscopy. 2023;39(4):981-987.e981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36334853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horner NS, Khanduja V, MacDonald AE, Naendrup JH, Simunovic N, Ayeni OR. Femoral neck fractures as a complication of hip arthroscopy: a systematic review. J Hip Preserv Surg. 2017;4(1):9-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5467412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28630716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karelson MC, Jokihaara J, Launonen AP, Huttunen T, Mattila VM. Lower nationwide rates of arthroscopic procedures in 2016 compared with 1997 (634925 total arthroscopic procedures): has the tide turned? Br J Sports Med. 2021;55(18):1018-1023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8408579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32241819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly BT, Williams RJ, III, Philippon MJ. Hip arthroscopy: current indications, treatment options, and management issues. Am J Sports Med. 2003;31(6):1020-1037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14623676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khazi ZM, An Q, Duchman KR, Westermann RW. Incidence and risk factors for venous thromboembolism following hip arthroscopy: a population-based study. Arthroscopy. 2019;35(8):2380-2384.e2381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31395174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kucharik MP, Abraham PF, Nazal MR, et al. Arthroscopic acetabular labral repair versus labral debridement: long-term survivorship and functional outcomes. Orthop J Sports Med. 2022;10(7):23259671221109012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9274418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35837442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyin C, Maldonado DR, Go CC, et al. Mid- to long-term outcomes of hip arthroscopy: a systematic review. Arthroscopy. 2021;37(3):1011-1025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33220468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YK, Ha YC, Hwang DS, Koo KH. Learning curve of basic hip arthroscopy technique: CUSUM analysis. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2013;21(8):1940-1944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23073816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YK, Ha YC, Yoon BH, Koo KH. National trends of hip arthroscopy in Korea. J Korean Med Sci. 2014;29(2):277-280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3924010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24550658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindman I, &#xd6;hlin A, Desai N, et al. Five-year outcomes after arthroscopic surgery for femoroacetabular impingement syndrome in elite athletes. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48(6):1416-1422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7227125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32195598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litrenta J, Mu BH, Ortiz-Declet V, et al. Hip arthroscopy successfully treats femoroacetabular impingement in adolescent athletes. J Pediatr Orthop. 2020;40(3):e156-e160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31192888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maradit Kremers H, Schilz SR, Van Houten HK, et al. Trends in utilization and outcomes of hip arthroscopy in the United States between 2005 and 2013. J Arthroplasty. 2017;32(3):750-755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27793498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mather RC, III, Nho SJ, Federer A, et al. Effects of arthroscopy for femoroacetabular impingement syndrome on quality of life and economic outcomes. Am J Sports Med. 2018;46(5):1205-1213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29533689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merz MK, Christoforetti JJ, Domb BG. Femoral neck fracture after arthroscopic femoroplasty of the hip. Orthopedics. 2015;38(8):e696-e700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26270756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minkara AA, Westermann RW, Rosneck J, Lynch TS. Systematic review and meta-analysis of outcomes after hip arthroscopy in femoroacetabular impingement. Am J Sports Med. 2019;47(2):488-500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29373805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mok TN, He QY, Teng Q, et al. Arthroscopic hip surgery versus conservative therapy on femoroacetabular impingement syndrome: a meta-analysis of RCTs. Orthop Surg. 2021;13(6):1755-1764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8523765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34351052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montgomery SR, Ngo SS, Hobson T, et al. Trends and demographics in hip arthroscopy in the United States. Arthroscopy. 2013;29(4):661-665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23375668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullis BH, Dahners LE. Hip arthroscopy to remove loose bodies after traumatic dislocation. J Orthop Trauma. 2006;20(1):22-26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16424806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers SR, Eijer H, Ganz R. Anterior femoroacetabular impingement after periacetabular osteotomy. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1999;(363):93-99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10379309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer AJ, Malak TT, Broomfield J, et al. Past and projected temporal trends in arthroscopic hip surgery in England between 2002 and 2013. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2016;2(1):e000082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5117047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27900161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry AK, DeFroda SF, Gursoy S, et al. Top ten pearls for successful hip arthroscopy for femoroacetabular impingement. Arthrosc Tech. 2021;10(8):e2033-e2042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8355535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34401251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid GD, Reid CG, Widmer N, Munk PL. Femoroacetabular impingement syndrome: an underrecognized cause of hip pain and premature osteoarthritis? J Rheumatol. 2010;37(7):1395-1404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20516017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saberi Hosnijeh F, Kavousi M, Boer CG, et al. Development of a prediction model for future risk of radiographic hip osteoarthritis. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2018;26(4):540-546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29382605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sardana V, Philippon MJ, de Sa D, et al. Revision hip arthroscopy indications and outcomes: a systematic review. Arthroscopy. 2015;31(10):2047-2055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26033461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schairer WW, Nwachukwu BU, McCormick F, Lyman S, Mayman D. Use of hip arthroscopy and risk of conversion to total hip arthroplasty: a population-based analysis. Arthroscopy. 2016;32(4):587-593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26671201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf6;der JH, Kr&#xfc;ger D, Perka C, Hufeland M. Arthroscopic treatment for primary septic arthritis of the hip in adults. Adv Orthop. 2016;2016:8713037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5069383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27800188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sing DC, Feeley BT, Tay B, Vail TP, Zhang AL. Age-related trends in hip arthroscopy: a large cross-sectional analysis. Arthroscopy. 2015;31(12):2307-2313.e2302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26194938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong JSH, Cheung KMC. Impact of COVID-19 on orthopaedic and trauma service: an epidemiological study. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2020;102(14):e80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7431143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32675668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>W&#xf6;rner T, Eek F, Kraus-Schmitz J, Sansone M, St&#xe5;lman A. Rapid decline of yearly number of hip arthroscopies in Sweden: a retrospective time series of 6,105 hip arthroscopies based on a national patient data register. Acta Orthop. 2021;92(5):562-567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8519534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34018896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang AL, Kreulen C, Ngo SS, et al. Demographic trends in arthroscopic SLAP repair in the United States. Am J Sports Med. 2012;40(5):1144-1147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22328710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zingg PO, Buehler TC, Poutawera VR, Alireza A, Dora C. Femoral neck fractures after arthroscopic femoral neck osteochondroplasty for femoroacetabular impingement. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2014;22(4):926-931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23263229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zusmanovich M, Haselman W, Serrano B, Banffy M. The incidence of hip arthroscopy in patients with femoroacetabular impingement syndrome and labral pathology increased by 85% between 2011 and 2018 in the United States. Arthroscopy. 2022;38(1):82-87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33964383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>