<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41872293</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Model test study on the vertical bearing performance of post-grouted piles based on different grouting materials.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-44882-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Post-grouting is an effective engineering technique for enhancing the bearing performance of pile foundations, and the grouting material is a key factor determining the performance of post-grouted piles. In this study, different grouting materials (fly ash-cement, geopolymer, cement, and cement-sodium silicate) were adopted in laboratory tests. Model tests of post-grouted piles were conducted under simulated groundwater flow conditions and long-term loading scenarios to investigate the influence of various grouting materials on pile bearing performance under vertical loading. The research focuses on the characteristics of load- settlement curves, the axial force transfer along the pile, and the mobilization behavior of side resistance and tip resistance, and employs scanning electron microscopy (SEM) tests to reveal the action mechanisms of different grouting materials. The test results indicate that the grouting process significantly enhances the pile-soil interaction. Compared with the ungrouted piles, the bearing capacity of the grouted piles increases markedly. Under flowing-water conditions, the cement-sodium silicate double-liquid grout provides the best reinforcement effect around the pile due to its short gel time, rapid solidification, and dense hydration products, whereas the fly ash-cement and geopolymer grouts mainly improve the soil via permeation grouting, with the hydration reaction of fly ash proceeding relatively slowly.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chu</LastName><ForeName>Chaomin</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ningbo Datong Development Co., Ltd, Ningbo, 315000, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yi</LastName><ForeName>Tianxing</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ningbo Datong Development Co., Ltd, Ningbo, 315000, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qin</LastName><ForeName>Yunjie</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ningbo Datong Development Co., Ltd, Ningbo, 315000, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hou</LastName><ForeName>Xuefei</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ningbo Yongtaiwen Transportation Development Co., Ltd, Ningbo, 315000, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dai</LastName><ForeName>Guoliang</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Southeast University, Nanjing, 211189, Jiangsu, China. daigl@seu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>52508371</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bearing characteristics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Grouting materials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-grouted pile</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41872293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-44882-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-44882-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Z., Wang, K., Feng, H., Tian, Y. &amp; Zhu, S. Centrifugal model test of post grouting pile group in loess area. Soil Dyn. Earthq. Eng. 151, 106985 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, Z. K., Wang, T. H. &amp; Jin, X. Study on permeation grouting rules for loess and method for predicting migration radius. KSCE J. Civ. Eng. 25(8), 2876&#x2013;2883 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji, Z., Dai, G., Hu, Y. &amp; Liu, H. Study on mechanical response and mechanism analysis of bored piles under different grouting combinations in coastal regions. Soil Dyn. Earthq. Eng. 198, 16 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao, D. P.; Wu, C. Q.; Wu, C. L. Bored pile post-grouting technology and its engineering application. Adv. Ground Improve. Res. Pract. 198&#x2013;206 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing, H. F., Liu, L. L. &amp; Luo, Y. Effects of construction technology on bearing behaviors of rock-socketed bored piles as bridge foundations. J. Bridge Eng. 24(4), 05019002 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, P. et al. Grouting diffusion characteristics in faults considering the interaction of multiple grouting. Int. J. GeoMech. 17(5), 04016117 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Y. et al. Grout diffusion mechanism along the pile shaft during the process of pile tip post-grouting in sand. Appl. Sci. 14(13), 5389 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Y., Deng, Y. T., Zhang, X. F., Zhao, C. &amp; Zhao, C. F. Modeling of grout returned height for postgrouting at pile tip considering the soil unloading and time-dependent behavior of cement viscosity effects. Int. J. GeoMech. 23(8), 04023127 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Y., Zhao, C., Zhao, C. F., Wang, Y. B. &amp; Fei, Y. Effect of grout conditions on the mechanical behaviors of unloading sand-concrete interface for reinforcing bored pile foundation. Constr. Build. Mater. 243, 118218 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiyyakkandi, S., Mcvay, M., Bloomquist, D. &amp; Lai, P. Experimental study, numerical modeling of and axial prediction approach to base grouted drilled shafts in cohesionless soils. Acta Geotech. 9, 439&#x2013;454 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong, D. Z., Li, H. &amp; Gan, W. S. Study on vertical load-carrying capacity of post grouting bored piles. Appl. Sci. 12(15), 7452 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>OuYang, H., Gong, Z., Zhu, M., Liu, H., Liu, Z., Dai, G. &amp; Gong, W. Numerical analysis of lateral bearing capacity of monopiles in clay, part 1: single uniform and isotropic soil layer with strength profile su = su1 &#xd7; z. Computers and Geotechnics 184, 107294 (2025). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compgeo.2025.107294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, N. W., Zhang, Z. M., Zhang, Q. Q. &amp; Fang, K. Destructive field tests on mobilization of end resistance of cast-in-situ bored piles. J. Cent. South Univ. 20, 1071&#x2013;1078 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, T., Wan, Z. &amp; Dai, G. Prediction and design of grouting parameters for long and large-diameter postgrouted drilled shafts. Int. J. Geomech. 24(2), 13 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullins, G., Winters, D. &amp; Dapp, S. Predicting end bearing capacity of post-grouted drilled shaft in cohesionless soils. J. Geotech. Geoenviron. Eng. https://doi.org/10.1061/(ASCE)1090-0241(2006)132:4(478) (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J. Exploring the relationship between the bottom rocks of the pile and the pile hole cleaning. Adv. Mater. Res. 261&#x2013;263, 999&#x2013;1002 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>OuYang, H., Chen, X., Gong, Z., Zuo, C., Dai, G. &amp; Gong, W. Large-scale model test study on lateral bearing characteristics of semi-rigid pile with cement-soil reinforcement under multistage loading and unidirectional multi-cycle loading in clay. Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering 195, 109421 (2025). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.soildyn.2025.109421</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, J., Cheng, Y. &amp; Chen, W. Experimental study on diffusion law of post-grouting slurry in sandy soil. Adv. Civ. Eng. https://doi.org/10.1155/2019/3493942 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, X., Wang, X., Cai, C. &amp; Yao, W. Improved calculation method of super-long pile in deep soft soil area. Int. J. Geomech. 18, 1&#x2013;11 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing, H. &amp; Liu, L. Field tests on influencing factors of negative skin friction for pile foundations in collapsible loess regions. Int. J. Civ. Eng. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40999-018-0294-z (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, M., Zhang, F. &amp; Ni, P. Load&#x2013;settlement behaviour of membrane-confined grouted pile: Experimental and analytical study. Acta Geotech. 18(5), 17 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, S. W., Zhang, Q. Q. &amp; Li, H. T. An analysis method for the response of combined side-and-tip grouting pile. Acta Geotech. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11440-022-01788-y (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambroise, J., Maximilien, S. &amp; Pera, J. Properties of metakaolin blended cements. Adv. Cem. Res. 1(4), 161&#x2013;168 (1994).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z. J. &amp; Ding, Z. Property improvement of Portland cement by incorporating with metakaolin and slag. Cem. Concr. Res. 33(4), 579&#x2013;584 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palomo, A., Macias, A. &amp; Blanco, M. T. Physical, chemical and mechanical characterization of geopolymers. Proc. 9th Int. Congr. Chem. Cem. 11, 505&#x2013;511 (1992).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alonso, S. &amp; Palomo, A. Calorimetric study of alkaline activation of calcium hydroxide-metakaolin solid mixtures. Cem. Concr. Res. 31(1), 25&#x2013;30 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Susan, A., Erich, D. &amp; Ruby, M. Mechanical and thermal characterization of geopolymers based on silicate-activated metakaolin/slag blends. J. Mater. Sci. 46, 5477&#x2013;5486 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuenzel, C., Li, L. &amp; Vandeperre, L. Influence of sand on the mechanical properties of metakaolin geopolymers. Constr. Build. Mater. 66, 442&#x2013;446 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poon, C. S., Kou, S. C. &amp; Lam, L. Compressive strength chloride diffusivity and pore structure of high performance metakaolin and silica fume concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 20, 858&#x2013;865 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wild, S., Khatib, J. M. &amp; Jones, A. Relative strength pozzolanic activity and cement hydration in superplasticised metakaolin. Cem. Concr. Res. 26(10), 1537&#x2013;1544 (1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagier, F. &amp; Kurtis, K. E. Influence of Portland cement composition on early age reactions with metakaolin. Cem. Concr. Res. 37, 1411&#x2013;1417 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gesoglu, E. G. &amp; Mermerdas, K. Improving strength drying shrinkage and pore structure of concrete using metakaolin. Mater. Struct. 41, 937&#x2013;949 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shekarchi, M., Bonakdar, A. &amp; Bakhshi, M. Transport properties in metakaolin blended concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 24(11), 2217&#x2013;2223 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khatib, J. M. &amp; Wild, S. Pore size distribution of metakaolin paste. Cem. Concr. Res. 26(10), 1545&#x2013;1553 (1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poon, C. S., Lam, L. &amp; Kou, S. C. Rate of pozzolanic reaction of metakaolin in high-performance cement pastes. Cem. Concr. Res. 31, 1301&#x2013;1306 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Jim&#xe9;nez, A., Palomo, A. &amp; Criado, M. Microstructure development of alkali-activated fly ash cement: A descriptive model. Cem. Concr. Res. 35(6), 1204&#x2013;1209 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, H. F., Shen, J. J. &amp; Liu, Y. Effect of nano-Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> on the mechanical and microstructural properties of cement-based grouting material. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 21, e03846 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J., Huang, Y. &amp; Liu, Y. Mechanical properties and impermeability strength evolution of the consolidated body of fiber-modified coal-based solid wastes grouting materials. Constr. Build. Mater. 450, 138556 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan, Z. H., Qi, K. &amp; Hu, T. Experimental study on the durability of cement-stabilized soil for post-grouted piles in calcareous sand under marine environment. Mar. Georesour. Geotech. 43(9), 19 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan, Z. H., Dai, G. L. &amp; Gong, W. M. Study on the response of postside-grouted piles subjected to lateral loading in calcareous sand. Acta Geotech. 7, 17 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan, Z. H., Dai, G. L. &amp; Gong, W. M. Field and theoretical analysis of response of axially loaded grouted drilled shafts in extra-thick fine sand. Can. Geotech. J. 57(3), 391&#x2013;407 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, F., Li, M. &amp; Liu, M. AI-assisted computational design with synchronous grouting materials in the framework of industrial solid waste. Constr. Build. Mater. 494, 143322 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, Y., Zhang, W. &amp; Li, G. Investigation into the sustainable solid waste-based grouting materials with enhanced injectability, fluidity and strength. Constr. Build. Mater. 498, 144002 (2025).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>