<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40705809</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluating the long-term strength of GGBFS-blended cement across various water-to-binder and superplasticizer ratios under heating/cooling cycles.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0319923</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0319923</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0319923</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0319923</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The investigation is to understand the combined effects of ground granulated blast furnace slag (GGBFS) content, superplasticizer (SP) dosages, and water-to-binder (w/b) ratios on the fresh and harden properties, as well as long-term durability under thermal cycles. This study aims to address these gaps by examining the influence of varying GGBFS replacement levels, SP dosage, and w/b ratios on blended mortar's fresh properties, mechanical strength, thermal performance, water absorption, and microstructure. The experimental method included testing for flowability, fresh density, and compressive strength over 56 and 90 days and 30% for 365 days and evaluating the microstructure through microscopy. The result showed that increasing GGBFS content improved both flowability and fresh density. Additionally, thermal cycling led to a significant increase in compressive strength with an average strength gain of 22% at 56 days, 40.9% at 90 days, and 30% at 365 days. The microstructure, which demonstrates a lot of calcium silicate hydrate (C-S-H) crystals and is relatively denser after 365 days, results in high strength. In conclusion, incorporating GGBFS in cement composites reduces CO2 emissions, improves performance, and enhances durability, especially under thermal conditions, making it a viable solution for providing high-performance concrete. This finding has significant implications for reducing the environmental footprint and life cycle in construction.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Omer et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Omer</LastName><ForeName>Bashdar</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7095-7789</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Civil Engineering Department, University of Raparin, Ranya, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saeed</LastName><ForeName>Najmadeen Mohammed</ForeName><Initials>NM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Civil Engineering Department, University of Raparin, Ranya, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dheyaaldin</LastName><ForeName>Mahmood Hunar</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9835-950X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Associate of the Department of Civil Engineering, American University in Dubai, Dubai, PO Box 28282, UAE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Civil Engineering Department, Faculty of Engineering, Tishk International University, Erbil, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jamal</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed Salah</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, American University in Dubai, Dubai, UAE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kurda</LastName><ForeName>Rawaz</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2429-4755</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Highway and Bridge Engineering, Technical Engineering College, Erbil Polytechnic University, Erbil, Iraq.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn"><RefSource>PLoS One. 2025 Nov 3;20(11):e0335994. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0335994.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">41183002</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019245" MajorTopicYN="N">Compressive Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003252" MajorTopicYN="Y">Construction Materials</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006358" MajorTopicYN="N">Hot Temperature</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008422" MajorTopicYN="N">Materials Testing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="Y">Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40705809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12289012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0319923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-24-20165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Friedlingstein P, Houghton RA, Marland G, Hackler J, Boden TA, Conway TJ. Update on CO2 emissions. Nat Geosci. 2010;3(12):811&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Habert G, Bouzidi Y, Jullien A. Environmental impact of cement production: detail of the different processes and cement plant variability evaluation. J Clean Prod. 2010;18(5):478&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang H, Elahi E, Gao M, Huang Y, Liu X. Digital economy to encourage sustainable consumption and reduce carbon emissions. J Cleaner Prod. 2024;140(867):140867. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.140867</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.140867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed AA, Tawfik TA, Aadi AA, Sor NH. Ultra-high performance of eco-friendly self-compacting concrete incorporated cement Kiln dust with/without waste plastic and polypropylene fiber. Innova Infrastruct Solut. 2023;8(3):94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawileh RA, Abdalla JA, Fardmanesh F, Shahsana P, Khalili A. Performance of reinforced concrete beams cast with different percentages of GGBS replacement to cement. Arch Civ Mech Eng. 2017;17:511&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neupane K. Fly ash and GGBFS based powder-activated geopolymer binders: A viable sustainable alternative of portland cement in concrete industry. Mech Mater. 2016;103(12):110&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oyebisi S, Ede A, Olutoge F, Omole D. Geopolymer concrete incorporating agro-industrial wastes: Effects on mechanical properties, microstructural behaviour and mineralogical phases. Constr Build Mater. 2020;256:119390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alamri M, Ali T, Ahmed H, Qureshi MZ, Elmagarhe A, Adil Khan M, et al. Enhancing the engineering characteristics of sustainable recycled aggregate concrete using fly ash, metakaolin and silica fume. Heliyon. 2024;10(7). doi: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e29014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e29014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11021967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38633632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oyebisi S, Ede A, Olutoge F, Ngene B. Assessment of activity indexes on the splitting tensile strengthening of geopolymer concrete incorporating supplementary cementitious materials. Mater Today Commun. 2020;24:101356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haris M, Saad S, Ammad S, Rasheed K. AI in fabrication and construction. In: AI in material science. CRC Press; p. 169&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamal A, Bzeni D, Noguchi T. An experimental investigation into the factors affecting strength and flowability of geopolymer binder. Zanco J Pure Appl Sci. 2019;31(s3):430&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dziejarski B, Krzy&#x17c;y&#x144;ska R, Andersson K. Current status of carbon capture, utilization, and storage technologies in the global economy: A survey of technical assessment. Fuel. 2023;342:127776. doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2023.127776</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2023.127776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Z. Study on sustainable technology of construction waste in carbon neutrality: concrete decarbonization in Hong Kong. Ninth International Conference on Energy Materials and Electrical Engineering (ICEMEE 2023). 2024;690&#x2013;700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawarneh A, Al A, Alam M. Experimental investigation on compressive, tensile, and flexural strengths of concrete with high volume of GGBS, fly ash, and silica fume. Canadian Society of Civil Engineering Annual Conference. 2022;805&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamad M, Nasr M, Shubbar A, Al-Khafaji Z, Al Masoodi Z, Al-Hashimi O. Production of ultra-high-performance concrete with low energy consumption and carbon footprint using supplementary cementitious materials instead of silica fume: A review. Energies. 2021;14(24):8291. doi: 10.3390/en14248291</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en14248291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganesh P, Murthy A. Tensile behaviour and durability aspects of sustainable ultra-high performance concrete incorporated with GGBS as cementitious material. Constr Build Mater. 2019;197:667&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicula L, Manea D, Simedru D, Cadar O, Ardelean I, Dragomir M. The advantages on using GGBS and ACBFS aggregate to obtain an ecological road concrete. Coatings. 2023;13(8):1368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallah MA, Ghasemzadeh Mousavinejad SH. A comparative study of properties of ambient-cured recycled GGBFS geopolymer concrete and recycled Portland cement concrete. J Mater Civ Eng. 2023;35(1):5022002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ducman V, Mladenovi&#x10d; A. The potential use of steel slag in refractory concrete. Mater Charact. 2011;62(7):716&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddique R, Khan MI. Supplementary cementing materials. Springer Science &amp; Business Media;2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Dey S. Study on strength and durability characteristics of nano-silica based blended concrete. Hybrid Advances. 2023;2:100011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vo D-H, Doan V-P, Nguyen MH, Nguyen T-K. Evaluation of the long-term performance of high-performance concrete produced with blended river sand/sea sand and high-volume GGBFS. J Mater Cycles Waste Manag. 2024;11&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh S, Kim J, Song C, Choi S. Effects of fineness and substitution rate of GGBFS on material characteristics of GGBFS-blended cement mortars: hydration, non-evaporable water, pore structure, mechanical properties, self-desiccation, and autogenous shrinkage. J Build Eng. 2024;92:109741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawileh RA, Abdalla JA, Nawaz W, Sharif Zadeh A, Mirghani A, Al Nassara A, et al. Effects of replacing cement with GGBS and fly ash on the flexural and shear performance of reinforced concrete beams. Pract Period Struct Des Constr. 2024;29(2):4024011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahal M, Oinam Y, Vashistha P, Oh J-E, Pyo S. Cementless ultra-high performance concrete (UHPC) using CaO-activated GGBFS and calcium formate as an accelerator. J Buil Eng. 2023;75:107000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dheyaaldin MH, Kianmehr P. Sustainable utilization of nanomaterials in reactive powder composite: State of the art review. J Buil Eng. 2024;98:111047. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.111047</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.111047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosseinzadeh H, Salehi AM, Mehraein M, Asadollahfardi G. The effects of steel, polypropylene, and high-performance macro polypropylene fibers on mechanical properties and durability of high-strength concrete. Constr Build Mater. 2023;386:131589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chougale J, Bage AA. Effect of manufactured sand, micro silica, and GGBS on properties of high-performance concrete. IOP Conf Ser: Earth Environ Sci. 2023;12024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yakobu KF, Ravichandran PT, CS N, . Influence of GGBS on rheology of cement paste and concrete with SNF and PCE based superplasticizers. Indian J Sci Technol. 2015;8(36):1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Kong Y, Wan T, Zhao G. Effects of thermal-cooling cycling curing on the mechanical properties of EVA-modified concrete. Constr Build Mater. 2018;165:443&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeed NM, Omer B, Jamal AS, Dheyaaldin MH. Performance of cement mortar modified with GGBFS at elevated temperatures with various w/b ratios and superplasticizer dosages. Constr Build Mater. 2023;368:130493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohan A, Mini KM. Strength Studies of SCC Incorporating Silica Fume and Ultra Fine GGBS. Mater Today: Proc. 2018;5(11):23752&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.matpr.2018.10.166</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2018.10.166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basha EA, Hashim R, Mahmud HB, Muntohar AS. Stabilization of residual soil with rice husk ash and cement. Const Buil Mater. 2005;19(6):448&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins D. Briefing: GGBS and sustainability. Proc Inst Civ Eng- Constr Mater. 2007;160(3):99&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddique R, Kaur D. Properties of concrete containing ground granulated blast furnace slag (GGBFS) at elevated temperatures. J Adv Res. 2012;3(1):45&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakeem I, Hosen MA, Alyami M, Qaidi S, &#xd6;zk&#x131;l&#x131;&#xe7; Y. Influence of heat--cool cyclic exposure on the performance of fiber-reinforced high-strength concrete. Sustainability. 2023;15(2):1433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu-Farsakh MY, Idries A, Chen S. Evaluating the effect of heating--cooling cycle on the clay-concrete pile interface. Geo-Congress 2022. 2022;50&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q, Qian Z, Wu Z. Micro/macro physical and mechanical variation of red sandstone subjected to cyclic heating and cooling: An experimental study. Bull Eng Geol Environ. 2019;78:1485&#x2013;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dheyaaldin MH, Mosaberpanah MA, Alzeebaree R. Shrinkage behavior and mechanical properties of alkali activated mortar incorporating nanomaterials and polypropylene fiber. Ceram Int. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dheyaaldin MH, Mosaberpanah MA, Alzeebaree R. Performance of fiber-reinforced alkali-activated mortar with/without nano silica and nano alumina. Sustainability. 2022;14(5):2527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Practice for Mechanical Mixing of Hydraulic Cement Pastes and Mortars of Plastic Consistency. ASTM International, West Conshohocken, PA; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ASTM Standard C1437. Standard Test Method for Flow of Hydraulic Cement Mortar. ASTM International, West Conshohocken, PA; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Test Method for Density (Unit Weight), Yield, and Air Content (Gravimetric) of Concrete. ASTM International, West Conshohocken, PA; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C109/C109M-20 A. Standard test method for compressive strength of hydraulic cement mortars (using 2-in. or [50-mm] cube specimens). ASTM International; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Test Method for Rate of Water Absorption of Masonry Mortars. ASTM International, West Conshohocken, PA; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander AE, Shashikala AP. Studies on the microstructure and durability characteristics of ambient cured FA-GGBS based geopolymer mortar. Constr Build Mater [Internet].
2022;347:128538. Available from: https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0950061822021985</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das KK, Lam ES-S, Jang JG. Effects of modified binders on flowability of grout and properties of preplaced aggregate concrete. J Build Eng. 2023;68:106235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palacios M, Puertas F, Bowen P, Houst YF. Effect of PCs superplasticizers on the rheological properties and hydration process of slag-blended cement pastes. J Mater Sci. 2009;44(10):2714&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shubbar AA, Nasr MS, Islam GMS, Al-Khafaji ZS, Sadique M, Hashim K, et al. Early Age and Long-term Mechanical Performance of Mortars Incorporating High-volume GGBS. In: Advances in Civil Engineering: Select Proceedings of ICACE 2020. 2022. p. 267&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nath P, Sarker PK. Effect of GGBFS on setting, workability and early strength properties of fly ash geopolymer concrete cured in ambient condition. Constr Build Mater. 2014;66(9):163&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zbay E, Erdemir M, Durmu&#x15f; HI. Utilization and efficiency of ground granulated blast furnace slag on concrete properties &#x2013; A review. Constr Build Mater. 2016;105:423&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Q, Guo R, Zhao Z, Lin Z, He K. Mechanical properties of concrete at high temperature: A review. Construction and Building Materials. 2015;93:371&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nematzadeh M, Mousavimehr M. Residual compressive stress--strain relationship for hybrid recycled PET--crumb rubber aggregate concrete after exposure to elevated temperatures. J Mater Civ Eng. 2019;31(8):4019136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ujhelyi JE, Ibrahim AJ. Hot weather concreting with hydraulic additives. Cem Concr Res. 1991;21(2&#x2013;3):345&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moodi Y, Mousavi SR, Ghavidel A, Sohrabi MR, Rashki M. Using response surface methodology and providing a modified model using whale algorithm for estimating the compressive strength of columns confined with FRP sheets. Constr Build Mater. 2018;183:163&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haque M, Ray S, Mita AF, Bhattacharjee S, Shams MdJB. Prediction and optimization of the fresh and hardened properties of concrete containing rice husk ash and glass fiber using response surface methodology. Case Stud Constr Mater. 2021;14:e00505. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00505</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan MN, Singla S, Garg R. Effect of Microsilica on Strength and Microstructure of the GGBS-based Cement composites. In: IOP Conference Series: Materials Science and Engineering. 2020. p. 12007.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>