<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40821079</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1943-8141</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of translational research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Transl Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intra-articular sodium hyaluronate, compound betamethasone, and ropivacaine combined with arthroscopic debridement in patients with knee osteoarthritis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5433</StartPage><EndPage>5440</EndPage><MedlinePgn>5433-5440</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.62347/BNMD7591</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the efficacy of sodium hyaluronate (SH), compound betamethasone (BT), and ropivacaine (Rop) in combination with arthroscopic debridement (AD) for the treatment of knee osteoarthritis (KOA).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A retrospective analysis was conducted on 107 KOA patients treated at Shantou Central Hospital l, including 52 patients in the control group who received AD alone and 55 patients in the observation group who additionally received intra-articular SH, compound BT, and Rop. Treatment efficacy, pain levels, knee joint function, lower limb motor function, serum inflammatory markers, quality of life, and sleep quality were assessed and compared between the two groups. Univariate and multivariate logistic regression analyses were performed to identify factors influencing treatment outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The observation group showed significantly better outcomes than the control group in terms of overall treatment efficacy, pain relief, improvement in joint and lower limb function, reduction in inflammatory markers, and enhancement of both sleep quality and overall quality of life. Prolonged disease duration was identified as an independent risk factor for poor treatment outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The combination of SH, compound BT, and Rop with AD offers significant clinical advantages in the management of KOA, supporting its broader adoption in clinical practice.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>AJTR Copyright &#xa9; 2025.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cai</LastName><ForeName>Shijian</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Joint Surgery and Sports Medicine, Shantou Central Hospital Shantou 515100, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Huiyang</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Joint Surgery and Sports Medicine, Shantou Central Hospital Shantou 515100, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yufeng</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trauma Orthopedics, Shantou Central Hospital Shantou 515100, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Shuxin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Joint Surgery and Sports Medicine, Shantou Central Hospital Shantou 515100, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Transl Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101493030</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1943-8141</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Knee osteoarthritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">arthroscopic debridement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">compound betamethasone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ropivacaine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sodium hyaluronate</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40821079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12351615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.62347/BNMD7591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kan HS, Chan PK, Chiu KY, Yan CH, Yeung SS, Ng YL, Shiu KW, Ho T. Non-surgical treatment of knee osteoarthritis. Hong Kong Med J. 2019;25:127&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30919810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain SM, Neilly DW, Baliga S, Patil S, Meek R. Knee osteoarthritis: a review of management options. Scott Med J. 2016;61:7&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27330013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michael JW, Schluter-Brust KU, Eysel P. The epidemiology, etiology, diagnosis, and treatment of osteoarthritis of the knee. Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2010;107:152&#x2013;162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2841860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20305774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Jordan JM. Epidemiology of osteoarthritis. Clin Geriatr Med. 2010;26:355&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2920533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20699159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giwnewer U, Rubin G, Orbach H, Rozen N. Treatment for Osteoarthritis of the Knee. Harefuah. 2016;155:403&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28514128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connor D, Johnston RV, Brignardello-Petersen R, Poolman RW, Cyril S, Vandvik PO, Buchbinder R. Arthroscopic surgery for degenerative knee disease (osteoarthritis including degenerative meniscal tears) Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2022;3:CD014328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8892839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35238404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge R, Zhang J, Yang Z. Evaluation of minimally invasive arthroscopy technology in sports medicine-an evaluation of nano silver disinfectants. J Nanosci Nanotechnol. 2021;21:1446&#x2013;1450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33404407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan F, Li Q, Tang X, Xue J, Li J. Method and effectiveness of arthroscopic debridement for treating gouty arthritis of the knee. Zhongguo Xiu Fu Chong Jian Wai Ke Za Zhi. 2011;25:937&#x2013;940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21923020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X, Liang W, Li J, Liu P. A meta-analysis and systematic review of the therapeutic effects of arthroscopy combined with intra-articular injection of sodium hyaluronate in the treatment of knee osteoarthritis. Ann Palliat Med. 2021;10:9859&#x2013;9869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34628912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P, Huang L, Ma Y, Zhang D, Zhang X, Zhou J, Ruan A, Wang Q. Intra-articular platelet-rich plasma injection for knee osteoarthritis: a summary of meta-analyses. J Orthop Surg Res. 2019;14:385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6880602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31775816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang HF, Wang CG, Li H, Huang YT, Li ZJ. Intra-articular platelet-rich plasma versus hyaluronic acid in the treatment of knee osteoarthritis: a meta-analysis. Drug Des Devel Ther. 2018;12:445&#x2013;453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5842781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29551888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da H, Song JK, Liu L, Zhou L. Compound betamethasone in the treatment of pain after supraspinatus tendon repair. J Int Med Res. 2022;50:3000605221121962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9478721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36113007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu P, Guo WS, Zhang QD, Wang WG, Zhang Y, Wang YY. Efficacy and safety of compound betamethasone cocktail therapy in primary unilateral unicompartmental knee arthroplasty. Zhonghua Yi Xue Za Zhi. 2019;99:3100&#x2013;3104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31648455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen G, Gong M, Liu Y. Comparison of ropivacaine plus sufentanil and ropivacaine plus dexmedetomidine for labor epidural analgesia: a randomized controlled trial protocol. Medicine (Baltimore) 2020;99:e22113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7478759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32899094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theodosiadis P, Sachinis N, Goroszeniuk T, Grosomanidis V, Chalidis B. Ropivacaine versus bupivacaine for 3-in-1 block during total knee arthroplasty. J Orthop Surg (Hong Kong) 2013;21:300&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24366788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Zhang Y, Zhu YL, Fu PL. Efficacy and safety of an intra-operative intra-articular magnesium/ropivacaine injection for pain control following total knee arthroplasty. J Int Med Res. 2012;40:2032&#x2013;2040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23206490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roos EM, Arden NK. Strategies for the prevention of knee osteoarthritis. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2016;12:92&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26439406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoudian A, Lohmander LS, Mobasheri A, Englund M, Luyten FP. Early-stage symptomatic osteoarthritis of the knee - time for action. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2021;17:621&#x2013;632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34465902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuchs L, Givon A, Shweiki F, Hovav T. Arthroscopic knee debridement in osteoarthritis in the older age can be satisfactory. J Clin Orthop Trauma. 2023;38:102130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9969278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36860995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin K, Yoder RG. Calcaneus fracture and posterior arthroscopic primary subtalar arthrodesis (C-PASTA) JBJS Essent Surg Tech. 2022;12:e21.00057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9931041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36816530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh YS, Yang SF, Chu SC, Chen PN, Chou MC, Hsu MC, Lu KH. Expression changes of gelatinases in human osteoarthritic knees and arthroscopic debridement. Arthroscopy. 2004;20:482&#x2013;488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15122138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duymus TM, Mutlu S, Dernek B, Komur B, Aydogmus S, Kesiktas FN. Choice of intra-articular injection in treatment of knee osteoarthritis: platelet-rich plasma, hyaluronic acid or ozone options. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2017;25:485&#x2013;492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27056686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maheu E, Bannuru RR, Herrero-Beaumont G, Allali F, Bard H, Migliore A. Why we should definitely include intra-articular hyaluronic acid as a therapeutic option in the management of knee osteoarthritis: results of an extensive critical literature review. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2019;48:563&#x2013;572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30072113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inagaki J, Nakano A, Hatipoglu OF, Ooka Y, Tani Y, Miki A, Ikemura K, Opoku G, Ando R, Kodama S, Ohtsuki T, Yamaji H, Yamamoto S, Katsuyama E, Watanabe S, Hirohata S. Potential of a novel chemical compound targeting matrix metalloprotease-13 for early osteoarthritis: an in vitro study. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23:2681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8910651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35269821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumann JR, Stoker AM, Bozynski CC, Sherman SL, Cook JL. An injectable containing morphine, ropivacaine, epinephrine, and ketorolac is not cytotoxic to articular cartilage explants from degenerative knees. Arthroscopy. 2022;38:1980&#x2013;1995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34952188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Giudice M, Gangestad SW. Rethinking IL-6 and CRP: why they are more than inflammatory biomarkers, and why it matters. Brain Behav Immun. 2018;70:61&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29499302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim W, Park S, Choi C, Kim YR, Park I, Seo C, Youn D, Shin W, Lee Y, Choi D, Kim M, Lee H, Kim S, Na C. Evaluation of anti-inflammatory potential of the new ganghwaljetongyeum on adjuvant-induced inflammatory arthritis in rats. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2016;2016:1230294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4921641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27382402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, He C. TNF-alpha and IL-6: the link between immune and bone system. Curr Drug Targets. 2020;21:213&#x2013;227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31433756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brun P, Zavan B, Vindigni V, Schiavinato A, Pozzuoli A, Iacobellis C, Abatangelo G. In vitro response of osteoarthritic chondrocytes and fibroblast-like synoviocytes to a 500-730 kDa hyaluronan amide derivative. J Biomed Mater Res B Appl Biomater. 2012;100:2073&#x2013;2081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22865740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovato P, Norsgaard H, Tokura Y, Ropke MA. Calcipotriol and betamethasone dipropionate exert additive inhibitory effects on the cytokine expression of inflammatory dendritic cell-Th17 cell axis in psoriasis. J Dermatol Sci. 2016;81:153&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26794805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brocco MC, Paulo DN, Almeida CE, Carraretto AR, Cabral SA, Silveira AC, Gomez RS, Baptista JF. A study of interleukin 6 (IL-6) and tumor necrosis factor alpha (TNF-alpha) serum levels in rats subjected to fecal peritonitis and treated with intraperitoneal ropivacaine. Acta Cir Bras. 2012;27:494&#x2013;498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22760836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>