<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40284450</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1999-4923</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pharmaceutics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pharmaceutics</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Granulation Methods and the Mechanisms for Improving Hardness of Loxoprofen Sodium Hydrate-Containing Tablets.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">455</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/pharmaceutics17040455</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Objectives:</b> We investigated the compression mechanisms for loxoprofen sodium (LXP), which is known to occur as a dihydrate, and identified parameters that influence the tablet hardness of LXP tablets prepared by the wet granulation method. <b>Method:</b> LXP granules were prepared with water or ethanol as the solvent, dried under various conditions and sieved for particle size control, with 1% Mg-st added before tablet compression. <b>Results</b>: The findings indicated that both the granulation solvent and drying temperature significantly impacted the tablet hardness. Granules prepared with ethanol exhibited higher hardness as compared with those prepared with water. The tablet hardness varied with varying drying temperatures. <b>Discussion:</b> Principal component analysis (PCA) identified positive correlations between the tablet hardness and the surface free energy (SFE), polar component (&#x3b3;(p)), and cohesion, and a negative correlation with the dispersive component (&#x3b3;(d)). Granules prepared with ethanol exhibited a higher &#x3b3;(p), likely due to the differing solubility in ethanol and water, leading to enhanced interparticle binding. This study confirmed that use of the eutectic mixture of LXP and Mg-st exerted no significant influence. Crystal structure analysis indicated that the hydration states varied according to the drying temperature, suggesting the higher &#x3b3;(p) in anhydrous forms, due to the lower hydrophobicity, contributed to increased tablet hardness. <b>Conclusion:</b> This research offers insights for optimizing the formulation conditions to improve the LXP tablet hardness. Appropriate selection of the solvent and drying temperature mitigates tablet hardness issues, while assessment of SFE can help in the selection of suitable additives.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuwata</LastName><ForeName>Aya</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research &amp; Development Headquarters Self-Medication, Taisho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., 1-403 Yoshino-Cho, Kita-ku, Saitama 331-9530, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Chemistry, Hoshi University, 2-4-41 Ebara, Tokyo 142-0063, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ishikawa</LastName><ForeName>Agata</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research &amp; Development Headquarters Self-Medication, Taisho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., 1-403 Yoshino-Cho, Kita-ku, Saitama 331-9530, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ono</LastName><ForeName>Tetsuo</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research &amp; Development Headquarters Self-Medication, Taisho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., 1-403 Yoshino-Cho, Kita-ku, Saitama 331-9530, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yonemochi</LastName><ForeName>Etsuo</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5255-5129</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Chemistry, Hoshi University, 2-4-41 Ebara, Tokyo 142-0063, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Chemistry, International University of Health and Welfare, 4-3 Kozunomori, Chiba 286-8686, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Pharmaceutics</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101534003</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1999-4923</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">crystal structure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hardness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydrate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">loxoprofen</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surface free energy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tablet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tensile strength</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>A.K., A.I. and T.O. are employees of Taisho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40284450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12030358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pharmaceutics17040455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">pharmaceutics17040455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Greig S.L., Garnock-Jones K.P. Loxoprofen: A Review in Pain and Inflammation. Clin. Drug Investig. 2016;36:771&#x2013;781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27444038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ushida T., Matsui D., Inoue T., Yokoyama M., Takatsuna H., Matsumoto T., Takita A., Kurusu T., Sakoda H., Okuizumi K. Recent prescription status of oral analgesics in Japan in real-world clinical settings: Retrospective study using a large-scale prescription database. Expert Opin. Pharmacother. 2019;20:2041&#x2013;2052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31422709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terada A., Naruto S., Wachi K., Tanaka S., Iizuka Y., Misaka E. Synthesis and Antiinflammatory Activity of [(Cycloalky lmethyl) Phenyl] acetic Acids and Related Compounds. J. Med. Chem. 1984;27:212&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6607354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuwata A., Ono T., Tsuchiya Y., Yonemochi E. Development of Fast Disintegrating Tablets Containing Loxoprofen Sodium by HYDROFLASH Manufacturing Method. Chem. Pharm. Bull. 2024;72:48&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38171904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayram G.S., Vikas W., Shravan S., Mahesh S. Solubility Enhancement of Ibuprofen by Different Techniques. Int. J. Res. Publ. Rev. 2023;4:1264&#x2013;1271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saddik J.S., Chaturvedi K., Dave R.H. Investigating the Impact of Manufacturing and Formulation Factors on the Compactability of Acetaminophen Tablets. Int. J. Pharm. Sci. Res. 2021;12:1240&#x2013;1250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkar S., Ooi S.M., Liew C.V., Heng P.S. Influence of rate of force application during compression on tablet capping. J. Pharm. Sci. 2015;104:1319&#x2013;1327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25581443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirai N., Takatani-Nakase T., Takahashi K. Preparation and Evaluation of Ibuprofen Solid Dispersion Tablets with Improved Dissolution and Less Sticking Using Porous Calcium Silicate. J. Pharm. Pharmacol. 2018;6:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng L., Li W., Li Y., Yang Y., Li Y., Cheng Y. Thermal analysis and decomposition kinetics of the dehydration of copper sulfate pentahydrate. J. Therm. Anal. Calorim. 2018;135:2697&#x2013;2703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arai Y., Yasue T. Mechanochemical Dehydration and Surface Property Change of Hydrated Crystals by Mechanical Treatment. J. Soc. Mater. Sci. 1973;22:649&#x2013;653.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burger A.D., Griesser U.J. Physical stability, hygroscopicity and solubility of succinylsulfathiazole crystal forms. The polymorphic drug substances of the European pharmacopoeia, part 7. Eur. J. Pharm. Biopharm. 1991;37:118&#x2013;124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yukoh S., Shiraishi S., Otsuka M. Characterization of dehydration and hydration behavior of calcium lactate pentahydrate and its anhydrate. Colloids Surf. B Biointerfaces. 2005;46:135&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16293401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto K., Kimura T., Nobui Y., Yonemochi E., Oguchi T., Yamamoto K. Relationship between the Physical Properties of Various Lactose on the Market and Characteristics of Their Tablets. Yakuzaigaku. 1997;57:1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aru P.B., Gulhane M.S., Katekar V.A., Deshmukh S.P. Quality by Design (QbD) in pharmaceutical development: A comprehensive review. GSC Biol. Pharm. Sci. 2024;26:328&#x2013;340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arndt O.-R., Baggio R., Adam A.K., Harting J., Franceschinis E., Kleinebudde P. Impact of Different Dry and Wet Granulation Techniques on Granule and Tablet Properties: A Comparative Study. J. Pharm. Sci. 2018;107:3143&#x2013;3152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30244008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajniak P., Stepanek F., Dhanasekharan K., Fan R., Mancinelli C., Chern R.T. A combined experimental and computational study of wet granulation in a Wurster fluid bed granulator. Powder Technol. 2009;189:190&#x2013;201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacher C., Olsen P.M., Bertelsen P., Sonnergaard J.M. Compressibility and compactibility of granules produced by wet and dry granulation. Int. J. Pharm. 2008;358:69&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18407441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudhat S.M., Kettler C.N., Dave R.H. To Study Capping or Lamination Tendency of Tablets Through Evaluation of Powder Rheological Properties and Tablet Mechanical Properties of Directly Compressible Blends. AAPS PharmSciTech. 2017;18:1177&#x2013;1189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27422654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran D.T., Kom&#xed;nov&#xe1; P., Kulaviak L., Zamostn&#xfd; P. Evaluation of multifunctional magnesium aluminosilicate materials as novel family of glidants in solid dosage products. Int. J. Pharm. 2021;592:120054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33176198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maharjan R., Lee J.C., Kim N.A., Jeong S.H. Preparation of seeded granules to improve mechanical properties and various drug loading for pharmaceutical application. Powder Technol. 2021;392:650&#x2013;660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukami J., Ozawa A., YoshihashI Y., Yonemochi E., Terada K. Development of Fast Disintegrating Compressed Tablets Using Amino Acid as Disintegratation Accelerator: Evaluation of Wetting and Disintegration of Tablet on the Basis of Surface Free Energy. Chem. Pharm. Bull. 2005;53:1536&#x2013;1539. doi: 10.1248/cpb.53.1536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1248/cpb.53.1536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16327184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashizaki K., Hoshii Y., Ikeuchi K., Imai M., Taguchi H., Goto Y., Fujiia M. A Method for Measuring the Surface Free Energy of Topical Semi-solid Dosage Forms. Chem. Pharm. Bull. 2021;69:1083&#x2013;1087. doi: 10.1248/cpb.c21-00537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1248/cpb.c21-00537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34719590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi Y., Nakano Y., Marumo Y., Kumada S., Okada K., Onuki Y. Application of machine learning to a material library for modeling of relationships between material properties and tablet properties. Int. J. Pharm. 2021;609:121158. doi: 10.1016/j.ijpharm.2021.121158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2021.121158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34624447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghazi N., Liu Z., Bhatt C., Kiang S., Cuitino A. Investigating the Effect of APAP Crystals on Tablet Behavior Manufactured by Direct Compression. AAPS PharmSciTech. 2019;20:168. doi: 10.1208/s12249-019-1369-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1208/s12249-019-1369-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30993408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Ban S., Goodwin D.J. The Impact of Granule Density on Tabletting and Pharmaceutical Product Performance. Pharm. Res. 2017;34:1002&#x2013;1011. doi: 10.1007/s11095-017-2115-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11095-017-2115-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28188541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matji A., Donato N., Gagol A., Morales E., Carvajal L., Serrano D.R., Worku Z.A., Healy A.M., Torrado J.J. Predicting the critical quality attributes of ibuprofen tablets via modelling of process parameters for roller compaction and tableting. Int. J. Pharm. 2021;609:121158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31075438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etzler F.M., Gardner D. Surface Free Energy Determination of Powders and Particles with Pharmaceutical Applications: A Critical Review. Adhes. Adhes. 2018;6:329&#x2013;367. doi: 10.7569/RAA.2018.097310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7569/RAA.2018.097310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trasi N.S., Boerrigter S.X.M., Byrn S.R., Carvajal T.M. Investigating the effect of dehydration conditions on the compactability of glucose. Int. J. Pharm. 2011;406:55&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1016/j.ijpharm.2010.12.042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2010.12.042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21232587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luangtana-Anan M., Fell J.T. Bonding mechanisms in tableting. Int. J. Pharm. 1990;60:197&#x2013;202. doi: 10.1016/0378-5173(90)90073-D.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0378-5173(90)90073-D</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pap&#xf3;s P., K&#xe1;sa P., Jr., Ili&#x10d; I., Blatnik-Urek S., Regdon G., Jr., Sr&#x10d;i&#x10d; S., Pintye-H&#xf3;di K., Sov&#xe1;ny T. Effect of the surface free energy of materials on the lamination tendency of bilayer tablets. Int. J. Pharm. 2015;496:609&#x2013;613. doi: 10.1016/j.ijpharm.2015.10.061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2015.10.061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26546910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ando H., Nozaki Y., Sato K., Dohi M., Hakomori T., Yonemochi E. Novel approach to evaluating granulation and segregation level considering the contribution of hydroxypropyl cellulose to the surface property change of granules. Int. J. Pharm. 2020;581:119254. doi: 10.1016/j.ijpharm.2020.119254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2020.119254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32220585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kano T., Yoshihashi Y., Yonemochi E., Terada K. Clarifying the Mechanism of Aggregation of Particles in High-Shear granulation Based on Their Surface Properties by using Micro-Spectroscopy. Int. J. Pharm. 2014;461:495&#x2013;504. doi: 10.1016/j.ijpharm.2013.12.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2013.12.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24368102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terada K., Yonemochi E. Physicochemical properties and surface free energy of ground talc. Solid State Ion. 2004;172:459&#x2013;462. doi: 10.1016/j.ssi.2004.03.032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ssi.2004.03.032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benmore C.J., Yarger J.L., Davidowski S.K., Shrader C.D., Smith P.A., Byrn S.R. Hydrogen Bonding in Amorphous Indomethacin. Pharmaceutics. 2024;16:1002. doi: 10.3390/pharmaceutics16081002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pharmaceutics16081002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11359274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39204347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saluja M.H., Atef E. Hydrogen Bonding: Between Strengthening the Crystal Packing and Improving Solubility of Three Haloperidol Derivatives. Molecules. 2016;21:719. doi: 10.3390/molecules21060719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules21060719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6273816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27258248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizumoto M.T., Masuda Y., Yamamoto T., Yonemochi E., Terada K. Formulation design of a novel fast-disintegrating tablet. Int. J. Pharm. 2005;306:83&#x2013;90. doi: 10.1016/j.ijpharm.2005.09.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2005.09.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16257154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PMDA . Japanese Pharmacopeia Commentary. 17th ed. PMDA; Tokyo, Japan: 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fratnik Z.P., Plohl O., Kokol V., Zemlji&#x10d; L.F. Using Different Surface Energy Models to Assess the Interactions between Antiviral Coating Films and phi6 Model Virus. J. Funct. Biomater. 2023;14:232. doi: 10.3390/jfb14040232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jfb14040232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10144987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37103322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong E., Huo Q., Zhang J., Han H., Cai T., Liu D. Advancements in nanoscale delivery systems: Optimizing intermolecular interactions for superior drug encapsulation and precision release. Drug Deliv. Transl. Res. 2025;15:7&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1007/s13346-024-01579-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13346-024-01579-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38573495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu H., Munk T., Cornett C., Wu J.X., B&#xf8;tker J.P., Christensen L.P., Rantanen J., Tian F. Influence of temperature on solvent-mediated anhydrate-to-hydrate transformation kinetics. Pharm. Res. 2011;28:364&#x2013;373. doi: 10.1007/s11095-010-0281-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11095-010-0281-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20886266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun D.E., Koztecki L.H., McMahon J.A., Price S.L., Reutzel-Edens S.M. Navigating the Waters of Unconventional Crystalline Hydrates. Mol. Pharm. 2015;12:3069&#x2013;30883. doi: 10.1021/acs.molpharmaceut.5b00357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.molpharmaceut.5b00357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4525282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26075319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brittain H.G., Byrn S.R., Lee E. Structural aspects of polymorphism. Polymorph. Pharm. Solids. 1999;95:73&#x2013;124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shukla A.J., Price J.C. Effect of moisture content on compression properties of directly compressible high beta-content anhydrous lactose. Drug Dev. Ind. Pharm. 1991;17:2067&#x2013;2081.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh W.-H., Cheng W.-T., Chen L.-C., Lin S.-Y. Non-isothermal dehydration kinetic study of aspartame hemihydrate using DSC, TGA and DSC-FTIR microspectroscopy. Asian J. Pharm. Sci. 2018;13:212&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7032143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32104394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voronin A.P., Vasilev N.A., Surov A.O., Churakov A.V., Perlovich G.L. Exploring the solid form landscape of the antifungal drug isavuconazole: Crystal structure analysis, phase transformation behavior and dissolution performance. CrystEngComm. 2021;23:8513&#x2013;8526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuang S., Shah H.S., Zhao B. Phase Transitions Involving Channel Hydrates of a New Pharmaceutical Compound. Pharm. Res. 2024;41:1533&#x2013;1541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38872035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakata Y., Tanabe E., Sumikawa T., Shiraishi S., Tokudome Y., Otsuka M. Effects of solid-state reaction between paracetamol and cloperastine hydrochloride on the pharmaceutical properties of their preparations. Int. J. Pharm. 2007;335:12&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17118591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thipparaboina R., Thumuri D., Chavan R., Naidu V.G.M., Shastri N.R. Fast dissolving drug-drug eutectics with improved compressibility and synergistic effects. Eur. J. Pharm. Sci. 2017;104:82&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28366649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts M., Ford J.L., MacLeod G.S., Fell J.T., Smith G.W., Rowe P.H., Days A.M. Effect of lubricant type and concentration on the punch tip adherence of model ibuprofen formulations. J. Pharm. Pharmacol. 2004;56:299&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15025854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jurczak E., Mazurek A.H., Szeleszczuk &#x141;., Pisklak D.M., Zieli&#x144;ska-Pisklak M. Pharmaceutical hydrates analysis&#x2014;Overview of methods and recent advances. Pharmaceutics. 2020;12:959. doi: 10.3390/pharmaceutics12100959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pharmaceutics12100959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7601571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33050621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nugrahani I., Slamet I., Mauludin R., Almira M. Hydrate transformation study of fluoroquinolone antibiotics using Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR) Int. J. Pharm. Pharm. Sci. 2015;7:246&#x2013;252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furuta H., Mori S., Yoshihashi Y., Yonemochi E., Uekusa H., Sugano K., Terada K. Physicochemical and crystal structure analysis of pranlukast pseudo-polymorphs I: Anhydrates and hydrate. J. Pharm. Biomed. Anal. 2015;107:11&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25562844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seton L., Khamar D., Bradshaw I.J., Hutcheon G.A. Solid State Forms of Theophylline: Presenting a New Anhydrous Polymorph. Cryst. Growth Des. 2010;10:3879&#x2013;3886.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jurczak E. Comparison of the analytical methods (solid state NMR, FT-IR, PXRD) in the analysis of the solid drug forms with low concentration of an active ingredient-17-&#x3b2;-estradiol case. J. Pharm. Biomed. Analysis. 2018;149:160&#x2013;165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29121569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith R.R., Shah U.V., Parambil J.V., Burnett D.J., Thielmann F., Heng J.Y.Y. The Effect of Polymorphism on Surface Energetics of D-Mannitol Polymorphs. AAPS J. 2017;19:103&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27631557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner T.D., Ma C.Y., Al Ayoub Y., Penchev R.Y., Dawson N., Ticehurst M., Docherty R., Roberts K.J. Calculating the surface energies of crystals on a face-specific and whole particle basis: Case study of the &#x3b1;- and &#x3b2;-polymorphic forms of L-glutamic acid. Powder Technol. 2024;448:120276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaminsky V.V., Vogler E.A. Hydrophobic hydration, Current Opinion in Colloid &amp; Interface Science. Curr. Opin. Colloid Interface Sci. 2001;6:342&#x2013;349.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>