<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39688252</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6543</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in nephrology and hypertension</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Nephrol Hypertens</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The kidney under heat stress: a vulnerable state.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>170</StartPage><EndPage>176</EndPage><MedlinePgn>170-176</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MNH.0000000000001050</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This review examines the effects of occupational heat stress on kidney health. It focuses on the role of hyperthermia in the development of acute kidney injury (AKI) and its potential progression to chronic kidney disease of nontraditional etiology (CKDnt). We highlight the physiological mechanisms by which hyperthermia affects kidney function and discuss emerging preventive strategies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Hyperthermia places the kidneys in a vulnerable state. As body temperature increases, blood flow is directed toward the skin to aid in cooling, diverting it away from internal organs like the kidneys to support blood pressure regulation. At the same time, hyperthermia and dehydration increases energetic demand to promote fluid and electrolyte conservation. Collectively, this can create a localized supply-demand mismatch, resulting in tissue hypoxia that can damage kidney tissues. These findings highlight that heat hyperthermia can lead to subclinical kidney damage, with potential long-term implications for kidney health.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Heat-induced AKI is a growing public health concern. Individuals engaged in manual labor with prolonged exposure are at risk of CKDnt. Interventions aimed to prevent hyperthermia show promise in mitigating the risk of AKI. Further research is necessary to refine these strategies and establish evidence-based guidelines for reducing heat-related kidney injuries.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amorim</LastName><ForeName>Fabiano</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health, Exercise, and Sports Sciences, University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, New Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schlader</LastName><ForeName>Zachary</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nutrition and Exercise Research Center, Indiana University School of Public Health - Bloomington, Bloomington, Indiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Nephrol Hypertens</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9303753</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1062-4821</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058186" MajorTopicYN="Y">Acute Kidney Injury</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007668" MajorTopicYN="Y">Kidney</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018882" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heat Stress Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051436" MajorTopicYN="Y">Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018869" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heat-Shock Response</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009784" MajorTopicYN="Y">Occupational Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016273" MajorTopicYN="Y">Occupational Exposure</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39688252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MNH.0000000000001050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00041552-990000000-00208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Francis A, Harhay MN, Ong ACM, et al. Chronic kidney disease and the global public health agenda: an international consensus. Nat Rev Nephrol 2024; 20:473&#x2013;485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovesdy CP. Epidemiology of chronic kidney disease: an update. Kidney Int Suppl 2022; 12:7&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson RJ, Wesseling C, Newman LS. Chronic kidney disease of unknown cause in agricultural communities. Ingelfinger JR, editor. N Engl J Med 2019; 380:1843&#x2013;1852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trabanino RG, Aguilar R, Silva CR, et al. Nefropat&#xed;a terminal en pacientes de un hospital de referencia en El Salvador [End-stage renal disease in patients at a referral hospital in El Salvador]. Rev Panam Salud P&#xfa;blica 2002; 12:202&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correa-Rotter R, Wesseling C, Johnson RJ. CKD of unknown origin in Central America: the case for a Mesoamerican nephropathy. Am J Kidney Dis 2014; 63:506&#x2013;520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wesseling C, Van Wendel De Joode B, Crowe J, et al. Mesoamerican nephropathy: geographical distribution and time trends of chronic kidney disease mortality between 1970 and 2012 in Costa Rica. Occup Environ Med 2015; 72:714&#x2013;721.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nerbass FB, Pecoits-Filho R, Clark WF, et al. Occupational heat stress and kidney health: from farms to factories. Kidney Int Rep 2017; 2:998&#x2013;1008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman CL, Hess HW, Lucas RAI, et al. Occupational heat exposure and the risk of chronic kidney disease of nontraditional origin in the United States. Am J Physiol-Regul Integr Comp Physiol 2021; 321:R141&#x2013;R151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roncal-Jimenez C, Lanaspa MA, Jensen T, et al. Mechanisms by which dehydration may lead to chronic kidney disease. Ann Nutr Metab 2015; 66: (Suppl 3): 10&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaser J, Hansson E, Weiss I, et al. Preventing kidney injury among sugarcane workers: promising evidence from enhanced workplace interventions. Occup Environ Med 2020; 77:527&#x2013;534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansson E, Jakobsson K, Glaser JR, et al. Association between acute kidney injury hospital visits and environmental heat stress at a Nicaraguan sugarcane plantation. Workplace Health Saf 2024; 72:131&#x2013;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wegman DH, Apelqvist J, Bottai M, et al. Intervention to diminish dehydration and kidney damage among sugarcane workers. Scand J Work Environ Health 2018; 44:16&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Meteorological Organization. 2023 smashes global temperature record, fueled by climate change and El Ni&#xf1;o. Geneva, Switzerland: World Meteorological Organization; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esper J, Torbenson M, B&#xfc;ntgen U. 2023 summer warmth unparalleled over the past 2,000&#x200a;years. Nature 2024; 631:94&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howard JT, Androne N, Alcover KC, Santos-Lozada AR. Trends of heat-related deaths in the US, 1999&#x2013;2023. JAMA 2024; 332:1203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor EV, Vaidyanathan A, Flanders WD, et al. Differences in heat-related mortality by citizenship status: United States, 2005&#x2013;2014. Am J Public Health 2018; 108 (S2):S131&#x2013;S136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flouris AD, Dinas PC, Ioannou LG, et al. Workers&#x2019; health and productivity under occupational heat strain: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Planet Health 2018; 2:e521&#x2013;e531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NIOSH. Criteria for a recommended standard. Occupational exposure to heath and hot environments. Cincinnati: DHHS (NIOSH). NIOSH; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenna ZJ, Nava RC, Magalh&#xe3;es C, et al. A comprehensive evaluation of heat stress and heat strain in a sample of sugarcane cutters in Brazil. J Appl Physiol 2023; 135:1431&#x2013;1439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman CL, Johnson BD, Parker MD, et al. Kidney physiology and pathophysiology during heat stress and the modification by exercise, dehydration, heat acclimation and aging. Temperature 2021; 8:108&#x2013;159.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masoud A, McKenna ZJ, Li Z, et al. Strategies to mitigate acute kidney injury risk during physical work in the heat. Am J Physiol-Ren Physiol 2024; 326:F499&#x2013;510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlader ZJ, Hostler D, Parker MD, et al. The potential for renal injury elicited by physical work in the heat. Nutrients 2019; 11:E2087.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strau&#xdf; C, Booke H, Forni L, Zarbock A. Biomarkers of acute kidney injury: from discovery to the future of clinical practice. J Clin Anesth 2024; 95:111458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cramer MN, Gagnon D, Laitano O, Crandall CG. Human temperature regulation under heat stress in health, disease, and injury. Physiol Rev 2022; 102:1907&#x2013;1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hess HW, Stooks JJ, Baker TB, et al. Kidney injury risk during prolonged exposure to current and projected wet bulb temperatures occurring during extreme heat events in healthy young men. J Appl Physiol Bethesda Md 19852022; 133:27&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlader ZJ, Chapman CL, Sarker S, et al. Firefighter work duration influences the extent of acute kidney injury. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2017; 49:1745&#x2013;1753.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hess HW, Baker TB, Tarr ML, et al. Occupational heat stress recommendation compliance attenuates AKI risk compared with a work&#x2013;rest ratio&#x2013;matched, positive control scenario. Kidney360 2023; 4:1752&#x2013;1756.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman CL, Johnson BD, Vargas NT, et al. Both hyperthermia and dehydration during physical work in the heat contribute to the risk of acute kidney injury. J Appl Physiol Bethesda Md 19852020; 128:715&#x2013;728.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radigan LR, Robinson S. Effects of environmental heat stress and exercise on renal blood flow and filtration rate. J Appl Physiol 1949; 2:185&#x2013;191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenney WL, Zappe DH. Effect of age on renal blood flow during exercise. Aging Clin Exp Res 1994; 6:293&#x2013;302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roncal-Jimenez CA, Sato Y, Milagres T, et al. Experimental heat stress nephropathy and liver injury are improved by allopurinol. Am J Physiol-Ren Physiol 2018; 315:F726&#x2013;F733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato Y, Roncal-Jimenez CA, Andres-Hernando A, et al. Increase of core temperature affected the progression of kidney injury by repeated heat stress exposure. Am J Physiol-Ren Physiol 2019; 317:F1111&#x2013;F1121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamoto M. Renal cortical and medullary tissue blood flow during experimental hyperthermia in dogs. Jpn J Hyperthermic Oncol 1994; 10:78&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuo JL, Li XC. Proximal nephron. In: Terjung R, editor. Comprehensive physiology [Internet]. 1st ed. Wiley; 2013 [cited 29 October 2024]. pp. 1079&#x2013;123. https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/cphy.c110061 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer LG, Schnermann J. Integrated control of Na transport along the nephron. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 2015; 10:676&#x2013;687.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doucet A. Function and control of Na-K-ATPase in single nephron segments of the mammalian kidney. Kidney Int 1988; 34:749&#x2013;760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melin B, Koulmann N, Jimenez C, et al. Comparison of passive heat or exercise-induced dehydration on renal water and electrolyte excretion: the hormonal involvement. Eur J Appl Physiol 2001; 85:250&#x2013;258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans RG, Ince C, Joles JA, et al. Haemodynamic influences on kidney oxygenation: clinical implications of integrative physiology. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol 2013; 40:106&#x2013;122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devarajan P. Update on mechanisms of ischemic acute kidney injury. J Am Soc Nephrol 2006; 17:1503&#x2013;1520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall DM, Buettner GR, Oberley LW, et al. Mechanisms of circulatory and intestinal barrier dysfunction during whole body hyperthermia. Am J Physiol-Heart Circ Physiol 2001; 280:H509&#x2013;H521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burhans WS, Rossiter Burhans CA, Baumgard LH. Invited review: lethal heat stress: the putative pathophysiology of a deadly disorder in dairy cattle. J Dairy Sci 2022; 105:3716&#x2013;3735.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houghton MJ, Snipe RMJ, Williamson G, Costa RJS. Plasma measurements of the dual sugar test reveal carbohydrate immediately alleviates intestinal permeability caused by exertional heat stress. J Physiol 2023; 601:4573&#x2013;4589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenna ZJ, Atkins WC, Wallace T, et al. Gastrointestinal permeability and kidney injury risk during hyperthermia in young and older adults. Exp Physiol 2024. E092204[Online ahead of print].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall DM, Baumgardner KR, Oberley TD, Gisolfi CV. Splanchnic tissues undergo hypoxic stress during whole body hyperthermia. Am J Physiol-Gastrointest Liver Physiol 1999; 276:G1195&#x2013;G1203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murashima M, Nishimoto M, Kokubu M, et al. Inflammation as a predictor of acute kidney injury and mediator of higher mortality after acute kidney injury in noncardiac surgery. Sci Rep 2019; 9:20260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houser MC, Smith DJ, Rhodes D, et al. Inflammatory profiles, gut microbiome, and kidney function are impacted after high-fidelity firefighter training. Int J Hyg Environ Health 2023; 248:114107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notley SR, Akerman AP, Friesen BJ, et al. Heat tolerance and occupational heat exposure limits in older men with and without Type 2 diabetes or hypertension. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2021; 53:2196&#x2013;2206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenny GP, Yardley J, Brown C, et al. Heat stress in older individuals and patients with common chronic diseases. Can Med Assoc J 2010; 182:1053&#x2013;1060.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grams ME, Sang Y, Ballew SH, et al. A meta-analysis of the association of estimated GFR, albuminuria, age, race, and sex with acute kidney injury. Am J Kidney Dis 2015; 66:591&#x2013;601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazancio&#x11f;lu R. Risk factors for chronic kidney disease: an update. Kidney Int Suppl 2013; 3:368&#x2013;371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics. Employed persons by detailed industry, sex, race, and Hispanic or Latino ethnicity [Internet]. 2023 [cited 2 November 2024]. (Current Population Survey). https://www.bls.gov/cps/cpsaat18b.htm .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong XS, Wang X, Daw C, Ringen K. Chronic diseases and functional limitations among older construction workers in the United States: a 10-year follow-up study. J Occup Environ Med 2011; 53:372&#x2013;380.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>