<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41525134</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1520-5827</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Langmuir : the ACS journal of surfaces and colloids</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Langmuir</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Relaxor Ferroelectric-Like Spatiotemporal Memory in Field-Driven Lipid Bilayers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2542</StartPage><EndPage>2547</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2542-2547</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c05017</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Lipid membranes are often regarded as passive barriers, yet their nonlinear dielectric response remains poorly understood. Using all-atom molecular dynamics, we show that fully hydrated dipalmitoylphosphatidylcholine bilayers exhibit relaxor ferroelectric-like behavior under time-dependent electric fields. Unlike crystalline relaxors, which are bipolar and display little remanent polarization, lipid bilayers exhibit a unipolar polarization response: even an alternating current field produces persistent, asymmetric polarization. The underlying free-energy landscape contains two distinct minima, a nonpolarized state and a unipolarly polarized state, between which stochastic thermally activated transitions occur. Directionally resolved Van Hove analysis reveals pronounced anisotropy arising from out-of-plane electric dipole alignment, interleaflet coupling, and lateral polarization domains. Each field cycle nucleates polarization at distinct sites and monitors their relaxation, marking a crossover from thermal fluctuations to field-sustained polarization. Remarkably, these polarized domains persist after field removal, generating long-lived, spatially coherent dipolar patterns that encode nanoscale polarization memory. Potassium chloride amplifies these effects via dielectric screening and a modified hydration structure, enhancing electric dipole flexibility and cooperativity. Together, these results establish protein-free bilayers as nonlinear, history-dependent dielectrics capable of sustaining field-tunable electromechanical coupling, providing an emergent physical foundation for nanoscale information storage and memory phenomena reminiscent of short- and long-term plasticity in soft neuromorphic systems.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bolmatov</LastName><ForeName>Dima</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4179-8971</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physics and Astronomy, Texas Tech University, Lubbock, Texas 79409, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zav'yalov</LastName><ForeName>Dmitry</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Volgograd State Technical University, Volgograd 400005, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Egami</LastName><ForeName>Takeshi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1126-0276</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Materials Science and Engineering, University of Tennessee, Knoxville, Tennessee 37996, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Materials Science and Technology Division, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Oak Ridge, Tennessee 37831, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Langmuir</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9882736</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0743-7463</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41525134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c05017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>