<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40134645</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2220-6124</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of nephrology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Nephrol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Optimizing chronic kidney disease management: The potential of a multi-strain probiotic formulation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>101515</StartPage><MedlinePgn>101515</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">101515</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5527/wjn.v14.i1.101515</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Chronic kidney disease (CKD), which represents a significant global health concern, is characterized by a gradual decline in kidney function, leading to complications such as electrolyte imbalance, cardiovascular disease, and immune dysfunction. Standard CKD management includes dietary modifications, ketoanalogues supplementation, blood pressure and blood glucose control, hydration maintenance, and treatment of the underlying causes. Emerging evidence has indicated a significant role of the gut microbiota in CKD, and that dysbiosis of the gut microbiota contributes to the progression of CKD towards end-stage renal disease. Probiotics and prebiotics have recently garnered attention owing to their potential to enhance gastrointestinal health and well-being by restoring the balance of the gut microbiota. Specific probiotic strains, including <i>Lactobacillus</i> and <i>Bifidobacterium</i>, promote beneficial bacterial growth, suppress harmful bacteria, and exert anti-inflammatory, antihypertensive, and antidiabetic effects. The combination of <i>Streptococcus thermophilus</i>, <i>Lactobacillus acidophilus</i>, <i>Bifidobacterium longum</i>, and <i>Bacillus coagulans</i> has demonstrated potential as a therapeutic formulation for CKD management in various studies, highlighting its promise in treating CKD; however, supporting evidence remains limited, making it crucial to conduct further investigations to determine the specific effects of different probiotic formulations on outcomes in patients with CKD.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2025. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chafekar</LastName><ForeName>Deodatta</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dr V N Pawar Medical College, Director Supreme Kidney Care, Nashik 422005, Mah&#x101;r&#x101;shtra, India. nchafy@hotmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Nephrol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101610229</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2220-6124</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bifidobacterium</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic kidney disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gut microbiota</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lactobacillus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prebiotics</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: The author reports no relevant conflicts of interest for this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40134645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11755232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5527/wjn.v14.i1.101515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Romagnani P, Remuzzi G, Glassock R, Levin A, Jager KJ, Tonelli M, Massy Z, Wanner C, Anders HJ. Chronic kidney disease. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2017;3:17088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29168475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill NR, Fatoba ST, Oke JL, Hirst JA, O'Callaghan CA, Lasserson DS, Hobbs FD. Global Prevalence of Chronic Kidney Disease - A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. PLoS One. 2016;11:e0158765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4934905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27383068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liyanage T, Toyama T, Hockham C, Ninomiya T, Perkovic V, Woodward M, Fukagawa M, Matsushita K, Praditpornsilpa K, Hooi LS, Iseki K, Lin MY, Stirnadel-Farrant HA, Jha V, Jun M. Prevalence of chronic kidney disease in Asia: a systematic review and analysis. BMJ Glob Health. 2022;7:e007525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8796212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35078812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li PK, Garcia-Garcia G, Lui SF, Andreoli S, Fung WW, Hradsky A, Kumaraswami L, Liakopoulos V, Rakhimova Z, Saadi G, Strani L, Ulasi I, Kalantar-Zadeh K. Kidney Health for Everyone Everywhere: From Prevention to Detection and Equitable Access to Care. Can J Kidney Health Dis. 2020;7:2054358120910569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7066467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32215213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aashima, Nanda M, Sharma R, Jani C. The burden of chronic kidney disease in Asia, 1990-2019: Examination of estimates from global burden of disease 2019 study. Nephrology (Carlton) 2022;27:610&#x2013;620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35506615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gansevoort RT, Correa-Rotter R, Hemmelgarn BR, Jafar TH, Heerspink HJ, Mann JF, Matsushita K, Wen CP. Chronic kidney disease and cardiovascular risk: epidemiology, mechanisms, and prevention. Lancet. 2013;382:339&#x2013;352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23727170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go AS, Chertow GM, Fan D, McCulloch CE, Hsu CY. Chronic kidney disease and the risks of death, cardiovascular events, and hospitalization. N Engl J Med. 2004;351:1296&#x2013;1305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15385656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization.  Global status report on noncommunicable diseases 2014. [cited 17 September 2024]. Available from: https://iris.who.int/bitstream/handle/10665/148114/9789241564854_eng.pdf .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25873596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly JT, Su G, Zhang L, Qin X, Marshall S, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Ortiz A, Clase CM, Campbell KL, Xu H, Carrero JJ. Modifiable Lifestyle Factors for Primary Prevention of CKD: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2021;32:239&#x2013;253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7894668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32868398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li PK, Garcia-Garcia G, Lui SF, Andreoli S, Fung WW, Hradsky A, Kumaraswami L, Liakopoulos V, Rakhimova Z, Saadi G, Strani L, Ulasi I, Kalantar-Zadeh K World Kidney Day 2020 Steering Committee. Kidney health for everyone everywhere - from prevention to detection and equitable access to care. Braz J Med Biol Res. 2020;53:e9614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7076785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32159613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Kidney Foundation. KDOQI Clinical Practice Guideline for Diabetes and CKD: 2012 Update. Am J Kidney Dis. 2012;60:850&#x2013;886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23067652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abiemo EE, Alonso A, Nettleton JA, Steffen LM, Bertoni AG, Jain A, Lutsey PL. Relationships of the Mediterranean dietary pattern with insulin resistance and diabetes incidence in the Multi-Ethnic Study of Atherosclerosis (MESA) Br J Nutr. 2013;109:1490&#x2013;1497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4002212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22932232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakayama M, Okuda S, Tamaki K, Fujishima M. Short- or long-term effects of a low-protein diet on fibronectin and transforming growth factor-beta synthesis in Adriamycin-induced nephropathy. J Lab Clin Med. 1996;127:29&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8592094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang AY, Mallamaci F, Zoccali C. What is central to renal nutrition: protein or sodium intake? Clin Kidney J. 2023;16:1824&#x2013;1833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10616450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37915942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhee CM, Wang AY, Biruete A, Kistler B, Kovesdy CP, Zarantonello D, Ko GJ, Piccoli GB, Garibotto G, Brunori G, Sumida K, Lambert K, Moore LW, Han SH, Narasaki Y, Kalantar-Zadeh K. Nutritional and Dietary Management of Chronic Kidney Disease Under Conservative and Preservative Kidney Care Without Dialysis. J Ren Nutr. 2023;33:S56&#x2013;S66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10756934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37394104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ariyanopparut S, Metta K, Avihingsanon Y, Eiam-Ong S, Kittiskulnam P. The role of a low protein diet supplemented with ketoanalogues on kidney progression in pre-dialysis chronic kidney disease patients. Sci Rep. 2023;13:15459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10509207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37726370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuchs M, Engel J, Campos M, Matejec R, Henrich M, Harbach H, Wolff M, Weism&#xfc;ller K, Menges T, Heidt MC, Welters ID, Kr&#xfc;ll M, Hempelmann G, M&#xfc;hling J. Intracellular alpha-keto acid quantification by fluorescence-HPLC. Amino Acids. 2009;36:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18283414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yen CL, Fan PC, Chen JJ, Kuo G, Hsiao CC, Chen CY, Tu YR, Hsu HH, Chen YC, Chang CH. Ketoanalogues Supplemental Low Protein Diet Safely Decreases Short-Term Risk of Dialysis among CKD Stage 4 Patients. Nutrients. 2022;14:4020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9571353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36235673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koppe L, Cassani de Oliveira M, Fouque D. Ketoacid Analogues Supplementation in Chronic Kidney Disease and Future Perspectives. Nutrients. 2019;11:2071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6770434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31484354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafar TH, Stark PC, Schmid CH, Landa M, Maschio G, de Jong PE, de Zeeuw D, Shahinfar S, Toto R, Levey AS AIPRD Study Group. Progression of chronic kidney disease: the role of blood pressure control, proteinuria, and angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibition: a patient-level meta-analysis. Ann Intern Med. 2003;139:244&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12965979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugh D, Gallacher PJ, Dhaun N. Management of Hypertension in Chronic Kidney Disease. Drugs. 2019;79:365&#x2013;379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6422950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30758803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atlas SA. The renin-angiotensin aldosterone system: pathophysiological role and pharmacologic inhibition. J Manag Care Pharm. 2007;13:9&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10437584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17970613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacIsaac RJ, Jerums G, Ekinci EI. Effects of glycaemic management on diabetic kidney disease. World J Diabetes. 2017;8:172&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5437616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28572879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hahr AJ, Molitch ME. Management of diabetes mellitus in patients with chronic kidney disease. Clin Diabetes Endocrinol. 2015;1:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5469199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28702221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Boer IH, Khunti K, Sadusky T, Tuttle KR, Neumiller JJ, Rhee CM, Rosas SE, Rossing P, Bakris G. Diabetes management in chronic kidney disease: a consensus report by the American Diabetes Association (ADA) and Kidney Disease: Improving Global Outcomes (KDIGO) Kidney Int. 2022;102:974&#x2013;989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36202661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouby N, Clark WF, Roussel R, Taveau C, Wang CJ. Hydration and kidney health. Obes Facts. 2014;7 Suppl 2:19&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5646211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24853348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalantar-Zadeh K, Jafar TH, Nitsch D, Neuen BL, Perkovic V. Chronic kidney disease. Lancet. 2021;398:786&#x2013;802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34175022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SY, Moon A. Drug-induced nephrotoxicity and its biomarkers. Biomol Ther (Seoul) 2012;20:268&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3794522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24130922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwiatkowska E, Doma&#x144;ski L, Dziedziejko V, Kajdy A, Stefa&#x144;ska K, Kwiatkowski S. The Mechanism of Drug Nephrotoxicity and the Methods for Preventing Kidney Damage. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:6109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8201165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34204029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x17e;idi&#x107;-Krivi&#x107; A, Sher EK, Kusturica J, Farhat EK, Nawaz A, Sher F. Unveiling drug induced nephrotoxicity using novel biomarkers and cutting-edge preventive strategies. Chem Biol Interact. 2024;388:110838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38104745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster AC, Nagler EV, Morton RL, Masson P. Chronic Kidney Disease. Lancet. 2017;389:1238&#x2013;1252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27887750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neale EP, Rosario VD, Probst Y, Beck E, Tran TB, Lambert K. Lifestyle Interventions, Kidney Disease Progression, and Quality of Life: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. Kidney Med. 2023;5:100643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10205767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37235039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill C, Guarner F, Reid G, Gibson GR, Merenstein DJ, Pot B, Morelli L, Canani RB, Flint HJ, Salminen S, Calder PC, Sanders ME. Expert consensus document. The International Scientific Association for Probiotics and Prebiotics consensus statement on the scope and appropriate use of the term probiotic. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2014;11:506&#x2013;514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24912386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaziri ND, Wong J, Pahl M, Piceno YM, Yuan J, DeSantis TZ, Ni Z, Nguyen TH, Andersen GL. Chronic kidney disease alters intestinal microbial flora. Kidney Int. 2013;83:308&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22992469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagundes RAB, Soder TF, Grokoski KC, Benetti F, Mendes RH. Probiotics in the treatment of chronic kidney disease: a systematic review. J Bras Nefrol. 2018;40:278&#x2013;286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6533949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29958304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalesi S, Sun J, Buys N, Jayasinghe R. Effect of probiotics on blood pressure: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized, controlled trials. Hypertension. 2014;64:897&#x2013;903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25047574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson GR, Hutkins R, Sanders ME, Prescott SL, Reimer RA, Salminen SJ, Scott K, Stanton C, Swanson KS, Cani PD, Verbeke K, Reid G. Expert consensus document: The International Scientific Association for Probiotics and Prebiotics (ISAPP) consensus statement on the definition and scope of prebiotics. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;14:491&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28611480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Wang X, Zhang P, Fang Y, Liu Y, Ding Y, Zhang W. Intestinal homeostasis in the gut-lung-kidney axis: a prospective therapeutic target in immune-related chronic kidney diseases. Front Immunol. 2023;14:1266792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10646503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38022571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujisaka S, Watanabe Y, Tobe K. The gut microbiome: a core regulator of metabolism. J Endocrinol. 2023;256:e220111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9874984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36458804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sender R, Fuchs S, Milo R. Revised Estimates for the Number of Human and Bacteria Cells in the Body. PLoS Biol. 2016;14:e1002533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4991899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27541692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>den Besten G, van Eunen K, Groen AK, Venema K, Reijngoud DJ, Bakker BM. The role of short-chain fatty acids in the interplay between diet, gut microbiota, and host energy metabolism. J Lipid Res. 2013;54:2325&#x2013;2340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3735932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23821742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natarajan N, Pluznick JL. From microbe to man: the role of microbial short chain fatty acid metabolites in host cell biology. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2014;307:C979&#x2013;C985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5243208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25273884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Argenio G, Mazzacca G. Short-chain fatty acid in the human colon. Relation to inflammatory bowel diseases and colon cancer. Adv Exp Med Biol. 1999;472:149&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10736623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner JR. Intestinal mucosal barrier function in health and disease. Nat Rev Immunol. 2009;9:799&#x2013;809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19855405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasano A. Leaky gut and autoimmune diseases. Clin Rev Allergy Immunol. 2012;42:71&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22109896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haussler MR, Whitfield GK, Kaneko I, Haussler CA, Hsieh D, Hsieh JC, Jurutka PW. Molecular mechanisms of vitamin D action. Calcif Tissue Int. 2013;92:77&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22782502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramezani A, Raj DS. The gut microbiome, kidney disease, and targeted interventions. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2014;25:657&#x2013;670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3968507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24231662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanholder R, De Smet R, Glorieux G, Argil&#xe9;s A, Baurmeister U, Brunet P, Clark W, Cohen G, De Deyn PP, Deppisch R, Descamps-Latscha B, Henle T, J&#xf6;rres A, Lemke HD, Massy ZA, Passlick-Deetjen J, Rodriguez M, Stegmayr B, Stenvinkel P, Tetta C, Wanner C, Zidek W European Uremic Toxin Work Group (EUTox) Review on uremic toxins: classification, concentration, and interindividual variability. Kidney Int. 2003;63:1934&#x2013;1943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12675874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evenepoel P, Meijers BK, Bammens BR, Verbeke K. Uremic toxins originating from colonic microbial metabolism. Kidney Int Suppl. 2009:S12&#x2013;S19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19946322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaziri ND, Yuan J, Norris K. Role of urea in intestinal barrier dysfunction and disruption of epithelial tight junction in chronic kidney disease. Am J Nephrol. 2013;37:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3686571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23258127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau WL, Kalantar-Zadeh K, Vaziri ND. The Gut as a Source of Inflammation in Chronic Kidney Disease. Nephron. 2015;130:92&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4485546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25967288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaziri ND, Zhao YY, Pahl MV. Altered intestinal microbial flora and impaired epithelial barrier structure and function in CKD: the nature, mechanisms, consequences and potential treatment. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2016;31:737&#x2013;746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25883197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evenepoel P, Poesen R, Meijers B. The gut-kidney axis. Pediatr Nephrol. 2017;32:2005&#x2013;2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27848096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramezani A, Massy ZA, Meijers B, Evenepoel P, Vanholder R, Raj DS. Role of the Gut Microbiome in Uremia: A Potential Therapeutic Target. Am J Kidney Dis. 2016;67:483&#x2013;498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5408507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26590448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fijan S. Microorganisms with claimed probiotic properties: an overview of recent literature. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2014;11:4745&#x2013;4767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4053917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24859749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemarajata P, Versalovic J. Effects of probiotics on gut microbiota: mechanisms of intestinal immunomodulation and neuromodulation. Therap Adv Gastroenterol. 2013;6:39&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3539293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23320049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davani-Davari D, Negahdaripour M, Karimzadeh I, Seifan M, Mohkam M, Masoumi SJ, Berenjian A, Ghasemi Y. Prebiotics: Definition, Types, Sources, Mechanisms, and Clinical Applications. Foods. 2019;8:92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6463098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30857316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu IW, Hsu KH, Lee CC, Sun CY, Hsu HJ, Tsai CJ, Tzen CY, Wang YC, Lin CY, Wu MS. p-Cresyl sulphate and indoxyl sulphate predict progression of chronic kidney disease. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2011;26:938&#x2013;947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3042976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20884620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang WH, Wang Z, Levison BS, Koeth RA, Britt EB, Fu X, Wu Y, Hazen SL. Intestinal microbial metabolism of phosphatidylcholine and cardiovascular risk. N Engl J Med. 2013;368:1575&#x2013;1584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3701945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23614584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehto M, Groop PH. The Gut-Kidney Axis: Putative Interconnections Between Gastrointestinal and Renal Disorders. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2018;9:553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6157406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30283404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zirker L. Probiotic Use in Chronic Kidney Disease Patients. J Renal Nutr. 2014;24:e47&#x2013;e49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vacca M, Celano G, Lenucci MS, Fontana S, Forgia FM, Minervini F, Scarano A, Santino A, Dalfino G, Gesualdo L, De Angelis M. In Vitro Selection of Probiotics, Prebiotics, and Antioxidants to Develop an Innovative Synbiotic (NatuREN G) and Testing Its Effect in Reducing Uremic Toxins in Fecal Batches from CKD Patients. Microorganisms. 2021;9:1316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8235484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34204263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei M, Wei L, Hu S, Yang B, Si J, Yang H, Zhai J. Probiotics, prebiotics and synbiotics for chronic kidney disease: protocol for a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Open. 2018;8:e020863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6067341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30056379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian N, Li L, Ng JK, Li PK. The Potential Benefits and Controversies of Probiotics Use in Patients at Different Stages of Chronic Kidney Disease. Nutrients. 2022;14:4044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9571670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36235699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Mauri A, Carrera D, Bagnati M, Rolla R, Vidali M, Chiarinotti D, Pane M, Amoruso A, Del Piano M. Probiotics-Supplemented Low-Protein Diet for Microbiota Modulation in Patients with Advanced Chronic Kidney Disease (ProLowCKD): Results from a Placebo-Controlled Randomized Trial. Nutrients. 2022;14:1637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9025298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35458199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner S, Merkling T, Metzger M, Koppe L, Laville M, Boutron-Ruault MC, Frimat L, Combe C, Massy ZA, Stengel B, Fouque D. Probiotic Intake and Inflammation in Patients With Chronic Kidney Disease: An Analysis of the CKD-REIN Cohort. Front Nutr. 2022;9:772596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9005823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35433774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miranda Alatriste PV, Urbina Arronte R, G&#xf3;mez Espinosa CO, Espinosa Cuevas Mde L. Effect of probiotics on human blood urea levels in patients with chronic renal failure. Nutr Hosp. 2014;29:582&#x2013;590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24559003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Natarajan R, Pechenyak B, Vyas U, Ranganathan P, Weinberg A, Liang P, Mallappallil MC, Norin AJ, Friedman EA, Saggi SJ. Randomized controlled trial of strain-specific probiotic formulation (Renadyl) in dialysis patients. Biomed Res Int. 2014;2014:568571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4132402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25147806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosola C, Rocchetti MT, di Bari I, Acquaviva PM, Maranzano V, Corciulo S, Di Ciaula A, Di Palo DM, La Forgia FM, Fontana S, De Angelis M, Portincasa P, Gesualdo L. An Innovative Synbiotic Formulation Decreases Free Serum Indoxyl Sulfate, Small Intestine Permeability and Ameliorates Gastrointestinal Symptoms in a Randomized Pilot Trial in Stage IIIb-IV CKD Patients. Toxins (Basel) 2021;13:334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8147955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34063068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong HJ, Xie X, Chen WJ, Zhuang YP, Hu X, Cai YL, Zeng HL, Xiao C, Li Y, Ding Y, Xue L, Chen M, Zhang J, Wu Q, He XX. Washed microbiota transplantation improves renal function in patients with renal dysfunction: a retrospective cohort study. J Transl Med. 2023;21:740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10588208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37858192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hida M, Aiba Y, Sawamura S, Suzuki N, Satoh T, Koga Y. Inhibition of the accumulation of uremic toxins in the blood and their precursors in the feces after oral administration of Lebenin, a lactic acid bacteria preparation, to uremic patients undergoing hemodialysis. Nephron. 1996;74:349&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8893154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takayama F, Taki K, Niwa T. Bifidobacterium in gastro-resistant seamless capsule reduces serum levels of indoxyl sulfate in patients on hemodialysis. Am J Kidney Dis. 2003;41:S142&#x2013;S145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12612972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakabayashi I, Nakamura M, Kawakami K, Ohta T, Kato I, Uchida K, Yoshida M. Effects of synbiotic treatment on serum level of p-cresol in haemodialysis patients: a preliminary study. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2011;26:1094&#x2013;1098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20929916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simenhoff ML, Dunn SR, Zollner GP, Fitzpatrick ME, Emery SM, Sandine WE, Ayres JW. Biomodulation of the toxic and nutritional effects of small bowel bacterial overgrowth in end-stage kidney disease using freeze-dried Lactobacillus acidophilus. Miner Electrolyte Metab. 1996;22:92&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8676836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi M, Johnson DW, Morrison M, Pascoe EM, Coombes JS, Forbes JM, Szeto CC, McWhinney BC, Ungerer JP, Campbell KL. Synbiotics Easing Renal Failure by Improving Gut Microbiology (SYNERGY): A Randomized Trial. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2016;11:223&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4741035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26772193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang IK, Wu YY, Yang YF, Ting IW, Lin CC, Yen TH, Chen JH, Wang CH, Huang CC, Lin HC. The effect of probiotics on serum levels of cytokine and endotoxin in peritoneal dialysis patients: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Benef Microbes. 2015;6:423&#x2013;430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25609654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viramontes-H&#xf6;rner D, M&#xe1;rquez-Sandoval F, Mart&#xed;n-del-Campo F, Vizmanos-Lamotte B, Sandoval-Rodr&#xed;guez A, Armend&#xe1;riz-Borunda J, Garc&#xed;a-Bejarano H, Renoirte-L&#xf3;pez K, Garc&#xed;a-Garc&#xed;a G. Effect of a symbiotic gel (Lactobacillus acidophilus + Bifidobacterium lactis + inulin) on presence and severity of gastrointestinal symptoms in hemodialysis patients. J Ren Nutr. 2015;25:284&#x2013;291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25455039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranganathan N, Ranganathan P, Friedman EA, Joseph A, Delano B, Goldfarb DS, Tam P, Rao AV, Anteyi E, Musso CG. Pilot study of probiotic dietary supplementation for promoting healthy kidney function in patients with chronic kidney disease. Adv Ther. 2010;27:634&#x2013;647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20721651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavan M. Influence of prebiotic and probiotic supplementation on the progression of chronic kidney disease. Minerva Urol Nefrol. 2016;68:222&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24990390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Mora J, Mart&#xed;nez-Hern&#xe1;ndez NE, Mart&#xed;n del Campo-L&#xf3;pez F, Viramontes-H&#xf6;rner D, Vizmanos-Lamotte B, Mu&#xf1;oz-Valle JF, Garc&#xed;a-Garc&#xed;a G, Parra-Rojas I, Castro-Alarc&#xf3;n N. Effects of a symbiotic on gut microbiota in Mexican patients with end-stage renal disease. J Ren Nutr. 2014;24:330&#x2013;335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25066654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guida B, German&#xf2; R, Trio R, Russo D, Memoli B, Grumetto L, Barbato F, Cataldi M. Effect of short-term synbiotic treatment on plasma p-cresol levels in patients with chronic renal failure: a randomized clinical trial. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2014;24:1043&#x2013;1049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24929795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranganathan N, Friedman EA, Tam P, Rao V, Ranganathan P, Dheer R. Probiotic dietary supplementation in patients with stage 3 and 4 chronic kidney disease: a 6-month pilot scale trial in Canada. Curr Med Res Opin. 2009;25:1919&#x2013;1930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19558344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taki K, Takayama F, Niwa T. Beneficial effects of Bifidobacteria in a gastroresistant seamless capsule on hyperhomocysteinemia in hemodialysis patients. J Ren Nutr. 2005;15:77&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15648012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ando Y, Miyata Y, Tanba K, Saito O, Muto S, Kurosu M, Homma S, Kusano E, Asano Y. [Effect of oral intake of an enteric capsule preparation containing Bifidobacterium longum on the progression of chronic renal failure] Nihon Jinzo Gakkai Shi. 2003;45:759&#x2013;764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14737993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade-Oliveira V, Amano MT, Correa-Costa M, Castoldi A, Felizardo RJ, de Almeida DC, Bassi EJ, Moraes-Vieira PM, Hiyane MI, Rodas AC, Peron JP, Aguiar CF, Reis MA, Ribeiro WR, Valduga CJ, Curi R, Vinolo MA, Ferreira CM, C&#xe2;mara NO. Gut Bacteria Products Prevent AKI Induced by Ischemia-Reperfusion. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2015;26:1877&#x2013;1888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4520159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25589612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranganathan N, Patel BG, Ranganathan P, Marczely J, Dheer R, Pechenyak B, Dunn SR, Verstraete W, Decroos K, Mehta R, Friedman EA. In vitro and in vivo assessment of intraintestinal bacteriotherapy in chronic kidney disease. ASAIO J. 2006;52:70&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16436893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prakash S, Chang TM. Microencapsulated genetically engineered live E. coli DH5 cells administered orally to maintain normal plasma urea level in uremic rats. Nat Med. 1996;2:883&#x2013;887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8705857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranganathan N, Patel B, Ranganathan P, Marczely J, Dheer R, Chordia T, Dunn SR, Friedman EA. Probiotic amelioration of azotemia in 5/6th nephrectomized Sprague-Dawley rats. ScientificWorldJournal. 2005;5:652&#x2013;660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5936581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16127597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plaza-D&#xed;az J, Ruiz-Ojeda FJ, Vilchez-Padial LM, Gil A. Evidence of the Anti-Inflammatory Effects of Probiotics and Synbiotics in Intestinal Chronic Diseases. Nutrients. 2017;9:555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5490534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28555037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suez J, Zmora N, Segal E, Elinav E. The pros, cons, and many unknowns of probiotics. Nat Med. 2019;25:716&#x2013;729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31061539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marco ML, Heeney D, Binda S, Cifelli CJ, Cotter PD, Folign&#xe9; B, G&#xe4;nzle M, Kort R, Pasin G, Pihlanto A, Smid EJ, Hutkins R. Health benefits of fermented foods: microbiota and beyond. Curr Opin Biotechnol. 2017;44:94&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27998788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanders ME, Merenstein DJ, Ouwehand AC, Reid G, Salminen S, Cabana MD, Paraskevakos G, Leyer G. Probiotic use in at-risk populations. J Am Pharm Assoc (2003) 2016;56:680&#x2013;686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27836128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwoji ID, Aiyegoro OA, Okpeku M, Adeleke MA. Multi-Strain Probiotics: Synergy among Isolates Enhances Biological Activities. Biology (Basel) 2021;10:322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8070017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33924344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nataraj BH, Ali SA, Behare PV, Yadav H. Postbiotics-parabiotics: the new horizons in microbial biotherapy and functional foods. Microb Cell Fact. 2020;19:168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7441679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32819443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parvez S, Malik KA, Ah Kang S, Kim HY. Probiotics and their fermented food products are beneficial for health. J Appl Microbiol. 2006;100:1171&#x2013;1185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16696665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seifert S, Bub A, Franz CM, Watzl B. Probiotic Lactobacillus casei Shirota supplementation does not modulate immunity in healthy men with reduced natural killer cell activity. J Nutr. 2011;141:978&#x2013;984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21430250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>