<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41676282</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1943-8141</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of translational research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Transl Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Rare neurological complications subsequent to brachial plexus block: a case report and literature review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>470</StartPage><EndPage>474</EndPage><MedlinePgn>470-474</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.62347/TMNU3861</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Brachial plexus block anesthesia is widely utilized for upper limb surgical procedures in clinical settings. The diffusion of local anesthetics within the intermuscular sulcus structure can lead to nerve paralysis. However, we report an exceptionally rare case of concurrent extensive neural blockade, with a spread far beyond expected boundaries, which carries significant clinical cautionary implications. This case report described a previously healthy patient who successfully underwent arthroscopic rotator cuff repair on the right shoulder under general anesthesia combined with a brachial plexus block. Following an ultrasound-guided intermuscular groove approach for brachial plexus block and superficial cervical plexus block, the patient developed numbness and reduced muscle strength in the right upper and lower limbs, along with unresponsiveness to painful stimuli. This paralysis lasted for at least 48 hours. Postoperative cranial computerized tomography (CT) and cervical X-ray showed no significant abnormalities. No neurological sequelae were observed after the complete resolution of the anesthetic effect. Necessary but limited tests and examinations were performed to establish a differential diagnosis, effectively excluding cerebral infarction, spinal disorders, peripheral vascular and nerve diseases, electrolyte abnormalities, and hysteria. While it is hypothesized that local anesthetics may contribute to lower limb paralysis, the specific mechanism by which these agents affect the nerves in this region remains unclear and requires further investigation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>AJTR Copyright &#xa9; 2026.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Long</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Ningbo No. 6 Hospital Ningbo 315040, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ningbo Clinical Research Center for Orthopedics, Sports Medicine &amp; Rehabilitation Ningbo, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Liangguang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Ningbo No. 6 Hospital Ningbo 315040, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ningbo Clinical Research Center for Orthopedics, Sports Medicine &amp; Rehabilitation Ningbo, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Miao</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Ningbo No. 6 Hospital Ningbo 315040, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ningbo Clinical Research Center for Orthopedics, Sports Medicine &amp; Rehabilitation Ningbo, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Jian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ningbo Clinical Research Center for Orthopedics, Sports Medicine &amp; Rehabilitation Ningbo, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Operating Room, Ningbo No. 6 Hospital Ningbo 315040, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Transl Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101493030</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1943-8141</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Complete unilateral limb paralysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">case report</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interscalene brachial plexus block</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41676282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12886102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.62347/TMNU3861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Feigl GC, Litz RJ, Marhofer P. Anatomy of the brachial plexus and its implications for daily clinical practice: regional anesthesia is applied anatomy. Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2020;45:620&#x2013;627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32471922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapral S, Greher M, Huber G, Willschke H, Kettner S, Kdolsky R, Marhofer P. Ultrasonographic guidance improves the success rate of interscalene brachial plexus blockade. Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2008;33:253&#x2013;258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18433677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danelli G, Bonarelli S, Togn&#xfa; A, Ghisi D, Fanelli A, Biondini S, Moschini E, Fanelli G. Prospective randomized comparison of ultrasound-guided and neurostimulation techniques for continuous interscalene brachial plexus block in patients undergoing coracoacromial ligament repair. Br J Anaesth. 2012;108:1006&#x2013;1010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22408273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellew B, Harrop-Griffiths WA, Bedforth N. Interscalene brachial plexus blocks and phrenic nerve palsy. Anesthesiology. 2014;120:1056&#x2013;1057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24694856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L, Gessner D, Kou A, Kasimova K, Memtsoudis SG, Mariano ER. Rate of occurrence of respiratory complications in patients who undergo shoulder arthroplasty with a continuous interscalene brachial plexus block and associated risk factors. Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2023;48:540&#x2013;546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37173097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stundner O, Meissnitzer M, Brummett CM, Moser S, Forstner R, Kok&#xf6;fer A, Danninger T, Gerner P, Kirchmair L, Fritsch G. Comparison of tissue distribution, phrenic nerve involvement, and epidural spread in standard- vs low-volume ultrasound-guided interscalene plexus block using contrast magnetic resonance imaging: a randomized, controlled trial. Br J Anaesth. 2016;116:405&#x2013;412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26865133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jadon A, Nage S, Swarupa CP, Motaka M. Weakness of contralateral upper limb after interscalene block - a case report. Indian J Anaesth. 2019;63:55&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6341887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30745614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lombard TP, Couper JL. Bilateral spread of analgesia following interscalene brachial plexus block. Anesthesiology. 1983;58:472&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6838002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritsch G, Hudelmaier M, Danninger T, Brummett C, Bock M, McCoy M. Bilateral loss of neural function after interscalene plexus blockade may be caused by epidural spread of local anesthetics: a cadaveric study. Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2013;38:64&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23222362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen R, Shi B, Zheng X, Zhou Z, Jin A, Ding Z, Lv H, Zhang H. Anatomic study and clinical significance of the dorsal meningovertebral ligaments of the thoracic dura mater. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2015;40:692&#x2013;698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25955087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyoshi S, Hamada K, Utsunomiya H, Nakayama K, Kizaki K, Horishita T, Uchida S. Intra-articular injection versus interscalene brachial plexus block for acute-phase postoperative pain management after arthroscopic shoulder surgery. J Orthop Sci. 2023;28:560&#x2013;566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35184956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin TH, Lee DY, Basith S, Manavalan B, Paik MJ, Rybinnik I, Mouradian MM, Ahn JH, Lee G. Metabolome changes in cerebral ischemia. Cells. 2020;9:1630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7407387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32645907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornung AL, Baker JD, Mallow GM, Sayari AJ, Albert HB, Tkachev A, An HS, Samartzis D. Resorption of lumbar disk herniation: mechanisms, clinical predictors, and future directions. JBJS Rev. 2023;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36722839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowley MP, Doughty CT. Entrapment neuropathies of the lower extremity. Med Clin North Am. 2019;103:371&#x2013;382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30704688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chin P, Kumaraswami S. Functional neurological symptom disorder: a continuing conundrum for the perioperative physician. Cureus. 2023;15:e42011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10430311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37593273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>