<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39320292</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1558-3597</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>84</Volume><Issue>18</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Am Coll Cardiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Asymptomatic vs Symptomatic Hypotension With Sacubitril/Valsartan in Heart&#xa0;Failure and Reduced Ejection Fraction in PARADIGM-HF.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1685</StartPage><EndPage>1700</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1685-1700</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jacc.2024.08.012</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0735-1097(24)08162-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Hypotension is an important clinical problem in heart failure (HF).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study sought to examine the association between asymptomatic vs symptomatic hypotension and outcomes in PARADIGM-HF (Prospective Comparison of ARNI With ACEI to Determine Impact on Global Mortality and&#xa0;Morbidity in Heart&#xa0;Failure).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In a post hoc analysis of PARADIGM-HF, the efficacy and safety of sacubitril/valsartan compared to enalapril were estimated using time-updated Cox proportional hazards models. The primary outcome was cardiovascular death or&#xa0;HF hospitalization.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Among 8,399 patients in PARADIGM-HF, 1,343 (16.0%) experienced only asymptomatic hypotension, and 936 (11.1%) experienced symptomatic hypotension at least once after randomization. Patients with symptomatic hypotension were older and more frequently had cardiovascular comorbidities compared to those developing only asymptomatic hypotension. By contrast, left ventricular ejection fraction was lower in those with asymptomatic hypotension. Patients who experienced either type of hypotension were at higher risk for all outcomes examined. However, the effect of sacubitril/valsartan on the primary outcome was not diminished in patients experiencing hypotension compared to those who did not: the HR for sacubitril/valsartan vs enalapril was 0.80 (95% CI: 0.72-0.89) for no hypotension, 0.87 (95% CI: 0.70-1.08) for asymptomatic hypotension, and 0.51 (95% CI: 0.38-0.69) for symptomatic hypotension (P<sub>interaction</sub>&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.01), and this was also true for cardiovascular and all-cause deaths. The safety of sacubitril/valsartan vs enalapril was also maintained regardless of the occurrence of hypotension. Discontinuation of randomized treatment was less common with sacubitril/valsartan vs enalapril in patients experiencing asymptomatic and symptomatic hypotension.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Although both asymptomatic and symptomatic hypotension during treatment with sacubitril/valsartan or enalapril were associated with worse outcomes, the benefits of sacubitril/valsartan were maintained (or even enhanced) in patients experiencing hypotension.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 American College of Cardiology Foundation. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsumoto</LastName><ForeName>Shingo</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>British Heart Foundation Cardiovascular Research Centre, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Li</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>British Heart Foundation Cardiovascular Research Centre, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Henderson</LastName><ForeName>Alasdair D</ForeName><Initials>AD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>British Heart Foundation Cardiovascular Research Centre, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>B&#xf6;hm</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Saarland University, Klink f&#xfc;r Innere Medizin III (Kardiologie, Angiologie und Internistische Intensivmedizin), Universit&#xe4;tsklinikum des Saarlandes, Homburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Desai</LastName><ForeName>Akshay S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiovascular Medicine, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>K&#xf8;ber</LastName><ForeName>Lars</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Copenhagen University Hospital-Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lefkowitz</LastName><ForeName>Martin P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Novartis, East Hanover, New Jersey, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Packer</LastName><ForeName>Milton</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baylor Heart and Vascular Institute, Baylor University Medical Center, Dallas, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rouleau</LastName><ForeName>Jean L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut de Cardiologie de Montr&#xe9;al, Universit&#xe9; de Montr&#xe9;al, Montreal, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Solomon</LastName><ForeName>Scott D</ForeName><Initials>SD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiovascular Medicine, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swedberg</LastName><ForeName>Karl</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Clinical Medicine, University of Gothenburg, Gothenburg, Sweden.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vaduganathan</LastName><ForeName>Muthiah</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiovascular Medicine, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vardeny</LastName><ForeName>Orly</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Minneapolis Veterans Affairs Center for Care Delivery and Outcomes Research, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Voors</LastName><ForeName>Adriaan A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Groningen, Groningen, the Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zile</LastName><ForeName>Michael R</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, South Carolina, USA; Ralph H. Johnson Veterans Administration Medical Center, Charleston, South Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jhund</LastName><ForeName>Pardeep S</ForeName><Initials>PS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>British Heart Foundation Cardiovascular Research Centre, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McMurray</LastName><ForeName>John J V</ForeName><Initials>JJV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>British Heart Foundation Cardiovascular Research Centre, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, United Kingdom. Electronic address: john.mcmurray@glasgow.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Am Coll Cardiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8301365</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0735-1097</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>80M03YXJ7I</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000068756">Valsartan</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001713">Biphenyl Compounds</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000613">Aminobutyrates</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004338">Drug Combinations</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>WB8FT61183</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C549068">sacubitril and valsartan sodium hydrate drug combination</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D057911">Angiotensin Receptor Antagonists</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013777">Tetrazoles</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>69PN84IO1A</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004656">Enalapril</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068756" MajorTopicYN="Y">Valsartan</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001713" MajorTopicYN="Y">Biphenyl Compounds</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006333" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heart Failure</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007022" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hypotension</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000139" MajorTopicYN="N">chemically induced</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000613" MajorTopicYN="Y">Aminobutyrates</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004338" MajorTopicYN="Y">Drug Combinations</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013318" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stroke Volume</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057911" MajorTopicYN="Y">Angiotensin Receptor Antagonists</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013777" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tetrazoles</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004656" MajorTopicYN="N">Enalapril</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058070" MajorTopicYN="N">Asymptomatic Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">asymptomatic hypotension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart failure with reduced ejection fraction (HFrEF)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypotension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sacubitril/valsartan</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">symptomatic hypotension</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Funding Support and Author Disclosures The PARADIGM-HF trial was sponsored by Novartis. Dr Matsumoto has received research grants and personal fees from Abbott, Bayer Pharma, Boehringer Ingelheim, Daiichi-Sankyo, Medtronic, Novartis, Ono Pharma, Orbus Neich, Otsuka Pharma, and the Uehara Memorial Foundation. Dr B&#xf6;hm has received lecture fees from Amgen, Bayer, Servier, Medtronic, Boehringer Ingelheim, ReCor, Vifor Pharma, and Bristol Myers Squibb; has received grant support and lecture fees from AstraZeneca; and has received grant support from Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft. Dr Desai has received grants and personal fees from AstraZeneca during the conduct of the study; has received personal fees from Abbott, Biofourmis, Boston Scientific, Boehringer Ingelheim, Corvidia, DalCor Pharma, Relypsa, Regeneron, and Merck; has received grants and personal fees from Alnylam and Novartis; and has received personal fees from Amgen, outside the submitted work. Dr K&#xf8;ber has received speaker fees from Novartis, Novo Nordisk, and AstraZeneca. Dr Lefkowitz is an employee of Novartis. Dr Packer has received consulting fees from 89bio, AbbVie, Actavis, Alderlyx, Amarin, Amgen, AstraZeneca, Attralus, Boehringer Ingelheim, Caladrius, Casana, CSL Behring, Cytokinetics, Imara, Lilly, Medtronic, Moderna, Novartis, Pharmacosmos, Reata, Regeneron, Relypsa, and Salamandra. Dr Rouleau has received grants and consulting fees from Novartis; and has received consulting fees from AstraZeneca. Dr Solomon has received research grants from Actelion, Alnylam, Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bellerophon, Bayer, Bristol Myers Squibb, Celladon, Cytokinetics, Eidos, Gilead, GlaxoSmithKline, Ionis, Lilly, Mesoblast, MyoKardia, National Institutes of Health/National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, Neurotronik, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Respicardia, Sanofi Pasteur, Theracos, and US2.AI; and has consulted for Abbott, Action, Akros, Alnylam, Amgen, Arena, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Cardior, Cardurion, Corvia, Cytokinetics, Daiichi-Sankyo, GlaxoSmithKline, Lilly, Merck, Myokardia, Novartis, Roche, Theracos, Quantum Genomics, Cardurion, Janssen, Cardiac Dimensions, Tenaya, Sanofi-Pasteur, Dinaqor, Tremeau, CellPro-Thera, Moderna, American Regent, and Sarepta. Dr Swedberg has received honoraria from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, and Novartis. Dr Vaduganathan has received research grant support from or served on Advisory Boards for American Regent, Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bayer AG, Baxter Healthcare, Boehringer Ingelheim, Chiesi, Cytokinetics, Lexicon Pharmaceuticals, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Pharmacosmos, Relypsa, Roche Diagnostics, Sanofi, and Tricog Health; has had speaker engagements with AstraZeneca, Novartis, and Roche Diagnostics; and participates on Clinical Trial Committees for studies sponsored by AstraZeneca, Occlutech, Impulse Dynamicx, Galmed, and Novartis. Dr&#xa0;Vardeny has received research support from AstraZeneca, Bayer, and Cardurion; and has received personal consulting fees from Bayer, Cytokinetics, Moderna, AstraZeneca, and Cardior. The employer of Dr Voors (University Medical Center Groningen) has received consultancy and/or research fees from Adrenomed, Anacardio, BMS, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bayer, Cardurion, Corteria, Cytokinetics, Eli Lilly, Moderna, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Roche Diagnostics, and Salubrisbio. Dr Zile has received fees for serving on a Steering Committee from Abbott and Ironwood Pharma; has received consulting fees from Boston Scientific and MyoKardia; has received grant support and fees for serving on a Steering Committee from CVRx and Medtronic; has received fees for serving on an Eligibility Committee from EBR Systems and V-Wave; has received fees for serving on a Clinical Events Committee from Endotronics; and has received fees for serving on a Data and Safety Monitoring Board from Merck. Dr Jhund has received speaker fees from AstraZeneca, Novartis, Alkem Metabolics, ProAdWise Communications, Sun Pharmaceuticals, and Intas Pharmaceuticals; has received Advisory Board fees from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, and Novartis; has received research funding from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, and Analog Devices Inc; Dr Jhund&#x2019;s employer (University of Glasgow) has been remunerated for clinical trial work by AstraZeneca, Bayer AG, Novartis, and Novo Nordisk; and is a director of Global Clinical Trial Partners Ltd. Dr McMurray has received payments through Glasgow University from work on clinical trials, consulting, and other activities from Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Cardurion, Cytokinetics, GSK, KBP Biosciences, and Novartis; has received personal consultancy fees from Alnylam Pharma, Bayer, BMS, George Clinical PTY Ltd, Ionis Pharma, Novartis, Regeneron Pharma, and River 2 Renal Corporation; has received personal lecture fees from Abbott, Alkem Metabolics, AstraZeneca, Blue Ocean Scientific Solutions Ltd, Boehringer Ingelheim, Canadian Medical and Surgical Knowledge, Emcure Pharma Ltd, Eris Lifesciences, European Academy of CME, Hikma Pharmaceuticals, Imagica health, Intas Pharma, J.B. Chemicals &amp; Pharma Ltd, Lupin Pharma, Medscape/Heart.Org, ProAdWise Communications, Radcliffe Cardiology, Sun Pharma, The Corpus, Translation Research Group, and Translational Medicine Academy; and is a director of Global Clinical Trial Partners Ltd. All other authors have reported that they have no relationships relevant to the contents of this paper to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39320292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2024.08.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0735-1097(24)08162-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>