<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41185024</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1749-799X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of orthopaedic surgery and research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Orthop Surg Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of cold water immersion on balance and postural control in young healthy individuals: a systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>948</StartPage><MedlinePgn>948</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">948</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13018-025-06398-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="ABRACTST" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">BACKGROUND: Proper recovery and a faster return to activity play an important role in injury prevention and can significantly impact performance. Also, maintaining balance and postural control are prerequisites for effective performance that can be strengthened based on proper recovery. This systematic review examined the effect of cold water immersion (CWI) on balance and postural control in healthy young adults.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study was searched from inception to early March 2025. Six databases, Web of Science (WOS), Scopus, PubMed, ScienceDirect, PEDro, and Cochrane Library, were searched, and studies published in English were selected. Experimental studies and controlled clinical trials that included at least two groups, a CWI experimental group and a control group, had to use at least traditional or no-intervention retrieval methods. The mean age of participants was 16. The Rob2 and critical appraisal scales were used to assess the risk of bias and quality of studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">386 studies were found in the first stage of the search, and eight were included in this review. The effects of CWI on balance in healthy individuals are varied, with some studies suggesting a positive impact and others suggesting no effect. Duration and temperature play important roles, with shorter and more moderate immersions being more effective. Temporary neural responses cause short-term instability, but in the long term, they help improve stability and control. Due to the heterogeneity among studies, conducting a meta-analysis was impossible.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The use of CWI can be done under different conditions, depending on the target population and their needs. Overall, its use yields more positive effects, although contradictions persist. It should be used with caution and tailored to the needs of the individual.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shahani</LastName><ForeName>Omid</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-7376-7361</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Injuries and Corrective Exercise, Faculty of Physical Education and Sports Sciences, University of Guilan, Rasht, 41996-13776, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khoshraftar Yazdi</LastName><ForeName>Nahid</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9969-8335</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Injuries and Corrective Exercise, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Ferdowsi University of Mashhad, Mashhad, 91779-48974, Iran. Khoshraftar@um.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mokhtaran</LastName><ForeName>Samineh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-7534-7716</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport Injury and Corrective Exercise, Faculty of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, Allameh Tabataba`I University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Orthop Surg Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101265112</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1749-799X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004856" MajorTopicYN="Y">Postural Balance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007101" MajorTopicYN="Y">Immersion</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003080" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cold Temperature</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064368" MajorTopicYN="N">Healthy Volunteers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="N">Water</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cold water immersion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cryotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stability</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41185024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12581590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-025-06398-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13018-025-06398-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pernigoni M, Calleja-Gonz&#xe1;lez J, Lukonaitien&#x117; I, Tessitore A, Stanislovaitien&#x117; J, Kamarauskas P, et al. Comparative effectiveness of active recovery and static stretching during post-exercise recovery in elite youth basketball. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2024;95(1):272&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02701367.2023.2195457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37039750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvez-Rodriguez C, Valenzuela-Reyes P, Fuentealba-Sep&#xfa;lveda S, Farias-Valenzuela C, Salinas AE. Cold water immersion, heart rate variability and post-exercise recovery: a systematic review. Physiother Res Int. 2025;30(2):e70033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pri.70033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39918163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afsharnezhad T, Faghihi S, Hazrati A, Bahrami K. The effects of cold water immersion on anaerobic power, dynamic balance and muscle activation after a karate kumite fighting in female karateka. Int J Appl Exerc Physiol. 2017;6(3):72&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22631/ijaep.v6i3.198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowalski M, Lubkowska A. Cold water immersion as a method supporting post-exercise recovery. Central European Journal of Sport Sciences and Medicine. 2022;38(02).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosiacki M, Gutowska I, Piotrowska K, Lubkowska A. Concentrations of Ca, Mg, P, prostaglandin E2 in bones and parathyroid hormone; 1, 25-dihydroxyvitamin D3; 17-&#x3b2;-estradiol; testosterone and somatotropin in plasma of aging rats subjected to physical training in cold water. Biomolecules. 2021;11(5):616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biom11050616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8143118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33919152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira Mianutti G, Milioni VL, Pesenti FB, Macedo CdSG. Effects of Different Cryotherapy Techniques on Skin Surface Temperature, Agility and Balance-Comparison Between Cold Water Immersion, Game Ready&#xae;, And Ice Pack: A Randomised Clinical Trial. Biomedical Journal of Scientific &amp; Technical Research. 2021;39(1):31011&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Qin F, Zheng X. The effects of post-exercise cold water immersion on neuromuscular control of knee. Brain Sci. 2024;14(6):555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/brainsci14060555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11201964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38928555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Versey NG, Halson SL, Dawson BT. Water immersion recovery for athletes: effect on exercise performance and practical recommendations. Sports Med. 2013;43:1101&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-013-0063-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23743793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaspar-Junior JJ, Dellagrana RA, Barbosa FS, Anghinoni AP, Taciro C, Carregaro RL, et al. Efficacy of different cold-water immersion temperatures on neuromotor performance in young athletes. Life. 2022;12(5):683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/life12050683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9147268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35629351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macedo CdSG, Vicente RC, Ces&#xe1;rio MD, Guirro RRdJ. Cold-water immersion alters muscle recruitment and balance of basketball players during vertical jump landing. J Sports Sci. 2016;34(4):348&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2015.1054861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26058795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow GCC, Yam TTT, Chung JWY, Fong SSM. Effects of postexercise ice-water and room-temperature water immersion on the sensory organization of balance control and lower limb proprioception in amateur rugby players: a randomized controlled trial. Medicine. 2017. 10.1097/MD.0000000000006146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000006146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5319535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28207546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyldahl RD, Peake JM. Combining cooling or heating applications with exercise training to enhance performance and muscle adaptations. J Appl Physiol. 2020;129(2):353&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00322.2020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F, Song Y, Cen X, Sun D, Lu Z, B&#xed;r&#xf3; I, et al., editors. Comparative efficacy of vibration foam rolling and cold water immersion in amateur basketball players after a simulated load of basketball game. Healthcare; 2023: MDPI.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10418479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37570418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busch A, Kubosch EJ, Leonhart R, Meidl V, Bretthauer B, Dallmann P, et al. Health problems in elite Para athletes&#x2013;a prospective cohort study of 53.739 athlete days. J Sci Med Sport. 2025. 10.1016/j.jsams.2025.01.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2025.01.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39971665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ega&#xf1;a M, Jordan L, Moriarty T. A 2.5 min cold water immersion improves prolonged intermittent sprint performance. J Sci Med Sport. 2019;22(12):1349&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2019.07.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31327650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinke L, Javanmardi S, Rappelt L, Konrad A, Schleip R, Knicker AJ, et al. Comparison of the effects of cold water immersion and percussive massage on the recovery after exhausting eccentric exercise: a three-armed randomized controlled trial. Front Physiol. 2024;15:1432009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2024.1432009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11456464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39376896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. bmj. 2021;372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Chandler J, Welch VA, Higgins JP, et al. Updated guidance for trusted systematic reviews: a new edition of the Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. The Cochrane database of systematic reviews. 2019;2019(10):ED000142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10284251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31643080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoch MC, Russell DM. Plantar cooling does not affect standing balance: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Gait Posture. 2016;43:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gaitpost.2015.10.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26669944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Blencowe NS, Boutron I, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019. 10.1136/bmj.l4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.l4898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douglas M, Bivens S, Pesterfield J, Clemson N, Castle W, Sole G, et al. Immediate effects of cryotherapy on static and dynamic balance. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2013;8(1):9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3578429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23439672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pesenti FB, Silva RAd, Monteiro DC, Silva LAd, Macedo CdSG. The effect of cold water immersion on pain, muscle recruitment and postural control in athletes. Rev Bras Med Esporte. 2020;26:323&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1517-869220202604214839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuchi CA, Duarte M, Stefanyshyn DJ. Postural sway following cryotherapy in healthy adults. Gait Posture. 2014;40(1):262&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gaitpost.2014.02.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24631278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong Y, Hossain MB, McNaboe R, Posada-Quintero HF, Daley M, Diaz K, et al. Sex differences in autonomic functions and cognitive performance during cold-air exposure and cold-water partial immersion. Front Physiol. 2024;15:1463784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2024.1463784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11521960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39479308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piasecki J, &#x160;karabot J, Spillane P, Piasecki M, Ansdell P. Sex differences in neuromuscular aging: the role of sex hormones. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2024;52(2):54&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/JES.0000000000000335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38329342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakabayashi H. Physiological responses and performance in cold environments. The Thermal Environment: From Viewpoints of Physiological Anthropology and Environmental Ergonomics: Springer; 2025. p. 101&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treigyte V, Eimantas N, Venckunas T, Brazaitis M, Chaillou T. Moderate muscle cooling induced by single and intermittent/prolonged cold-water immersions differently affects muscle contractile function in young males. Front Physiol. 2023;14:1172817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2023.1172817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10070757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37025384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue L, Ding L, Zhang J, Nie J, Zhang Q. Thermal response of human body with immersion suit in cold environment. Int J Biometeorol. 2023;67(3):447&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36633693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindsay A, Carr S, Cross S, Petersen C, Lewis JG, Gieseg SP. The physiological response to cold-water immersion following a mixed martial arts training session. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2017;42(5):529&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/apnm-2016-0582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28177718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavares F, Smith TB, Driller M. Fatigue and recovery in rugby: a review. Sports Med. 2017;47:1515&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-017-0679-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28150163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunutsor SK, Lehoczki A, Laukkanen JA. The untapped potential of cold water therapy as part of a lifestyle intervention for promoting healthy aging. Geroscience. 2025;47(1):387&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11357-024-01295-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11872954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39078461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakabayashi H, Wijayanto T, Tochihara Y. Neuromuscular function during knee extension exercise after cold water immersion. J Physiol Anthropol. 2017;36(1):28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40101-017-0144-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5481952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28645314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eimonte M, Paulauskas H, Daniuseviciute L, Eimantas N, Vitkauskiene A, Dauksaite G, et al. Residual effects of short-term whole-body cold-water immersion on the cytokine profile, white blood cell count, and blood markers of stress. Int J Hyperthermia. 2021;38(1):696&#x2013;707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02656736.2021.1915504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33910456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stedge HL, Armstrong K. The effects of intermittent pneumatic compression on the reduction of exercise-induced muscle damage in endurance athletes: a critically appraised topic. J Sport Rehabil. 2021;30(4):668&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jsr.2020-0364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33418535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade A, Bevilacqua G, Casagrande P, Brandt R, Coimbra D. Sleep quality associated with mood in elite athletes. Physician Sportsmed. 2019;47(3):312&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00913847.2018.1553467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30477376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte JP, Fernandes RJ, Silva G, Sousa F, Machado L, Pereira JR, et al., editors. Lower limbs wearable sports garments for muscle recovery: An umbrella review. Healthcare; 2022: MDPI.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9408502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36011209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bezuglov E, Lazarev A, Khaitin V, Chegin S, Tikhonova A, Talibov O, et al. The prevalence of use of various post-exercise recovery methods after training among elite endurance athletes. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(21):11698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph182111698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8583677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34770213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buoite Stella A, Ruzza FR, Callovini A, Bortolan L, Martini M, Sabot R, et al. Immediate effects of sports massage on muscle strength, power and balance after simulated trail running in the cold. Sport Sci Health. 2025. 10.1007/s11332-025-01348-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11332-025-01348-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>