<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40924293</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-1934</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>39</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>CNS drugs</Title><ISOAbbreviation>CNS Drugs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Statins in Acute Ischemic Stroke: Mechanisms, Resistance, and Precision Strategies for Neurovascular and Cognitive Protection.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1083</StartPage><EndPage>1107</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1083-1107</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40263-025-01222-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Acute ischemic stroke (AIS) remains a leading cause of mortality and long-term disability globally, with survivors at high risk of recurrent stroke, cardiovascular events, and post-stroke dementia. Statins, while widely used for their lipid-lowering effects, also possess pleiotropic properties, including anti-inflammatory, endothelial-stabilizing, and neuroprotective actions, which may offer added benefit in AIS management. This article synthesizes emerging evidence on statins' dual mechanisms of action and evaluates their role in reducing recurrence, improving survival, and mitigating cognitive decline. Key challenges limiting the full therapeutic potential of statins include interindividual variability in response and pharmacogenomic and biomarker-related resistance, inconsistencies across clinical guidelines, and limited central nervous system bioavailability. Innovations such as pharmacogenomic-guided therapy, pleiotropy-linked biomarkers, and advanced drug delivery systems (e.g., nanoparticle and intranasal formulations) may help overcome these barriers. Combination strategies with agents such as proprotein convertase subtilisin/kexin type 9 (PCSK9) inhibitors or sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 (SGLT2) inhibitors, and targeted interventions against neuroinflammatory resistance, show promise in enhancing treatment efficacy. In doing so, we propose a shift from conventional statin use to a precision medicine paradigm that can better serve AIS survivors, especially those at risk of post-stroke dementia or those living in resource-constrained settings. While such innovations, for example, genetic testing and novel delivery methods, may not yet be feasible in all contexts, particularly low-resource environments, they represent long-term goals for equity-driven innovation. Equity in access to high-intensity statins and novel therapies remains a global priority, particularly in low- and middle-income countries. Future research should prioritize personalized, biomarker-driven approaches and inclusive clinical trials to optimize statin use across diverse AIS populations. By advancing these strategies, statins can evolve from cardiovascular agents into integral components of precision neurovascular medicine, improving long-term outcomes and quality of life for stroke survivors.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gupta</LastName><ForeName>Muskaan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Global Health Neurology Lab, Sydney, NSW, 2150, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UNSW Medicine and Health, University of New South Wales (UNSW), South West Sydney Clinical Campuses, Sydney, NSW, 2170, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smokovski</LastName><ForeName>Ivica</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6814-1748</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Clinic of Endocrinology, Diabetes and Metabolic Disorders, Skopje, North Macedonia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medical Sciences, The Goce Del&#x10d;ev University, &#x160;tip, North Macedonia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chatzis</LastName><ForeName>Dimitrios G</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1610-3736</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical School, European University Cyprus, 76 Siggrou Avenue, 11742, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spring</LastName><ForeName>Kevin J</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0601-924X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UNSW Medicine and Health, University of New South Wales (UNSW), South West Sydney Clinical Campuses, Sydney, NSW, 2170, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NSW Brain Clot Bank, NSW Health Pathology, Sydney, NSW, 2170, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Oncology Group, Ingham Institute for Applied Medical Research, Sydney, NSW, 2751, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Western Sydney University, Sydney, NSW, 2000, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehndiratta</LastName><ForeName>Man Mohan</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4428-9980</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, BLK Super Speciality Hospital, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beran</LastName><ForeName>Roy G</ForeName><Initials>RG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5884-0606</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Global Health Neurology Lab, Sydney, NSW, 2150, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UNSW Medicine and Health, University of New South Wales (UNSW), South West Sydney Clinical Campuses, Sydney, NSW, 2170, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NSW Brain Clot Bank, NSW Health Pathology, Sydney, NSW, 2170, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Western Sydney University, Sydney, NSW, 2000, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Griffith Health, School of Medicine and Dentistry, Griffith University, Southport, QLD, 4215, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ingham Institute for Applied Medical Research, Clinical Sciences Stream, Liverpool, NSW, 2170, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Neurophysiology, Liverpool Hospital and South West Sydney Local Health District, Liverpool, NSW, 2150, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhaskar</LastName><ForeName>Sonu M M</ForeName><Initials>SMM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9783-3628</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Global Health Neurology Lab, Sydney, NSW, 2150, Australia. Sonu.Bhaskar@globalhealthneurolab.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UNSW Medicine and Health, University of New South Wales (UNSW), South West Sydney Clinical Campuses, Sydney, NSW, 2170, Australia. Sonu.Bhaskar@globalhealthneurolab.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NSW Brain Clot Bank, NSW Health Pathology, Sydney, NSW, 2170, Australia. Sonu.Bhaskar@globalhealthneurolab.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ingham Institute for Applied Medical Research, Clinical Sciences Stream, Liverpool, NSW, 2170, Australia. Sonu.Bhaskar@globalhealthneurolab.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Neurophysiology, Liverpool Hospital and South West Sydney Local Health District, Liverpool, NSW, 2150, Australia. Sonu.Bhaskar@globalhealthneurolab.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cerebrovascular Medicine and Neurology, Department of Neurology, National Cerebral and Cardiovascular Center (NCVC), Suita, Osaka, 564-8565, Japan. Sonu.Bhaskar@globalhealthneurolab.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Cerebral and Cardiovascular Center (NCVC), 6-1 Kishibeshimmachi, Suita, Osaka, 564-8565, Japan. Sonu.Bhaskar@globalhealthneurolab.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P23712</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>23KF0126</GrantID><Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>CNS Drugs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9431220</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1172-7047</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D019161">Hydroxymethylglutaryl-CoA Reductase Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018696">Neuroprotective Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019161" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hydroxymethylglutaryl-CoA Reductase Inhibitors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000083242" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ischemic Stroke</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018696" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neuroprotective Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057285" MajorTopicYN="N">Precision Medicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Stroke is a leading cause of death and disability worldwide. After a stroke, patients are at high risk of having another stroke, developing heart problems, or experiencing long-term difficulties with memory and thinking, often referred to as post-stroke dementia. This article explores how a group of medications called statins, commonly used to lower cholesterol, may offer additional benefits beyond cholesterol reduction. Recent research suggests that statins have &#x201c;pleiotropic&#x201d; effects, meaning that they can reduce inflammation, stabilize blood vessels, and potentially support brain recovery after a stroke. These effects may help lower the risk of further strokes, reduce mortality, and protect against post-stroke cognitive decline. However, the evidence for cognitive benefits remains mixed, and further high-quality clinical trials are needed. Importantly, statins do not work equally well for everyone. Some patients experience limited benefits or side effects. This article discusses emerging strategies in stroke care, including the use of genetic tests and biomarkers to predict individual responses to statin therapy. It also highlights innovative delivery methods, such as nasal sprays or nanoparticles, that may help statins reach the brain more effectively. We propose moving away from a one-size-fits-all approach toward personalized treatment that considers a patient&#x2019;s stroke subtype, genetic profile, and overall health. This approach could be especially valuable in low-resource settings where access to specialized stroke care is limited. If adopted more broadly, these strategies may help statins evolve from cardiovascular drugs into tools that also support brain health after stroke.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><CoiStatement>Declarations. Funding: The financial support for a separate project was received through the Grant-in-Aid for Scientific Research (KAKENHI) (principal investigator [PI]: S.M.M.B.), funded by the Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS), Japanese Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology (MEXT), Japan (Grant no.: 23KF0126). S.M.M.B was awarded the JSPS International Fellowship, supported by MEXT and the Australian Academy of Science, for the period 2023&#x2013;2025 (Grant no.: P23712). Conflict of interest: S.M.M.B. reports leadership or a fiduciary role in other board, society, committee, or advocacy group activity, paid or unpaid, with the National Cerebral and Cardiovascular Center (Osaka, Japan) as visiting director (2023&#x2013;2025); Rotary District 9675 (Sydney, Australia) as district chair for Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion; the Global Health and Migration Hub Community, Global Health Hub Germany (Berlin, Germany) as chair, founding member, and manager; and editorial board memberships at PLOS One, BMC Neurology, Frontiers in Neurology, Frontiers in Stroke, Frontiers in Public Health, Journal of Aging Research, Neurology International, Diagnostics, and BMC Medical Research Methodology. Additionally, S.M.M.B. serves as a member of the College of Reviewers for the Canadian Institutes of Health Research (CIHR), Government of Canada; director of research for the World Headache Society (Bengaluru, India); a member of the Scientific Review Committee at Cardiff University Biobank (Cardiff, UK); chair of the Rotary Reconciliation Action Plan (RAP), Rotary District 9675 (NSW, Australia); healthcare and medical adviser for the Japan Connect (Osaka, Japan); and as an expert adviser/reviewer for the Cariplo Foundation (Milan, Italy). These roles are unrelated to the submitted work. Other authors (M.G., K.J.S., I.S., D.M., M.M.M., and R.G.B.) report no conflicts of interest. The funding body has had no role in the study design, data collection, analysis, interpretation of findings, and manuscript preparation. The content is solely the responsibility of the authors and does not necessarily represent the official views of the affiliated/funding organization/s. Availability of data and material: The original contributions presented in the study are included in the article. Further inquiries can be directed at the corresponding author. Ethics approval: Not applicable. Consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Code availability: Not applicable. Authors&#x2019; contributions: S.M.M.B. conceived the study and contributed to its planning, drafting, and revision while supervising the Global Health Neurology Lab members. S.M.M.B. is the principal investigator for the Impact of Statin Therapy on the Risk of Stroke Recurrence, Mortality, and Dementia After Ischemic Stroke (ISMARDD) study. S.M.M.B. encouraged M.G. to investigate the topic and oversaw the synthesis of findings. M.G. and S.M.M.B. contributed to the literature review, data collection, initial draft, manuscript revisions, and overall discussion. K.J.S., I.S., D.G.C., M.M.M., and R.G.B. contributed to initial discussion, validation, intellectual content, and manuscript revisions. S.M.M.B. provided critical revisions, supervised the project, and approved the final manuscript. All authors reviewed and approved the final draft of the manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40924293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40263-025-01222-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40263-025-01222-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>GBD 2021 Stroke Risk Factor Collaborators. Global, regional, and national burden of stroke and its risk factors, 1990&#x2013;2021: a systematic analysis for the Global burden of disease study 2021. Lancet Neurol. 2024;23(10):973&#x2013;1003. https://doi.org/10.1016/s1474-4422(24)00369-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1474-4422(24)00369-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswas R, Wijeratne T, Zelenak K, Huasen BB, Iacobucci M, Killingsworth MC, et al. Disparities in access to reperfusion therapy for acute ischemic stroke (DARTS): a comprehensive meta-analysis of ethnicity, socioeconomic status, and geographical factors. CNS Drugs. 2025;39(4):417&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40263-025-01161-z .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40263-025-01161-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39954118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2021 Nervous System Disorders Collaborators. Global, regional, and national burden of disorders affecting the nervous system, 1990&#x2013;2021: a systematic analysis for the Global burden of Disease study 2021. Lancet Neurol. 2024;23(4):344&#x2013;81. https://doi.org/10.1016/s1474-4422(24)00038-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1474-4422(24)00038-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv W, Wang A, Wang Q, Wang R, Xu Q, Wu S, et al. One-year direct and indirect costs of ischaemic stroke in China. Stroke Vasc Neurol. 2024;9(4):380&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1136/svn-2023-002296 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/svn-2023-002296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37788911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strilciuc S, Grad DA, Radu C, Chira D, Stan A, Ungureanu M, et al. The economic burden of stroke: a systematic review of cost of illness studies. J Med Life. 2021;14(5):606&#x2013;19. https://doi.org/10.25122/jml-2021-0361 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25122/jml-2021-0361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35027963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8742896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Spencer G, Husain MJ, Nugent R, Auzenne D, Kostova D, et al. Barriers to accessibility of medicines for hyperlipidemia in low- and middle-income countries. PLoS Glob Public Health. 2024;4(2):e0002905. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pgph.0002905 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgph.0002905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38346061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10861044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anand A, Hegde NC, Chhabra P, Purohit J, Kumar R, Gupta A, et al. Pharmacogenetic guided versus standard warfarin dosing for routine clinical care with its pharmacoeconomic impact: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Ann Hematol. 2024;103(6):2133&#x2013;44. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00277-024-05757-1 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00277-024-05757-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38634917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phipps MS, Cronin CA. Management of acute ischemic stroke. Br Med J. 2020;368:l6983. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.l6983 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.l6983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okada T, Suzuki H, Travis ZD, Zhang JH. The stroke-induced blood-brain barrier disruption: current progress of inspection technique, mechanism, and therapeutic target. Curr Neuropharmacol. 2020;18(12):1187&#x2013;212. https://doi.org/10.2174/1570159x18666200528143301 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1570159x18666200528143301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32484111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7770643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudd A, Le TN, Nguyen NH. Stroke management in Vietnam. 1 ed. Key considerations for the implementation of healthcare services. Singapore: Springer; 2024. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-96-0221-6 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanct&#xf4;t KL, Lindsay MP, Smith EE, Sahlas DJ, Foley N, Gubitz G, et al. Canadian stroke best practice recommendations: mood, cognition and fatigue following stroke, 6th edition update 2019. Int J Stroke. 2020;15(6):668&#x2013;88. https://doi.org/10.1177/1747493019847334 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1747493019847334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31221036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Z, Sun J. The role of the neurovascular unit in vascular cognitive impairment: current evidence and future perspectives. Neurobiol Dis. 2025;204:106772. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nbd.2024.106772 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nbd.2024.106772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39710068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor F, Huffman MD, Macedo AF, Moore THM, Burke M, Davey Smith G, et al. Statins for the primary prevention of cardiovascular disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2013(1). https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD004816.pub5 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feigin VL, Owolabi MO. Pragmatic solutions to reduce the global burden of stroke: a World Stroke Organization-Lancet Neurology Commission. Lancet Neurol. 2023;22(12):1160&#x2013;206. https://doi.org/10.1016/s1474-4422(23)00277-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1474-4422(23)00277-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37827183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10715732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oesterle A, Laufs U, Liao JK. Pleiotropic effects of statins on the cardiovascular system. Circ Res. 2017;120(1):229&#x2013;43. https://doi.org/10.1161/circresaha.116.308537 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/circresaha.116.308537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28057795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5467317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>German CA, Liao JK. Understanding the molecular mechanisms of statin pleiotropic effects. Arch Toxicol. 2023;97(6):1529&#x2013;45. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00204-023-03492-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00204-023-03492-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37084080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10119541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Libby P, Aikawa M. Stabilization of atherosclerotic plaques: new mechanisms and clinical targets. Nat Med. 2002;8(11):1257&#x2013;62. https://doi.org/10.1038/nm1102-1257 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm1102-1257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12411953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khatiwada N, Hong Z. Potential benefits and risks associated with the use of statins. Pharmaceutics. 2024;16(2):214. https://doi.org/10.3390/pharmaceutics.16020214 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pharmaceutics16020214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38399268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10892755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahid MS, Bourgleh MS, Alharfi A, Albariqi S, Albalawi L, Alohali R, et al. High-dose statins for the prevention of recurrent ischemic stroke: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Ann Saudi Med. 2025;45(2):112&#x2013;28. https://doi.org/10.5144/0256-4947.2025.112 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5144/0256-4947.2025.112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40189852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach F, Skajaa N, Esen BO, Fuglsang CH, Horv&#xe1;th-Puh&#xf3; E, S&#xf8;rensen HT, et al. High-intensity versus moderate-intensity statin treatment for patients with ischemic stroke: nationwide cohort study. Eur Stroke J. 2023;8(4):1041&#x2013;52. https://doi.org/10.1177/23969873231193288 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23969873231193288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37555324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10683733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao J, Zhang Y, Li Y, Guo J, He L. Low-to-moderate dose statins improve the functional outcome of acute ischemic stroke with conventional medication treatment. Cardiovasc Diagn Ther. 2023;13(4):686&#x2013;99. https://doi.org/10.21037/cdt-23-77 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/cdt-23-77</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37675093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10478016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi SE, Bucci T, Huang JY, Yiu KH, Tsang CT, Lau KK, et al. Early statin use is associated with improved survival and cardiovascular outcomes in patients with atrial fibrillation and recent ischaemic stroke: a propensity-matched analysis of a global federated health database. Eur Stroke J. 2024;10(1):116&#x2013;27. https://doi.org/10.1177/23969873241274213 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23969873241274213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39254367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11558656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui C, Dong S, Liu Q, Bao J, Gao L, Li Y, et al. Low-dose statins improve prognosis of patients with ischaemic stroke undergoing intra-arterial thrombectomy: a prospective cohort study. J Clin Neurosci. 2022;103:124&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jocn.2022.07.001 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jocn.2022.07.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35868229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui C, Li Y, Bao J, Dong S, Gao L, He L. Low dose statins improve prognosis of ischemic stroke patients with intravenous thrombolysis. BMC Neurol. 2021;21(1):220. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12883-021-02259-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12883-021-02259-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34107911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8188651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dearborn-Tomazos JL, Hu X, Bravata DM, Phadke MA, Baye FM, Myers LJ, et al. Deintensification or no statin treatment is associated with higher mortality in patients with ischemic stroke or transient ischemic attack. Stroke. 2021;52(8):2521&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.030089 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.030089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34015937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan H, Wang Y, Zhang K, Liu T, Li X, Li Y, et al. Intensive versus moderate statin-based therapies in patients with mild ischemic stroke: a prospective multicenter cohort study. J Am Heart Assoc. 2024;13(14):e035337. https://doi.org/10.1161/JAHA.124.035337 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.124.035337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38979802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11292746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y, Jiang L, Pan Y, Chen W, Jing J, Wang C, et al. Immediate- or delayed-intensive statin in acute cerebral ischemia: the INSPIRES randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol. 2024;81(7):741&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaneurol.2024.1433 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2024.1433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38805216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11134282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong C, Liu C, Wang Y, Chen L, Yuan J, Zhang J, et al. Effect of statin treatment on clinical outcomes in cardioembolic stroke with endovascular thrombectomy. J Neurointerv Surg. 2024;16(9):947&#x2013;54. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnis-2023-020619 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnis-2023-020619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37586821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JT, Lee JS, Kim BJ, Kang J, Lee KJ, Park JM, et al. Statin treatment in patients with stroke with low-density lipoprotein cholesterol levels below 70 mg/dL. J Am Heart Assoc. 2023;12(18):e030738. https://doi.org/10.1161/jaha.123.030738 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/jaha.123.030738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37681519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10547296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YS, Jeong HG, Chang JY, Kim JY, Kim BJ, Bae HJ, et al. Effect of statin therapy on cardiovascular outcome in stroke patients with low baseline low-density lipoprotein cholesterol. Ann Neurol. 2024;95(5):876&#x2013;85. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.26895 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.26895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38400785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyt&#xf6; V, &#xc5;ivo J, Ruuskanen JO. Intensity of statin therapy after ischaemic stroke and long-term outcomes: a nationwide cohort study. Stroke Vasc Neurol. 2025;10(1):142&#x2013;5. https://doi.org/10.1136/svn-2024-003230 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/svn-2024-003230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38876780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park HK, Lee JS, Hong KS, Cho YJ, Park JM, Kang K, et al. Statin therapy in acute cardioembolic stroke with no guidance-based indication. Neurology. 2020;94(19):e1984&#x2013;95. https://doi.org/10.1212/wnl.0000000000009397 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/wnl.0000000000009397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32273430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitturi BK, Gagliardi RJ. The role of statins in cardioembolic stroke. J Clin Neurosci. 2020;72:174&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jocn.2019.12.028 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jocn.2019.12.028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tramacere I, Boncoraglio G, Banzi R, Del Giovane C, Kwag K, Squizzato A, et al. Comparison of statins for secondary prevention in patients with ischemic stroke or transient ischemic attack: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. BMC Med. 2019. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12916-019-1298-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-019-1298-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30914063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6436237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stroke Foundation. Australian and New Zealand living clinical guidelines for stroke management. https://strokefoundation.org.au/what-we-do/for-health-professionals/clinical-guidelines . Stroke Foundation; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson J, B&#xe9;jot Y, Christensen LM, De Marchis GM, Dichgans M, Hagberg G, et al. European Stroke Organisation (ESO) guideline on pharmacological interventions for long-term secondary prevention after ischaemic stroke or transient ischaemic attack. Eur Stroke J. 2022;7(3):1&#x2013;2. https://doi.org/10.1177/23969873221100032 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23969873221100032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. Stroke and transient ischaemic attack in over 16s: diagnosis and initial management. 2022. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK542436/ . Accessed 1 Apr 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladstone DJ, Lindsay MP, Douketis J, Smith EE, Dowlatshahi D, Wein T, et al. Canadian stroke best practice recommendations: secondary prevention of stroke update 2020. Can J Neurol Sci. 2022;49(3):315&#x2013;37. https://doi.org/10.1017/cjn.2021.127 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/cjn.2021.127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34140063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleindorfer DO, Towfighi A, Chaturvedi S, Cockroft KM, Gutierrez J, Lombardi-Hill D, et al. 2021 Guideline for the prevention of stroke in patients with stroke and transient ischemic attack: a guideline from the American Heart Association/American Stroke Association. Stroke. 2021;52(7):e364&#x2013;467. https://doi.org/10.1161/STR.0000000000000375 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STR.0000000000000375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamoto S, Ogasawara K, Kuroda S, Itabashi R, Toyoda K, Itoh Y, et al. Japan Stroke Society guideline 2021 for the treatment of stroke. Int J Stroke. 2022;17(9):1039&#x2013;49. https://doi.org/10.1177/17474930221090347 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17474930221090347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35443847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9615334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intercollegiate Stroke Working Party. National clinical guideline for stroke for the UK and Ireland. 2023. www.strokeguideline.org . Accessed 01 Apr 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad K, Srivastava MVP, Narayan S, Kumar MV, Lal V, Bhatia R, et al. National Programme for Prevention and Control of Cancer, Diabetes, Cardiovascular Diseases &amp; Stroke (NPCDCS): guidelines for prevention and management of stroke. 2019. https://strokesupport.in/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Guidelines-for-Prevention-and-Managment-of-Stroke-GOI-2019.pdf . Accessed 01 Apr 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, Li Z, Zhou H, Duan W, Huo X, Xu W, et al. Chinese Stroke Association guidelines for clinical management of ischaemic cerebrovascular diseases: executive summary and 2023 update. Stroke Vasc Neurol. 2023;8(6):e3. https://doi.org/10.1136/svn-2023-002998 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/svn-2023-002998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38158224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10800268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamshidnejad-Tosaramandani T, Kashanian S, Al-Sabri MH, Kro&#x10d;ianov&#xe1; D, Clemensson LE, Gentreau M, et al. Statins and cognition: modifying factors and possible underlying mechanisms. Front Aging Neurosci. 2022;14:968039. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnagi.2022.968039 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2022.968039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36046494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9421063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkahtani R. Molecular mechanisms underlying some major common risk factors of stroke. Heliyon. 2022;8(8):e10218. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2022.e10218 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2022.e10218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36060992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9433609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams HP Jr., Bendixen BH, Kappelle LJ, Biller J, Love BB, Gordon DL, et al. Classification of subtype of acute ischemic stroke. Definitions for use in a multicenter clinical trial. TOAST. Trial of org 10172 in acute stroke treatment. Stroke. 1993;24(1):35&#x2013;41. https://doi.org/10.1161/01.str.24.1.35 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.str.24.1.35</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7678184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donnell MJ, Xavier D, Liu L, Zhang H, Chin SL, Rao-Melacini P, et al. Risk factors for ischaemic and intracerebral haemorrhagic stroke in 22 countries (the INTERSTROKE study): a case-control study. Lancet. 2010;376(9735):112&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0140-6736(10)60834-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(10)60834-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20561675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boehme AK, Esenwa C, Elkind MS. Stroke risk factors, genetics, and prevention. Circ Res. 2017;120(3):472&#x2013;95. https://doi.org/10.1161/circresaha.116.308398 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/circresaha.116.308398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28154098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5321635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan U, Porteous L, Hassan A, Markus HS. Risk factor profile of cerebral small vessel disease and its subtypes. J Neurol, Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2007;78(7):702&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp.2006.103549 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.2006.103549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17210627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mergenthaler P, Dirnagl U, Kunz A. Ischemic stroke: basic pathophysiology and clinical implication. In: Pfaff DW, Volkow ND, Rubenstein JL, editors. Neuroscience in the 21st century: From Basic to Clinical. Cham: Springer; 2022. p. 3807&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao R, Zong N, Hu Y, Chen Y, Xu Y. Neuronal death mechanisms and therapeutic strategy in ischemic stroke. Neurosci Bull. 2022;38(10):1229&#x2013;47. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12264-022-00859-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12264-022-00859-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35513682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9554175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing C, Arai K, Lo EH, Hommel M. Pathophysiologic cascades in ischemic stroke. Int J Stroke. 2012;7(5):378&#x2013;85. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1747-4949.2012.00839.x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1747-4949.2012.00839.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22712739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3985770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakhan SE, Kirchgessner A, Hofer M. Inflammatory mechanisms in ischemic stroke: therapeutic approaches. J Transl Med. 2009;7:97. https://doi.org/10.1186/1479-5876-7-97 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1479-5876-7-97</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19919699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2780998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma D, Spring KJ, Bhaskar SMM. Neutrophil-lymphocyte ratio in acute ischemic stroke: immunopathology, management, and prognosis. Acta Neurol Scand. 2021;144(5):486&#x2013;99. https://doi.org/10.1111/ane.13493 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ane.13493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34190348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekerdag E, Solaroglu I, Gursoy-Ozdemir Y. Cell death mechanisms in stroke and novel molecular and cellular treatment options. Curr Neuropharmacol. 2018;16(9):1396&#x2013;415. https://doi.org/10.2174/1570159x16666180302115544 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1570159x16666180302115544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29512465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6251049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walther J, Kirsch EM, Hellwig L, Schmerbeck SS, Holloway PM, Buchan AM, et al. Reinventing the penumbra&#x2014;the emerging clockwork of a multi-modal mechanistic paradigm. Transl Stroke Res. 2023;14(5):643&#x2013;66. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12975-022-01090-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12975-022-01090-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36219377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romero LMB, Vallejo-Vaz AJ, Grijalvo OM. Cerebrovascular disease and statins. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2021;8:778740. https://doi.org/10.3389/fcvm.2021.778740 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2021.778740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasull T, Arboix A. Molecular mechanisms and pathophysiology of acute stroke: recent advances and controversies. Curr Issues Mol Biol. 2024;46(4):2926&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.3390/cimb46040182 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cimb46040182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38666912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11048782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner RC, Dodson SC, Rosen CL, Huber JD. The science of cerebral ischemia and the quest for neuroprotection: navigating past failure to future success. J Neurosurg. 2013;118(5):1072&#x2013;85. https://doi.org/10.3171/2012.11.Jns12408 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/2012.11.Jns12408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23331000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4652647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markus A, Valerie S, Mira K. Promising biomarker candidates for cardioembolic stroke etiology. A brief narrative review and current opinion. Front Neurol. 2021;12:624930. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2021.624930 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2021.624930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33716927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7947187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mijajlovi&#x107; MD, Pavlovi&#x107; A, Brainin M, Heiss W, Quinn TJ, Ihle-Hansen HB, et al. Post-stroke dementia&#x2014;a comprehensive review. BMC Med. 2017;15(1):11. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12916-017-0779-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-017-0779-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28095900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5241961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Fawal B, Ibrahim A, Abd EM. Post-stroke dementia: frequency, predictors, and health impact. Egypt J Neurol Psychiatry Neurosurg. 2021;57(1):15. https://doi.org/10.1186/s41983-021-00270-y .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41983-021-00270-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Husseini N, Katzan IL, Rost NS, Blake ML, Byun E, Pendlebury ST, et al. Cognitive impairment after ischemic and hemorrhagic stroke: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association/American Stroke Association. Stroke. 2023;54(6):e272&#x2013;91. https://doi.org/10.1161/STR.0000000000000430 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STR.0000000000000430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37125534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu G-C, Chen Y-M. Post-stroke dementia: epidemiology, mechanisms and management. Int J Gerontol. 2017;11(4):210&#x2013;4. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijge.2017.07.004 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijge.2017.07.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douiri A, Rudd AG, Wolfe CD. Prevalence of poststroke cognitive impairment: South London Stroke Register 1995&#x2013;2010. Stroke. 2013;44(1):138&#x2013;45. https://doi.org/10.1161/strokeaha.112.670844 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/strokeaha.112.670844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23150656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacquin A, Binquet C, Rouaud O, Graule-Petot A, Daubail B, Osseby GV, et al. Post-stroke cognitive impairment: high prevalence and determining factors in a cohort of mild stroke. J Alzheimers Dis. 2014;40(4):1029&#x2013;38. https://doi.org/10.3233/jad-131580 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/jad-131580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24577459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo JW, Crawford JD, Desmond DW, Godefroy O, Jokinen H, Mahinrad S, et al. Profile of and risk factors for poststroke cognitive impairment in diverse ethnoregional groups. Neurology. 2019;93(24):e2257&#x2013;71. https://doi.org/10.1212/wnl.0000000000008612 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/wnl.0000000000008612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31712368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6937495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ihle-Hansen H, Thommessen B, Wyller TB, Engedal K, &#xd8;kseng&#xe5;rd AR, Stenset V, et al. Incidence and subtypes of MCI and dementia 1 year after first-ever stroke in patients without pre-existing cognitive impairment. Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord. 2011;32(6):401&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1159/000335361 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000335361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22311341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig L, Hoo ZL, Yan TZ, Wardlaw J, Quinn TJ. Prevalence of dementia in ischaemic or mixed stroke populations: systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2022;93(2):180&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp-2020-325796 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2020-325796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34782389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zupanic E, von Euler M, Winblad B, Xu H, Secnik J, Kramberger MG, et al. Mortality after ischemic stroke in patients with Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease dementia and other dementia disorders. J Alzheimers Dis. 2021;81(3):1253&#x2013;61. https://doi.org/10.3233/jad-201459 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/jad-201459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33935077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8293632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatemichi TK, Paik M, Bagiella E, Desmond DW, Pirro M, Hanzawa LK. Dementia after stroke is a predictor of long-term survival. Stroke. 1994;25(10):1915&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1161/01.str.25.10.1915 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.str.25.10.1915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8091433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su X, Pan D, Meng H, Lu W, Wang X, Liu Z, et al. Dementia increases the risk of death in stroke patients: a retrospective cohort-based risk score model study. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2023;32(11):107337. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2023.107337 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2023.107337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37677896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dammavalam V, Rupert D, Lanio M, Jin Z, Nadkarni N, Tsirka SE, et al. Dementia after ischemic stroke, from molecular biomarkers to therapeutic options. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25(14):7772. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms25147772 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms25147772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39063013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11276729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferri N, Corsini A. Clinical pharmacology of statins: an update. Curr Atheroscler Rep. 2020;22(7):26. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11883-020-00844-w .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11883-020-00844-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32494971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang CY, Liu PY, Liao JK. Pleiotropic effects of statin therapy: molecular mechanisms and clinical results. Trends Mol Med. 2008;14(1):37&#x2013;44. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molmed.2007.11.004 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molmed.2007.11.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18068482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2621332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu JC, Lei SY, Zhang DH, He QY, Sun YY, Zhu HJ, et al. The pleiotropic effects of statins: a comprehensive exploration of neurovascular unit modulation and blood-brain barrier protection. Mol Med. 2024;30(1):256. https://doi.org/10.1186/s10020-024-01025-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s10020-024-01025-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39707228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11660731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood WG, M&#x3b0;ller WE, Eckert GP. Statins and neuroprotection: basic pharmacology needed. Mol Neurobiol. 2014;50(1):214&#x2013;20. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12035-014-8647-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12035-014-8647-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24474514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasull T, Arboix A. Molecular mechanisms and pathophysiology of acute stroke: emphasis on biomarkers in the different stroke subtypes. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23:9476. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms23169476 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23169476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36012743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9409332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolmos M, Christoffersen L, Kruuse C. Recurrent ischemic stroke&#x2014;a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2021;30(8):105935. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2021.105935 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2021.105935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34153594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modrego PJ, Pina MA, Mar Fraj M, Llorens N. Type, causes, and prognosis of stroke recurrence in the province of Teruel, Spain. A 5-year analysis. Neurol Sci. 2000;21(6):355&#x2013;60. https://doi.org/10.1007/s100720070050 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s100720070050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11441572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng YS, Tan KHX, Chen C, Senolos GC, Koh GCH. How do recurrent and first-ever strokes differ in rehabilitation outcomes? Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2016. https://doi.org/10.1097/PHM.0000000000000502 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0000000000000502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27088474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skajaa N, Adelborg K, Horv&#xe1;th-Puh&#xf3; E, Rothman KJ, Henderson VW, Thygesen LC, et al. Risks of stroke recurrence and mortality after first and recurrent strokes in Denmark: a nationwide registry study. Neurology. 2022;98(4):e329&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.1212/wnl.0000000000013118 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/wnl.0000000000013118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34845054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amarenco P, Bogousslavsky J, Callahan A, Goldstein LB, Hennerici M, Rudolph AE, et al. High-dose atorvastatin after stroke or transient ischemic attack. N Engl J Med. 2006;355(6):549&#x2013;59. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa061894 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa061894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16899775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escudero-Mart&#xed;nez I, Morales-Caba L, Segura T. Atrial fibrillation and stroke: a review and new insights. Trends Cardiovasc Med. 2023;33(1):23&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tcm.2021.12.001 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tcm.2021.12.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34890796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatia R, Sharma G, Patel C, Garg A, Roy A, Bali P, et al. Coronary artery disease in patients with ischemic stroke and TIA. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2019;28(12):104400. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2019.104400 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2019.104400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31606321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin Y, Zhang L, Marshall I, Wolfe C, Wang Y. Statin therapy for preventing recurrent stroke in patients with ischemic stroke: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials and observational cohort studies. Neuroepidemiology. 2022;56(4):240&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1159/000525672 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000525672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35753307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc5;ivo J, Ruuskanen JO, Tornio A, Rautava P, Kyt&#xf6; V. Lack of statin therapy and outcomes after ischemic stroke: a population-based study. Stroke. 2023;54(3):781&#x2013;90. https://doi.org/10.1161/strokeaha.122.040536 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/strokeaha.122.040536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36748465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10561684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitturi BK, Gagliardi RJ. The influence of statin withdrawal and adherence on stroke outcomes. Neurol Sci. 2021;42(6):2317&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10072-020-04790-y .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-020-04790-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33037514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitturi BK, Gagliardi RJ. Effects of statin therapy on outcomes of ischemic stroke: a real-world experience in Brazil. Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2020;78(8):461&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1590/0004-282x20200027 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/0004-282x20200027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32627806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhai C, Hou K, Li R, Hu Y, Zhang J, Zhang Y, et al. Efficacy of statin treatment based on cardiovascular outcomes in elderly patients: a standard meta-analysis and Bayesian network analysis. J Int Med Res. 2020;48(6):300060520926349. https://doi.org/10.1177/0300060520926349 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0300060520926349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32529863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ray KK, Haq I, Bilitou A, Manu MC, Burden A, Aguiar C, et al. Treatment gaps in the implementation of LDL cholesterol control among high- and very high-risk patients in Europe between 2020 and 2021: the multinational observational SANTORINI study. Lancet Reg Health. 2023. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lanepe.2023.100624 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lanepe.2023.100624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaam M, Al-Naimi HN, Haddad MM, Abushanab D, Al-Badriyeh D. Comparative efficacy and safety among high-intensity statins. Systematic review and meta-analysis. J Comp Eff Res. 2023;12(3):e220163. https://doi.org/10.57264/cer-2022-0163 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.57264/cer-2022-0163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36847307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10288954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekker MS, Verhoeven JI, Vaartjes I, Jolink WMT, Klijn CJM, de Leeuw FE. Association of stroke among adults aged 18 to 49 years with long-term mortality. JAMA. 2019;321(21):2113&#x2013;23. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2019.6560 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2019.6560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31121602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6547225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hankey GJ, Jamrozik K, Broadhurst RJ, Forbes S, Burvill PW, Anderson CS, et al. Five-year survival after first-ever stroke and related prognostic factors in the Perth Community Stroke Study. Stroke. 2000;31(9):2080&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1161/01.STR.31.9.2080 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.STR.31.9.2080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10978033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh R, Chen S, Ganesh A, Hill MD. Long-term neurological, vascular, and mortality outcomes after stroke. Int J Stroke. 2018;13(8):787&#x2013;96. https://doi.org/10.1177/1747493018798526 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1747493018798526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30160619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furlan NE, Souza JT, Bazan SGZ, Franco R, Luvizutto GJ, Gut AL, et al. Association between statin use and mortality risks during the acute phase of ischemic stroke in patients admitted to an intensive care unit. Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2020;78(3):158&#x2013;62. https://doi.org/10.1590/0004-282x20190172 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/0004-282x20190172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32215458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gardener H, Rundek T, Lichtman J, Leifheit E, Wang K, Asdaghi N, et al. Adherence to acute care measures affects mortality in patients with ischemic stroke: the Florida Stroke Registry. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2021;30(3):105586. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2020.105586 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2020.105586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33412397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7880890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han J, Choi YK, Leung WK, Hui MT, Leung MKW. Long term clinical outcomes of patients with ischemic stroke in primary care&#x2014;a 9-year retrospective study. BMC Fam Pract. 2021;22(1):164. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12875-021-01513-w .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12875-021-01513-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34364364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8349500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefeber GJ, Knol W, Souverein PC, Bouvy ML, de Boer A, Koek HL. Statins after ischemic stroke in the oldest. Stroke. 2021;52(4):1244&#x2013;52. https://doi.org/10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.030755 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.030755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33563018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phan A, Indredavik B, Lydersen S, Morsund &#xc5;H, Seljeseth YM, Ildstad F, et al. Estimates and predictors of mortality, stroke recurrence, and functional dependency 1-year after ischemic stroke: a prospective multicenter longitudinal cohort study in Central Norway. Acta Neurol Scand. 2024;2024(1):8805152. https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/8805152 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2024/8805152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mele C, Maggioni G, Giordano A, Lunardon C, Balsamo F, Mazzone A, et al. A retrospective study on statins and post-stroke patients: what about functional outcome and follow-up in a stroke rehabilitation cohort? Front Neurol. 2021;12:744732. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2021.744732 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2021.744732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34744982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8567028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalli LL, Kim J, Cadilhac DA, Greenland M, Sanfilippo FM, Andrew NE, et al. Greater adherence to secondary prevention medications improves survival after stroke or transient ischemic attack: a linked registry study. Stroke. 2021;52(11):3569&#x2013;77. https://doi.org/10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.033133 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.120.033133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34315251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flint AC, Conell C, Klingman JG, Rao VA, Chan SL, Kamel H, et al. Impact of increased early statin administration on ischemic stroke outcomes: a multicenter electronic medical record intervention. J Am Heart Assoc. 2016;5(8):e003413. https://doi.org/10.1161/JAHA.116.003413 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.116.003413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27473035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5015276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filler J, Georgakis MK, Dichgans M. Risk factors for cognitive impairment and dementia after stroke: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Healthy Longev. 2024;5(1):e31&#x2013;44. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2666-7568(23)00217-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2666-7568(23)00217-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38101426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pendlebury ST, Rothwell PM. Incidence and prevalence of dementia associated with transient ischaemic attack and stroke: analysis of the population-based Oxford Vascular Study. Lancet Neurol. 2019;18(3):248&#x2013;58. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(18)30442-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(18)30442-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30784556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6390174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Wang H, Edwards D, Ding C, Yan L, Brayne C, et al. Association of blood lipids, atherosclerosis and statin use with dementia and cognitive impairment after stroke: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ageing Res Rev. 2020;57:100962. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arr.2019.100962 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2019.100962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31505259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heart Protection Study Collaborative Group. MRC/BHF Heart Protection Study of cholesterol lowering with simvastatin in 20,536 high-risk individuals: a randomised placebo-controlled trial. Lancet. 2002;360(9326):7&#x2013;22. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0140-6736(02)09327-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(02)09327-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepherd J, Blauw GJ, Murphy MB, Bollen EL, Buckley BM, Cobbe SM, et al. Pravastatin in elderly individuals at risk of vascular disease (PROSPER): a randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2002;360(9346):1623&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0140-6736(02)11600-x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(02)11600-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12457784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joundi RA, Fang J, Austin PC, Smith EE, Yu AYX, Hachinski V, et al. Magnitude and time-course of dementia risk in stroke survivors: a population-wide matched cohort study. Neurology. 2025;104(1):e210131. https://doi.org/10.1212/wnl.0000000000210131 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/wnl.0000000000210131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39631038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Toh S, Li X, Edwards D, Brayne C, Mant J. Statin use is associated with lower risk of dementia in stroke patients: a community-based cohort study with inverse probability weighted marginal structural model analysis. Eur J Epidemiol. 2022;37(6):615&#x2013;27. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10654-022-00856-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10654-022-00856-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35305172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9288375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Yang S, Jia J. Factors related to long-term post-stroke cognitive impairment in young adult ischemic stroke. Med Sci Monit. 2015;21:654&#x2013;60. https://doi.org/10.12659/msm.892554 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12659/msm.892554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25729006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4354446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muldoon MF, Barger SD, Ryan CM, Flory JD, Lehoczky JP, Matthews KA, et al. Effects of lovastatin on cognitive function and psychological well-being. Am J Med. 2000;108(7):538&#x2013;46. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0002-9343(00)00353-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0002-9343(00)00353-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10806282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trompet S, van Vliet P, de Craen AJM, Jolles J, Buckley BM, Murphy MB, et al. Pravastatin and cognitive function in the elderly. Results of the PROSPER study. J Neurol. 2010;257(1):85&#x2013;90. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-009-5271-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-009-5271-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19653027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagstaff LR, Mitton MW, Arvik BM, Doraiswamy PM. Statin-associated memory loss: analysis of 60 case reports and review of the literature. Pharmacotherapy. 2003;23(7):871&#x2013;80. https://doi.org/10.1592/phco.23.7.871.32720 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1592/phco.23.7.871.32720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12885101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Food &amp; Drug Administration. FDA drug safety communication: important safety label changes to cholesterol-lowering statin drugs. 2016. https://www.fda.gov/drugs/drug-safety-and-availability/fda-drug-safety-communication-important-safety-label-changes-cholesterol-lowering-statin-drugs . Accessed 29 July 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moskowitz MA, Lo EH, Iadecola C. The science of stroke: mechanisms in search of treatments. Neuron. 2010;67(2):181&#x2013;98. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2010.07.002 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2010.07.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20670828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2957363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du S, Wang X, Xiao L, Tu J, Zhu W, He T, et al. Molecular mechanisms of vascular dementia: what can be learned from animal models of chronic cerebral hypoperfusion? Mol Neurobiol. 2017;54(5):3670&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12035-016-9915-1 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12035-016-9915-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27206432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dichgans M, Leys D. Vascular cognitive impairment. Circ Res. 2017;120(3):573&#x2013;91. https://doi.org/10.1161/circresaha.116.308426 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/circresaha.116.308426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28154105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sriram S, Mehkri Y, Quintin S, Lucke-Wold B. Shared pathophysiology: understanding stroke and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2022;218:107306. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clineuro.2022.107306 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clineuro.2022.107306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35636382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elman-Shina K, Efrati S. Ischemia as a common trigger for Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Front Aging Neurosci. 2022;14:1012779. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnagi.2022.1012779 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2022.1012779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36225888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9549288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee PH, Bang OY, Hwang EM, Lee JS, Joo US, Mook-Jung I, et al. Circulating beta amyloid protein is elevated in patients with acute ischemic stroke. J Neural Transm. 2005;112(10):1371&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00702-004-0274-0 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00702-004-0274-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15682267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenowitz WD, Nelson PT, Besser LM, Heller KB, Kukull WA. Cerebral amyloid angiopathy and its co-occurrence with Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and other cerebrovascular neuropathologic changes. Neurobiol Aging. 2015;36(10):2702&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2015.06.028 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2015.06.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26239176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4562901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serrano-Pozo A, Das S, Hyman BT. APOE and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: advances in genetics, pathophysiology, and therapeutic approaches. Lancet Neurol. 2021;20(1):68&#x2013;80. https://doi.org/10.1016/s1474-4422(20)30412-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1474-4422(20)30412-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33340485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8096522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong S, Maniar S, Manole MD, Sun D. Cerebral hypoperfusion and other shared brain pathologies in ischemic stroke and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Transl Stroke Res. 2018;9(3):238&#x2013;50. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12975-017-0570-2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12975-017-0570-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28971348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsbrook DL, Di Napoli M, Bhatia K, Biller J, Andalib S, Hinduja A, et al. Neuroinflammation in acute ischemic and hemorrhagic stroke. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2023;23(8):407&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11910-023-01282-2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11910-023-01282-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37395873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10544736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker KJ, Kalil AJ, Tanzi P, Zierath DK, Savos AV, Gee JM, et al. Autoimmune responses to the brain after stroke are associated with worse outcome. Stroke. 2011;42(10):2763&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1161/strokeaha.111.619593 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/strokeaha.111.619593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21799171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3183403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doyle KP, Buckwalter MS. Immunological mechanisms in poststroke dementia. Curr Opin Neurol. 2020;33(1):30&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1097/wco.0000000000000783 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/wco.0000000000000783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31789707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7251986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon HS, Koh S-H. Neuroinflammation in neurodegenerative disorders: the roles of microglia and astrocytes. Transl Neurodegener. 2020;9(1):42. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40035-020-00221-2 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40035-020-00221-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33239064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7689983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iadecola C. The overlap between neurodegenerative and vascular factors in the pathogenesis of dementia. Acta Neuropathol. 2010;120(3):287&#x2013;96. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00401-010-0718-6 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00401-010-0718-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20623294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3001188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalaria RN, Akinyemi R, Ihara M. Stroke injury, cognitive impairment and vascular dementia. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2016;1862(5):915&#x2013;25. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbadis.2016.01.015 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbadis.2016.01.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26806700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4827373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F, Mei Y, Wu Q, Wu X. Drug target mendelian randomization study of PCSK9 and HMG-CoA reductase inhibition and atrial fibrillation. Cardiology. 2024;149(5):495&#x2013;501. https://doi.org/10.1159/000538551 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000538551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38531334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safarova M, Bimal T, Soffer DE, Hirsh B, Shapiro MD, Mintz G, et al. Advances in targeting LDL cholesterol: PCSK9 inhibitors and beyond. Am J Prev Cardiol. 2024;19:100701. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajpc.2024.100701 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajpc.2024.100701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39070027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11278114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oldgren J, &#xc5;sberg S, Hijazi Z, Wester P, Bertilsson M, Norrving B, et al. Early versus delayed non&#x2013;vitamin k antagonist oral anticoagulant therapy after acute ischemic stroke in atrial fibrillation (TIMING): a registry-based randomized controlled noninferiority study. Circulation. 2022;146(14):1056&#x2013;66. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.122.060666 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.122.060666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36065821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9648987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maningat P, Gordon BR, Breslow JL. How do we improve patient compliance and adherence to long-term statin therapy? Curr Atheroscler Rep. 2013;15(1):291. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11883-012-0291-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11883-012-0291-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23225173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3534845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross S, Krebs K, Par&#xe9; G, Milani L. Pharmacogenomics in stroke and cardiovascular disease: state of the art. Stroke. 2023;54(1):270&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1161/strokeaha.122.037717 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/strokeaha.122.037717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36325912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kee PS, Chin PKL, Kennedy MA, Maggo SDS. Pharmacogenetics of statin-induced myotoxicity. Front Genet. 2020;11:575678. https://doi.org/10.3389/fgene.2020.575678 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fgene.2020.575678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33193687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7596698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldmann E, Bamberger C, Parhofer KG. Statin intolerance is the main indication for PCSK9 inhibition in clinical practice. Atherosclerosis. 2017;263:e80. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2017.06.261 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2017.06.261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LaFratte C, Peasah SK, Huang Y, Hall D, Patel U, Good CB. Association of PCSK9 inhibitor initiation on statin adherence and discontinuation. J Am Heart Assoc. 2023;12(18):e029707. https://doi.org/10.1161/JAHA.123.029707 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.123.029707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37702065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10547275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waters DD, Hsue PY, Bangalore S. PCSK9 inhibitors for statin intolerance? JAMA. 2016;315(15):1571&#x2013;2. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2016.3670 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2016.3670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27039138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5761646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan Y, Gong K, Xu S, Zhang F, Meng X, Han J. Regulation of cholesterol homeostasis in health and diseases: from mechanisms to targeted therapeutics. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2022;7(1):265. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41392-022-01125-5 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41392-022-01125-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35918332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9344793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchward MA, Todd KG. Statin treatment affects cytokine release and phagocytic activity in primary cultured microglia through two separable mechanisms. Mol Brain. 2014;7:85. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13041-014-0085-7 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13041-014-0085-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25424483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4247600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koushki K, Shahbaz SK, Mashayekhi K, Sadeghi M, Zayeri ZD, Taba MY, et al. Anti-inflammatory action of statins in cardiovascular disease: the role of inflammasome and toll-like receptor pathways. Clin Rev Allergy Immunol. 2021;60(2):175&#x2013;99. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12016-020-08791-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12016-020-08791-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32378144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obadia N, Andrade G, Leardini-Trist&#xe3;o M, Albuquerque L, Garcia C, Lima F, et al. Tlr4 mutation protects neurovascular function and cognitive decline in high-fat diet-fed mice. J Neuroinflamm. 2022;19(1):104. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12974-022-02465-3 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12974-022-02465-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alikiaii B, Heidari Z, Bagherniya M, Askari G, Sathyapalan T, Sahebkar A. The effect of statins on C-reactive protein in stroke patients: a systematic review of clinical trials. Mediat Inflamm. 2021;2021:7104934. https://doi.org/10.1155/2021/7104934 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/7104934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan H, Ma Q, Hao W, Yang N, Chen Z-S, Deng L, et al. Targeting autophagy to counteract neuroinflammation: a novel antidepressant strategy. Pharmacol Res. 2024;202:107112. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.phrs.2024.107112 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phrs.2024.107112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38403256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H, Cao H, Cui X, Zheng W, Wang S, Yu J, et al. Silymarin&#x2019;s inhibition and treatment effects for Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Molecules. 2019. https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules24091748 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules24091748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31878172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6982833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu&#xf1;&#xf3;n J, Badim&#xf3;n L, Bochaton-Piallat ML, Cariou B, Daemen MJ, Egido J, et al. Identifying the anti-inflammatory response to lipid lowering therapy: a position paper from the working group on atherosclerosis and vascular biology of the European Society of Cardiology. Cardiovasc Res. 2019;115(1):10&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1093/cvr/cvy293 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cvr/cvy293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30534957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding L, Mane R, Wu Z, Jiang Y, Meng X, Jing J, et al. Data-driven clustering approach to identify novel phenotypes using multiple biomarkers in acute ischaemic stroke: a retrospective, multicentre cohort study. eClinicalMedicine. 2022;53:101639. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2022.101639 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2022.101639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36105873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9465270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim TJ, Lee JS, Yoon JS, Oh MS, Kim JW, Park SH, et al. The impact of statin treatment duration on the risk of new-onset diabetes mellitus and recurrent vascular events in ischemic stroke patients: a linked data analysis. Cerebrovasc Dis. 2025;54(2):147&#x2013;55. https://doi.org/10.1159/000538485 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000538485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38527440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabatine MS, Giugliano RP, Keech AC, Honarpour N, Wiviott SD, Murphy SA, et al. Evolocumab and clinical outcomes in patients with cardiovascular disease. N Engl J Med. 2017;376(18):1713&#x2013;22. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa1615664 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1615664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28304224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone NJ, Robinson JG, Lichtenstein AH, Bairey Merz CN, Blum CB, Eckel RH, et al. 2013 ACC/AHA guideline on the treatment of blood cholesterol to reduce atherosclerotic cardiovascular risk in adults. Circulation. 2014;129(25_suppl_2):S1&#x2013;45. https://doi.org/10.1161/01.cir.0000437738.63853.7a .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.cir.0000437738.63853.7a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24222016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart RG, Sharma M, Mundl H, Kasner SE, Bangdiwala SI, Berkowitz SD, et al. Rivaroxaban for stroke prevention after embolic stroke of undetermined source. N Engl J Med. 2018;378(23):2191&#x2013;201. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa1802686 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1802686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29766772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amarenco P, Labreuche J, Lavall&#xe9;e P, Touboul PJ. Statins in stroke prevention and carotid atherosclerosis: systematic review and up-to-date meta-analysis. Stroke. 2004;35(12):2902&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1161/01.STR.0000147965.52712.fa .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.STR.0000147965.52712.fa</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15514180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ridker PM, Danielson E, Fonseca FA, Genest J, Gotto AM Jr, Kastelein JJ, et al. Rosuvastatin to prevent vascular events in men and women with elevated C-reactive protein. N Engl J Med. 2008;359(21):2195&#x2013;207. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa0807646 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa0807646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18997196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnett DK, Blumenthal RS, Albert MA, Buroker AB, Goldberger ZD, Hahn EJ, et al. 2019 ACC/AHA guideline on the primary prevention of cardiovascular disease: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Circulation. 2019;140(11):e596&#x2013;646. https://doi.org/10.1161/cir.0000000000000678 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/cir.0000000000000678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30879355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7734661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aygun S, Tokgozoglu L. Comparison of current international guidelines for the management of dyslipidemia. J Clin Med. 2022. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm11237249 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm11237249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36498823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9737468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen KA, Li L, Lu D, Yazdanparast A, Wang L, Kreutz RP, et al. A comprehensive review and meta-analysis of risk factors for statin-induced myopathy. Eur J Clin Pharmacol. 2018;74(9):1099&#x2013;109. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00228-018-2482-9 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00228-018-2482-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29785580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonvico F, Zimetti F, Pohlmann AR, Guterres SS. Drug delivery to the brain: how can nanoencapsulated statins be used in the clinic? Ther Deliv. 2017;8(8):625&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.4155/tde-2017-0044 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4155/tde-2017-0044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28730939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clementino A, Batger M, Garrastazu G, Pozzoli M, Del Favero E, Rondelli V, et al. The nasal delivery of nanoencapsulated statins&#x2014;an approach for brain delivery. Int J Nanomed. 2016;11:6575&#x2013;90. https://doi.org/10.2147/ijn.S119033 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/ijn.S119033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R, Wang X, Zhao H, Li N, Li J, Zhang H, et al. Targeted delivery of hybrid nanovesicles for enhanced brain penetration to achieve synergistic therapy of glioma. J Control Release. 2024;365:331&#x2013;47. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jconrel.2023.11.033 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jconrel.2023.11.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38000664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tashima T. Smart strategies for therapeutic agent delivery into brain across the blood&#x2013;brain barrier using receptor-mediated transcytosis. Chem Pharm Bull. 2020;68(4):316&#x2013;25. https://doi.org/10.1248/cpb.c19-00854 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1248/cpb.c19-00854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prins SR, Vermeer SE, Damoiseaux-Volman BA, Priester-Vink S, Van der Velde N, Van den Berg-Vos RM. Statins&#x2019; effect on quality of life and functioning in older stroke patients: systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Neurosci. 2025;132:110989. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jocn.2024.110989 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jocn.2024.110989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39693808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinci P, Panizon E, Tosoni LM, Cerrato C, Pellicori F, Mearelli F, et al. Statin-associated myopathy: emphasis on mechanisms and targeted therapy. Int J Mol Sci. 2021. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms222111687 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms222111687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34769118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8583847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangravite LM, Engelhardt BE, Medina MW, Smith JD, Brown CD, Chasman DI, et al. A statin-dependent QTL for GATM expression is associated with statin-induced myopathy. Nature. 2013;502(7471):377&#x2013;80. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature12508 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature12508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23995691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3933266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhaskar SMM. Bridging the gap between research and clinical practice in treatment strategies and mechanisms of acute ischemic stroke. Neurol Int. 2025. https://doi.org/10.3390/neurolint17040054 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/neurolint17040054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40278425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12029360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswas M, Sawajan N, Rungrotmongkol T, Sanachai K, Ershadian M, Sukasem C. Pharmacogenetics and precision medicine approaches for the improvement of COVID-19 therapies. Front Pharmacol. 2022;13:835136. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2022.835136 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.835136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35250581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8894812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung BM, Lauder IJ, Lau CP, Kumana CR. Meta-analysis of large randomized controlled trials to evaluate the impact of statins on cardiovascular outcomes. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2004;57(5):640&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2125.2003.02060.x .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2125.2003.02060.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15089818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1884492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He G, Yang G, Huang X, Luo D, Tang C, Zhang Z. SGLT2 inhibitors for prevention of primary and secondary cardiovascular outcomes: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Heart Lung. 2023;59:109&#x2013;16. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hrtlng.2023.02.009 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.hrtlng.2023.02.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36801545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopaschuk GD, Verma S. Mechanisms of cardiovascular benefits of sodium glucose co-transporter 2 (SGLT2) inhibitors: a state-of-the-art review. JACC Basic Transl Sci. 2020;5(6):632&#x2013;44. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacbts.2020.02.004 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacbts.2020.02.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32613148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7315190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korani S, Korani M, Bahrami S, Johnston TP, Butler AE, Banach M, et al. Application of nanotechnology to improve the therapeutic benefits of statins. Drug Discov Today. 2019;24(2):567&#x2013;74. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.drudis.2018.09.023 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drudis.2018.09.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30292917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan ML, Hsu CC, Chen YM, Yu HK, Hu GC. Statin use and the risk of dementia in patients with stroke: a nationwide population-based cohort study. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2018;27(11):3001&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2018.06.036 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2018.06.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30087076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajeswaran P, Huasen BB, Stanwell P, Killingsworth MC, Bhaskar SMM. Prevalence and outcomes of mild stroke patients undergoing reperfusion therapy: a meta-analysis and SAFE recommendations for optimal management. J Cent Nerv Syst Dis. 2025;17:11795735251314881. https://doi.org/10.1177/11795735251314881 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/11795735251314881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39944087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11815822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhaskar SMM. G20 Policy for health systems: promoting holistic outcomes and addressing vulnerabilities in healthcare 2023. https://www.global-solutions-initiative.org/publication/g20-policy-for-health-systems-promoting-holistic-outcomes-and-addressing-vulnerabilities-in-healthcare/ . Accessed 27 July 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhaskar SMM. Advancing understanding and addressing disparities in cardiomyopathy care in Southern Africa. JACC Adv. 2024;3(12):100957. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacadv.2024.100957 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacadv.2024.100957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39817075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">11733959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh B, Bhaskar SMM. The role of artificial intelligence in optimizing management of atrial fibrillation in acute ischemic stroke. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2024;1541(1):24&#x2013;36. https://doi.org/10.1111/nyas.15231 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nyas.15231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39377991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh PF, Tung H, Lin CH. Statin effects on post-stroke epilepsy and mortality&#x2014;Taiwan population-based study. Neurol Res. 2020;42(5):422&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1080/01616412.2020.1735821 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01616412.2020.1735821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32122287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yakusevich VV, Malygin AY, Lychenka SV, Petrochenko AS, Kabanov AV. The efficacy of high-dose simvastatin in acute period of ischemic stroke. Ration Pharmacother Cardiol. 2012;8(1):4&#x2013;16. https://doi.org/10.20996/1819-6446-2012-8-1-4-16 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20996/1819-6446-2012-8-1-4-16</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim TJ, Lee JS, Oh MS, Park S-H, Lee K, Yu K-H, et al. Risk of long-term post-stroke dementia using a linked dataset of patients with ischemic stroke without a history of dementia. Int J Stroke. 2025. https://doi.org/10.1177/17474930241310730 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17474930241310730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40884091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>