<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41141198</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Tumor Lysis Syndrome Triggered by Acalabrutinib in Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia (CLL): Diagnostic and Therapeutic Implications.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e93185</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e93185</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e93185</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.93185</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Tumor lysis syndrome (TLS) is an uncommon but potentially life-threatening oncologic emergency, typically associated with highly proliferative hematologic malignancies. It is rarely encountered in chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL), a generally indolent B-cell neoplasm. We report a unique case of therapy-induced TLS in a patient newly diagnosed with CLL, following the initiation of acalabrutinib, a Bruton's tyrosine kinase (BTK) inhibitor. The patient presented with marked hyperleukocytosis, severe thrombocytopenia, and acute kidney injury at diagnosis. Immunophenotyping and histopathological evaluation confirmed the diagnosis of CLL, supported by a Matutes score of 4/5 and characteristic CD5+/CD23+/weak CD20 expression. Cytogenetic analysis revealed no high-risk abnormalities. Following acalabrutinib initiation, the patient rapidly developed metabolic disturbances, including severe hyperuricemia, hyperphosphatemia, hyperkalemia, hypocalcemia, and worsening renal function, consistent with laboratory and clinical TLS. Prompt management with intravenous hydration, Rasburicase, calcium supplementation, and potassium-lowering agents led to gradual metabolic correction. This case highlights the importance of recognizing the potential for TLS even in slow-growing hematologic malignancies like CLL, especially in patients with high tumor burden or compromised renal function. Clinicians must maintain a high index of suspicion and initiate appropriate prophylactic measures when starting targeted therapies, particularly BTK inhibitors, to prevent life-threatening&#xa0;complications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Fadi et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fadi</LastName><ForeName>Monsif</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hematology and Medical Oncology, Centre d'&#xc9;tudes Doctorales - CeDOC, Mohammed VI University of Sciences and Health (UM6SS), Casablanca, MAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oncopathology, Cancer Biology and Environment Laboratory, Mohammed VI Faculty of Medicine, Mohammed VI University of Sciences and Health (UM6SS), Casablanca, MAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lahlou</LastName><ForeName>Fatima Azzahra</ForeName><Initials>FA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biochemistry, Faculty of Medicine, Mohamed VI University of Health Sciences (UM6SS), Casablanca, MAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El Ouafa</LastName><ForeName>Yasmine</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nutrition, Centre d'&#xc9;tudes Doctorales - CeDOC, Mohammed VI University of Sciences and Health (UM6SS), Casablanca, MAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Laboratory of Biotechnology and Health, Mohammed VI University of Sciences and Health (UM6SS), Casablanca, MAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chahdi</LastName><ForeName>Hafsa</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pathology, Cheikh Khalifa International University Hospital, Mohammed VI University of Health Sciences, Casablanca, MAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bouanani</LastName><ForeName>Nouama</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hematology, Faculty of Medicine, Mohammed VI University of Health Sciences (UM6SS), Casablanca, MAR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bruton&#x2019;s tyrosine kinase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bruton&#x2019;s tyrosine kinase inhibitor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic lymphocytic leukemia (cll)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immunophenotype</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tumor-lysis syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Comit&#xe9; d'Ethique de l'Universit&#xe9; Mohammed VI des Sciences de la Sant&#xe9; de Casablanca issued approval CE/UM6SS/01/25. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41141198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12553324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.93185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chronic lymphocytic leukemia. Chiorazzi N, Chen SS, Rai KR. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med. 2021;11:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7849345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32229611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cancer incidence and mortality worldwide: Sources, methods and major patterns in GLOBOCAN 2012. Ferlay J, Soerjomataram I, Dikshit R, et al. Int J Cancer. 2015;136:0&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25220842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tumor lysis syndrome in patients with hematological malignancies. Belay Y, Yirdaw K, Enawgaw B. J Oncol. 2017;2017:9684909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5688348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29230244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acute tumor lysis syndrome: Update on therapy. (Article in French) Jabbour E, Ribrag V. Rev Med Interne. 2005;26:27&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15639323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tumor lysis syndrome in chronic lymphocytic leukemia with novel targeted agents. Cheson BD, Heitner Enschede S, Cerri E, Desai M, Potluri J, Lamanna N, Tam C. Oncologist. 2017;22:1283&#x2013;1291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5679833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28851760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical and economic burden of tumor lysis syndrome among patients with chronic lymphocytic leukemia/small lymphocytic lymphoma: A real-world US retrospective study. Rogers KA, Lu X, Emond B, et al. J Manag Care Spec Pharm. 2022;28:1033&#x2013;1045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12101563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35816124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The tumor lysis syndrome. Howard SC, Jones DP, Pui CH. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMra0904569. N Engl J Med. 2011;364:1844&#x2013;1854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3437249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21561350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tumor lysis syndrome in the era of novel and targeted agents in patients with hematologic malignancies: A systematic review. Howard SC, Trifilio S, Gregory TK, Baxter N, McBride A. Ann Hematol. 2016;95:563&#x2013;573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26758269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidelines for the management of pediatric and adult tumor lysis syndrome: An evidence-based review. Coiffier B, Altman A, Pui CH, Younes A, Cairo MS. J Clin Oncol. 2008;26:2767&#x2013;2778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18509186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tumor lysis syndrome after tamoxifen flare. Cech P, Block JB, Cone LA, Stone R. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJM198607243150417. N Engl J Med. 1986;315:263&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3014336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tumor lysis syndrome in solid tumors: An up to date review of the literature. Mirrakhimov AE, Ali AM, Khan M, Barbaryan A. https://doi.org/10.4081/rt.2014.5389. Rare Tumors. 2014;6:5389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4083673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25002953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acute spontaneous tumor lysis syndrome in a patient with squamous cell carcinoma of the lung. Shenoy C. https://doi.org/10.1093/qjmed/hcn129. QJM. 2009;102:71&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18829711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A rare case of spontaneous tumor lysis syndrome in idiopathic primary myelofibrosis. Na YS, Park SG. Am J Case Rep. 2019;20:146&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6369657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30712053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tumour lysis syndrome: New therapeutic strategies and classification. Cairo MS, Bishop M. Br J Haematol. 2004;127:3&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15384972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etiology and management of tumor lysis syndrome in patients with chronic lymphocytic leukemia. Cheson BD. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19521331/ Clin Adv Hematol Oncol. 2009;7:263&#x2013;271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19521331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syndrome de lyse tumorale. Grewal K, Herrity E, Pasic I. CMAJ. 2023;195:0&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10365857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37487612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A rare side effect of ibrutinib: Tumor lysis syndrome. Ozturk E, Erdogan Ozunal I. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC8226401/ Medeni Med J. 2021;36:176&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8226401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34239769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>