<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41174807</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2055-0294</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of pharmaceutical health care and sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Pharm Health Care Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ofloxacin, paracetamol and cefixime induced Stevens-Johnson syndrome - toxic epidermal necrolysis in an adult female patient: a case report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>98</StartPage><MedlinePgn>98</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">98</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40780-025-00488-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Stevens-Johnson Syndrome (SJS) and Toxic Epidermal Necrolysis (TEN) represent life-threatening mucocutaneous reactions, predominantly triggered by medications. This case report presents a rare instance of SJS-TEN overlap in a young Indian female precipitated by the combined use of fluoroquinolone (ofloxacin), cephalosporin (cefixime), and paracetamol-an uncommon drug triad not widely reported in existing literature. The case highlights the importance of early diagnosis, thorough drug history evaluation, and the challenges of managing polypharmacy-induced severe cutaneous adverse reactions (SCARs).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CASE PRESENTATION" NlmCategory="METHODS">A 29-year-old Indian female developed widespread dusky purpuric plaques, mucosal erosions (oral, genital, conjunctival, nasal), and bullae six days after local consultation with ofloxacin, cefixime, paracetamol, and other symptomatic agents. She presented to the emergency department with painful vesiculobullous eruptions involving&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;10% body surface area, mucosal ulcerations, eye involvement with crusting, and systemic symptoms including fever, vomiting, and urinary discomfort. Laboratory investigations revealed anemia, elevated RDW, and positive ketones in urine. Diagnosis of SJS-TEN overlap was made clinically. The patient was managed with a multi-disciplinary approach involving systemic corticosteroids (IV dexamethasone), hydration, antibiotics (azithromycin), antihistamines, electrolyte balance, topical agents, ophthalmic care, and pain management. The extensive yet individualized treatment regimen reflected a robust pharmacovigilance response to avoid further drug-induced complications. Improvement was noted with complete re-epithelialization and symptomatic resolution over two weeks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This case highlights the necessity for clinicians to maintain high suspicion for SCARs in patients presenting with mucocutaneous symptoms and recent drug exposure-even with commonly used medications not frequently associated with SJS-TEN. The unique presentation involving synchronous ocular, nasal, oral, and genital erosions alongside use of a rare drug combination strengthens the need for early recognition, comprehensive clinical assessment, and cautious prescription practices. Individualized treatment and close monitoring are crucial in preventing mortality and minimizing complications. This case underscores the importance of pharmacovigilance and personalized care in managing drug-induced hypersensitivity reactions, especially in resource-limited or polypharmacy scenarios.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Desai</LastName><ForeName>Margi R</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy Practice, Parul Institute of Pharmacy, Parul University, Vadodara, Gujarat, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jaiswal</LastName><ForeName>Harshita</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7341-5483</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy Practice, School of Pharmacy, Parul University, P.O. limda, Tal. Waghodiya,, Vadodara, 391760, Gujarat, India. harshita.jaiswal29333@paruluniversity.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rathod</LastName><ForeName>Mrudangsinh M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy Practice, Parul Institute of Pharmacy, Parul University, Vadodara,, Gujarat, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vijayvargi</LastName><ForeName>Sakshi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CBCC Global Research, Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Pharm Health Care Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101672177</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2055-0294</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Case report</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drug-induced hypersensitivity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Early diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Individualized treatment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mucocutaneous reaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pharmacovigilance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Polypharmacy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stevens-Johnson syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Toxic epidermal necrolysis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: The authors hereby declare that informed patient consent has been obtained for the above case report and accompanying images. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Clinical trial number: Not applicable.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41174807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12579416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40780-025-00488-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40780-025-00488-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Marzouq MK. Case presentation of stevens&#x2019;johnson syndrome/toxic epidermal necrolysis. Biomedical J Sci Tech Res. 2023;50(4):41874&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racha AS, Ashwani P, Swarnalatha P. Cefditoren pivoxil induced toxic epidermal necrolysis: a case report. Int J Res Dermatol. 2023;9(5):307&#x2013;10. Available from: 10.18203/issn.2455-4529.intjresdermatol20232550</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee S, Saha D, Dasgupta S, Kumar Tripathi S. Case report: suspected case of Stevens&#x2013;Johnson syndrome and toxic epidermal necrolysis overlap due to ursodeoxycholic acid. EMJ Dermatol. 2020:96&#x2013;9. Available from: 10.33590/emjdermatol/20-00117</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah H, Parisi R, Mukherjee E, Phillips EJ, Dodiuk-Gad RP. Update on Stevens-Johnson syndrome and toxic epidermal necrolysis: diagnosis and management. Am J Clin Dermatol. 2024;25(6):891&#x2013;908. 10.1007/s40257-024-00889-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40257-024-00889-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11511757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39278968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neagu TP, Tiglis M, Peride I, Niculae A. Toxic epidermal necrolysis, a serious side effect of tenoxicam use: a case report. Healthcare (Basel). 2023;11(15):2195. Available from: 10.3390/healthcare11152195</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10418430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37570435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinkle A, Pettit C, Jani A, Keller J, Lu Y, Malachowski S, Trinidad JC, Kaffenberger BH, Ergen EN, Hughey LC, Smith D, Seminario-Vidal L. Distinguishing Stevens-Johnson syndrome/toxic epidermal necrolysis from clinical mimickers during inpatient dermatologic consultation-a retrospective chart review. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2019;81(3):749&#x2013;57. 10.1016/j.jaad.2019.05.061</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2019.05.061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31150704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seminario-Vidal L, Kroshinsky D, Malachowski SJ, Sun J, Markova A, Beachkofsky TM, Kaffenberger BH, Ergen EN, Mauskar M, Bridges A, Calhoun C, Cardones AR, Chen ST, Chodosh J, Cotliar J, Davis MDP, DeNiro KL, Dominguez AR, Eljure-T&#xe9;llez J, Micheletti RG. Society of dermatology hospitalists supportive care guidelines for the management of Stevens-Johnson syndrome/toxic epidermal necrolysis in adults. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2020;82(6):1553&#x2013;67. 10.1016/j.jaad.2020.02.066</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2020.02.066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32151629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wetter DA, Camilleri MJ. Clinical, etiologic, and histopathologic features of Stevens-Johnson syndrome during an 8-year period at Mayo Clinic. Mayo Clin Proc. Mayo Clinic. 2010;85(2):131&#x2013;8 10.4065/mcp.2009.0379</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4065/mcp.2009.0379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2813820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20118388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobry AS, Himed S, Waters M, Kaffenberger BH. Scoring assessments in Stevens-Johnson syndrome and toxic epidermal necrolysis. Front Med (Lausanne). 2022;9:883121. Available from: 10.3389/fmed.2022.883121</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9245022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35783656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koh HK, Fook-Chong SMC, Lee HY. Improvement of mortality prognostication in patients with epidermal necrolysis: the role of novel inflammatory markers and proposed revision of SCORTEN (Re-SCORTEN): the role of novel inflammatory markers and proposed revision of SCORTEN (re-SCORTEN). JAMA Dermatol. 2022;158(2):160&#x2013;6. Available from: 10.1001/jamadermatol.2021.5119</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8696686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34935871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanbhag SS, Chodosh J, Fathy C, Goverman J, Mitchell C, Saeed HN. Multidisciplinary care in Stevens-Johnson syndrome. Ther Adv Chronic Dis. 2020;11:2040622319894469. Available from: 10.1177/2040622319894469</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32523661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>