<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40818766</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-8414</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cardiac failure</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Card Fail</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Rationale, design, and baseline characteristics of the multicENter, randomized, open-label, parallel group, study to evaluate the use of sacubitril/valsartan in HeartMate 3 left ventricular assist device recipients (ENVAD-HF).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>406</StartPage><EndPage>418</EndPage><MedlinePgn>406-418</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.cardfail.2025.07.015</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1071-9164(25)00336-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">With notable improvements in long-term survival and hemocompatibility-related events, heart failure (HF) is emerging as a leading cause of death in the contemporary left ventricular assist device (LVAD) population. Although prospective randomized controlled trials have not investigated the use of HF therapies in recipients of LVAD, observational data suggest benefits of neurohormonal blockers, especially in achieving blood pressure (BP) targets associated with improved outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study "multicENter, randomized, open-label, parallel group, pilot study to evaluate the use of sacubitril/valsartan in HeartMate 3 LVAD recipients" (ENVAD-HF) is an investigator-initiated prospective multicenter, randomized, open-label, parallel group, pilot study of recipients of HeartMate 3 (HM3) LVADs to evaluate the safety and tolerability and insights on efficacy of sacubitril/valsartan compared to standard of care (SOC) for managing BP. Medically stable recipients of LVADs after a recent HM3 implantation or in ambulatory follow-up were eligible for participation and randomized 1:1 to receive sacubitril/valsartan or SOC used for treating BP, both titrated aiming for a mean arterial pressure goal 75-90 mm Hg over a 12-month follow-up. The primary endpoint, designed to assess the safety and efficacy of sacubitril/valsartan compared with SOC, is a composite of freedom from all-cause death, deterioration in renal function, hyperkalemia, or symptomatic hypotension. The occurrence of the primary endpoint will be assessed in the first three months and during the overall duration of the trial (12 months). Other endpoints include clinical and patient-reported outcomes, biomarker, and echocardiography assessments during follow-up.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">ENVAD-HF enrolled 60 patients between February 2021 and March 2024: 17% were female, mean age was 57 &#xb1; 12 years, 67% were in ambulatory follow-up, 55% had ischemic etiology, and 25% were receiving an LVAD as destination therapy, with mean baseline mean arterial pressure 87 &#xb1; 7 mm Hg and median N-terminal pro B-type natriuretic peptide 2552 (1595-3543) pg/mL.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">ENVAD-HF is the first prospective randomized controlled trial of pharmacologic therapy for the management of BP in stable recipients with HM3 LVADs achieving target enrollment. It will provide data on safety, tolerability, and insights on efficacy of sacubitril/valsartan versus SOC used for treating BP.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cikes</LastName><ForeName>Maja</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Diseases, University of Zagreb School of Medicine, University Hospital Centre Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia. Electronic address: maja.cikes@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Planinc</LastName><ForeName>Ivo</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Diseases, University of Zagreb School of Medicine, University Hospital Centre Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia. Electronic address: ivo.planinc@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brugts</LastName><ForeName>Jasper J</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Institute, Thorax Center, Department of Cardiology, Erasmus Medical Centre, Rotterdam, the Netherlands. Electronic address: j.brugts@erasmusmc.nl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Claggett</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts. Electronic address: bclaggett@bwh.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jorde</LastName><ForeName>Ulrich P</ForeName><Initials>UP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Montefiore Health System, Bronx, New York. Electronic address: ujorde@montefiore.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Milicic</LastName><ForeName>Davor</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Diseases, University of Zagreb School of Medicine, University Hospital Centre Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia. Electronic address: davormilicic01@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ruschitzka</LastName><ForeName>Frank</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, University Hospital of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland. Electronic address: frank.ruschitzka@usz.ch.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Uriel</LastName><ForeName>Nir</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Seymour, Paul, and Gloria Milstein Division of Cardiology, Department of Medicine, Columbia University Irving Medical Center/NewYork-Presbyterian Hospital, New York, New York. Electronic address: nu2126@cumc.columbia.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jakus</LastName><ForeName>Nina</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Diseases, University of Zagreb School of Medicine, University Hospital Centre Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia. Electronic address: nina.jakush@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Loncaric</LastName><ForeName>Filip</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Diseases, University of Zagreb School of Medicine, University Hospital Centre Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia. Electronic address: loncaric.filip@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Puskaric</LastName><ForeName>Filip</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Zagreb School of Medicine, Zagreb, Croatia. Electronic address: fpuskaric@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rubis</LastName><ForeName>Pawel</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiac and Vascular Diseases, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Institute of Cardiology; John Paul II Hospital, Krakow, Poland. Electronic address: pawelrub@poczta.onet.pl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Laake</LastName><ForeName>Linda W</ForeName><Initials>LW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Division of Heart &amp; Lungs, University Medical Centre Utrecht, University of Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands. Electronic address: l.w.vanlaake@umcutrecht.nl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rudez</LastName><ForeName>Igor</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiac and Transplant Surgery, Dubrava University Hospital, Zagreb, Croatia. Electronic address: rudi@kbd.hr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hegarova</LastName><ForeName>Marketa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Clinical and Experimental Medicine, Prague, Czech Republic. Electronic address: mahg@ikem.cz.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehra</LastName><ForeName>Mandeep</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts. Electronic address: mmehra@bwh.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Solomon</LastName><ForeName>Scott D</ForeName><Initials>SD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts. Electronic address: ssolomon@bwh.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078325">Clinical Trial Protocol</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Card Fail</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9442138</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1071-9164</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001713">Biphenyl Compounds</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000613">Aminobutyrates</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>WB8FT61183</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C549068">sacubitril and valsartan sodium hydrate drug combination</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>80M03YXJ7I</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000068756">Valsartan</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004338">Drug Combinations</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D057911">Angiotensin Receptor Antagonists</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006353" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heart-Assist Devices</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001713" MajorTopicYN="Y">Biphenyl Compounds</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006333" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heart Failure</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000613" MajorTopicYN="Y">Aminobutyrates</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068756" MajorTopicYN="Y">Valsartan</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004338" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Combinations</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010865" MajorTopicYN="N">Pilot Projects</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057911" MajorTopicYN="N">Angiotensin Receptor Antagonists</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015337" MajorTopicYN="N">Multicenter Studies as Topic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005500" MajorTopicYN="N">Follow-Up Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Left ventricular assist device</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood pressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sacubitril/valsartan</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Disclosures MC reports investigator-initiated research grants to institution: Novartis, Abbott, Pfizer; clinical study contracts with institution: NovoNordisk, CorVia; and advisory role, speaker honoraria, travel grants: Abbott, Amgen, Amicus Therapeutics, Astra Zeneca, Bayer, Boehringer-Ingelheim, Bristol Meyers Squibb, GE Healthcare, Novartis, NovoNordisk, Pfizer, Roche, Swixx, Takeda, Teva Pharmaceutical Industries, and Viatris. IP reports investigator-initiated research grant to institution: Pfizer; clinical study contracts with institution: CPC Clinical Research; and advisory role, speaker honoraria, travel grants: Astra Zeneca, Bayer, Belupo, Berlin Chemie Menarini, Boehringer-Ingelheim, Cardio Medical, Evidera, Krka Pharma, Novartis, NovoNordisk, Pfizer, PharmaS, Swixx, Teva Pharmaceutical Industries, and Zentiva. JB has received an independent research grant for ISS from Abbott to the Institute and has had speaker engagements with Astra Zeneca, Abbott, Boehringer, Bayer, Novartis, and Vifor in the past 5 years. BC reports consulting for Alexion, Alnylam, Cardior, Cardurion, Corvia, CVRx, Eli Lilly, Intellia, Rocket, and Valo. NJ reports speaker honoraria and travel grants: Abbott, Astra Zeneca, Bayer, Boehringer-Ingelheim, Krka, NovoNordisk, Pfizer, and Teva Pharmaceutical Industries. The UMC Utrecht, which employs LWVL, has received speaker fees and research grants from Medtronic, Abbott, Novartis, and Vifor. SDS has received research grants from Alexion, Alnylam, Applied Therapeutics, AstraZeneca, Bellerophon, Bayer, BMS, Boston Scientific, Cytokinetics, Edgewise, Eidos/Bridgebio, Gossamer, GSK, Ionis, Intellia, Lilly,NIH/NHLBI, Novartis, NovoNordisk, Respicardia, Sanofi Pasteur, Tenaya, Theracos, and US2.AI and has consulted for Abbott, Action, Akros, Alexion, Alnylam, Amgen, Arena, Askbio, AstraZeneca, Bayer, BMS, Cardior, Cardurion, Corvia, Cytokinetics, GSK, Lilly, Novartis, NovoNordisk, Roche, Theracos, Quantum Genomics, Tenaya, Sanofi-Pasteur, Dinaqor, Tremeau, CellProThera, Moderna, American Regent, Sarepta, Lexicon, Anacardio, Akros, Valo, Synhale, and Recordati.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40818766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cardfail.2025.07.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1071-9164(25)00336-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>