<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41069280</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1520-5827</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>41</Volume><Issue>41</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Langmuir : the ACS journal of surfaces and colloids</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Langmuir</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Reversible Bacterial Depletion Aggregation and Restabilization by Water-Soluble Polymers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>28109</StartPage><EndPage>28118</EndPage><MedlinePgn>28109-28118</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c04060</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Depletion forces are ubiquitous in soft materials and biological systems; however, their role in producing depletion aggregation of bacterial cells is becoming recognized as an important factor impacting bacterial growth and infection. The concentration of the depletant has been quantified only in limited cases. To provide a broader perspective, this work compares depletion aggregation of flagella-free <i>Escherichia coli</i> by several different macromolecules relevant to food and biomedical applications, to provide perspective on the concentration range of each polymer that produces aggregation: both the onset of depletion aggregation and restabilization. The macromolecules include hyaluronic acid, poly(acrylic acid) (PAA), guar, and albumin, in comparison to previously published results with poly(ethylene oxide) and the same <i>E. coli</i>. The reversibility of aggregation is established to distinguish depletion from other potential aggregation mechanisms. We report that due to the varying size of the macromolecular depletants, the depletant concentration needed to produce bacterial aggregation can vary by 2 orders of magnitude, with guar producing aggregation below 0.03 wt% while about 1 wt% albumin can be tolerated in solution before aggregation occurs. At reduced ionic strengths approaching freshwater conditions, polyanionic depletants produced aggregation below concentrations of 0.01 wt%. Restabilization at higher polymer concentrations was seen, consistent with concentrations exceeding the polymer overlap concentration. Restabilization occurred more readily with more dilute cell suspensions. Concentrated cell suspensions did not restabilize at the same high (&#x223c;1 wt%) polymer concentrations. Low molecular weight 5K PAA produced aggregation only in a narrow window. Data for the minimum depletant concentration needed to produce depletion aggregation were collapsed by considering the effective depletant volume fraction based on a hydrated random coil or, for albumin, globule.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weinhofer</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra C</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0802-6187</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Polymer Science and Engineering, University of Massachusetts, 120 Governors Drive, Amherst, Massachusetts 01003, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fuller</LastName><ForeName>Grace</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology, University of Massachusetts, 611 North Pleasant Street, Amherst, Massachusetts 01003, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Sihang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-8757-9708</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Engineering, University of Massachusetts, 686 North Pleasant Street, Amherst, Massachusetts 01003, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brooks</LastName><ForeName>Sorrel</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, University of Massachusetts, 710 North Pleasant Street, Amherst, Massachusetts 01003, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santore</LastName><ForeName>Maria M</ForeName><Initials>MM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3689-5064</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Polymer Science and Engineering, University of Massachusetts, 120 Governors Drive, Amherst, Massachusetts 01003, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>T32 GM108556</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>T32 GM135096</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>T32 GM139789</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Langmuir</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9882736</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0743-7463</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000180">Acrylic Resins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>4Q93RCW27E</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C006903">carbopol 940</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9004-61-9</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006820">Hyaluronic Acid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>E89I1637KE</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C007894">guar gum</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008351">Mannans</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005685">Galactans</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D053149">Plant Gums</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011108">Polymers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004926" MajorTopicYN="Y">Escherichia coli</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="N">cytology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="Y">Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Acrylic Resins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012995" MajorTopicYN="N">Solubility</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006820" MajorTopicYN="N">Hyaluronic Acid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008351" MajorTopicYN="N">Mannans</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005685" MajorTopicYN="N">Galactans</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053149" MajorTopicYN="N">Plant Gums</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011108" MajorTopicYN="Y">Polymers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41069280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2114756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12614645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.5c04060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Asakura S; Oosawa F On Interactions between 2 Bodies Immersed in a Solution of Macromolecules. Journal of Chemical Physics 1954, 22, 1255&#x2013;1256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asakura S; Oosawa F Interaction between Particles Suspended in Solutions of Macromolecules. Journal of Polymer Science 1958, 33, 183&#x2013;192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yodh AG; Lin KH; Crocker JC; Dinsmore AD; Verma R; Kaplan PD Entropically Driven Self-Assembly and Interaction in Suspension. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London Series a-Mathematical Physical and Engineering Sciences 2001, 359, 921&#x2013;937.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim AJ; Biancaniello PL; Crocker JC Engineering DNA-Mediated Colloidal Crystallization. Langmuir 2006, 22, 1991&#x2013;2001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16489780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koenderink GH; Vliegenthart GA; Kluijtmans S; van Blaaderen A; Philipse AP; Lekkerkerker HN W. Depletion-Induced Crystallization in Colloidal Rod-Sphere Mixtures. Langmuir 1999, 15, 4693&#x2013;4696.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuhl T; Guo YQ; Alderfer JL; Berman AD; Leckband D; Israelachvili J; Hui SW Direct Measurement of Polyethylene Glycol Induced Depletion Attraction between Lipid Bilayers. Langmuir 1996, 12, 3003&#x2013;3014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purcell IP; Lu JR; Thomas RK; Howe AM; Penfold J Adsorption of Sodium Dodecyl Sulfate at the Surface of Aqueous Solutions of Poly(Vinylpyrrolidone) Studied by Neutron Reflection. Langmuir 1998, 14, 1637&#x2013;1645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trokhymchuk A; Henderson D; Nikolov A; Wasan DT A Simple Calculation of Structural and Depletion Forces for Fluids/Suspensions Confined in a Film. Langmuir 2001, 17, 4940&#x2013;4947.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lekkerkerker HNW; Tuinier R; Vis M, Colloids and the Depletion Interaction, 2ed. Springer: Switzerland, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nam J; Santore MM Depletion Versus Deflection: How Membrane Bending Can Influence Adhesion. Physical Review Letters 2011, 107, 078101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21902431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marenduzzo D; Micheletti C; Cook PR Entropy-Driven Genome Organization. Biophysical Journal 2006, 90, 3712&#x2013;3721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1440752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16500976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosek M; Tang JX Polymer-Induced Bundling of F Actin and the Depletion Force -: Art. No. 051907. Physical Review E 2004, 69, 051907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15244847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hancock R A Role for Macromolecular Crowding Effects in the Assembly and Function of Compartments in the Nucleus. Journal of Structural Biology 2004, 146, 281&#x2013;290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15099570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosania GR; Swanson JA Effects of Macromolecular Crowding on Nuclear Size. Experimental Cell Research 1995, 218, 114&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7537686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zosel F; Soranno A; Buholzer KJ; Nettels D; Schuler B Depletion Interactions Modulate the Binding between Disordered Proteins in Crowded Environments. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America 2020, 117, 13480&#x2013;13489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7306994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32487732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones CW; Wang JC; Ferrone FA; Briehl RW; Turner MS Interactions between Sickle Hemoglobin Fibers. Faraday Discussions 2003, 123, 221&#x2013;236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12638863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu YS; Dufour S; Thiery JP; Perez E; Pincet F Johnson-Kendall-Roberts Theory Applied to Living Cells. Physical Review Letters 2005, 94, 028102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15698233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Corte SG; Stevens CA; C&#xe1;rcamo-Oyarce G; Ribbeck K; Wingreen NS; Datta SS Morphogenesis of Bacterial Cables in Polymeric Environments. Science Advances 2025, 11, q7797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11740958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39823332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Secor PR; Michaels LA; Bublitz DC; Jennings LK; Singh PK The Depletion Mechanism Actuates Bacterial Aggregation by Exopolysaccharides and Determines Species Distribution &amp; Composition in Bacterial Aggregates. Frontiers in Cellular and Infection Microbiology 2022, 12, 869736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9243289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35782109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu WA; Rivera SL; Siegrist MS; Santore MM Depletion Forces Drive Reversible Capture of Live Bacteria on Non-Adhesive Surfaces. Soft Matter 2021, 17, 8185&#x2013;8194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34525168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu WA; Smith MN; Santore MM Depletion Attractions Drive Bacterial Capture on Both Non-Fouling and Adhesive Surfaces, Enhancing Cell Orientation. Soft Matter 2022, 18, 9205&#x2013;9215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9837788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36426747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaliyaperumal R; Deng XP; Meiselman HJ; Song H; Dalan R; Leow MKS; Neu B Depletion Interaction Forces Contribute to Erythrocyte-Endothelial Adhesion in Diabetes. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications 2019, 516, 144&#x2013;148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31200959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neu B; Meiselman HJ Depletion Interactions in Polymer Solutions Promote Red Blood Cell Adhesion to Albumin-Coated Surfaces. Biochimica Et Biophysica Acta-General Subjects 2006, 1760, 1772&#x2013;1779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2668949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17049748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarz-Linek J; Dorken G; Winkler A; Wilson LG; Pham NT; French CE; Schilling T; Poon WCK Polymer-Induced Phase Separation in Suspensions of Bacteria. Epl 2010, 89, 68003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarz-Linek J; Winkler A; Wilson LG; Pham NT; Schilling T; Poon WCK Polymer-Induced Phase Separation in Escherichia Coli Suspensions. Soft Matter 2010, 6, 4540&#x2013;4549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai YM Non-Surface Attached Bacterial Aggregates: A Ubiquitous Third Lifestyle. Frontiers in Microbiology 2020, 11, 557035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7746683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33343514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu CM; Zhang JY; Guan R; Hale L; Chen N; Li M; Lu ZH; Ge QY; Yang YF; Zhou JZ; Chen T Alternate Succession of Aggregate-Forming Cyanobacterial Genera Correlated with Their Attached Bacteria by Co-Pathways. Science of the Total Environment 2019, 688, 867&#x2013;879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31255824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman J; Codd GA; Paerl HW; Ibelings BW; Verspagen JMH; Visser PM Cyanobacterial Blooms. Nature Reviews Microbiology 2018, 16, 471&#x2013;483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29946124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhede M; Kragh KN; Qvortrup K; Allesen-Holm M; van Gennip M; Christensen LD; Jensen PO; Nielsen AK; Parsek M; Wozniak D; Molin S; Tolker-Nielsen T; Hoiby N; Givskov M; Bjarnsholt T Phenotypes of Non-Attached Pseudomonas Aeruginosa Aggregates Resemble Surface Attached Biofilm. Plos One 2011, 6, e27943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3221681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22132176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall-Stoodley L; Stoodley P; Kathju S; Hoiby N; Moser C; Costerton JW; Moter A; Bjarnsholt T Towards Diagnostic Guidelines for Biofilm-Associated Infections. Fems Immunology and Medical Microbiology 2012, 65, 127&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22469292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sriramulu DD; L&#xfc;nsdorf H; Lam JS; R&#xf6;mling U Microcolony Formation:: A Novel Biofilm Model of Pseudomonas Aeruginosa for the Cystic Fibrosis Lung. Journal of Medical Microbiology 2005, 54, 667&#x2013;676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15947432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pabst B; Pitts B; Lauchnor E; Stewart PS Gel-Entrapped Staphylococcus Aureus Bacteria as Models of Biofilm Infection Exhibit Growth in Dense Aggregates, Oxygen Limitation, Antibiotic Tolerance, and Heterogeneous Gene Expression. Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy 2016, 60, 6294&#x2013;6301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5038234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27503656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Secor PR; Michaels LA; Ratjen A; Jennings LK; Singh PK Entropically Driven Aggregation of Bacteria by Host Polymers Promotes Antibiotic Tolerance in Pseudomonas Aeruginosa. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America 2018, 115, 10780&#x2013;10785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6196481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30275316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhede M; Er &#xd6;; Eickhardt S; Kragh K; Alhede M; Christensen LD; Poulsen SS; Givskov M; Christensen LH; Hoiby N; Tvede M; Bjarnsholt T Bacterial Biofilm Formation and Treatment in Soft Tissue Fillers. Pathogens and Disease 2014, 70, 339&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24482426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staats A; Burback PW; Casillas-Ituarte NN; Li D; Hostetler MR; Sullivan A; Horswill AR; Lower SK; Stoodley P In Vitro Staphylococcal Aggregate Morphology and Protection from Antibiotics Are Dependent on Distinct Mechanisms Arising from Postsurgical Joint Components and Fluid Motion. Journal of Bacteriology 2023, 205, e0045122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10127631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36951588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Secor PR; Jennings LK; Michaels LA; Sweere JM; Singh PK; Parks WC; Bollyky PL Biofilm Assembly Becomes Crystal Clear - Filamentous Bacteriophage Organize the Pseudomonas Aeruginosa Biofilm Matrix into a Liquid Crystal. Microbial Cell 2016, 3, 49&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5354590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28357315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eboigbodin KE; Newton JRA; Routh AF; Biggs CA Role of Nonadsorbing Polymers in Bacterial Aggregation. Langmuir 2005, 21, 12315&#x2013;12319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16343008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewangan NK; Tran N; Wang-Reed J; Conrad JC Bacterial Aggregation Assisted by Anionic Surfactant and Calcium Ions. Soft Matter 2021, 17, 8474&#x2013;8482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34586147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azimi S; Thomas J; Cleland SE; Curtis JE; Goldberg JB; Diggle SP O-Specific Antigen-Dependent Surface Hydrophobicity Mediates Aggregate Assembly Type in Pseudomonas Aeruginosa. Mbio 2021, 12, 00860&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8406328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34372703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dilanji GE; Teplitski M; Hagen SJ Entropy-Driven Motility of Sinorhizobium Meliloti on a Semi-Solid Surface. Proceedings of the Royal Society B-Biological Sciences 2014, 281, e2575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4043075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24741008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorken G; Ferguson GP; French CE; Poon WCK Aggregation by Depletion Attraction in Cultures of Bacteria Producing Exopolysaccharide. Journal of the Royal Society Interface 2012, 9, 3490&#x2013;3502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3481587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22896568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebrahimi A; Schwartzman J; Cordero OX Multicellular Behaviour Enables Cooperation in Microbial Cell Aggregates. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B-Biological Sciences 2019, 374, 20190077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6792450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31587643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh P; Mondal J; Ben-Jacob E; Levine H Mechanically-Driven Phase Separation in a Growing Bacterial Colony. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America 2015, 112, E2166&#x2013;E2173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4418877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25870260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jarrett CO; Leung JM; Motoshi S; Sturdevant DE; Zhang YX; Hoyt FH; Hinnebusch BJ Role of the Yersinia Pestis Phospholipase D (Ymt) in the Initial Aggregation Step of Biofilm Formation in the Flea. Mbio 2024, 15, e0012424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11237439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38722159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marenduzzo D; Finan K; Cook PR The Depletion Attraction: An Underappreciated Force Driving Cellular Organization. Journal of Cell Biology 2006, 175, 681&#x2013;686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2064666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17145959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazeer N; Ahmed M Hydrophilic and Salt Responsive Polymers Promote Depletion Aggregation of Bacteria. European Polymer Journal 2019, 119, 148&#x2013;154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benadiva CA; Kuczynskibrown B; Maguire TG; Mastroianni L; Flickinger GL Bovine Serum Albumin (Bsa) Can Replace Patient Serum as a Protein-Source in an Invitro Fertilization Program Journal of in Vitro Fertilization and Embryo Transfer 1989, 6, 164&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2794734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>https://www.thermofisher.com/de/de/home/life-science/cell-culture/mammalian-cell-culture
2025, September.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>https://shop.neofroxx.com/pi/bf/PRODUCTINFO_EN_1638_Albumin%20Fraction%20V_V1.pdf
2025, September.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troncoso JB; Fernandez JR; Hubeny J; Grzywacz M; Silwanowicz A; Bunikowska M; Kozlowski P; Martyniak M Different Hyaluronan Concentration Determinate Distinctive Physicochemical and Biological Properties of the Intra-Articular Gel but Does Not Affect Satisfactory Clinical Outcome. Journal of Orthopaedic Reports 2024, 4, 100445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semp DA; Beeson D; Sheppard AL; Dutta D; Wolffsohn JS Artificial Tears: A Systematic Review. Clinical Optometry 2023, 15, 9&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9840372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36647552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mudgil D; Barak S; Khatkar BS Guar Gum: Processing, Properties and Food Applications-a Review. Journal of Food Science and Technology-Mysore 2014, 51, 409&#x2013;418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3931889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24587515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivasan S; Williams R Propylene Glycol and Hydroxypropyl Guar Nanoemulsion-Safe and Effective Lubricant Eye Drops in the Management of Dry Eye Disease. Clinical Ophthalmology 2022, 16, 3311&#x2013;3326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9553314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36237486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shave MK; Xu Z; Raman V; Kalasin S; Tuominen MT; Forbes NS; Santore MM Escherichia Coli Swimming Back toward Stiffer Polyetheylene Glycol Coatings, Increasing Contact in Flow. Acs Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces 2021, 13, 17196&#x2013;17206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8503937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33821607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickinson E; Eriksson L Particle Flocculaton by Adsorbing Polymers. Advances in Colloid and Interface Science 1991, 34, 1&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory J; Barany S Adsorption and Flocculation by Polymers and Polymer Mixtures. Advances in Colloid and Interface Science 2011, 169, 1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21762869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon SY; Deng YL Flocculation and Reflocculation of Clay Suspension by Different Polymer Systems under Turbulent Conditions. Journal of Colloid and Interface Science 2004, 278, 139&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15313647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duffadar R; Kalasin S; Davis JM; Santore MM The Impact of Nanoscale Chemical Features on Micron-Scale Adhesion: Crossover from Heterogeneity-Dominated to Mean-Field Behavior. Journal of Colloid and Interface Science 2009, 337, 396&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19539949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin JL; Huang CP; Chin CJM; Pan JR Coagulation Dynamics of Fractal Flocs Induced by Enmeshment and Electrostatic Patch Mechanisms. Water Research 2008, 42, 4457&#x2013;4466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18804257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y; Franks GV Flocculation Mechanism Induced by Cationic Polymers Investigated by Light Scattering. Langmuir 2006, 22, 6775&#x2013;6786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16863222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozlova N; Santore MM Manipulation of Micrometer-Scale Adhesion by Tuning Nanometer-Scale Surface Features. Langmuir 2006, 22, 1135&#x2013;1142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16430276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calero C; Pagonabarraga I Self-Assembly of Microscopic Rods Due to Depletion Interaction. Entropy 2020, 22, e22101114</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7597238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33286883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das DR; Mahalik S Engineering Escherichia Coli to Metabolize Sorbitol as the Sole Carbon Source for Synthesis of Recombinant L-Asparaginase-Ii. Preparative Biochemistry &amp; Biotechnology 2025, 55, 567&#x2013;576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39672810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shave MK; Kalasin S; Ying E; Santore MM Nanoscale Functionalized Particles with Rotation-Controlled Capture in Shear Flow. Acs Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces 2018, 10, 29058&#x2013;29068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6171355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30109808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feigin RI; Napper DH Depletion Stbilization and Depletion Flocculation. Journal of Colloid and Interface Science 1980, 75, 525&#x2013;541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Gennes PG, Scaling Concepts in Polymer Physics. Cornell University Press: Ithaca, 1979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gast AP; Russel WB; Hall CK An Experimental and Theoretical Study of Phase Transitions in the Polystyrene Latex and Hydroxyethylcellulose System Journal of Colloid and Interface Science 1986, 109, 161&#x2013;171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lekkerkerker HNW; Poon WCK; Pusey PN; Stroobants A; Warren PB Phase Behavior of Colloid Plus Polymer Mixtures Europhysics Letters 1992, 20, 559&#x2013;564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santore MM; Russel WB; Prudhomme RK Experimental and Theoretical-Study of Phase-Transitions Induced in Colloidal Dispersions by Associative Polymers. Faraday Discussions 1990, 90, 323&#x2013;333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santore MM; Russel WB; Prudhomme RK A One-Component Model for the Phase Behavior of Dispersions Containing Assocaiative Polymers. Macromolecules 1990, 23, 3821&#x2013;3832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santore MM; Russel WB; Prudhomme RKA 2-Component Model for the Phase Bavior of Dispersions Containing Associative Polymer Macromolecules 1989, 22, 1317&#x2013;1325.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards TD; Bevan MA Depletion-Mediated Potentials and Phase Behavior for Micelles, Macromolecules, Nanoparticles, and Hydrogel Particles. Langmuir 2012, 28, 13816&#x2013;13823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22950666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes GE; Beltran-Villegas DJ; Bevan MA Interfacial Colloidal Crystallization Via Tunable Hydrogel Depletants. Langmuir 2008, 24, 10776&#x2013;10785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18774826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>