<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40225506</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Rhabdomyolysis and Acute Kidney Injury: Exploring the Potential Causes in a Hospitalized Patient.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e80535</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e80535</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e80535</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.80535</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Rhabdomyolysis refers to the breakdown of skeletal muscle with subsequent release of intracellular contents into blood, causing elevated creatine kinase (CK) and renal damage. The four main etiological categories are traumatic, non-traumatic, non-traumatic exertional, and non-traumatic&#xa0;non-exertional. We report a case of a young female who presented with rhabdomyolysis due to agitation, increased motor activity, and venlafaxine use, resulting in severe organ dysfunction.&#xa0;A 30-year-old female&#xa0;on venlafaxine,&#xa0;pregabalin, and fentanyl patch presented to our hospital with a sudden onset of generalized pain and agitation. Before presentation, the patient was flailing her extremities and thrashing herself against the wall, and the patient became more confused, which prompted the mother to bring her to our emergency department. She had icterus, diffuse ecchymosis over bilateral upper and lower extremities, edematous extremities, and generalized weakness of all extremities with 3/5 strength, normal reflexes without rigidity or clonus or tremors. At presentation, the patient had elevated CK, elevated creatinine, transaminitis, international normalized ratio (INR) of 5.4, and ammonia of 126 umol/L. Given rhabdomyolysis and non-oliguric acute kidney injury, the patient was started on aggressive intravenous hydration at admission. However, her creatinine worsened in the next 24 hours, and the patient developed a worsening of creatinine&#xa0;with high anion gap metabolic acidosis. The patient was given a Lasix challenge and sodium bicarbonate infusion to aid in the excretion of myoglobin and N-acetylcysteine infusion for worsening liver function. She became anuric despite diuretics, developed acute tubular necrosis, and was started on intermittent hemodialysis. Over the next few days, her urine output improved and her creatinine gradually improved. During her hospital course, her mental status returned to baseline, she was started on physical therapy as tolerated, her lower extremity strength gradually improved, and she was discharged to an inpatient rehabilitation facility. Agitation is one of the most common presentations to the emergency department and can cause rhabdomyolysis. Careful monitoring, evaluation of other coexisting causes of rhabdomyolysis, and early aggressive hydration are of paramount importance. Additionally, the use of prediction tools such as the McMahon score can aid in identifying patients who will need renal replacement therapy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Upadrista et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Upadrista</LastName><ForeName>Pratap Kumar</ForeName><Initials>PK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nephrology, Northwell Health, East Meadow, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peketi</LastName><ForeName>Sindhu Harika</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Nassau University Medical Center, East Meadow, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sudireddy</LastName><ForeName>Nagakowsikreddy</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Nassau University Medical Center, East Meadow, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cadet</LastName><ForeName>Bair</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nephrology, Nassau University Medical Center, East Meadow, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Zae</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nephrology, Nassau University Medical Center, East Meadow, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuroleptic malignant syndrome (nms)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-traumatic rhabdomyolysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rhabdomyolysis aki</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">serotonin syndrome diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">venlafaxine rhabdomyolysis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40225506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11993355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.80535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Beyond muscle destruction: a systematic review of rhabdomyolysis for clinical practice. Chavez LO, Leon M, Einav S, Varon J. Crit Care. 2016;20:135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4908773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27301374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The syndrome of rhabdomyolysis: pathophysiology and diagnosis. Giannoglou GD, Chatzizisis YS, Misirli G. Eur J Intern Med. 2007;18:90&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17338959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathogenesis of renal failure in rhabdomyolysis: the role of myoglobin. Holt S, Moore K. Exp Nephrol. 2000;8:72&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10729745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bench-to-bedside review: rhabdomyolysis - an overview for clinicians. Huerta-Alard&#xed;n AL, Varon J, Marik PE. Crit Care. 2005;9:158&#x2013;169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1175909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15774072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The spectrum of rhabdomyolysis. Gabow PA, Kaehny WD, Kelleher SD. https://journals.lww.com/md-journal/citation/1982/05000/the_spectrum_of_rhabdomyolysis.2.aspx. Medicine. 1982;61:141&#x2013;152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7078398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corwin HL, Schreiber MJ, Fang LS. Arch Intern Med. Vol. 144. 981-982: 144; 1984. Low fractional excretion of sodium: occurrence with hemoglobinuric- and myoglobinuric-induced acute renal failure; pp. 981&#x2013;982.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6712414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Predicting the outcomes of rhabdomyolysis: a good starting point. Wilhelm-Leen ER, Winkelmayer WC. JAMA Intern Med. 2013;173:1828&#x2013;1829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4122503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23999843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhabdomyolysis: an evaluation of 475 hospitalized patients. Melli G, Chaudhry V, Cornblath DR. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16267412/ Medicine (Baltimore) 2005;84:377&#x2013;385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16267412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhabdomyolysis. Vanholder R, Sever MS, Erek E, Lameire N. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2000;11:1553&#x2013;1561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10906171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhabdomyolysis and myoglobin-induced acute renal failure. Malik GH. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/18408300/ Saudi J Kidney Dis Transpl. 1998;9:273&#x2013;284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18408300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of combining intermittent hemodiafiltration with forced alkaline diuresis on plasma myoglobin in rhabdomyolysis. Peltonen S, Ahlstr&#xf6;m A, Kyl&#xe4;vainio V, Honkanen E, Pettil&#xe4; V. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2007;51:553&#x2013;558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17430315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>