<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40770393</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of precursor materials and activator interactions on the microstructural and mechanical properties of one part alkali activated concrete.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>28826</StartPage><MedlinePgn>28826</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">28826</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-13775-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The practical implementation of alkali activateds is frequently constrained by the complexities associated with preparing alkaline solutions. The advent of one-part alkali activated concrete presents substantial advantages over conventional two-part systems by negating the need for a separate activation process. This simplification not only enhances consistency, workability, and sustainability but also minimizes mixing errors, thereby facilitating broader adoption in construction applications. This study comprehensively examines the effects of various activators on the mechanical properties and microstructural characteristics of one-part alkali activated concrete. Utilizing Scanning Electron Microscopy (SEM) and Energy-Dispersive X-ray Spectroscopy (EDAX), we investigate the elemental compositions and microstructural features of the alkali activated samples. Our findings underscore the pivotal role of both precursor materials and activator selection in determining hydration products and overall material performance. Notably, the slag-only alkali activated exhibited a dense microstructure characterized by the formation of calcium-aluminum-silicate-hydrate (C-A-S-H) and sodium-aluminum-silicate-hydrate (N-A-S-H) gel phases. The addition of bentonite introduced a more heterogeneous microstructure, with elevated aluminum content indicative of a complex N-A-S-H structure. Furthermore, the choice of activator markedly influenced hydration reactions. The optimal ternary activator (6:3:1 Na-silicate: Na-hydroxide: Na-carbonate) achieved 47&#xa0;MPa compressive strength, reducing CO&#x2082; emissions by 80% compared to OPC [8]. This research provides critical insights for optimizing alkali activated concrete formulations, highlighting the significance of precursor materials and activator interactions. By advancing the understanding of one-part alkali activateds, this study establishes a foundation for innovative and sustainable solutions in building engineering, addressing practical challenges while enhancing the performance of construction materials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Serag</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed I</ForeName><Initials>MI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Engineering, Cairo University, Giza, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ibrahim</LastName><ForeName>Sara</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Engineering, Cairo University, Giza, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Badawy</LastName><ForeName>Amr H</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Civil Engineering Department, National Research Centre, Giza, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Helal</LastName><ForeName>Y H</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Higher Technological Institute, 10th of Ramadan City, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Feky</LastName><ForeName>M S</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Civil Engineering Department, National Research Centre, Giza, Egypt. msaelfeky@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Activator</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eco-friendly alkali activated cement production</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">One-part alkali activated</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sustainable construction materials</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40770393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12328721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-13775-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-13775-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Miller, S. A., Horvath, A. &amp; Monteiro, P. J. Readily implementable techniques can cut annual CO<sub>2</sub> emissions from the production of concrete by over 20%. <i>Environ. Res. Lett.</i><b>11</b> (7), 074029 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen, W. et al. Cement industry of china: driving force, environment impact and sustainable development. <i>Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev.</i><b>75</b>, 618&#x2013;628 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, C. Y., Han, R., Yu, B. &amp; Wei, Y. M. Accounting process-related CO<sub>2</sub> emissions from global cement production under shared socioeconomic pathways. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>184</b>, 451&#x2013;465 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, M. B., Saidur, R. &amp; Hossain, M. S. A review on emission analysis in cement industries. <i>Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev.</i><b>15</b> (5), 2252&#x2013;2261 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shekhovtsova, J. et al. Estimation of fly Ash reactivity for use in alkali-activated cements-a step towards sustainable building material and waste utilization. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>178</b>, 22&#x2013;33 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, C., Shi, Z., Hu, X., Zhao, R. &amp; Chong, L. A review on alkali-aggregate reactions in alkali-activated mortars/concretes made with alkali-reactive aggregates. <i>Mater. Struct.</i><b>48</b>, 621&#x2013;628 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vishwakarma, V. &amp; Ramachandran, D. Green concrete mix using solid waste and nanoparticles as alternatives&#x2014;A review. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>162</b>, 96&#x2013;103 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nematollahi, B., Sanjayan, J. &amp; Shaikh, F. U. A. Synthesis of heat and ambient cured one-part alkali activated mixes with different grades of sodium silicate. <i>Ceram. Int.</i><b>41</b> (4), 5696&#x2013;5704 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assi, L., Carter, K., Deaver, E. E., Anay, R. &amp; Ziehl, P. Sustainable concrete: Building a greener future. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>198</b>, 1641&#x2013;1651 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Deventer, J. S., Provis, J. L., Duxson, P. &amp; Brice, D. G. Chemical research and climate change as drivers in the commercial adoption of alkali activated materials. <i>Waste Biomass Valoriz.</i><b>1</b>, 145&#x2013;155 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humbert, P. S. &amp; Castro-Gomes, J. CO2 activated steel slag-based materials: A review. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>208</b>, 448&#x2013;457 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L. Production of bricks from waste materials&#x2014;A review. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>47</b>, 643&#x2013;655 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandanayake, M., Gunasekara, C., Law, D., Zhang, G. &amp; Setunge, S. Greenhouse gas emissions of different fly Ash based alkali activated concretes in Building construction. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>204</b>, 399&#x2013;408 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, L., Gao, X. &amp; Chen, T. Recycling of raw rice husk to manufacture magnesium oxysulfate cement based lightweight building materials. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>191</b>, 220&#x2013;232 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, H. et al. Utilization of lithium slag by wet-grinding process to improve the early strength of sulphoaluminate cement paste. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>205</b>, 536&#x2013;551 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernal, S. A. &amp; Provis, J. L. Durability of alkali-activated materials: progress and perspectives. <i>J. Am. Ceram. Soc.</i><b>97</b> (4), 997&#x2013;1008 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hojati, M. &amp; Radli&#x144;ska, A. Shrinkage and strength development of alkali-activated fly ash-slag binary cements. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>150</b>, 808&#x2013;816 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdi, M. A., Liebscher, M., Hempel, S., Yang, J. &amp; Mechtcherine, V. Correlation of microstructural and mechanical properties of alkali activateds produced from fly Ash and slag at room temperature. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>191</b>, 330&#x2013;341 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Provis, J. L. Activating solution chemistry for alkali activateds. In <i>Alkali Activateds</i>, 50&#x2013;71. (Woodhead Publishing, 2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Somna, K., Jaturapitakkul, C., Kajitvichyanukul, P. &amp; Chindaprasirt, P. NaOH-activated ground fly Ash alkali activated cured at ambient temperature. <i>Fuel</i>. <b>90</b> (6), 2118&#x2013;2124 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oderji, S. Y., Chen, B. &amp; Jaffar, S. T. A. Effects of relative humidity on the properties of fly ash-based alkali activateds. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>153</b>, 268&#x2013;273 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheah, C. B., Samsudin, M. H., Ramli, M., Part, W. K. &amp; Tan, L. E. The use of high calcium wood ash in the preparation of ground granulated blast furnace slag and pulverized fly ash alkali activateds: A complete microstructural and mechanical characterization. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>156</b>, 114&#x2013;123 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta, A. &amp; Siddique, R. Sustainable alkali activated concrete using ground granulated blast furnace slag and rice husk ash: strength and permeability properties. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>205</b>, 49&#x2013;57 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuang, X. Y. et al. Fly ash-based alkali activated: clean production, properties and applications. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>125</b>, 253&#x2013;267 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duxson, P. &amp; Provis, J. L. Designing precursors for alkali activated cements. <i>J. Am. Ceram. Soc.</i><b>91</b> (12), 3864&#x2013;3869 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adesanya, E., Ohenoja, K., Luukkonen, T., Kinnunen, P. &amp; Illikainen, M. One-part alkali activated cement from slag and pretreated paper sludge. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>185</b>, 168&#x2013;175 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luukkonen, T., Abdollahnejad, Z., Yliniemi, J., Kinnunen, P. &amp; Illikainen, M. One-part alkali-activated materials: A review. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>103</b>, 21&#x2013;34 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashad, A. M. A comprehensive overview about the influence of different admixtures and additives on the properties of alkali-activated fly ash. <i>Mater. Des</i>. <b>53</b>, 1005&#x2013;1025 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saha, S. &amp; Rajasekaran, C. Enhancement of the properties of fly Ash based alkali activated paste by incorporating ground granulated blast furnace slag. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>146</b>, 615&#x2013;620 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang, J. et al. Alternation of traditional cement mortars using fly ash-based alkali activated mortars modified by slag. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>203</b>, 746&#x2013;756 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, N. K. &amp; Lee, H. K. Setting and mechanical properties of alkali-activated fly ash/slag concrete manufactured at room temperature. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>47</b>, 1201&#x2013;1209 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Temuujin, J. V., Van Riessen, A. &amp; Williams, R. Influence of calcium compounds on the mechanical properties of fly Ash alkali activated pastes. <i>J. Hazard. Mater.</i><b>167</b> (1&#x2013;3), 82&#x2013;88 (2009).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19201089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pern&#xe1;, I. &amp; Hanzl&#xed;&#x10d;ek, T. The setting time of a clay-slag alkali activated matrix: the influence of blast-furnace-slag addition and the mixing method. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>112</b>, 1150&#x2013;1155 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, C., Zhao, B., Guo, S., Long, G. &amp; Xie, Y. Properties and characterization of green one-part alkali activated activated by composite activators. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>220</b>, 188&#x2013;199 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oderji, S. Y., Chen, B., Ahmad, M. R. &amp; Shah, S. F. A. Fresh and hardened properties of one-part fly ash-based alkali activated binders cured at room temperature: effect of slag and alkali activators. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>225</b>, 1&#x2013;10 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luukkonen, T., Abdollahnejad, Z., Yliniemi, J., Kinnunen, P. &amp; Illikainen, M. Comparison of alkali and silica sources in one-part alkali-activated blast furnace slag mortar. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>187</b>, 171&#x2013;179 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azevedo, A. G. S. &amp; Strecker, K. Kaolin, fly-ash and ceramic waste based alkali-activated materials production by the one-part method. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>269</b>, 121306 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samadhiya, A., Bhunia, D., Chakraborty, S. &amp; Lahoti, M. <i>Influence of Activator Ratios and Concentration on the Physio-mechanical and Microstructural Characteristics of the Alkali Activateds Derived from Sandstone Processing Waste</i>, 1&#x2013;16 (Environmental Science and Pollution Research, 2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38526714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samadhiya, A., Bhunia, D. &amp; Chakraborty, S. Alkali-activation potential of sandstone wastes with electric arc furnace slag as co-additive. <i>Arab. J. Sci. Eng.</i><b>49</b> (4), 5817&#x2013;5833 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samadhiya, A., Bhunia, D., Chakraborty, S. &amp; Lahoti, M. <i>Optimization of Sandstone Processing Waste, Electric Arc Furnace Slag, and Fly Ash-based Ternary Blended Eco-friendly Alkali Activateds</i>, 1&#x2013;22 (Environmental Science and Pollution Research, 2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39585565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samadhiya, A., Bhunia, D., Chakraborty, S. &amp; Kaushik, T. Alkali-activation potential of stone wastes. <i>Mater. Today Proc</i>. (2023).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>