<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40572806</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Development of Grouting Materials from Shield Sludge via Alkaline Hydrothermal Activation: A Resource Utilization Approach.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2673</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma18122673</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Frequently, the viscous mixture from shield operations is disposed of because its significant water ratio and the presence of polymers like foaming agents result in subpar structural qualities, contributing to the unnecessary consumption of land and the squandering of soil assets. Therefore, these problems urgently need to be solved economically and effectively. This study relies on the shield sludge produced by Qingdao Metro Line 6 project, and sand and shield sludge were used as the raw materials for synchronous grouting. By applying the basic principles of geopolymerization, ingredients like shield sludge and ground granulated blast furnace slag (GGBS) were mixed with sodium hydroxide, serving as the activating agent, in the preparation of the simultaneous grout formulas. A broad range of laboratory tests was conducted to evaluate the performance of these grout formulations. The effects of varying material ratios on key performance indicators-namely, fluidity, water secretion rate, setting time, and 3-day unconfined compressive strength (UCS)-were systematically analyzed. Based on these findings, the optimal material ratios for shield sludge-based synchronous grouting materials were proposed. Subsequently, component geopolymer was prepared from the activated shield sludge and shield sludge without adding any additional alkaline activators by simply adding water. A geopolymer with a 28-day compressive strength of 51.08 MPa was obtained when the shield sludge dosing was 60 wt%. This study aims to provide a reference for the preparation of synchronous grouting materials for the resource utilization of shield sludge.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Lianjun</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Safety and Environmental Engineering, Shandong University of Science and Technology, Qingdao 266590, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical &amp; Automotive Engineering, Qingdao University of Technology, Qingdao 266520, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Meiyue</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Safety and Environmental Engineering, Shandong University of Science and Technology, Qingdao 266590, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Penghui</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-1405-4461</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Safety and Environmental Engineering, Shandong University of Science and Technology, Qingdao 266590, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Junxiang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Safety and Environmental Engineering, Shandong University of Science and Technology, Qingdao 266590, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Energy and Mining Engineering, Shandong University of Science and Technology, Qingdao 266590, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoqiang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Safety and Environmental Engineering, Shandong University of Science and Technology, Qingdao 266590, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Yellow River Delta Earth Surface Processes and Ecological Integrity, Shandong University of Science and Technology, Qingdao 266590, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">alkaline hydrothermal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydration product</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">shield sludge</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">synchronous grouting</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40572806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12193796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma18122673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma18122673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Min F., Dai J., Zhang N., Ma J., Zhang L., Li B. Investigation into strength development mechanism of lime-modified dehydrated clay of slurry shield tunneling operation. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;438:137224. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu T., Huang F., Li S., Ouyang T., Ying J., Zhao H. Optimization of pre-grouting construction and evaluation of grouting effect in a deeply buried silt-filled shield tunnel. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2024;152:105902. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2024.105902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2024.105902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H., Wang X., Zhang X., Zhou Y., Wang T., Xue Y. Preparation of high-strength ceramsite via co-sintering of shield tunnel muck and steel slag: Correlation investigation on phase composition and particle strength. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;439:137413. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao N., Wan X., Ding J., Zhang X., Xue C. Mechanical properties and microstructure of lime-treated shield tunnel muck improved with carbide slag and soda residue. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;428:136419. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei J., Yang Y., Chen X. Mechanics and permeability properties of ecological concrete mixed with recycled engineering muck particles. J. Build. Eng. 2024;91:109560. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K., Pei H., Liang X., Zhao W., Dai G. Characteristics and modification mechanism of recycled waste silty clay slurry as the shield slag conditioner. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;444:137792. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakao K., Shiina M., Inazumi S. Assessment of plasticity of muddy soil for earth pressure balance shield tunneling. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2024;153:106044. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2024.106044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2024.106044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee H., Kim H.K., Hwang B., Yoon Y., Choi H. Coupled DEM-FDM numerical model for EPB shield tunnelling simulation with foam conditioning. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2024;147:105718. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2024.105718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2024.105718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbaz K., Zhou A., Shen S.-L. Deep reinforcement learning approach to optimize the driving performance of shield tunnelling machines. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2023;136:105104. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2023.105104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2023.105104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Z., Ye C., Cao F. Performance and Microstructure of Grouting Materials Made from Shield Muck. Materials. 2024;17:4074. doi: 10.3390/ma17164074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17164074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11356173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39203252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni Z., Wang S., Zheng X., Qi C. Application of geopolymer in synchronous grouting for reusing of the shield muck in silty clay layer. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;419:135345. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X., Yu J., Yu F., Pan J., Li S. The Role of a New Stabilizer in Enhancing the Mechanical Performance of Construction Residue Soils. Materials. 2024;17:4293. doi: 10.3390/ma17174293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17174293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11396160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39274683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang Y., Yao Y., Wang J., Li B., Dou L., Wei L., Zhuo B., Zhang W., Hu X. Effective dewatering and resourceful utilization of high-viscosity waste slurry through magnetic flocculation. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;425:136014. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z., Wu S., Zhou A., Sun X., Xu H., Dong S. New insight into the additives in preparation and reduction of shield slurry. Sci. Rep. 2023;13:15969. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-42939-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-42939-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10519938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37749126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang F., Cao T., Zhang T., Hu J., Wang X., Ding Z., Wu Z. An Implementation Framework for On-Site Shield Spoil Utilization&#x2014;A Case Study of a Metro Project. Sustainability. 2023;15:9304. doi: 10.3390/su15129304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su15129304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong C.-j., Xie C.-r., Lin Z.-q., Xie D.-w., Zhou Z. Ground deformation prediction induced by shield tunnelling considering existing multi-story buildings. J. Cent. South Univ. 2023;30:1373&#x2013;1387. doi: 10.1007/s11771-023-5307-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11771-023-5307-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K., Zhang Z., Chen H., Hu Z. Experimental investigation on rheological properties and diffusion-related performance of clay shock slurry for excavation gap filling during shield tunnelling. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2024;146:105660. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2024.105660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2024.105660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X., Yang T., Yu Z., Zong Z., Li J. Study on the Unconfined Compressive Strength Property and Mechanism of Soda Residue Soil. Geotech. Geol. Eng. 2024;42:5085&#x2013;5106. doi: 10.1007/s10706-024-02831-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10706-024-02831-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Y., Liu X. Research on the Pressure Distribution Law of Synchronous Grouting in Shield Tunnels and the Force on Segments. Buildings. 2024;14:1099. doi: 10.3390/buildings14041099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings14041099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Y., Gao Y., Tao W., Huang S. Study on the Reuse of Shield Mud from Clay Stratum in Synchronous Grouting Slurry. Buildings. 2024;14:2537. doi: 10.3390/buildings14082537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings14082537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Z., Geng J., Jin C., Liu G., Xia Z. Influence of Residue Soil on the Properties of Fly Ash&#x2013;Slag-Based Geopolymer Materials for 3D Printing. Materials. 2024;17:2992. doi: 10.3390/ma17122992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17122992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11205839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38930361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oggeri C., Fenoglio T.M., Vinai R. Tunnel spoil classification and applicability of lime addition in weak formations for muck reuse. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2014;44:97&#x2013;107. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2014.07.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2014.07.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H., Joshi P., Lau C., Ng K. Novel application of sustainable coal-derived char in cement soil stabilization. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;414:134960. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.134960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.134960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuncdemir H., Bilgin N., Copur H., Balci C. Control of rock cutting efficiency by muck size. Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci. 2008;45:278&#x2013;288. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrmms.2007.04.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2007.04.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Y., Xi X., Liu H., Du C., Lu H. A review: Enhanced performance of recycled cement and CO2 emission reduction effects through thermal activation and nanosilica incorporation. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;422:135763. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C., Liu J., Zhang S., Kong X. Mechanical properties of polymer modified mortars using polymer latexes with varied glass transition temperature and surface charges. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2024;150:105573. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2024.105573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2024.105573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basquiroto de Souza F., Kai D., Pang S.D. Nacre-inspired geopolymer cement composite with high flexural strength. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2024;152:105683. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2024.105683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2024.105683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C., Liu H., Zhang Y., Gu G., Hu J. Micro-assessment of heavy metal immobilization within alkali-activated copper tailings-slag geopolymer. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2024;149:105510. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2024.105510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2024.105510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou H., Li H., Wang Z., Yan D., Wang W., Zhang G., Cheng Z., Sun S., Wang M. Experimental investigation on the anti-detonation performance of composite structure containing foam geopolymer backfill material. Defence Technol. 2024;43:304&#x2013;318. doi: 10.1016/j.dt.2024.08.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dt.2024.08.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R., Li F., Zhou S., Hou Y. Carbon nanofiber dispersion in alkali solution and its reinforcement of alkali-activated volcanic ash-based geopolymers. J. Clean. Prod. 2023;405:137021. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.137021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.137021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maaze M.R., Shrivastava S. Development of framework in the selection and reuse of concrete waste and brick waste powder as pozzolanic material in cement concrete application using analytical hierarchy process technique. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;393:132056. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao L., Wang C., Guo C., Ma X., Li Z., Du X., Jiang W. Properties of Low-Exothermic polymer grouting materials and its application on highway. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;408:133771. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C., Shen S.-L., Hou D.-W., Liao S.-M., Yuan D.-J. Material properties of the seal gasket for shield tunnels: A review. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;191:877&#x2013;890. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.10.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.10.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Test Method of Cement Mortar Strength (ISO Method) Standards Press of China; Beijing, China: 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Common Portland Cement. Standards Press of China; Beijing, China: 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanda R.P., Priya N., Kumar A. Enhancement of strength of soft soil utilizing construction and demolition wastes reinforced with Recron-3s fibres. J. Clean. Prod. 2025;505:145442. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.145442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2025.145442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J., Zhang M., Lu J., Wang K., Yang F., Chen S., Xu F. The Influence Mechanism of Molar Ratio on the Performance of Phosphogypsum-Modified Geopolymer Material. Coatings. 2023;13:2070. doi: 10.3390/coatings13122070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/coatings13122070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perumal P., Niu H., Kiventer&#xe4; J., Kinnunen P., Illikainen M. Upcycling of mechanically treated silicate mine tailings as alkali activated binders. Miner. Eng. 2020;158:106587. doi: 10.1016/j.mineng.2020.106587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mineng.2020.106587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeyaprakash R.K.R., Surehali S., Simon A., Han T., Kumar A., Neithalath N. Early-age reactivity and strength development in high volume mine tailings-based alkali activated binders and their application potential. Miner. Eng. 2024;213:108759. doi: 10.1016/j.mineng.2024.108759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mineng.2024.108759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cacciuttolo C., Atencio E. An Alternative Technology to Obtain Dewatered Mine Tailings: Safe and Control Environmental Management of Filtered and Thickened Copper Mine Tailings in Chile. Minerals. 2022;12:1334. doi: 10.3390/min12101334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min12101334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao N., Ding J., Wan X., Gao M., Xue C. Mechanical properties and micro-mechanism of improved shield tunnel muck with phosphogypsum and lime. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;411:134437. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taqa A.A., Al-Ansari M., Taha R., Senouci A., Al-Marwani H.A., Al-Zubi G.M., Mohsen M.O. Characterization of TBM Muck for Construction Applications. Appl. Sci. 2021;11:8623. doi: 10.3390/app11188623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app11188623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo X., Huang L., Yan L., Li Y., Wei L., Chen Z., Qu Y. Preparation of geopolymers from thermally activated lithium slag: Activity enhancement and microstructure. J. Build. Eng. 2024;88:109256. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q., Cui M., Li X., Wang J., Wang Z., Li L., Lyu X. Alkali-hydrothermal activation of mine tailings to prepare one-part geopolymer: Activation mechanism, workability, strength, and hydration reaction. Ceram. Int. 2022;48:30407&#x2013;30417. doi: 10.1016/j.ceramint.2022.06.318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceramint.2022.06.318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maruyama I., Meawad A., Kondo T., Sawada S., Halodova P., Fedorikova A., Ohkubo T., Murakami K., Igari T., Rodriguez E.T., et al. Radiation-induced alteration of sandstone concrete aggregate. J. Nucl. Mater. 2023;583:154547. doi: 10.1016/j.jnucmat.2023.154547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnucmat.2023.154547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duhme R., Rasanavaneethan R., Pakianathan L., Herud A. Theoretical basis of slurry shield excavation management systems. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2016;57:211&#x2013;224. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2016.01.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2016.01.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naqi A., Otsubo M., Kuwano R., Nagatani H., Kawano K., Liu W. Influence of length and configurations of stirring rods on the mixing of cohesionless granular particles in earth pressure balance shields. Powder Technol. 2025;458:120963. doi: 10.1016/j.powtec.2025.120963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.powtec.2025.120963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y., Yin S., Li K., Han B., Zhang B. Formation mechanism and thermal decomposition properties of hydration products of superfine tailings cemented paste backfill. Arab. J. Chem. 2023;16:104977. doi: 10.1016/j.arabjc.2023.104977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arabjc.2023.104977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C., Zhang N., Zhang J., Song S., Zhang Y. C-A-S-H Gel and Pore Structure Characteristics of Alkali-Activated Red Mud&#x2013;Iron Tailings Cementitious Mortar. Materials. 2022;15:112. doi: 10.3390/ma15010112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15010112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8746001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35009257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad M.R., Medepalli S., Wang T., Dai J.-G., Zheng Y., Ishida T. Effect of alkali-hydroxide on hydration kinetics and microstructure of high-volume fly ash blended cement pastes. Cem. Concr. Res. 2024;185:107641. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2024.107641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2024.107641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qing L., Shaokang S., Zhen J., Junxiang W., Xianjun L. Effect of CaO on hydration properties of one-part alkali-activated material prepared from tailings through alkaline hydrothermal activation. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;308:124931. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jallow A., Ou C.-Y., Lim A. Three-dimensional numerical study of long-term settlement induced in shield tunneling. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2019;88:221&#x2013;236. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2019.02.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2019.02.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughn J.S., Marple M.A.T., Mason H.E. Mechanochemical formation of highly stable amorphous calcium carbonate in calcium silicates: Potential long-term storage of CO2 in cement. Cem. Concr. Res. 2024;176:107413. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2023.107413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2023.107413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu X., Jiang Y., Zhao Y., Xu Z., Shen M., Zhong X. Superimposed hydration exothermic model of cement slurry considering different reaction rates of various active substances. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;372:130783. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.130783.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.130783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baltakys K., Dambrauskas T., Rubinaite D., Siauciunas R., Grineviciene A. Formation and hydration of eco-friendly cement using industrial wastes as raw materials. Sci. Rep. 2021;11:14742. doi: 10.1038/s41598-021-94148-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-94148-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8292434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34285281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q., Li X., Cui M., Wang J., Lyu X. Preparation of eco-friendly one-part geopolymers from gold mine tailings by alkaline hydrothermal activation. J. Clean. Prod. 2021;298:126806. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.126806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.126806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouyang S., Huang Y., Zhou N., Li J., Gao H., Guo Y. Experiment on hydration exothermic characteristics and hydration mechanism of sand-based cemented paste backfill materials. Constr. Build. Mater. 2022;318:125870. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.125870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.125870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballim Y., Graham P.C. The effects of supplementary cementing materials in modifying the heat of hydration of concrete. Mater. Struct. 2009;42:803&#x2013;811. doi: 10.1617/s11527-008-9425-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1617/s11527-008-9425-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>