<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39410492</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>19</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Compressive Strength and Chloride Ion Penetration Resistance of GGBFS-Based Alkali-Activated Composites Containing Ferronickel Slag Aggregates.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4922</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma17194922</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Various studies have reported the use of alkali-activated composites to enable sustainable development in the construction industry as these composites eliminate the need for cement. However, few studies have used ferronickel slag aggregates (FSAs) as an aggregate material for alkali-activated composites. Alkali-activated composites are environmentally friendly and sustainable construction materials that can reduce carbon dioxide emissions from cement production, which accounts for 7% of global carbon emissions. In the construction industry, various research was conducted to improve the performance of alkali-activated composites, such as changing the binder, alkali activator, or aggregate. However, research on the application of ferronickel slag aggregate as an aggregate in alkali-activated composites is still insufficient. In addition, the effect of ferronickel slag aggregate on the performance of alkali-activated composites when using calcium-based or sodium-based alkali activators has not been reported yet. Thus, this study prepared ground granulated blast-furnace slag-based alkali-activated composites with 0, 10, 20, and 30% FSA as natural fine aggregate substitutes. Then, the fluidity, micro-hydration heat, compressive strength properties, and resistance to chloride ion penetration of the alkali-activated composite were evaluated. The test results showed that the maximum temperature of the CF10, CF20, and CF30 samples with FSA was 35.4-36.4 &#xb0;C, which is 3.8-6.7% higher than that of the CF00 sample. The 7 d compressive strength of the sample prepared with CaO was higher than that of the sample prepared with Na<sub>2</sub>SiO<sub>3</sub>. Nevertheless, the 28 d compressive strength of the NF20 sample with Na<sub>2</sub>SiO<sub>3</sub> and 20% FSA was the highest, with a value of approximately 55.0 MPa. After 7 d, the total charge passing through the sample with Na<sub>2</sub>SiO<sub>3</sub> was approximately 1.79-2.24 times higher than that of the sample with CaO. Moreover, the total charge decreased with increasing FSA content.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Jae-In</ForeName><Initials>JI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Architectural Engineering, Wonkwang University, 460 Iksan-daero, Iksan 54538, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Chae-Young</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Architectural Engineering, Wonkwang University, 460 Iksan-daero, Iksan 54538, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoon</LastName><ForeName>Joo-Ho</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Architectural Engineering, Wonkwang University, 460 Iksan-daero, Iksan 54538, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Se-Jin</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2142-3745</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Architectural Engineering, Wonkwang University, 460 Iksan-daero, Iksan 54538, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>RS-2024-00405537</GrantID><Agency>National Research Foundation of Korea</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">alkali-activated composites</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chloride ion penetrability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">compressive strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ferronickel slag aggregate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mortar flow</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39410492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11477681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17194922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma17194922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Almutari A.L.A., Tayeh B.A., Adesina A., Isleem H.F., Zeyad A.M. Potential applications of geopolymer concrete in construction: A review. Case. Stud. Constr. Mater. 2021;15:E00733. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma C.K., Awang A.Z., Omar W. Structural and material performance of geopolymer concrete: A review. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;186:90&#x2013;102. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.07.111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.07.111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ken P.W., Ramli M., Ban C.C. An overview on the influence of various factors on the properties of geopolymer concrete derived from industrial by-products. Constr. Build. Mater. 2015;77:370&#x2013;395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amran M., Fakih A.A., Fediuk R., Hruna S., Azevedo A., Vatian N. Long-term durability properties of geopolymer concrete: An in-depth review. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2021;15:e00661. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhawat M., Ashour A., Yildirim G., Alemir A., Sahamaran M. Properties of geopolymers sourced from construction and demolition waste: A review. J. Build. Eng. 2022;50:104104. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jwaida Z., Dulaimi A., Mashaan N., Mydin M.D.O. Gropolymers: The green alternative to traditional materials of engineering applications. Infrastructures. 2023;8:98. doi: 10.3390/infrastructures8060098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/infrastructures8060098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H.Y., Qiu G.H., Kodur V., Yuan Z.S. Spalling behavior of metakaolin-fly ash based geopolymer concrete under elevated temperature exposure. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2020;106:103483. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2019.103483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2019.103483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun K., Peng X., Chu S.H., Wang S., Zeng L., Ji G. Utilization of BOF steel aggregate in metakaolin-based geopolymer. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;300:124024. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prochon P., Zhao Z., Courard L., Piotrowski T., Michel F., Garbacz A. Influence of activators on mechanical properties of modified fly ash based geopolymer mortars. Materials. 2020;13:1033. doi: 10.3390/ma13051033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma13051033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7084247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32106414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A., Bhadauria S.S., Thakare A.A., Kumar A., Mudgal M., Chaudhary S. Durability assessment of mechanochemically activated geopolymer concrete with a low molarity alkali solution. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2024;20:e02715. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha T.D.S., Dias D.P., Franca F.C., Guerra R.R.D.S., Marques L.R.D.C.D.O. Metakaolin-based geopolymer mortars with different alkaline activators (Na+ and K+) Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;178:453&#x2013;461. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.05.172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.05.172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makul N., Fediuk R., Amran M., Zeyad A.M., Klyuev S., Chulkova I., Ozbakkaloglu T., Vatin N., Karelina M., Azevedo A. Design strategy for recycled aggregate concrete: A review of status and future perspectives. Crystals. 2021;11:695. doi: 10.3390/cryst11060695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cryst11060695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan M.S.H., Castel A., Akbarnezhad A., Foster S.J., Smith M. Utilisation of steel furnace slag coarse aggregate in a low calcium fly ash geopolymer concrete. Cem. Concr. Res. 2016;89:220&#x2013;229. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2016.09.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2016.09.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J.I., Choi S.J. Effect of replacement ratio of ferronickel slag aggregate on characteristics of cementitious mortars at different curing temperatures. Case. Stud. Constr. Mater. 2023;18:e01882. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e01882.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e01882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saha A.K., Sarker P.K. Sustainable use of ferronickel slag fine aggregate and fly ash in structural concrete: Mechanical properties and leaching study. J. Clean. Prod. 2017;162:438&#x2013;448. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2017.06.035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2017.06.035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao J., Zheng R., Yu Z., Zhang P., Song Q., Xu J., Gao S. Freeze-thaw resistance of recycled aggregate concrete incorporating ferronickel slag as fine aggregate. Constr. Build. Mater. 2022;356:129178. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yum W.S., Yu J., Jeon D., Song H., Sim S., Kim D.H., Oh J.E. Mechanical and Durability properties of Cementless Concretes Made Using Three Types of CaO-Activated GGBFS Binders. Materials. 2022;15:271. doi: 10.3390/ma15010271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15010271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8745988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35009417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Testing Method for Compressive Strength of Hydraulic Cement Mortars. Korean Standards &amp; Certification Information Center; Seoul, Republic of Korea: 2007. 5p Korea Industrial Standards.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Practice for Evaluation Early Hydration of Hydraulic Cementitious Mixtures Using Thermal Measurements. American Society for Testing and Materials; West Conshohocken, PA, USA: 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Test Method for Tensile Splitting Strength of Concrete. Korean Standards &amp; Certification Information Center; Seoul, Republic of Korea: 2011. Korea Industrial Standards.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Test Method for Electrical Indication of Concrete&#x2019;s Ability to Resist Chloride Ion Penetration. American Society for Testing and Materials; West Conshohocken, PA, USA: 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu H., Xiao J., Liang C., Ma Z. Properties of Cementitious Materials with Recycled Aggregate and Powder Both Clay Brick Waste. Buildings. 2021;11:119. doi: 10.3390/buildings11030119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings11030119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee C.H., Kim S.C., Kim Y.J., Kim S.K., Hwang J.P., Park J.W. Experimental Study on Thermal Conductivity of Concrete Using Ferronickel Slag Powder. KSCE J. Civ. Eng. 2020;24:219&#x2013;227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashad A.M. A Concise on the Effect of Calcium Oxide on the Properties of Alkali-Activated Materials: A Manual for Civil Engineers. Int. J. Concr. Struct. Mater. 2023;17:72. doi: 10.1186/s40069-023-00635-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40069-023-00635-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma C., Liu H. Delaying the hydration of Portland cement by sodium silicate: Setting time and retarding mechanism. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;205:543&#x2013;548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shilat F.A., Ganachari S.V., Patil V.B., Khan T.M.Y., Javer S., Baig R.U. Optimization of Alkaline Activator on the Strength Properties of Geopolymer Concrete. Polymers. 2022;14:2434. doi: 10.3390/polym14122434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym14122434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9230036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35746009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaowalt T., Sudsaynate W., Horplibulsuk S., CHinkulkijiniwat A., Arulrajah A., Horpibulsuk J. Mechanical Properties of Fly Ash-Asphalt Emulsion Geopolymer Stabilized Crushed Rock for Sustainable Pavement Base. J. Mater. Civ. Eng. 2021;33:04021220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R., Zhang J., Liu Z., Li Y., Xu C. Effect of Cao and MgO additives on the compressive strength of pellets: Exploration on the decisive stage during induration. Powder Technol. 2021;390:496&#x2013;503. doi: 10.1016/j.powtec.2021.06.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.powtec.2021.06.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koohestani B., Mokhtari P., Yilmaz E., Mahdipour F., Darban A.K. Geopolymerization mechanism of binder-free mine tailings by sodium silicate. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;268:121217. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouyang X., Ma Y., Liu Z., Laing J., Ye G. Effect of Sodium Silicate Modulus and Slag Content on Fresh and Hardened Properties of Alkali-Activated Fly Ash/Slag. Minerals. 2020;10:15. doi: 10.3390/min10010015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min10010015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J., Feng J., Chen Z. Effect of ferronickel slag as fine aggregate on properties of concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;206:201&#x2013;209. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.01.187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.01.187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi M.G., Son J.S., Cho B.S., Lee J.Y. Strength Evaluation of Concrete Containing Ferronickel Slag Aggregate. J. Korean Soc. Agric. Eng. 2022;64:65&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuruzzaman M.D., Casimiro J.O.C., Sarker P.K. Fresh and hardened properties of high strength self-compacting concrete using by-product ferronickel slag fine aggregate. J. Build. Eng. 2020;32:101686. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed O. Durability and Compressive Strength of High Cement Replacement Ratio Self-Consolidating Concrete. Buildings. 2018;8:153. doi: 10.3390/buildings8110153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings8110153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laxmi G., Patil S., Hossiney N., Thejas H.K. Effect of hooked end steel fibers on strength and durability properties of ambient cured geopolymer concrete. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2023;18:e02122. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gang R., Garg R., Eddy N.O., Khan A.H., Alomayri T., Berwal P. Mechanical strength and durability analysis of mortars prepared with fly ash and nano-metakaolin. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2023;18:e01796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen Q.D., Castel A., Kim T.H., Khan M.S.H. Performance of fly ash concrete with ferronickel slag fine aggregate against alkali-silica reaction and chloride diffusion. Cem. Concr. Res. 2021;139:106265. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2020.106265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2020.106265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro M.S., Goncalver A.F., Branco F.A.B. Styrene-butadiene polymer action of compressive strength and tensile strengths of cement mortars. Mater. Struct. 2008;4:1263&#x2013;1273. doi: 10.1617/s11527-007-9324-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1617/s11527-007-9324-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L., Yang J., Li H. Quantifying the microstructure and phase assemblage of alkali-activated fly ash/slag materials by EDS mapping analysis. Mater. Des. 2023;234:112320. doi: 10.1016/j.matdes.2023.112320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2023.112320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moshen A., Kohail M., Alharbi Y.R., Abadel A., Soliman A.M., Ramadan M. Bio-mechanical efficacy for slag/fly ash-based geopolymer mingled with mesoporous NiO. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2023;19:e02283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Shan Y., Ni P., Li Y., Zhou J. Mechanics, durability, and microstructure analysis of marine soil stabilized by an eco-friendly calcium carbide residue-activated coal gangue geopolymer. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2024;20:e02687. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian Y., Xu C., Yang T., Yu H., Zhou G., Zhuang P. Alkali-silica reaction of ferronickel slag fine aggregate in Portland cement and alkali-activated slag mortars: Pessimum effect investigation. J. Build. Eng. 2024;89:109349. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>