<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40333360</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1944-8252</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>20</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Appl Mater Interfaces</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ionic Associations and Hydration in the Electrical Double Layer of Water-in-Salt Electrolytes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>29515</StartPage><EndPage>29534</EndPage><MedlinePgn>29515-29534</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsami.5c01781</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Water-in-Salt-Electrolytes (WiSEs) are an exciting class of concentrated electrolytes finding applications in energy storage devices because of their expanded electrochemical stability window, good conductivity and cation transference number, and fire-extinguishing properties. These distinct properties are thought to originate from the presence of an anion-dominated ionic network and interpenetrating water channels for cation transport, which indicates that associations in WiSEs are crucial to understanding their properties. Currently, associations have mainly been investigated in the bulk, while little attention has been given to the electrolyte structure near electrified interfaces. Here, we develop a theory for the electrical double layer (EDL) of WiSEs, where we consistently account for the thermoreversible associations of species into Cayley tree aggregates. The theory predicts an asymmetric structure of the EDL. At negative voltages, hydrated Li<sup>+</sup> dominates, and cluster aggregation is initially slightly enhanced before disintegration at larger voltages. At positive voltages, when compared to the bulk, clusters are strictly diminished. Performing atomistic molecular dynamics (MD) simulations of the EDL of WiSE provides EDL data for validation and bulk data for parametrization of our theory. Validating the predictions of our theory against MD showed good qualitative agreement. Furthermore, we performed electrochemical impedance measurements to determine the differential capacitance of the studied LiTFSI WiSE and also found reasonable agreement with our theory. Overall, the developed approach can be used to investigate ionic aggregation and solvation effects in the EDL, which, among other properties, can be used to understand the precursors for solid-electrolyte interphase formation.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Markiewitz</LastName><ForeName>Daniel M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9148-0668</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Engineering, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Massachusetts 02139, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goodwin</LastName><ForeName>Zachary A H</ForeName><Initials>ZAH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2760-4499</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>John A. Paulson School of Engineering and Applied Sciences, Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts 02138, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Materials, University of Oxford, Parks Road, Oxford OX1 3PH, U.K.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Qianlu</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, The Grainger College of Engineering, University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, Urbana, Illinois 61801, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McEldrew</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Engineering, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Massachusetts 02139, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Espinosa-Marzal</LastName><ForeName>Rosa M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3442-2511</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, The Grainger College of Engineering, University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, Urbana, Illinois 61801, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Materials Science and Engineering, The Grainger College of Engineering, University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, Urbana, Illinois 61801, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bazant</LastName><ForeName>Martin Z</ForeName><Initials>MZ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8200-4501</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Engineering, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Massachusetts 02139, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Massachusetts 02139, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Appl Mater Interfaces</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101504991</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1944-8244</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chemical thermodynamics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">concentrated electrolytes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electric double layer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interfacial properties</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">water-in-salt electrolytes</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40333360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12100604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.5c01781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Suo L., Hu Y.-S., Li H., Armand M., Chen L.. A new class of Solvent-in-Salt electrolyte for high-energy rechargeable metallic lithium batteries. Nat. Commun. 2013;4:1481. doi: 10.1038/ncomms2513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms2513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23403582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suo L., Borodin O., Gao T., Olguin M., Ho J., Fan X., Luo C., Wang C., Xu K.. &#x201c;Water-in-salt&#x201d; electrolyte enables high-voltage aqueous lithium-ion chemistries. Science. 2015;350:938&#x2013;943. doi: 10.1126/science.aab1595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aab1595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26586759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Yamada Y., Sodeyama K., Chiang C. H., Tateyama Y., Yamada A.. Superconcentrated electrolytes for a high-voltage lithium-ion battery. Nat. Commun. 2016;7:12032. doi: 10.1038/ncomms12032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms12032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4931331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27354162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F., Borodin O., Gao T., Fan X., Sun W., Han F., Faraone A., Dura J. A., Xu K., Wang C.. Highly reversible zinc metal anode for aqueous batteries. Nat. Mater. 2018;17:543&#x2013;549. doi: 10.1038/s41563-018-0063-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41563-018-0063-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29662160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada Y., Usui K., Sodeyama K., Ko S., Tateyama Y., Yamada A.. Hydrate-melt electrolytes for high-energy-density aqueous batteries. Nat. Energy. 2016;1:16129. doi: 10.1038/nenergy.2016.129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nenergy.2016.129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suo L., Borodin O., Wang Y., Rong X., Sun W., Fan X., Xu S., Schroeder M. A., Cresce A. V., Wang F.. &#x201c;Water-in-salt&#x201d; electrolyte makes aqueous sodium-ion battery safe, green, and long-lasting. Adv. Energy Mater. 2017;7:1701189. doi: 10.1002/aenm.201701189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aenm.201701189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dou Q., Lei S., Wang D.-W., Zhang Q., Xiao D., Guo H., Wang A., Yang H., Li Y., Shi S., Yan X.. Safe and high-rate supercapacitors based on an &#x201c;acetonitrile/water in salt&#x201d; hybrid electrolyte. Energy Environ. Sci. 2018;11:3212&#x2013;3219. doi: 10.1039/C8EE01040D.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C8EE01040D</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borodin O., Self J., Persson K. A., Wang C., Xu K.. Uncharted Waters: Super-Concentrated Electrolytes. Joule. 2020;4:69&#x2013;100. doi: 10.1016/j.joule.2019.12.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2019.12.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayah S., Ghosh A., Baazizi M., Amine R., Dahbi M., Amine Y., Ghamouss F., Amine K.. How do super concentrated electrolytes push the Li-ion batteries and supercapacitors beyond their thermodynamic and electrochemical limits? Nano Energy. 2022;98:107336. doi: 10.1016/j.nanoen.2022.107336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nanoen.2022.107336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vatamanu J., Borodin O.. Ramifications of water-in-salt interfacial structure at charged electrodes for electrolyte electrochemical stability. J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2017;8:4362&#x2013;4367. doi: 10.1021/acs.jpclett.7b01879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpclett.7b01879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28846430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEldrew M., Goodwin Z. A., Kornyshev A. A., Bazant M. Z.. Theory of the double layer in water-in-salt electrolytes. journal of physical chemistry letters. 2018;9:5840&#x2013;5846. doi: 10.1021/acs.jpclett.8b02543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpclett.8b02543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30229648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEldrew M., Goodwin Z. A., Bi S., Kornyshev A., Bazant M. Z.. Ion Clusters and Networks in Water-in-Salt Electrolytes. J. Electrochem. Soc. 2021;168:050514. doi: 10.1149/1945-7111/abf975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1149/1945-7111/abf975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borodin O., Suo L., Gobet M., Ren X., Wang F., Faraone A., Peng J., Olguin M., Schroeder M., Ding M. S.. et al. Liquid structure with nano-heterogeneity promotes cationic transport in concentrated electrolytes. ACS Nano. 2017;11:10462&#x2013;10471. doi: 10.1021/acsnano.7b05664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsnano.7b05664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29016112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng J., Tan G., Shan P., Liu T., Hu J., Feng Y., Yang L., Zhang M., Chen Z., Lin Y.. et al. Understanding thermodynamic and kinetic contributions in expanding the stability window of aqueous electrolytes. Chem. 2018;4:2872&#x2013;2882. doi: 10.1016/j.chempr.2018.09.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chempr.2018.09.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim J., Park K., Lee H., Kim J., Kwak K., Cho M.. Nanometric water channels in water-in-salt lithium ion battery electrolyte. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2018;140:15661&#x2013;15667. doi: 10.1021/jacs.8b07696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.8b07696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30358996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson R., &#xc5;r&#xe9;n F., Franco A. A., Johansson P.. Ion Transport Mechanisms via Time-Dependent Local Structure and Dynamics in Highly Concentrated Electrolytes. J. Electrochem. Soc. 2020;167:140537. doi: 10.1149/1945-7111/abc657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1149/1945-7111/abc657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z., Curtiss L. A., Winans R. E., Zhang Y., Li T., Cheng L.. Asymmetric Composition of Ionic Aggregates and the Origin of High Correlated Transference Number in Water-in-Salt Electrolytes. J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2020;11:1276&#x2013;1281. doi: 10.1021/acs.jpclett.9b03495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpclett.9b03495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31951143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R., Han M., Ta K., Madsen K. E., Chen X., Zhang X., Espinosa-Marzal R. M., Gewirth A. A.. Potential-dependent layering in the electrochemical double layer of water-in-salt electrolytes. ACS Applied Energy Materials. 2020;3:8086&#x2013;8094. doi: 10.1021/acsaem.0c01534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsaem.0c01534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han M., Zhang R., Gewirth A. A., Espinosa-Marzal R. M.. Nanoheterogeneity of LiTFSI Solutions Transitions Close to a Surface and with Concentration. Nano Lett. 2021;21:2304&#x2013;2309. doi: 10.1021/acs.nanolett.1c00167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.nanolett.1c00167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33616411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ichii T., Ichikawa S., Yamada Y., Murata M., Utsunomiya T., Sugimura H.. Solvation structure on water-in-salt/mica interfaces and its molality dependence investigated by atomic force microscopy. Jpn. J. Appl. Phys. 2020;59:SN1003. doi: 10.35848/1347-4065/ab80a6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.35848/1347-4065/ab80a6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C.-Y., Chen M., Liu S., Lu X., Meng J., Yan J., Abru&#xf1;a H. D., Feng G., Lian T.. Unconventional interfacial water structure of highly concentrated aqueous electrolytes at negative electrode polarizations. Nat. Commun. 2022;13:5330. doi: 10.1038/s41467-022-33129-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-022-33129-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9464189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36088353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazant M. Z., Storey B. D., Kornyshev A. A.. Double Layer in Ionic Liquids: Overscreening versus Crowding. Phys. Rev. Lett. 2011;106:046102. doi: 10.1103/PhysRevLett.106.046102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.106.046102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21405339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEldrew M., Goodwin Z. A., Bi S., Bazant M. Z., Kornyshev A. A.. Theory of Ion Aggregation and Gelation in Super-Concentrated Electrolytes. J. Chem. Phys. 2020;152:234506. doi: 10.1063/5.0006197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/5.0006197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32571055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEldrew M., Goodwin Z. A. H., Zhao H., Bazant M. Z., Kornyshev A. A.. Correlated Ion Transport and the Gel Phase in Room Temperature Ionic Liquids. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2021;125:2677&#x2013;2689. doi: 10.1021/acs.jpcb.0c09050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcb.0c09050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33689352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEldrew M., Goodwin Z. A. H., Molinari N., Kozinsky B., Kornyshev A. A., Bazant M. Z.. Salt-in-ionic-liquid electrolytes: Ion network formation and negative effective charges of alkali metal cations. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2021;125:13752&#x2013;13766. doi: 10.1021/acs.jpcb.1c05546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcb.1c05546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34902256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodwin Z. A. H., McEldrew M., Kozinsky B., Bazant M. Z.. Theory of Cation Solvation and Ionic Association in Nonaqueous Solvent Mixtures. PRX Energy. 2023;2:013007. doi: 10.1103/PRXEnergy.2.013007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PRXEnergy.2.013007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodwin Z. A., McEldrew M., de Souza J. P., Bazant M. Z., Kornyshev A. A.. Gelation, Clustering and Crowding in the Electrical Double Layer of Ionic Liquids. J. Chem. Phys. 2022;157:094106. doi: 10.1063/5.0097055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/5.0097055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36075727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodwin Z. A., Kornyshev A. A.. Cracking Ion Pairs in the Electrical Double Layer of Ionic Liquids. Electrochim. Acta. 2022;434:141163. doi: 10.1016/j.electacta.2022.141163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2022.141163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markiewitz D. M., Goodwin Z. A., McEldrew M., de Souza J. P., Zhang X., Espinosa-Marzal R. M., Bazant M. Z.. Electric field induced associations in the double layer of salt-in-ionic-liquid electrolytes. Faraday Discuss. 2024:365&#x2013;384. doi: 10.1039/D4FD00021H.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D4FD00021H</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39176453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kornyshev A. A.. Double-Layer in Ionic Liquids: Paradigm Change? J. Phys. Chem. B. 2007;111:5545&#x2013;5557. doi: 10.1021/jp067857o.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp067857o</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17469864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazant M. Z., Kilic M. S., Storey B. D., Ajdari A.. Towards an understanding of induced-charge electrokinetics at large applied voltages in concentrated solutions. Advances in colloid and interface science. 2009;152:48&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1016/j.cis.2009.10.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cis.2009.10.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19879552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrashkin A., Andelman D., Orland H.. Dipolar Poisson-Boltzmann equation: ions and dipoles close to charge interfaces. Phys. Rev. Lett. 2007;99:077801. doi: 10.1103/PhysRevLett.99.077801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.99.077801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17930925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gongadze E., van Rienen U., Kralj-Igli&#x10d; V., Igli&#x10d; A.. Spatial variation of permittivity of an electrolyte solution in contact with a charged metal surface: A mini review. Computer methods in biomechanics and biomedical engineering. 2013;16:463&#x2013;480. doi: 10.1080/10255842.2011.624769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10255842.2011.624769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3664910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22263808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Souza J. P., Goodwin Z. A., McEldrew M., Kornyshev A. A., Bazant M. Z.. Interfacial layering in the electrical double layer of ionic liquids. Phys. Rev. Lett. 2020;125:116001. doi: 10.1103/PhysRevLett.125.116001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.125.116001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32975984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M., Goodwin Z. A. H., Feng G., Kornyshev A. A.. On the temperature dependence of the double layer capacitance of ionic liquids. J. Electroanal. Chem. 2018;819:347&#x2013;358. doi: 10.1016/j.jelechem.2017.11.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jelechem.2017.11.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Ye T., Chen M., Goodwin Z. A., Feng G., Huang J., Kornyshev A. A.. Enforced Freedom: Electric-Field-Induced Declustering of Ionic-Liquid Ions in the Electrical Double Layer. Energy Environ. Mater. 2020;3:414&#x2013;420. doi: 10.1002/eem2.12107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eem2.12107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodwin Z. A., Feng G., Kornyshev A. A.. Mean-field theory of electrical double layer in ionic liquids with account of short-range correlations. Electrochim. Acta. 2017;225:190&#x2013;197. doi: 10.1016/j.electacta.2016.12.092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2016.12.092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jitvisate M., Seddon J. R. T.. Direct Measurement of the Differential Capacitance of Solvent-Free and Dilute Ionic Liquids. J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2018;9:26&#x2013;131. doi: 10.1021/acs.jpclett.7b02946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpclett.7b02946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6150683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29256620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjellander R., Mar&#x10d;elja S.. Interaction of charged surfaces in electrolyte solutions. Chemical physics letters. 1986;127:402&#x2013;407. doi: 10.1016/0009-2614(86)80304-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0009-2614(86)80304-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avni Y., Adar R. M., Andelman D.. Charge oscillations in ionic liquids: A microscopic cluster model. Phys. Rev. E. 2020;101:010601. doi: 10.1103/PhysRevE.101.010601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevE.101.010601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32069538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adar R. M., Safran S. A., Diamant H., Andelman D.. Screening length for finite-size ions in concentrated electrolytes. Phys. Rev. E. 2019;100:042615. doi: 10.1103/PhysRevE.100.042615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevE.100.042615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31771021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy A., McEldrew M., Bazant M. Z.. Spin-glass charge ordering in ionic liquids. Physical Review Materials. 2019;3:055606. doi: 10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.3.055606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.3.055606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiemenz, P. C. ; Rajagopalan, R. . Principles of Colloid and Surface Chemistry, revised and expanded; CRC Press, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu K. T., Bazant M. Z.. Surface conservation laws at microscopically diffuse interfaces. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2007;315:319&#x2013;329. doi: 10.1016/j.jcis.2007.06.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2007.06.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17610886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason P., Ansell S., Neilson G., Rempe S.. Neutron scattering studies of the hydration structure of Li+ J. Phys. Chem. B. 2015;119:2003&#x2013;2009. doi: 10.1021/jp511508n.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp511508n</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25559086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanwell M. D., Curtis D. E., Lonie D. C., Vandermeersch T., Zurek E., Hutchison G. R.. Avogadro: an advanced semantic chemical editor, visualization, and analysis platform. J. Cheminf. 2012;4:17. doi: 10.1186/1758-2946-4-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1758-2946-4-17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3542060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22889332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kilic M. S., Bazant M. Z., Ajdari A.. Steric effects in the dynamics of electrolytes at large applied voltages. I. Double-layer charging. Physical review E. 2007;75:021502. doi: 10.1103/PhysRevE.75.021502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevE.75.021502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17358343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budkov Y. A., Kolesnikov A. L., Goodwin Z. A. H., Kiselev M., Kornyshev A. A.. Theory of Electrosorption of Water from Ionic Liquids. Electrochim. Acta. 2018;284:346&#x2013;354. doi: 10.1016/j.electacta.2018.07.139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.electacta.2018.07.139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Q., Goodwin Z. A., Gopalakrishnan V., Hoane A. G., Han M., Zhang R., Hawthorne N., Batteas J. D., Gewirth A. A., Espinosa-Marzal R. M.. Water in the Electrical Double Layer of Ionic Liquids on Graphene. ACS Nano. 2023;17:9347&#x2013;9360. doi: 10.1021/acsnano.3c01043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsnano.3c01043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10210538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37163519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brug G., van den Eeden A. L., Sluyters-Rehbach M., Sluyters J. H.. The analysis of electrode impedances complicated by the presence of a constant phase element. Journal of electroanalytical chemistry and interfacial electrochemistry. 1984;176:275&#x2013;295. doi: 10.1016/S0022-0728(84)80324-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-0728(84)80324-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoane A. G., Zheng Q., Maldonado N. D., Espinosa-Marzal R. M., Gewirth A. A.. Impact of Multivalent Cations on Interfacial Layering in Water-In-Salt Electrolytes. ACS Applied Energy Materials. 2024;7:5179&#x2013;5192. doi: 10.1021/acsaem.4c00507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsaem.4c00507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Goodwin Z. A., Hoane A. G., Deptula A., Markiewitz D. M., Molinari N., Zheng Q., Li H., McEldrew M., Kozinsky B.. et al. Long-Range Surface Forces in Salt-in-Ionic Liquids. ACS Nano. 2024;18:34007&#x2013;34022. doi: 10.1021/acsnano.4c09355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsnano.4c09355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11656838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39641512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu C.-C., Chiang K.-Y., Dhinojwala A., Bonn M., Hunger J., Nagata Y.. Flipping Water Orientation at the Surface of Water-in-Salt and Salt-in-Water Solutions. J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2024;15:10265&#x2013;10271. doi: 10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11472344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39360956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Q., McDowell M. T., Qi Y.. Effect of the electric double layer (EDL) in multicomponent electrolyte reduction and solid electrolyte interphase (SEI) formation in lithium batteries. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2023;145:2473&#x2013;2484. doi: 10.1021/jacs.2c11807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.2c11807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9896563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36689617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Wald Cresce A., Borodin O., Xu K.. Correlating Li+ solvation sheath structure with interphasial chemistry on graphite. J. Phys. Chem. C. 2012;116:26111&#x2013;26117. doi: 10.1021/jp303610t.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp303610t</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinson M. B., Bazant M. Z.. Theory of SEI formation in rechargeable batteries: capacity fade, accelerated aging and lifetime prediction. J. Electrochem. Soc. 2013;160:A243. doi: 10.1149/2.044302jes.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1149/2.044302jes</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rakov D. A., Chen F., Ferdousi S. A., Li H., Pathirana T., Simonov A. N., Howlett P. C., Atkin R., Forsyth M.. Engineering high-energy-density sodium battery anodes for improved cycling with superconcentrated ionic-liquid electrolytes. Nature materials. 2020;19:1096&#x2013;1101. doi: 10.1038/s41563-020-0673-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41563-020-0673-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32367080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebbie M. A., Valtiner M., Banquy X., Fox E. T., Henderson W. A., Israelachvili J. N.. Ionic liquids behave as dilute electrolyte solutions. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2013;110:9674&#x2013;9679. doi: 10.1073/pnas.1307871110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1307871110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3683794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23716690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espinosa-Marzal R. M., Arcifa A., Rossi A., Spencer N. D.. Microslips to &#x201c;Avalanches&#x201d; in Confined, Molecular Layers of Ionic Liquids. J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2014;5:179&#x2013;184. doi: 10.1021/jz402451v.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jz402451v</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26276199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith A. M., Lee A. A., Perkin S.. The Electrostatic Screening Length in Concentrated Electrolytes Increases with Concentration. J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2016;7:2157&#x2013;2163. doi: 10.1021/acs.jpclett.6b00867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpclett.6b00867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27216986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krucker-Velasquez E., Swan J. W.. Underscreening and hidden ion structures in large scale simulations of concentrated electrolytes. J. Chem. Phys. 2021;155:134903. doi: 10.1063/5.0061230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/5.0061230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34624965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espinosa-Marzal, R. M. ; Goodwin, Z. A. H. ; Zhang, X. ; Zheng, Q. ; Nagarajan, R. ; Espinosa-Marzal, R. M. ; Goodwin, Z. A. ; Zhang, X. ; Zheng, Q. . ;. Colloidal Interactions in Ionic Liquids&#xe5f8;The Electrical Double Layer Inferred from Ion Layering and Aggregation. In One Hundred Years of Colloid Symposia: Looking Back and Looking Forward, 2023; pp 123&#x2013;148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;rtel A., B&#xfc;ltmann M., Coupette F.. Anomalous underscreening in the restricted primitive model. Phys. Rev. Lett. 2023;130:108202. doi: 10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.108202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.130.108202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36962045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S., Cats P., Alotaibi M. B., Ayirala S. C., Yousef A. A., van Roij R., Siretanu I., Mugele F.. Absence of anomalous underscreening in highly concentrated aqueous electrolytes confined between smooth silica surfaces. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2022;622:819&#x2013;827. doi: 10.1016/j.jcis.2022.05.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2022.05.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35561602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeman J., Kondrat S., Holm C.. Bulk ionic screening lengths from extremely large-scale molecular dynamics simulations. Chem. Commun. 2020;56:15635&#x2013;15638. doi: 10.1039/D0CC05023G.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D0CC05023G</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33283802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez-Martinez C. S., Smith A. M., Perkin S.. et al. Underscreening in concentrated electrolytes. Faraday Discuss. 2017;199:239&#x2013;259. doi: 10.1039/C6FD00250A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C6FD00250A</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28466925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leote de Carvalho R., Evans R.. The decay of correlations in ionic fluids. Mol. Phys. 1994;83:619&#x2013;654. doi: 10.1080/00268979400101491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00268979400101491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodwin Z. A. H., de Souza J. P., Bazant M. Z., Kornyshev A. A.. Mean-Field Theory of the Electrical Double Layer in Ionic Liquids. Encyclopedia of Ionic Liquids. 2021:1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1007/978-981-10-6739-6_62-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-10-6739-6_62-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazant M. Z.. Unified quantum theory of electrochemical kinetics by coupled ion&#x2013;electron transfer. Faraday Discuss. 2023;246:60&#x2013;124. doi: 10.1039/D3FD00108C.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D3FD00108C</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37676178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira P. I. C., Sciortino F.. Patchy particles at a hard wall: Orientation-dependent bonding. J. Chem. Phys. 2019;151:174903. doi: 10.1063/1.5124008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.5124008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31703486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>