<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39679902</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2198-3844</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advanced science (Weinheim, Baden-Wurttemberg, Germany)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Sci (Weinh)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>High-Performance Pure Water-Fed Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis with Patterned Membrane via Mechanical Stress and Hydration-Mediated Patterning Technique.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2409563</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2409563</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2409563</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/advs.202409563</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Despite rapid advancements in anion exchange membrane water electrolysis (AEMWE) technology, achieving pure water-fed AEMWE remains critical for system simplification and cost reduction. Under pure water-fed conditions, electrochemical reactions occur solely at active sites connected to ionic networks. This study introduces an eco-friendly patterning technique leveraging membrane swelling properties by applying mechanical stress during dehydration under fixed constraints. The method increases active sites by creating additional hydroxide ion pathways at the membrane-electrode interface, eliminating the need for additional ionomers in the electrode. This innovation facilitates ion conduction via locally shortened pathways. Membrane electrode assemblies (MEAs) with patterned commercial membranes demonstrated significantly improved performance and durability compared to MEAs with conventional catalyst-coated substrates and flat membranes under pure water-fed conditions. The universal applicability of this technique was confirmed using in-house fabricated anion exchange membranes, achieving exceptional current densities of 13.7 A cm<sup>-2</sup> at 2.0 V in 1.0 M potassium hydroxide (KOH) and 2.8 A cm<sup>-2</sup> at 2.0 V in pure water at 60&#xa0;&#xb0;C. Furthermore, the scalability of the technique was demonstrated through successful fabrication and operation of large-area cells. These findings highlight the potential of this patterning method to advance AEMWE technology, enabling practical applications under pure water-fed conditions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Author(s). Advanced Science published by Wiley&#x2010;VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Yeonjae</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, Kookmin University, Seoul, 02707, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Sungjun</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hydrogen Energy Research Center, Korea Research Institute of Chemical Technology (KRICT), Daejeon, 34114, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shin</LastName><ForeName>Yoseph</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, Kookmin University, Seoul, 02707, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shin</LastName><ForeName>Yeram</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hydrogen Energy Research Center, Korea Research Institute of Chemical Technology (KRICT), Daejeon, 34114, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shin</LastName><ForeName>Seongmin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hydrogen Energy Research Center, Korea Research Institute of Chemical Technology (KRICT), Daejeon, 34114, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Sanghyeok</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, Kookmin University, Seoul, 02707, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>So</LastName><ForeName>Minseop</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, Kookmin University, Seoul, 02707, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Tae-Ho</ForeName><Initials>TH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hydrogen Energy Research Center, Korea Research Institute of Chemical Technology (KRICT), Daejeon, 34114, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Sehkyu</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Engineering, Kwangwoon University, Seoul, 01897, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Jang Yong</ForeName><Initials>JY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Engineering, Konkuk University, Seoul, 05029, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jang</LastName><ForeName>Segeun</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8319-8400</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanical Engineering, Kookmin University, Seoul, 02707, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R23XO04</GrantID><Agency>Open R&amp;D program of Korea Electric Power Corporation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>RS-2024-00409675</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Science and ICT</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Sci (Weinh)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101664569</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2198-3844</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anion exchange membrane water electrolysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dehydration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enlarged interfacial area</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patterned membrane</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pure water fed</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39679902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11792040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/advs.202409563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>a) Capurso T., Stefanizzi M., Torresi M., Camporeale S. M., Energy Conversion and Management 2022, 251, 114898;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Shi X. F., Qian Y., Yang S. Y., Acs Sustain. Chem. Eng. 2020, 8, 7097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Gao X. Q., Chen Y. T., Wang Y. J., Zhao L. Y., Zhao X. Y., Du J., Wu H. X., Chen A. B., Nano&#x2010;Micro Lett. 2024, 16, 237;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11226619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38967856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Pham C. V., Escalera&#x2010;L&#xf3;pez D., Mayrhofer K., Cherevko S., Thiele S., Adv. Energy Mater. 2021, 11, 2101998;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) Du N. Y., Roy C., Peach R., Turnbull M., Thiele S., Bock C., Chem. Rev. 2022, 122, 11830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9284563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35442645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Lindquist G. A., Gaitor J. C., Thompson W. L., Brogden V., Noonan K. J. T., Boettcher S. W., Energy Environ. Sci. 2023, 16, 4373;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Lindquist G. A., Boettcher S. W., Electrochem. Soc. Int. 2023, 32, 32;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) Krivina R. A., Lindquist G. A., Beaudoin S. R., Stovall T. N., Thompson W. L., Twight L. P., Marsh D., Grzyb J., Fabrizio K., Hutchison J. E., Boettcher S. W., Adv. Mater. 2022, 34, 2203033;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35790033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>d) Lindquist G. A., Oener S. Z., Krivina R., Motz A. R., Keane A., Capuano C., Ayers K. E., Boettcher S. W., Acs Appl. Mater. Inter. 2021, 13, 51917;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34374278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>e) Xiao J. W., Oliveira A. M., Wang L., Zhao Y., Wang T., Wang J. H., Setzler B. P., Yan Y. S., ACS Catal. 2021, 11, 264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Razmjooei F., Morawietz T., Taghizadeh E., Hadjixenophontos E., Mues L., Gerle M., Wood B. D., Harms C., Gago A. S., Ansar S. A., Friedrich K. A., Joule 2021, 5, 1776.;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Xu Q. C., Zhang L. Y., Zhang J. H., Wang J. Y., Hu Y. J., Jiang H., Li C. Z., Energychem. 2022, 4, 100087.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Wan L., Xu Z., Xu Q., Pang M. B., Lin D. C., Liu J., Wang B. G., Energy Environ. Sci. 2023, 16, 1384;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Xie J. Y., Wang F. L., Zhou Y. A., Dong Y. W., Chai Y. M., Dong B., Nano&#x2010;Micro Lett. 2024, 16, 39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10689691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38032501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D. G., Park E. J., Zhu W. L., Shi Q. R., Zhou Y., Tian H. Y., Lin Y. H., Serov A., Zulevi B., Baca E. D., Fujimoto C., Chung H. T., Kim Y. S., Nat. Energy 2020, 5, 378.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei C., Yang K. C., Wang G. Z., Wang G. W., Lu J. T., Xiao L., Zhuang L., Acs Sustain. Chem. Eng. 2022, 10, 16725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D. G., Matanovic I., Lee A. S., Park E. J., Fujimoto C., Chung H. T., Kim Y. S., Acs Appl. Mater. Inter. 2019, 11, 9696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30811171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Tongsh C., Wu S. Y., Jiao K., Huo W. M., Du Q., Park J. W., Xuan J., Wang H. Z., Brandon N. P., Guiver M. D., Joule 2024, 8, p175;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Zhao C. F., Yuan S., Cheng X. J., Zheng Z. F., Liu J., Yin J. W., Shen S. Y., Yan X. H., Zhang J. L., Energy Ai 2023, 13, 100245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulkarni D., Huynh A., Satjaritanun P., O'Brien M., Shimpalee S., Parkinson D., Shevchenko P., DeCarlo F., Danilovic N., Ayers K. E., Capuano C., Zenyuk I. V., Appl. Catal. B&#x2010;Environ. 2022, 308, 121213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan L., Pang M. B., Le J. F., Xu Z., Zhou H. Y., Xu Q., Wang B. G., Nat. Commun. 2022, 13, 7956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9794718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36575177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Park J. E., Kang S. Y., Oh S. H., Kim J. K., Lim M. S., Ahn C. Y., Cho Y. H., Sung Y. E., Electrochim. Acta 2019, 295, 99;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Hu C., Lee Y. J., Ma Y., Zhang X. H., Jung S. W., Hwang H., Cho H. K., Kim M. G., Yoo S. J., Zhang Q. G., Lee Y. M., Acs Energy Lett. 2024, 9, 1219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Jang S., Kim S., Kim S. M., Choi J., Yeon J., Bang K., Ahn C. Y., Hwang W., Her M., Cho Y. H., Sung Y. E., Choi M., Nano Energy 2018, 43, 149;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Cho H., Kim S. M., Kang Y. S., Kim J., Jang S., Kim M., Park H., Bang J. W., Seo S., Suh K. Y., Sung Y. E., Choi M., Nat. Commun. 2015, 6, 8484;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4598841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26412619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) Jang S., Kang Y. S., Kim D., Park S., Seol C., Lee S., Kim S. M., Yoo S. J., Adv. Mater. 2023, 35, 2204902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36222387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang S., Her M., Kim S., Jang J. H., Chae J. E., Choi J., Choi M., Kim S. M., Kim H. J., Cho Y. H., Sung Y. E., Yoo S. J., Acs Appl. Mater. Inter. 2019, 11, 34805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31469540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Carbone A., Zignani S. C., Gatto I., Pedicini R., Oldani C., Cattaneo A., Arico A. S., Chem. Eng. J. 2023, 455, 140765;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Carbone A., Zignani S. C., Gatto I., Trocino S., Aric&#xf2; A. S., Int. J. Hydrogen Energy 2020, 45, 9285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Wan L., Xu Z., Xu Q., Wang P. C., Wang B. G., Energy Environ. Sci. 2022, 15, 1882;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Holzapfel P., B&#xfc;hler M., Pham C. V., Hegge F., B&#xf6;hm T., McLaughlin D., Breitwieser M., Thiele S., Electrochem. Commun. 2020, 110, 106640;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) St&#xe4;hler M., St&#xe4;hler A., Scheepers F., Carmo M., Stolten D., Int. J. Hydrogen Energy 2019, 44, 7053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seo J., Kushner D. I., Hickner M. A., Acs Appl. Mater. Inter. 2016, 8, 16656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27218137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuynet S., Caillard A., Kaya&#x2010;Boussougou S., Lecas T., Semmar N., Bigarr&#xe9; J., Buvat P., Brault P., J. Power Sources 2015, 298, 299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke Y. Z., Yuan W., Zhou F. K., Guo W. W., Li J. G., Zhuang Z. Y., Su X. Q., Lu B. W., Zhao Y. H., Tang Y., Chen Y., Song J. L., Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2021, 145, 110860.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Jang S., Kim M., Kang Y. S., Choi Y. W., Kim S. M., Sung Y. E., Choi M., Acs Appl. Mater. Inter. 2016, 8, 11459;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27116979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Jang S., Choi J., Shin M., Yeon J. H., Kim S. M., Choi M., Adv. Mater. Interfaces 2019, 6, 1900606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majsztrik P. W., Bocarsly A. B., Benziger J. B., Macromolecules 2008, 41, 9849.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S. M., Kang Y. S., Ahn C., Jang S., Kim M., Sung Y. E., Yoo S. J., Choi M., J. Power Sources 2016, 317, 19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Cossar E., Barnett A. O., Seland F., Safari R., Botton G. A., Baranova E. A., J. Power Sources 2021, 514, 230563;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Faid A. Y., Xie L., Barnett A. O., Seland F., Kirk D., Sunde S., Int. J. Hydrogen Energy 2020, 45, 28272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maruyama N., Hiromoto S., Akiyama E., Nakamura M., Sci. Technol. Adv. Mater. 2013, 14, 025002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5074373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27877571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Yang J. H., Yang S. X., An L. L., Zhu J., Xiao J. W., Zhao X., Wang D. L., ACS Catal. 2024, 14, 3466;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Osmieri L., He Y. H., Chung H. T., McCool G., Zulevi B., Cullen D. A., Zelenay P., J. Power Sources 2023, 556, 232484;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) Kwak M., Ojha K., Shen M. K., Boettcher S. W., Acs Energy Lett. 2024, 9, 1025;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>d) Cha M. S., Park J. E., Kim S., Han S. H., Shin S. H., Yang S. H., Kim T. H., Yu D. M., So S. Y., Hong Y. T., Yoon S. J., Oh S. G., Kang S. Y., Kim O. H., Park H. S., Bae B., Sung Y. E., Cho Y. H., Lee J. Y., Energy Environ. Sci. 2020, 13, 3633;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>e) Kang S. Y., Park J. E., Jang G. Y., Kim O. H., Kwon O. J., Cho Y. H., Sung Y. E., Int. J. Hydrogen Energy 2022, 47, 9115;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>f) Xu D. Y., Stevens M. B., Cosby M. R., Oener S. Z., Smith A. M., Enman L. J., Ayers K. E., Capuano C. B., Renner J. N., Danilovic N., Li Y. G., Wang H. Z., Zhang Q. H., Boettcher S. W., ACS Catal. 2019, 9, 7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S., Yang S. H., Shin S. H., Cho H. J., Jang J. K., Kim T. H., Oh S. G., Kim T. H., Han H., Lee J. Y., Energy Environ. Sci. 2024, 17, 5399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Zheng Y. W., Serban A., Zhang H. Y., Chen N. J., Song F., Hu X. L., ACS Energy Lett. 2023, 8, 5018;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Wan L., Liu J., Xu Z., Xu Q., Pang M. B., Wang P. C., Wang B. G., Small 2022, 18, 2200380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35491509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim H., Jeong J. Y., Shin G., Kim C., Choi G., Myeong S. W., Choi S. M., Park T., Adv. Energy Mater. 2024, 14, 2401725.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>