<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39629100</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-2360</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in pediatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Case Report: Nephrocalcinosis in an infant due to vitamin-D food supplement overdose.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1485814</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1485814</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1485814</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fped.2024.1485814</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Vitamin D is a vital lipophilic vitamin that plays a pivotal role in calcium regulation, bone metabolism, and overall health. It is of the utmost importance to maintain appropriate serum levels of vitamin D from the moment of birth. The recommended daily intake for infants under the age of 12 months is 400&#x2005;IU. In Europe, vitamin D is available in two forms: as a medicinal product and as a food supplement. The food supplement market is experiencing rapid growth, yet it is characterised by a lack of harmonised regulations, which may give rise to potential risks associated with their widespread use. While food supplements are typically regarded as safe, there is a potential for adverse effects, particularly when dosages are not properly managed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CASE REPORT AND MANAGEMENT" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This report presents the case of a 22-month-old girl who developed nephrocalcinosis as a result of an overdose of vitamin D from a dietary supplement purchased online. The initial presentation was characterised by symptoms such as polydipsia, polyuria and decreased growth. It was subsequently revealed that the child had been receiving an excessively high dose of vitamin D, amounting to 25 times the recommended amount, over a period of seven months. Despite normal calcium levels and renal function at the time of presentation, ultrasound imaging revealed the presence of early-stage nephrocalcinosis. The treatment plan involved hospital admission, intravenous hydration, a thiazide diuretic, potassium citrate, and a low-calcium diet. The vitamin D supplement was ceased. Over the course of a year, the patient demonstrated recovery in growth and normalization of vitamin D levels, although nephrocalcinosis remained stable.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This case study highlights the potential dangers of unsupervised vitamin D supplementation, emphasising the importance of healthcare professionals exercising vigilance in prescribing and advising on vitamin D use, particularly in children. Furthermore, it underscores the necessity of establishing a database to track long-term outcomes in paediatric vitamin D intoxication cases, given the rarity of such incidents. This would facilitate the development of appropriate treatment protocols and provide valuable information to parents.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Pizzini, Ossato, Realdon and Tessari.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Pizzini</LastName><ForeName>Carla</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, IRCCS Ospedale Sacro Cuore Don Calabria, Negrar di Valpolicella, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Ossato</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical and Pharmacological Sciences, University of Padova, Padova, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Realdon</LastName><ForeName>Nicola</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical and Pharmacological Sciences, University of Padova, Padova, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tessari</LastName><ForeName>Roberto</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital Pharmacy, IRCCS Ospedale Sacro Cuore Don Calabria, Negrar di Valpolicella, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101615492</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-2360</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">calciferol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">food supplement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypercalcaemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nephrocalcinosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vitamin D</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39629100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11611577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fped.2024.1485814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Galior K, Grebe S, Singh R. Development of vitamin D toxicity from overcorrection of vitamin D deficiency: a review of case reports. Nutrients. (2018) 10(8):953. 10.3390/nu10080953</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10080953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6115827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30042334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levita J, Wilar G, Wahyuni I, Bawono LC, Ramadaini T, Rohani R, et al. Clinical toxicology of vitamin D in pediatrics: a review and case reports. Toxics. (2023) 11(7):642. 10.3390/toxics11070642</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/toxics11070642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10385357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37505607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Mauro G, Saggese G, Vierucci F, Agostiniani R, Bona G, Cardinale F, et al. Consensus vitamina D in et&#xe0; pediatrica. Pediatria Preventiva e Sociale. (2015) 3:141&#x2013;258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson RR. Handbook of Vitamin D in Human Health. The Netherlands: Wageningen Academic Pub; (2013). 10.3920/978-90-8686-765-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3920/978-90-8686-765-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glade MJ. A 21st century evaluation of the safety of oral vitamin D. Nutrition. (2012) 28(4):344&#x2013;56. 10.1016/j.nut.2011.11.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2011.11.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22414585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fortune Business Insights. Nutraceuticals Market Size, Share &amp; Industry Analysis, by Product Type (Dietary Supplements, Functional Foods, and Functional Beverages), Distribution Channel (Hypermarkets/Supermarkets, Convenience Stores, Online Retail, and Others) and Regional Forecast, 2024-2032. Pune, Maharashtra, India: Fortune Business Insights (2024). Available online at:
https://www.fortunebusinessinsights.com/nutraceutical-ingredients-market-102282</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menniti-Ippolito F, Aiello E, Arzenton E, Assisi A, Blaznik U, Castenmiller JJM, et al. Erice manifesto 2022: on the surveillance of potential Harms caused by food supplements in Europe. Drug Saf. (2023) 46(5):435&#x2013;7. 10.1007/s40264-023-01284-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40264-023-01284-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37022637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor PN, Davies JS. A review of the growing risk of vitamin D toxicity from inappropriate practice. Br J Clin Pharmacol. (2018) 84(6):1121&#x2013;7. 10.1111/bcp.13573</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bcp.13573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5980613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29498758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurevich E, Levi S, Borovitz Y, Alfandary H, Ganon L, Dinour D, et al. Childhood hypercalciuric hypercalcemia with elevated vitamin D and suppressed parathyroid hormone: long-term follow up. Front Pediatr. (2021) 9:752312. 10.3389/fped.2021.752312</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fped.2021.752312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8631469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34858904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaptein S, Risselada AJ, Boerma EC, Egbers PH, Nieboer P. Life-threatening complications of vitamin D intoxication due to over-the-counter supplements. Clin Toxicol. (2010) 48(5):460&#x2013;2. 10.3109/15563650.2010.486382</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/15563650.2010.486382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20515399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koutkia P, Chen TC, Holick MF. Vitamin D intoxication associated with an over-the-counter supplement. N Engl J Med. (2001) 345(1):66&#x2013;7. 10.1056/NEJM200107053450115</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM200107053450115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11439958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manappallil RG, Shylendran S, Kakkattil A, Thomas AD. Multiple renal calculi due to hypercalcaemia induced by over-the-counter vitamin D intoxication. BMJ Case Rep. (2018) 2018:bcr2018225849. 10.1136/bcr-2018-225849</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bcr-2018-225849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6109724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30131404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaidya SR, Yarrarapu SNS, Aeddula NR. Nephrocalcinosis. In StatPearls. Treasure Island, FL: StatPearls Publishing; (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30725890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Food Safety Authority (EFSA). Scientific opinion on dietary reference values for calcium. EFSA Journal. (2015) 13(5):4101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munns CF, Shaw N, Kiely M, Specker BL, Thacher TD, Ozono K, et al. Global consensus recommendations on prevention and management of nutritional rickets. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. (2016) 101(2):394&#x2013;415. 10.1210/jc.2015-2175</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2015-2175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4880117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26745253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross AC, Manson JE, Abrams SA, Aloia JF, Brannon PM, Clinton SK, et al. The 2011 report on dietary reference intakes for calcium and vitamin D from the institute of medicine: what clinicians need to know. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. (2011) 96(1):53&#x2013;8. 10.1210/jc.2010-2704</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2010-2704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3046611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21118827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holick MF, Binkley NC, Bischoff-Ferrari HA, Gordon CM, Hanley DA, Heaney RP, et al. Evaluation, treatment, and prevention of vitamin D deficiency: an endocrine society clinical practice guideline. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. (2011) 96(7):1911&#x2013;30. 10.1210/jc.2011-0385 Erratum in: J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2011 Dec;96(12):3908. Erratum in: J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2024 September 16;109(10):e1991. doi: 10.1210/clinem/dgae373. PMID: 21646368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2011-0385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21646368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giustina A, Bilezikian JP, Adler RA, Banfi G, Bikle DD, Binkley NC. Consensus statement on vitamin D Status assessment and supplementation: whys, whens, and hows. Endocr Rev. (2024) 45:625. 10.1210/endrev/bnae009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/endrev/bnae009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11405507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38676447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>