<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41426270</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2325-9671</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Orthopaedic journal of sports medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Orthop J Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Machine Learning Prediction of Poor Flexion-Extension Outcome After Open Elbow Arthrolysis: Identifying Individual Predisposition Using Clinical and Laboratory Indicators.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23259671251389129</StartPage><MedlinePgn>23259671251389129</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">23259671251389129</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/23259671251389129</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Elbow stiffness is a condition that causes mobility dysfunction and severe suffering in patients. Patients with posttraumatic elbow stiffness who undergo open elbow arthrolysis are at risk for poor postoperative flexion-extension outcome, which leads us to suspect that these patients possess a unique "elbow stiffness predisposition."</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To develop an innovative predictive model that combines clinical and laboratory indicators to forecast poor flexion-extension outcomes after open elbow arthrolysis, thereby interpreting the "elbow stiffness predisposition."</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Cohort study; Level of evidence, 3.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Patients who underwent open elbow arthrolysis between 2019 and 2022 were selected for model training and validation (n = 254), while those who underwent open elbow arthrolysis between 2016 and 2017 served as a test set (n = 35). The study assessed 19 clinical features and 58 laboratory parameters. A comparative analysis of several machine learning models-logistic regression, Naive Bayes, decision trees, random forest, gradient boosting, and XGBoost-was performed to identify the most effective approach. SHapley Additive exPlanations (SHAP) were employed to prioritize the key factors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Using univariate analysis and the least absolute shrinkage and selection operator (LASSO) regression, 14 key variables were selected for inclusion in the model. The XGBoost model demonstrated superior performance, reaching an area under the curve of 0.909 on the test dataset. The most important indicator identified by LASSO was alkaline phosphatase. Indicators ranked by SHAP were lipoprotein(a), alkaline phosphatase, visual analog scale score, serum calcium, basophil count, serum sodium, previous arthrolysis, alanine aminotransferase, blood glucose, preoperative elbow range of motion, Cystatin C, uric acid, tobacco use, and serum cholinesterase.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We have successfully developed a machine learning model using 14 key indicators to predict poor flexion-extension outcomes, which preliminarily explains the "elbow stiffness predisposition."</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2025.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xinyu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3744-7255</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Orthopaedics, Department of Orthopaedics, Shanghai Sixth People's Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Wencai</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5350-3125</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Orthopaedics, Department of Orthopaedics, Shanghai Sixth People's Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tong</LastName><ForeName>Yuanhao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8842-1974</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Orthopaedics, Department of Orthopaedics, Shanghai Sixth People's Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lv</LastName><ForeName>Yaowei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5269-4548</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Orthopaedics, Department of Orthopaedics, Shanghai Sixth People's Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Limin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Orthopaedics, Department of Laboratory Science, Shanghai Sixth People's Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Cunyi</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Orthopaedics, Department of Orthopaedics, Shanghai Sixth People's Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ouyang</LastName><ForeName>Yuanming</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Center for Orthopaedics, Department of Orthopaedics, Shanghai Sixth People's Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Orthop J Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101620522</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2325-9671</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">open elbow arthrolysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">posttraumatic elbow stiffness</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>One or more of the authors has declared the following potential conflict of interest or source of funding: This study was funded by the National Key R&amp;D Program of China, the National Natural Science Foundation of China, the Medical Engineering Co-Project at the University of Shanghai for Science and Technology, and the Shanghai Municipal Health Commission. AOSSM checks author disclosures against the Open Payments Database (OPD). AOSSM has not conducted an independent investigation on the OPD and disclaims any liability or responsibility relating thereto.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41426270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12717415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/23259671251389129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_23259671251389129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Angl&#xe9;s-Cano E. Structural basis for the pathophysiology of lipoprotein(a) in the athero-thrombotic process. Braz J Med Biol Res. 1997;30(11):1271-1280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9532233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boffa MB, Koschinsky ML. Oxidized phospholipids as a unifying theory for lipoprotein(a) and cardiovascular disease. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2019;16(5):305-318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30675027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng X, Wang L, Wen X, et al. TNAP is a novel regulator of cardiac fibrosis after myocardial infarction by mediating TGF-&#x3b2;/Smads and ERK1/2 signaling pathways. EBioMedicine. 2021;67:103370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8122000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33971401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciancaglini P, Simao AMS, Camolezi FL, Millan JL, Pizauro JM. Contribution of matrix vesicles and alkaline phosphatase to ectopic bone formation. Braz J Med Biol Res. 2006;39(5):603-610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16648897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen MS, Schimmel DR, Masuda K, Hastings H, II, Muehleman C. Structural and biochemical evaluation of the elbow capsule after trauma. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2007;16(4):484-490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2080784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17368926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danjo A, Yamaza T, Kido MA, et al. Cystatin C stimulates the differentiation of mouse osteoblastic cells and bone formation. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2007;360(1):199-204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17592728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Munter W, Blom AB, Helsen MM, et al. Cholesterol accumulation, caused by low-density lipoprotein receptor deficiency or a cholesterol-rich diet, results in ectopic bone formation during experimental osteoarthritis. Arthritis Res Ther. 2013;15(6):R178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3978425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24286458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Munter W, van den Bosch MH, Sloetjes AW, et al. High LDL levels lead to increased synovial inflammation and accelerated ectopic bone formation during experimental osteoarthritis. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2016;24(5):844-855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26687826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dellon AL. Review of treatment results for ulnar nerve entrapment at the elbow. J Hand Surg Am. 1989;14(4):688-700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2666496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duriez J, Flautre B, Blary MC, Duriez R. Effet d'un inhibiteur calcique, le v&#xe9;rapamil, sur le d&#xe9;veloppement des ossifications h&#xe9;t&#xe9;rotopiques. Etude exp&#xe9;rimentale chez le rat [Effect of a calcium inhibitor, verapamil, on the development of heterotopic ossifications. An experimental study in rats]. Int Orthop. 1990;14(4):415-421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2127590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekiz T, Demir SO, Dogan A, Ozgirgin N. Coexistence of heterotopic ossification of the elbow and vitamin D deficiency following stroke: can calcium and vitamin D treatment aggravate ossification? West Indian Med J. 2014;63(6):682-683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4663966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25803393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawker GA, Mian S, Kendzerska T, French M. Measures of adult pain: visual analog scale for pain (VAS pain), numeric rating scale for pain (NRS pain), McGill pain questionnaire (MPQ), short-form McGill pain questionnaire (SF-MPQ), chronic pain grade scale (CPGS), short form-36 bodily pain scale (SF-36 BPS), and measure of intermittent and constant osteoarthritis pain (ICOAP). Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2011;63(suppl 11):S240-S252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22588748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hovater MB, Sanders PW. Effect of dietary salt on regulation of TGF-&#x3b2; in the kidney. Semin Nephrol. 2012;32(3):269-276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3407676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22835458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin XX, Ji XR, Yin HP, et al. Identification of potential targets of stress cardiomyopathy by a machine learning algorithm. Cardiovasc Innov Appl. 2024;9(1):973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kontokostopoulos AP, Gkiatas I, Vasileiadis GI, et al. Heterotopic Ossification around the Elbow Revisited. Life (Basel). 2023;13(12):2358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10744911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38137958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunze KNN, Sculco PKK, Zhong H, et al. Development and internal validation of machine learning algorithms for predicting hyponatremia after TJA. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2022;104(3):265-270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34898530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lalmanach G, Rigoux B, David A, et al. Human cystatin C in fibrotic diseases. Clin Chim Acta. 2025;565:120016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39461496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau FD, Giugliano RP. Lipoprotein(a) and its significance in cardiovascular disease: a review. JAMA Cardiol. 2022;7(7):760-769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35583875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leopold JA. Cellular mechanisms of aortic valve calcification. Circ Cardiovasc Interv. 2012;5(4):605-614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3427002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22896576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu D, Liu ZX, Zhang JE, et al. Classification and prediction of skyrmion material based on machine learning. Research (Wash D C). 2023;6:0082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10019916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36939441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W, Sun Z, Xiong H, et al. Development and validation of a prognostic nomogram for open elbow arthrolysis: the Shanghai Prediction model for Elbow Stiffness Surgical Outcome. Bone Joint J. 2022;104-B(4):486-494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9020519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35360939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorch IJ. Alkaline phosphatase and the mechanism of ossification. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 1949;31(1):94-99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18112923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv DM, Xu ZY, Cheng P, et al. S-Nitrosylation-mediated coupling of DJ-1 with PTEN induces PI3K/AKT/mTOR pathway-dependent keloid formation. Burns Trauma. 2023;11:tkad024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10729783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38116467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv YW, Zhan L, Yao XY, et al. Piezoelectric polyvinylidene fluoride-trifluoroethylene/reduced graphene oxide/polycaprolactone fiber material: modulating neutrophil extracellular traps and reshaping the immune microenvironment in peripheral nerves. Adv Fiber Mater. 2025;7(2):645-663.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansat P, Morrey BF. The column procedure: a limited lateral approach for extrinsic contracture of the elbow. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1998;80(11):1603-1615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9840628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin RK, Wastvedt S, Pareek A, et al. Predicting anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction revision: a machine learning analysis utilizing the Norwegian Knee Ligament Register. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2022;104(2):145-153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34662318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masci G, Cazzato G, Milano G, et al. The stiff elbow: current concepts. Orthop Rev (Pavia). 2020;12(suppl 1):8661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7459370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32913596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta A, Vasquez N, Ayers CR, et al. Independent association of lipoprotein(a) and coronary artery calcification with atherosclerotic cardiovascular risk. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2022;79(8):757-768.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10966924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35210030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyake K, Ito J, Karasuyama H. Role of basophils in a broad spectrum of disorders. Front Immunol. 2022;13:902494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9186123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35693800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohler ER, Gannon F, Reynolds C, et al. Bone formation and inflammation in cardiac valves. Circulation. 2001;103(11):1522-1528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11257079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhammad AN, Ijaz A, Khalid A, et al. Renal effects of graphite oxide sheets in albino rats (Rattus norvegicus): a preliminary study. BIO Integration. 2024;5(1):966.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pap D, Pajt&#xf3;k C, Veres-Sz&#xe9;kely A, et al. High salt promotes inflammatory and fibrotic response in peritoneal cells. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24(18):13765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10531298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37762068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ponzano M, Wiest MJ, Coleman A, et al. The use of alkaline phosphatase as a bone turnover marker after spinal cord injury: a scoping review of human and animal studies. J Spinal Cord Med. 2023;46(2):167-180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9987745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34935593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi R, Zou Q. Trends and potential of machine learning and deep learning in drug study at single-cell level. Research (Wash D C). 2023;6:0050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10013796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36930772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian Y, Liu W, Wang W, Fan C. Obesity may be a risk factor for recurrent heterotopic ossification in post-traumatic stiff elbow among children and teenagers. Orthop Traumatol Surg Res. 2019;105(6):1193-1198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31088773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian Y, Yu S, Shi Y, Huang H, Fan C. Risk factors for the occurrence and progression of posttraumatic elbow stiffness: a case-control study of 688 cases. Front Med (Lausanne). 2020;7:604056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7772462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33392226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin T, Ma TY, Huang K, et al. Lipoprotein (a)-related inflammatory imbalance: a novel horizon for the development of atherosclerosis. Curr Atheroscler Rep. 2024;26(8):383-394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11236888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38878139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruan J-h, Cui H-m, Sun Z-y, et al. Midterm outcomes after open arthrolysis for posttraumatic elbow stiffness in children and adolescents. J Pediatr Orthop. 2021;41(3):E266-E271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7952043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33492039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sage AP, Tintut Y, Demer LL. Regulatory mechanisms in vascular calcification. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2010;7(9):528-536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3014092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20664518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Herrero S, Carbonero Martinez F, Serna J, et al. Embedding R inside the PhysPK Biosimulation software for pharmacokinetics population analysis. BIO Integration. 2023;4(3):97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santarpia L, Grandone I, Contaldo F, Pasanisi F. Butyrylcholinesterase as a prognostic marker: a review of the literature. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2013;4(1):31-39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3581611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22956442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siemensma MF, van der Windt AE, van Es EM, Colaris JW, Eygendaal D. Management of the stiff elbow: a literature review. EFORT Open Rev. 2023;8(5):351-360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10233805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37158372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobus KM, Sherman N, Alexander MA. Coexistence of deep venous thrombosis and heterotopic ossification in the pediatric patient. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1993;74(5):547-551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8489369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohn W, Jun DW, Kwak MJ, et al. Upper limit of normal serum alanine and aspartate aminotransferase levels in Korea. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2013;28(3):522-529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22497339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun YB, Cai JY, Li FF, et al. The efficacy of celecoxib in preventing heterotopic ossification recurrence after open arthrolysis for post-traumatic elbow stiffness in adults. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2015;24(11):1735-1740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26480878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Z, Wang W, Fan C. Tobacco use predicts poorer clinical outcomes and higher post-operative complication rates after open elbow arthrolysis. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg. 2019;139(7):883-891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30610418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timsans J, Palom&#xe4;ki A, Kauppi M. Gout and hyperuricemia: a narrative review of their comorbidities and clinical implications. J Clin Med. 2024;13(24):7616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11678569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39768539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuleta I, Frangogiannis NG. Diabetic fibrosis. Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Basis Dis. 2021;1867(4):166044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7867637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33378699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vongpromek R, Bos S, ten Kate GJR, et al. Lipoprotein(a) levels are associated with aortic valve calcification in asymptomatic patients with familial hypercholesterolaemia. J Intern Med. 2015;278(2):166-173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25487646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang RY, Yang SH, Xu WH. Role of epithelium sodium channel in bone formation. Chin Med J (Engl). 2016;129(5):594-600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4804442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26904995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong H, Sun Z, Chen S, et al. Effect of hyperuricemia on functional outcomes and complications in patients with elbow stiffness after open arthrolysis combined with hinged external fixation: a retrospective study. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2020;29(7):1387-1393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32553439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng KH, Tsimikas S, Pawade T, et al. Lipoprotein(a) and oxidized phospholipids promote valve calcification in patients with aortic stenosis. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2019;73(17):2150-2162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6494952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31047003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou BF. Cooperative meta-analysis group of the working group on obesity in C. Predictive values of body mass index and waist circumference for risk factors of certain related diseases in Chinese adults&#x2014;study on optimal cut-off points of body mass index and waist circumference in Chinese adults. Biomed Environ Sci. 2002;15(1):83-96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12046553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu LY, Chen YN, Li Q, et al. Liver fibrosis scores as predictors of long-term outcomes in patients with ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction. Cardiovasc Innov Appl. 2024;9(1).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>