<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article article-type="research-article" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">2083</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">bmcssmr</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>BMC Sports Science, Medicine and Rehabilitation</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2052-1847</issn><publisher><publisher-name>BMC</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC13040763</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC13040763.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">13040763</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">13040763</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">41724971</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s13102-026-01622-y</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">1622</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Research</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Sprint performance changes in adolescent athletes following a 6-week elastic resistance training program: a preliminary field study</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">http://orcid.org/0000-0001-5798-263X</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Kocakulak</surname><given-names initials="NA">Nese Akpinar</given-names></name><address><email>nese.kocakulak@idu.edu.tr</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">http://orcid.org/0000-0002-2551-4273</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Esenkaya</surname><given-names initials="H">Hasan</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/04c152q53</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 6045 8574</institution-id><institution>Department of Exercise and Sports Sciences, Faculty of Health Sciences, </institution><institution>Izmir Democracy University, </institution></institution-wrap>İzmir, 35140 Türkiye </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>23</day><month>2</month><year>2026</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2026</year></pub-date><volume>18</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">503802</issue-id><elocation-id>164</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>15</day><month>10</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>18</day><month>2</month><year>2026</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>23</day><month>02</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>02</day><month>04</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2026-04-02 10:25:13.330"><day>02</day><month>04</month><year>2026</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>© The Author(s) 2026</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2026</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License, which permits any non-commercial use, sharing, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons licence, and indicate if you modified the licensed material. You do not have permission under this licence to share adapted material derived from this article or parts of it. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article’s Creative Commons licence, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article’s Creative Commons licence and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this licence, visit <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="13102_2026_Article_1622.pdf"/><abstract id="Abs1"><sec><title>Background</title><p id="Par1">Elastic Resistance Training (ERT) is a widely used modality in rehabilitation, but its efficacy for enhancing sprint performance in adolescents is under-researched.</p></sec><sec><title>Methods</title><p id="Par2">Twenty-eight competitive adolescent track and field athletes (mean age: 16.64 ± 1.37 years) participated in a 6-week progressive ERT program added to their standard technical training.</p></sec><sec><title>Results</title><p id="Par3">Significant improvements were observed across all distances. The 30 m sprint time decreased from 4.36 s to 4.29 s (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, Cohen’s d = 0.24, small effect). The 60 m time improved from 8.16 s to 8.08 s (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, d = 0.11, trivial effect). The most meaningful change occurred in the 400 m sprint, decreasing from 70.98 s to 68.30 s (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001, d = 0.29, small-to-moderate effect).</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusion</title><p id="Par4">While absolute improvements in short acceleration (30 m) were small, the intervention showed greater practical relevance for speed endurance (400 m). Coaches should consider ERT as a supplementary tool for developing anaerobic capacity in youth athletes.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group xml:lang="en"><title>Keywords</title><kwd>Elastic resistance training</kwd><kwd>Sprint performance</kwd><kwd>Speed development</kwd><kwd>Thera-band</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-ND</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>© BioMed Central Ltd., part of Springer Nature 2026</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par5">The unique properties of ERT, specifically its accommodating resistance, increase tension as the range of motion is completed. While traditional inertial loads provide maximum resistance at the beginning of a movement (where the mechanical advantage is often lowest), elastic bands provide peak resistance at the end of the range of motion (terminal stance phase). This matches the human strength curve in extension movements (squats and jumps) and may enhance the ability to apply force at full hip extension—a critical component of maximum velocity sprinting. Furthermore, the elastic energy recoil requires athletes to control the eccentric (deceleration) phase actively, potentially improving neuromuscular control and stiffness. The primary advantages of ERT include the development of fundamental biomotor abilities such as strength, speed, and power [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>]. Resistance training is a fundamental method used to safely and effectively develop physical performance foundations in adolescents [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. While traditional resistance training often relies on constant external load (free weights), elastic resistance offers unique advantages by providing accommodating resistance. This dynamic tension increases towards the end of the range of motion, potentially demanding higher muscle activation during the peak contraction phase of movement [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>]. Despite its popularity, research specifically examining the transfer of these strength gains to sprint speed in adolescent populations remains limited.</p><p id="Par6">Furthermore, exercises such as resisted running directly overload sprint-specific musculature and movement patterns, potentially improving stride power and frequency. Sport is a dynamic field that demands the highest level of physical performance from individuals. Sustaining this performance requires athletes to establish a delicate balance among training, competition stress, and recovery processes [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>]. Athletic success depends not only on genetic predisposition but also on appropriate training methodologies aimed at developing all components of physical fitness, including strength, speed, endurance, anaerobic power, flexibility, and agility [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>]. In this context, the intensity, duration, and frequency of training programs must be meticulously calibrated to minimize injury risk and guide the athlete toward peak performance [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>]. Resistance training is a cornerstone of athletic development, essential for enhancing muscular power and speed. Within this domain, Elastic Resistance Training (ERT) offers a distinct mechanical stimulus compared to traditional free weights. Unlike constant resistance, elastic bands provide variable load (accommodating resistance) that increases linearly with elongation. This property potentially allows for greater loading in the terminal range of motion during extension movements (squats, jumps), matching the ascending strength curve of the lower limb extensor muscles. However, the specific transfer of these mechanical benefits to track-based sprint performance in adolescents remains unclear. Furthermore, the practicality, low cost, and applicability of this training method in various settings make it an attractive option for both professional and amateur athletes.</p><p id="Par7">Resistance training is a fundamental method used to safely and effectively develop the foundations of physical performance in individuals of all ages, including children and adolescents [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. It plays a critical role in enhancing key motor abilities such as strength, speed, endurance, agility, and flexibility in young and elite athletes. These gains not only maximize athletic performance but are also utilized as a supportive measure in the treatment and rehabilitation of sports injuries [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>].</p><p id="Par8">Resistance exercises can be performed using a variety of materials, such as functional training equipment, free weights, and elastic bands [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>]. Each material yields different effects depending on parameters like training intensity, set and repetition counts, and rest intervals. For instance, some research indicates that higher-intensity, low-repetition training programs are more effective for improving the physical performance metrics of elite athletes [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>].</p><p id="Par9">Elastic resistance bands offer unique advantages, particularly in increasing muscle activation levels and providing resistance throughout every phase of a movement [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. Compared to exercises with free weights, elastic bands generate a dynamic and accommodating tension across the entire range of motion [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>]. This suggests that elastic bands can be an effective training tool in sports that require significant shoulder strength and stability. Research has demonstrated that training with elastic bands can increase throwing velocity and force in sports requiring throwing performance, such as tennis and handball [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>].</p><p id="Par10">Elastic resistance bands (e.g., Thera-Band) are an ideal tool for athletes and physiotherapists due to their lightweight, portable, and space-efficient design. These bands, available in different colors, offer graded levels of resistance, with a scale ranging from tan to gold, allowing individuals to select exercises appropriate for their strength levels [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. This feature makes the bands suitable for both injury rehabilitation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>] and elite-level training.</p><p id="Par11">The importance of elastic bands in rehabilitation is underscored by their ability to facilitate movement independent of gravity and provide greater control over the phases of motion [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>]. Consequently, they serve as an effective alternative to traditional training for improving balance and postural stability following lower-extremity injuries [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>]. Despite the extensive use of ERT in rehabilitation, there is a paucity of research examining its efficacy for performance enhancement in healthy adolescent populations. Specifically, while the effects of ERT on static strength are well-documented, its transfer to dynamic sprint performance—particularly speed endurance (e.g., 400 m) versus acceleration (e.g., 30 m)—remains under-explored in youth athletes. Furthermore, most existing studies utilize complex laboratory setups; there is a need for practical, field-based protocols that coaches can implement with minimal equipment. Given the practical challenges of implementing controlled trials in competitive team settings, the primary purpose of this study was to observe and quantify the changes in 30 m, 60 m, and 400 m sprint performance in adolescent athletes following a 6-week progressive ERT program. This preliminary field study aims to assess the feasibility and potential magnitude of performance changes to inform future randomized controlled trials. Based on the existing literature, we hypothesized that the 6-week ERT program would significantly improve sprint performance, with potentially greater relative gains in speed-endurance (400 m) due to the metabolic demands of the time-under-tension protocol.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2"><title>Methodology</title><p id="Par12">Ethical approval for the study was obtained from the Izmir Democracy University Non-Interventional Clinical Research Ethics Committee (No: 2022/02–08). All research activities were conducted in full accordance with the ethical principles for human research as outlined in the WMA Declaration of Helsinki. Written informed consent to participate was obtained from all participants. For participants under the age of 18, written informed consent was also obtained from their parents or legal guardians prior to the commencement of the study.</p><p id="Par13">The study group was composed of a total of 28 athletes, with a mean age of 16.64 years, a mean height of 172.18 cm, and a mean body weight of 61.10 kg, and competitive adolescent track and field athletes (sprinters and long jumpers) actively engaged in the competitive season. Long jumpers were included in the sprinter cohort as their training regimens and plyometric profiles are highly comparable to pure sprinters during the general preparation phase. Participants had a mean training age of 3 ± 1 years. Throughout the 6-week intervention, athletes continued their standard technical track training (3 sessions/week), which included low-volume block starts and technical drills. The ERT protocol was added as a specific strength module at the beginning of these sessions.</p><sec id="Sec3"><title>Participants and sample size</title><p id="Par14">The study employed a convenience sampling method, recruiting the entire available roster of a local youth athletic team (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 28). A post-hoc power analysis indicated that for a Paired Samples t-Test with a medium effect size (d = 0.5) and an alpha level of 0.05, a sample size of 28 provides a statistical power (1 - β) of approximately 0.82, which is considered adequate for this pilot intervention.</p></sec><sec id="Sec4"><title>Controls and standardization</title><p id="Par15">To minimize confounding variables, participants were instructed to maintain their standard sleep habits and dietary intake throughout the study. However, specific hydration status, sleep quality, and biological maturity (e.g., Peak Height Velocity) were not instrumentally monitored, which is noted as a limitation of the field-based design.</p></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Protocol considerations</title><p id="Par16">The study utilized a fixed time-under-tension approach (increasing from 15 to 25 s) rather than individualized relative loading (e.g., % of 1RM). While this ensured logistical consistency in a team setting, it may not have provided an optimal overload stimulus for the stronger athletes or may have induced excessive fatigue in others. We recommend that future interventions incorporate individualized fatigue monitoring, such as Session Rate of Perceived Exertion (sRPE), to adjust daily training volumes and mitigate the risk of overtraining.</p><p id="Par17">The training program was administered for 6 weeks, 3 days per week, and consisted of 3 sets. The duration commenced at 15 s and was progressively increased by 5 s every two weeks [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>]. To account for physiological baseline strength differences and ensure proper exercise technique, resistance levels were stratified by sex. Female athletes utilized yellow bands (approx. 1.3 kg at 100% elongation) and male athletes utilized red bands (approx. 1.8 kg at 100% elongation). This differentiation aimed to equalize the Relative Perceived Exertion (RPE) during the high-repetition protocols (15–25 s), preventing technical breakdown that might occur if heavier resistance was applied to athletes with lower absolute upper-body strength [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. Furthermore, lighter resistance was deliberately selected to prioritize movement velocity and proper sprint mechanics over maximal force production, ensuring that the athletes could maintain high-speed technical execution without kinematic degradation.</p></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Elongation percentage of elastic bands </title><p id="Par18">To quantify the resistance used, we empirically measured the tension of the Thera-Band elastic bands (Yellow and Red) at 25% increments of elongation. Our measurements indicated that at 100% elongation (the estimated peak stretch during exercises), the Yellow bands provided approximately 1.17 kg of force, and the Red bands provided 1.60 kg. These values differed slightly from the manufacturer’s reference values (Mean Difference ≈ 15%), underscoring the importance of verifying resistance in field studies.</p><p id="Par19">We stratified band selection by sex (Yellow for females, Red for males) to approximate similar relative intensity levels. However, we acknowledge that tension in elastic bands is directly proportional to elongation. Therefore, participants with longer limb lengths (greater height) experienced slightly higher absolute resistance at full extension than shorter participants. This anthropometric variation is an inherent limitation of using fixed-length elastic bands in a heterogeneous group.</p><p id="Par20">Exercises with resistance bands are intended to work the body in various ways. One such exercise is the Squat, for which the resistance band is placed under the feet and held behind the nape of the neck. In this position, a squat is performed until the hips are lowered to a 90-degree angle. Another exercise is the in-place run (skip). During this movement, the elastic band is anchored to a fixed point, passed around the abdomen, and an in-place running motion is performed while maintaining tension on the band. Simultaneously, an arm and leg pull is performed with the resistance band. The band is anchored, with one end attached to the right ankle and the other end passed under the left arm and held by the hand. While keeping the band taut, the arm and leg are pulled forward at the same time. Finally, a single-leg jump onto a box can be performed with the resistance band. In this movement, the band is anchored at abdominal height and held under tension. A jump is then performed onto a box with one leg while the other knee is driven upward. These exercises are repeated for both legs. The detailed 6-week progressive training protocol is outlined in Table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>.</p><p id="Par21">
<table-wrap id="Tab1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Training programs</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Phase</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Weeks</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Duration (Time Under Tension)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Rest Interval</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Phase 1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Weeks 1–2</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">15 s</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1 min</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Phase 2</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Weeks 3–4</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">20 s</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2 min</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Phase 3</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Weeks 5–6</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">25 s</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3 min</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>6-Week Progressive Exercise Program</p><p>Exercises performed: 1. Squat, 2. Hand &amp; Foot Pulls (Standing), 3. Resisted Vertical Jump, 4. Resisted Skip Run</p><p>These runs were performed without resistance to facilitate the transfer of potentiated neural drive to sprinting mechanics [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>]</p><p>Finishing Cool-down Phase: After completing 4 × 30 m incremental runs, jog for 2 laps to cool down</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>
</p><sec id="Sec7"><title>Height and body weight measurements</title><p id="Par22">Participants’ body weights (kg) were measured with precision using an electronic scale (Tanita BC-418 MA). Their heights (cm) were recorded while they stood in an anatomical position without shoes.</p></sec><sec id="Sec8"><title>Body Mass Index (BMI)</title><p id="Par23">The Body Mass Index was calculated using the following formula [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>]: <disp-formula id="Equa"><tex-math id="d33e350">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\mathrm{Body}\;\mathrm{Mass}\;(\mathrm{kg})\;/\;\mathrm{Height}\;{(\mathrm m)}^2$$\end{document}</tex-math></disp-formula></p></sec><sec id="Sec9"><title>Sprint speed tests (30 m, 60 m, 400 m)</title><p id="Par24">Sprint tests were conducted on a tartan track using a precision timing gate system (Brower Timing System, Salt Lake City, UT, USA). Each athlete performed two trials for every distance, and the best result was recorded for analysis [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>]. The principle of full recovery was applied between trials [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR19">19</xref>].</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec10"><title>Data analysis</title><p id="Par25">The collected data were analyzed using IBM SPSS Statistics 26 software.</p><sec id="Sec11"><title>Descriptive statistics</title><p id="Par26">Categorical variables (e.g., gender, age, BMI groups) were expressed as frequency (n) and percentage (%). Numerical variables (e.g., age, height, weight, BMI) were presented as mean (x̄) and standard deviation (SD).</p></sec><sec id="Sec12"><title>Statistical analyses</title><p id="Par27">Data were analyzed using IBM SPSS Statistics 26. Normality of distribution was assessed using the Shapiro-Wilk test in conjunction with visual inspection of Q-Q plots. Levene’s test was used to assess homogeneity of variance. Effect sizes (Cohen’s d) were calculated for all significant pairwise comparisons to determine the practical magnitude of the differences, interpreted as: 0.2 (small), 0.5 (medium), and 0.8 (large).</p></sec></sec></sec><sec id="Sec13"><title>Results</title><p id="Par28">A total of 28 adolescent track and field athletes participated in the study. The cohort consisted of 15 males (53.6%) and 13 females (46.4%), with a mean age of 16.64 ± 1.37 years. The participants were active competitive athletes (sprinters and long jumpers) with a mean training experience of 3 ± 1 years. Anthropometric data indicated a mean height of 172.18 ± 9.46 cm, body weight of 61.10 ± 10.01 kg, and Body Mass Index (BMI) of 20.50 ± 1.99 kg/m². The detailed descriptive characteristics are summarized in Table <xref rid="Tab2" ref-type="table">2</xref>.</p><p id="Par29">
<table-wrap id="Tab2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Distribution of statistical findings regarding the descriptive characteristics of the participants in the study</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Descriptive Characteristics</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Number</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">%</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Gender</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Female</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">13</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">46.4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Male</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">15</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">53.6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Age (years)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Under 18</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">17</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">60.7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">18 and over</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">39.3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">BMI <italic toggle="yes">(kg/m²)</italic></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Underweight or slightly overweight</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14.3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Normal</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">23</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">85.7</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Age (years)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Mean ± SD (Min.-Max.)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">16.64 ± 1.37 (14–19)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Height (cm)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Mean ± SD (Min.-Max.)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">172.18 ± 9.46 (156–187)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Weight (kg)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Mean ± SD (Min.-Max.)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">61.10 ± 10.01 (44.50–82.80)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">BMI <italic toggle="yes">(kg/m²)</italic></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Mean ± SD (Min.-Max.)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">20.50 ± 1.99 (17.38–25.38)</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p><italic toggle="yes">Mean</italic> Average, <italic toggle="yes">SD</italic> Standard Deviation, <italic toggle="yes">Min.</italic> Minimum, <italic toggle="yes">Max.</italic> Maximum</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par30">Regarding the age distribution of the participants, 60.7% were under 18 years old, while 39.3% were 18 years or older. In terms of weight classification, 4 participants were categorized as underweight, 1 as overweight, and 23 were within the normal weight range. The mean age of the participants was 16.64 years, mean height was 172.18 cm, mean body weight was 61.10 kg, and the mean BMI was 20.50 kg/m².</p><p id="Par31">In this study, the effect of elastic resistance band usage on sprint performance was statistically examined across different distances (Table <xref rid="Tab3" ref-type="table">3</xref>). The 30-meter sprint time significantly decreased from a pre-test mean of 4.36 ± 0.30 s to a post-test mean of 4.29 ± 0.28 s (t(27) = 3.742, p &lt; 0.001, Cohen’s d = 0.24). Similarly, the 60-meter sprint time improved from 8.16 ± 0.70 s to 8.08 ± 0.70 s (t(27) = 5.878, p &lt; 0.001, Cohen’s d = 0.11). The most substantial effect was observed at the longest distance; the 400-meter sprint time decreased from 70.98 ± 9.36 s to 68.30 ± 9.26 s (t(27) = 5.774, p &lt; 0.001, Cohen’s d = 0.29). The analyses reveal that the running times for all distances decreased to a statistically significant degree (p &lt; 0.01). According to our findings, the 30-meter running time was determined to have decreased from a mean of 4.36 s in the pre-test to 4.29 s in the post-test. Likewise, the 60-meter running time was 8.16 s in the pre-test and improved to 8.08 s in the post-test. The most notable change occurred in the 400-meter distance, where the mean running time decreased from 70.98 s in the pre-test to 68.30 s in the post-test. These results indicate that resistance band training positively impacts the sprint performance of athletes across all tested distances and significantly shortens their running times. The pre- and post-intervention sprint times, stratified by gender, are presented in.</p><p id="Par32">
<table-wrap id="Tab3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3</label><caption><p>Running speeds of study participants over various distances before and after using an elastic resistance band</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Pre-Post Test</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">N</italic>
</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Mean Time(s)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">SD</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">t</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">p</italic>
</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Pre-Test-30 m run</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.36</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.30</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.742</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.001**</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Post-Test-30 m run</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.29</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.28</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Pre-Test-60 m run</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.16</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.70</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5.878</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.001**</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Post-Test-60 m run</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">08.08</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.70</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Pre-Test-400 m run</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">70.98</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9.36</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5.774</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.001**</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Post-Test-400 m run</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">68.30</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9.26</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>*<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05, **<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.01, t: Paired Sample T-Test</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par33">The pre- and post-intervention sprint times, stratified by gender, are presented in Table <xref rid="Tab4" ref-type="table">4</xref>. According to Table <xref rid="Tab4" ref-type="table">4</xref>, the running times for both female and male participants after the elastic resistance band intervention were significantly shorter than their pre-intervention times.</p><p id="Par34">
<table-wrap id="Tab4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 4</label><caption><p>Comprehensive analysis of pre- and post-training sprint performance by subgroup</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Subgroup</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">N</italic>
</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">30 m Pre (s)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">30 m Post (s)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">60 m Pre (s)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">60 m Post (s)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">400 m Pre (s)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">400 m Post (s)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Overall</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">28</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.36 ± 0.30</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.29 ± 0.28**</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.16 ± 0.70</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.08 ± 0.70**</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">70.98 ± 9.36</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">68.30 ± 9.26**</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Female</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">13</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.57 ± 0.22</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.50 ± 0.22*</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.72 ± 0.53</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.63 ± 0.55**</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">78.13 ± 6.58</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">74.99 ± 7.10**</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Male</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">15</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.17 ± 0.23</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.10 ± 0.16*</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.68 ± 0.38</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.58 ± 0.35**</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">64.77 ± 6.57</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">62.50 ± 6.67**</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>Values are Mean ± SD. * <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05, ** <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.01</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par35">In the 30-meter sprint, the mean time for females decreased from 4.57 s to 4.50 s (t = 3.136, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.009), while the mean time for males decreased from 4.17 s to 4.10 s (t = 2.409, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.030). For the 60-meter sprint, the mean time for females improved from 8.72 s to 8.63 s, a highly significant change (t = 3.889, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.002), and the mean time for males was found to have decreased from 7.68 s to 7.58 s (t = 4.281, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.001). In the 400-meter run, the mean time for females decreased from 78.13 s to 74.99 s (t = 3.326, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.006), while the mean time for males decreased from 64.77 s to 62.50 s, creating a very highly significant difference (t = 7.73, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.001).</p><sec id="Sec14"><title>Subgroup analysis</title><p id="Par36">A Two-Way Mixed ANOVA (Time × Gender) revealed a significant main effect for Time (F(1, 26) = 13.34, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> = 0.001), confirming that sprint performance improved significantly regardless of gender. There was no significant Interaction effect (Time × Gender, <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &gt; 0.05), indicating that males and females improved at similar rates.</p><sec id="Sec15"><title>Descriptive statistics by group</title><p id="Par37">
<list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p id="Par38">Females (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 13): 30 m time improved from 4.57 ± 0.22 s to 4.50 ± 0.22 s.</p></list-item><list-item><p id="Par39">Males (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 15): 30 m time improved from 4.17 ± 0.23 s to 4.10 ± 0.16 s.</p></list-item></list>
</p><p id="Par40">Similar descriptive trends were observed for age subgroups, where the Over-18 group (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 11) showed greater absolute speed but similar relative improvements to the Under-18 group (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 17).</p><p id="Par41">Regarding the changes in running speeds, the use of elastic bands did not produce a significant difference in the 30-meter performance of athletes under 18 years of age (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &gt; 0.05), whereas it resulted in a significant improvement in the 18-and-over group (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05). In contrast, for the 60-meter and 400-meter running speeds, statistically significant improvements were observed in both age groups following the elastic resistance band intervention (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05). Across all running distances, the Time*Age interaction effect was found to have no significant impact on the change in running speeds. The overall results indicate that the use of resistance bands positively influenced the running speeds of all age groups, particularly at longer distances (60 m and 400 m).</p><p id="Par42">When the changes in running speeds according to BMI groups were examined, it was observed that the use of elastic bands did not produce a significant difference in the 30-meter performance of the Underweight BMI group (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &gt; 0.05). In contrast, a statistically significant improvement in running speeds was found in the Normal BMI group (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.01). For the 60-meter and 400-meter runs, however, the situation was different, as the use of elastic resistance bands led to statistically significant improvements in the running speeds of both the Underweight and Normal BMI groups (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.05 and <italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &lt; 0.01, respectively).</p><p id="Par43">While participants in the Normal BMI group demonstrated significant progress across all running distances, the Underweight BMI group recorded significant improvements only at the 60-meter and 400-meter distances. The analyses determined that the Time*BMI interaction did not have a significant effect on the change in running speeds (<italic toggle="yes">p</italic> &gt; 0.05). These results indicate that while resistance band training was generally effective for improving running speeds, the level of improvement did not significantly differ between the BMI groups.</p></sec></sec></sec><sec id="Sec16"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par44">This preliminary field study aimed to observe changes in sprint performance (30 m, 60 m, and 400 m) in adolescent track and field athletes following a 6-week progressive Elastic Resistance Training (ERT) program. The primary finding was that significant improvements were observed across all tested distances following the intervention, with the most distinct relative changes occurring in the 400 m sprint.</p><sec id="Sec17"><title>Sprint performance improvements</title><p id="Par45">The analysis revealed statistically significant reductions in sprint times for the 30 m, 60 m, and 400 m distances. While the absolute improvement in the 30 m sprint (0.07 s) and 60 m sprint (0.08 s) was small, these changes occurred within a relatively short 6-week period. Previous literature suggests that resistance training can support athletic performance by providing variable load stimuli [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>]. In this study, the use of ERT may have offered a supplementary training stimulus to the athletes’ standard technical regimen. Although we did not measure ground reaction forces or electromyographic (EMG) activity, theoretical models suggest that accommodating resistance might encourage force application through the full range of motion [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>]. However, without direct physiological monitoring, we cannot attribute these gains to specific neural or morphological adaptations [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="Sec18"><title>Speed endurance and training volume</title><p id="Par46">A notable observation was the improvement in the 400 m sprint time (mean reduction of ~ 2.68 s). The specific ERT protocol employed in this study utilized time-under-tension sets ranging from 15 to 25 s. This duration targets metabolic pathways distinct from purely explosive, short-duration activities. It is plausible that the high-repetition nature of the protocol imposed a metabolic demand that transferred favorably to speed-endurance performance. This aligns with suggestions that resistance training can enhance fatigue resistance during high-intensity exercise [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>]. Nevertheless, in the absence of a control group, it is difficult to determine the extent to which these improvements were driven by the ERT intervention versus the athletes’ concurrent track training.</p></sec><sec id="Sec19"><title>Subgroup observations</title><p id="Par47">Gender-based analyses indicated that both male and female participants showed improved sprint times post-intervention. While male participants exhibited faster absolute times—consistent with established physiological differences in muscle mass and power output [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR24">24</xref>]—the similar rate of improvement suggests that the ERT protocol was feasible for both groups. Similarly, improvements were observed across age groups (under 18 vs. over 18) and BMI categories [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR25">25</xref>]. The finding that athletes with a normal BMI showed more consistent statistical significance in short sprints compared to underweight athletes may relate to baseline strength-to-weight ratios, though the small sample size of the underweight group (<italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 5) limits this interpretation.</p></sec><sec id="Sec20"><title>Limitations and future directions</title><p id="Par48">The results of this study must be interpreted with caution due to several limitations inherent to its exploratory field-based design. First and foremost, the lack of a control group and randomization precludes causal conclusions; factors such as the “learning effect” (familiarity with timing gates), natural biological maturation, and concurrent technical training likely contributed to the observed results. Second, biological maturity (e.g., peak height velocity) was not assessed, preventing differentiation between training effects and natural growth. Third, resistance bands were assigned based on sex rather than individual strength levels (e.g., % 1RM), which may have resulted in suboptimal loading for some athletes. Finally, no physiological (e.g., lactate, EMG) or biomechanical (e.g., force plate) variables were measured to verify the underlying mechanisms of performance change.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec21"><title>Conclusion</title><p id="Par49">This preliminary study demonstrates that a 6-week progressive ERT program implemented within a standard track and field curriculum was associated with improved sprint performance in adolescent athletes. The protocol appeared particularly relevant for speed endurance (400 m). However, these findings are descriptive in nature. Future research utilizing randomized controlled trials, biological maturity assessments, and objective load monitoring is required to validate the effectiveness of ERT and elucidate the physiological mechanisms responsible for performance enhancement in youth populations.</p></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher’s note</bold></p><p>Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><ack><p>Not applicable.</p><sec id="FPar1"><title><bold>Clinical trial number</bold></title><p id="Par50">Clinical trial number: not applicable.</p></sec></ack><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Authors’ contributions</title><p>Neşe Akpınar Kocakulak: Conceptualization, Methodology, Supervision, Research Administration, Writing – Original Draft, Writing – Review &amp; Editing. Hasan Esenkaya: Data Curation, Formal Analysis, Investigation, Visualization. All authors have read and agreed to the published version of the manuscript.</p></notes><notes notes-type="funding-information"><title>Funding</title><p>No funding was received for this study.</p></notes><notes notes-type="data-availability"><title>Data availability</title><p>The datasets used and/or analyzed during the current study are available from the corresponding author on reasonable request.</p></notes><notes><title>Declarations</title><notes id="FPar2"><title>Ethics approval and consent to participate</title><p id="Par51">Ethical approval for the study was obtained from the Izmir Democracy University Non-Interventional Clinical Research Ethics Committee (Decision No: 2022/02–08). All research activities were conducted in full accordance with the ethical principles for human research as outlined in the WMA Declaration of Helsinki. Written informed consent to participate was obtained from all participants. For participants under the age of 18, written informed consent was also obtained from their parents or legal guardians prior to the commencement of the study.</p></notes><notes id="FPar3"><title>Consent for publication</title><p id="Par52">Written informed consent to publish the data collected was obtained from all participants and, where applicable, their legal guardians.</p></notes><notes id="FPar4" notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing interests</title><p id="Par53">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR1" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lopes</surname><given-names>JSS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Machado</surname><given-names>AF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Micheletti</surname><given-names>JK</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>de Almeida</surname><given-names>AC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cavina</surname><given-names>AP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pastre</surname><given-names>CM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effects of training with elastic resistance versus conventional resistance on muscular strength: A systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title><source>SAGE Open Med</source><year>2019</year><volume>7</volume><fpage>2050312119831116</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/2050312119831116</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30815258</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6383082</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR1" publication-type="journal">Lopes JSS, Machado AF, Micheletti JK, de Almeida AC, Cavina AP, Pastre CM. Effects of training with elastic resistance versus conventional resistance on muscular strength: A systematic review and meta-analysis. SAGE Open Med. 2019;7:2050312119831116.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30815258</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/2050312119831116</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6383082</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR2" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Uchida</surname><given-names>MC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nishida</surname><given-names>MM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sampaio</surname><given-names>RA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Moritani</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Arai</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Thera-band(<sup>®</sup>) elastic band tension: Reference values for physical activity</article-title><source>J Phys Ther Sci</source><year>2016</year><volume>28</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1266</fpage><lpage>71</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1589/jpts.28.1266</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27190465</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4868225</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR2" publication-type="journal">Uchida MC, Nishida MM, Sampaio RA, Moritani T, Arai H. Thera-band(<sup>®</sup>) elastic band tension: Reference values for physical activity. J Phys Ther Sci. 2016;28(4):1266–71.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27190465</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1589/jpts.28.1266</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4868225</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR3" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bergquist</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Iversen</surname><given-names>VM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mork</surname><given-names>PJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Fimland</surname><given-names>MS</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Muscle Activity in Upper-Body Single-Joint Resistance Exercises with Elastic Resistance Bands vs. Free Weights</article-title><source>J Hum Kinet</source><year>2018</year><volume>61</volume><fpage>5</fpage><lpage>13</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1515/hukin-2017-0137</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29599855</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5873332</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR3" publication-type="journal">Bergquist R, Iversen VM, Mork PJ, Fimland MS. Muscle Activity in Upper-Body Single-Joint Resistance Exercises with Elastic Resistance Bands vs. Free Weights. J Hum Kinet. 2018;61:5–13.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29599855</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1515/hukin-2017-0137</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5873332</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR4" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kellmann</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bertollo</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bosquet</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Brink</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Coutts</surname><given-names>AJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Duffield</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Recovery and Performance in Sport: Consensus Statement</article-title><source>Int J Sports Physiol Perform</source><year>2018</year><volume>13</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>240</fpage><lpage>5</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1123/ijspp.2017-0759</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29345524</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR4" publication-type="journal">Kellmann M, Bertollo M, Bosquet L, Brink M, Coutts AJ, Duffield R, et al. Recovery and Performance in Sport: Consensus Statement. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018;13(2):240–5.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29345524</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1123/ijspp.2017-0759</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR5" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Eraslan</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Castelein</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Spanhove</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Orhan</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Duzgun</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cools</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effect of Plyometric Training on Sport Performance in Adolescent Overhead Athletes: A Systematic Review</article-title><source>Sports Health</source><year>2021</year><volume>13</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>37</fpage><lpage>44</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/1941738120938007</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32903164</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7734361</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR5" publication-type="journal">Eraslan L, Castelein B, Spanhove V, Orhan C, Duzgun I, Cools A. Effect of Plyometric Training on Sport Performance in Adolescent Overhead Athletes: A Systematic Review. Sports Health. 2021;13(1):37–44.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32903164</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1177/1941738120938007</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7734361</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR6" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Seiler</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>What is best practice for training intensity and duration distribution in endurance athletes?</article-title><source>Int J Sports Physiol Perform</source><year>2010</year><volume>5</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>276</fpage><lpage>91</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1123/ijspp.5.3.276</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20861519</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR6" publication-type="journal">Seiler S. What is best practice for training intensity and duration distribution in endurance athletes? Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2010;5(3):276–91.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20861519</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1123/ijspp.5.3.276</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR7" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lesinski</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Herz</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schmelcher</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Granacher</surname><given-names>U</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effects of Resistance Training on Physical Fitness in Healthy Children and Adolescents: An Umbrella Review</article-title><source>Sports Med</source><year>2020</year><volume>50</volume><issue>11</issue><fpage>1901</fpage><lpage>28</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s40279-020-01327-3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32757164</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7575465</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR7" publication-type="journal">Lesinski M, Herz M, Schmelcher A, Granacher U. Effects of Resistance Training on Physical Fitness in Healthy Children and Adolescents: An Umbrella Review. Sports Med. 2020;50(11):1901–28.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32757164</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1007/s40279-020-01327-3</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7575465</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR8" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lesinski</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Prieske</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Granacher</surname><given-names>U</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effects and dose-response relationships of resistance training on physical performance in youth athletes: A systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title><source>Br J Sports Med</source><year>2016</year><volume>50</volume><issue>13</issue><fpage>781</fpage><lpage>95</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095497</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26851290</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4941165</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR8" publication-type="journal">Lesinski M, Prieske O, Granacher U. Effects and dose-response relationships of resistance training on physical performance in youth athletes: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(13):781–95.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26851290</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095497</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4941165</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR9" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Anderson</surname><given-names>CE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sforzo</surname><given-names>GA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sigg</surname><given-names>JA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The effects of combining elastic and free weight resistance on strength and power in athletes</article-title><source>J Strength Cond Res</source><year>2008</year><volume>22</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>567</fpage><lpage>74</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181634d1e</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18550975</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR9" publication-type="journal">Anderson CE, Sforzo GA, Sigg JA. The effects of combining elastic and free weight resistance on strength and power in athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(2):567–74.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18550975</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181634d1e</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR10" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gül</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Direnç lastiği ile yapılan üst ektremite antrenmanlarının tenis servis atışına etkisi</article-title><source>Spor ve Performans Araştırmaları Dergisi</source><year>2019</year><volume>10</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>198</fpage><lpage>207</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.17155/omuspd.557305</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR10" publication-type="journal">Gül M. Direnç lastiği ile yapılan üst ektremite antrenmanlarının tenis servis atışına etkisi. Spor ve Performans Araştırmaları Dergisi. 2019;10(3):198–207.</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR11" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Makaracı</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Tenisçilerde direnç lastiği ile yapılan kuvvet antrenmanlarının servis hızı ve isabetine etkisi [The effect of resistance band training on service speed and accuracy in tennis players]</article-title><source>Spormetre</source><year>2021</year><volume>19</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>105</fpage><lpage>15</lpage></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR11" publication-type="journal">Makaracı Y. Tenisçilerde direnç lastiği ile yapılan kuvvet antrenmanlarının servis hızı ve isabetine etkisi [The effect of resistance band training on service speed and accuracy in tennis players]. Spormetre. 2021;19(2):105–15.</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR12" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gaballah</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zeyada</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Elgeidi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bressel</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Six-week physical rehabilitation protocol for anterior shoulder dislocation in athletes</article-title><source>J Exerc Rehabil</source><year>2017</year><volume>13</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>353</fpage><lpage>8</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.12965/jer.1734976.488</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28702449</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5498094</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR12" publication-type="journal">Gaballah A, Zeyada M, Elgeidi A, Bressel E. Six-week physical rehabilitation protocol for anterior shoulder dislocation in athletes. J Exerc Rehabil. 2017;13(3):353–8.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28702449</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.12965/jer.1734976.488</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5498094</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR13" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bench</surname><given-names>RW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Thompson</surname><given-names>SE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cudlip</surname><given-names>AC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>MW</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Examining Muscle Activity Differences During Single and Dual Vector Elastic Resistance Exercises</article-title><source>Int J Sports Phys Ther</source><year>2021</year><volume>16</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>322</fpage><lpage>34</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.26603/001c.21309</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33842028</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8016432</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR13" publication-type="journal">Bench RW, Thompson SE, Cudlip AC, Holmes MW. Examining Muscle Activity Differences During Single and Dual Vector Elastic Resistance Exercises. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2021;16(2):322–34.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33842028</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.26603/001c.21309</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8016432</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR14" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zemková</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Instability resistance training for health and performance</article-title><source>J Tradit Complement Med</source><year>2016</year><volume>7</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>245</fpage><lpage>50</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jtcme.2016.05.007</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28417093</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5388079</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR14" publication-type="journal">Zemková E. Instability resistance training for health and performance. J Tradit Complement Med. 2016;7(2):245–50.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28417093</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jtcme.2016.05.007</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5388079</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR15" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Seguin</surname><given-names>RC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cudlip</surname><given-names>AC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Holmes</surname><given-names>MWR</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The Efficacy of Upper-Extremity Elastic Resistance Training on Shoulder Strength and Performance: A Systematic Review</article-title><source>Sports (Basel)</source><year>2022</year><volume>10</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>24</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/sports10020024</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35202063</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8879764</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR15" publication-type="journal">Seguin RC, Cudlip AC, Holmes MWR. The Efficacy of Upper-Extremity Elastic Resistance Training on Shoulder Strength and Performance: A Systematic Review. Sports (Basel). 2022;10(2):24.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35202063</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3390/sports10020024</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8879764</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR16" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Aagaard</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Simonsen</surname><given-names>EB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Andersen</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Magnusson</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dyhre-Poulsen</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Increased rate of force development and neural drive of human skeletal muscle following resistance training</article-title><source>J Appl Physiol</source><year>2002</year><volume>93</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>1318</fpage><lpage>26</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00283.2002</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12235031</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR16" publication-type="journal">Aagaard P, Simonsen EB, Andersen JL, Magnusson P, Dyhre-Poulsen P. Increased rate of force development and neural drive of human skeletal muscle following resistance training. J Appl Physiol. 2002;93(4):1318–26.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12235031</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1152/japplphysiol.00283.2002</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR17" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Neyzi</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Günöz</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Furman</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bundak</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gökçay</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Darendeliler</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Baş</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Türk çocuklarında vücut ağırlığı, boy uzunluğu, baş çevresi ve vücut kitle indeksi referans değerleri</article-title><source>Çocuk Sağlığı ve Hastalıkları Dergisi</source><year>2008</year><volume>51</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>14</lpage></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR17" publication-type="journal">Neyzi O, Günöz H, Furman A, Bundak R, Gökçay G, Darendeliler F, Baş F. Türk çocuklarında vücut ağırlığı, boy uzunluğu, baş çevresi ve vücut kitle indeksi referans değerleri. Çocuk Sağlığı ve Hastalıkları Dergisi. 2008;51(1):1–14.</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR18" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Loturco</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>D’Antino</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ghedini</surname><given-names>LG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jeffreys</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Simim</surname><given-names>MAM</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Validity and reliability of speed tests used in soccer: A systematic review</article-title><source>J Sports Sci</source><year>2019</year><volume>37</volume><issue>18</issue><fpage>2157</fpage><lpage>70</lpage></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR18" publication-type="journal">Loturco I, D’Antino E, Ghedini LG, Jeffreys I, Simim MAM. Validity and reliability of speed tests used in soccer: A systematic review. J Sports Sci. 2019;37(18):2157–70.</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR19" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tomlin</surname><given-names>DL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wenger</surname><given-names>HA</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The relationship between aerobic fitness and recovery from high intensity intermittent exercise</article-title><source>Sports Med</source><year>2001</year><volume>31</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>1</fpage><lpage>11</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2165/00007256-200131010-00001</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11219498</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR19" publication-type="journal">Tomlin DL, Wenger HA. The relationship between aerobic fitness and recovery from high intensity intermittent exercise. Sports Med. 2001;31(1):1–11.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11219498</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2165/00007256-200131010-00001</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR20" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Colado</surname><given-names>JC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Triplett</surname><given-names>NT</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effects of training with elastic bands on body composition, strength, and power in athletic older adults</article-title><source>J Strength Cond Res</source><year>2008</year><volume>22</volume><issue>5</issue><fpage>1435</fpage><lpage>42</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31817ae67a</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18714245</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR20" publication-type="journal">Colado JC, Triplett NT. Effects of training with elastic bands on body composition, strength, and power in athletic older adults. J Strength Cond Res. 2008;22(5):1435–42.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31817ae67a</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18714245</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR21" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cormie</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>McGuigan</surname><given-names>MR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Newton</surname><given-names>RU</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Developing maximal neuromuscular power: Part 2—Training considerations for improving maximal power production</article-title><source>Sports Med</source><year>2011</year><volume>41</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>125</fpage><lpage>46</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2165/11538500-000000000-00000</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21244105</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR21" publication-type="journal">Cormie P, McGuigan MR, Newton RU. Developing maximal neuromuscular power: Part 2—Training considerations for improving maximal power production. Sports Med. 2011;41(2):125–46.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21244105</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2165/11538500-000000000-00000</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR22" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Folland</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Williams</surname><given-names>AG</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The adaptations to strength training: morphological and neurological contributions to increased strength</article-title><source>Sports Med</source><year>2007</year><volume>37</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>145</fpage><lpage>68</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2165/00007256-200737020-00004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17241104</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR22" publication-type="journal">Folland JP, Williams AG. The adaptations to strength training: morphological and neurological contributions to increased strength. Sports Med. 2007;37(2):145–68.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">17241104</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2165/00007256-200737020-00004</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR23" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wallace</surname><given-names>BJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Winchester</surname><given-names>JB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>McGuigan</surname><given-names>MR</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Effects of elastic bands on force and power characteristics during the back squat exercise</article-title><source>J Strength Cond Res</source><year>2006</year><volume>20</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>268</fpage><lpage>72</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16686552</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1519/R-16854.1</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR23" publication-type="journal">Wallace BJ, Winchester JB, McGuigan MR. Effects of elastic bands on force and power characteristics during the back squat exercise. J Strength Cond Res. 2006;20(2):268–72.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16686552</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1519/R-16854.1</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR24"><label>24.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR24" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Joyner</surname><given-names>MJ</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>The sex difference in athletic performance</article-title><source>Front Physiol</source><year>2017</year><volume>8</volume><fpage>808</fpage></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR24" publication-type="journal">Joyner MJ. The sex difference in athletic performance. Front Physiol. 2017;8:808.29089904
</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR25"><label>25.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR25" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tønnessen</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Svendsen</surname><given-names>IS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Olsen</surname><given-names>IC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Guttormsen</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Haugen</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Performance Development in Adolescent Track and Field Athletes According to Age, Sex and Sport Discipline</article-title><source>PLoS ONE</source><year>2015</year><volume>10</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>e0129014</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0129014</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26043192</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4456243</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR25" publication-type="journal">Tønnessen E, Svendsen IS, Olsen IC, Guttormsen A, Haugen T. Performance Development in Adolescent Track and Field Athletes According to Age, Sex and Sport Discipline. PLoS ONE. 2015;10(6):e0129014.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26043192</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1371/journal.pone.0129014</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4456243</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>