<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article article-type="research-article" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">J Epidemiol Glob Health</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">J Epidemiol Glob Health</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">3870</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">jegh</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Journal of Epidemiology and Global Health</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">2210-6006</issn><issn pub-type="epub">2210-6014</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Springer</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC13046983</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC13046983.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">13046983</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">13046983</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">41857332</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s44197-026-00523-0</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">523</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Research</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Epidemiological Measles Outbreaks Investigation in Nogob Zone, Somali Region, Eastern Ethiopia: Trends and Insights from 2019 To 2024</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Abdi</surname><given-names initials="AB">Ahmed Bihi</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1">1</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Abdilaahi</surname><given-names initials="SM">Seid Muhumed</given-names></name><address><email>seidmuhumedabdilaahi@gmail.com</email><email>seid.muhumed@jju.edu.et</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff2">2</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Maalin</surname><given-names initials="MA">Mohammed Adem</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff3">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ibrahim</surname><given-names initials="AM">Ahmed Mohammed</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff4">4</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff5">5</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff6">6</xref></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><label>1</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/033v2cg93</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.449426.9</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1783 7069</institution-id><institution>Regional COVAX and Immunization Officer, </institution><institution>World Health Organization, </institution></institution-wrap>Jigjiga, Somali Regional State Ethiopia </aff><aff id="Aff2"><label>2</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/033v2cg93</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.449426.9</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1783 7069</institution-id><institution>Department of Pediatrics and Child Health Nursing, Institute of Health Science, </institution><institution>Jigjiga University, </institution></institution-wrap>Jigjiga, Ethiopia </aff><aff id="Aff3"><label>3</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/033v2cg93</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.449426.9</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1783 7069</institution-id><institution>Field hub coordinator, </institution><institution>World Health Organization, </institution></institution-wrap>Jigjiga, Somali Regional State Ethiopia </aff><aff id="Aff4"><label>4</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/033v2cg93</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.449426.9</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1783 7069</institution-id><institution>Department of Public Health, Institute of Health Science, </institution><institution>Jigjiga University, </institution></institution-wrap>Jigjiga, Ethiopia </aff><aff id="Aff5"><label>5</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/03adhka07</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.416786.a</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 0587 0574</institution-id><institution>Swiss Tropical and Public Health Institute, </institution></institution-wrap>Kreuzstrasse 2, Allschwil, 4123 Switzerland </aff><aff id="Aff6"><label>6</label><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/02s6k3f65</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.6612.3</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 1937 0642</institution-id><institution>University of Basel, </institution></institution-wrap>Petersplatz 1, Basel, 4003 Switzerland </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>19</day><month>3</month><year>2026</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><month>12</month><year>2026</year></pub-date><volume>16</volume><issue>1</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">504529</issue-id><elocation-id>44</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>7</day><month>8</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>30</day><month>1</month><year>2026</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>19</day><month>03</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>04</day><month>04</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2026-04-04 00:25:13.100"><day>04</day><month>04</month><year>2026</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>© The Author(s) 2026</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2026</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License, which permits any non-commercial use, sharing, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons licence, and indicate if you modified the licensed material. You do not have permission under this licence to share adapted material derived from this article or parts of it. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article’s Creative Commons licence, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article’s Creative Commons licence and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this licence, visit <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="44197_2026_Article_523.pdf"/><abstract id="Abs1" abstract-type="structured"><sec><title>Background</title><p id="Par1">Measles remains a major vaccine-preventable cause of childhood morbidity and mortality, particularly in low-coverage settings. Measles remains endemic in Ethiopia, and Somali Regional State (SRS) experiences high incidence rates despite vaccination efforts.</p></sec><sec><title>Objectives</title><p id="Par2">This study aimed to investigate measles outbreaks and provide critical insights into the epidemiological trends.</p></sec><sec><title>Methods</title><p id="Par3">A retrospective descriptive study was conducted using surveillance data from Nogob Zone. All reported measles cases (confirmed, epidemiologically linked, and clinically compatible; <italic toggle="yes">n</italic> = 2,214) were included through inclusion of complete line lists. WHO case definitions were applied. Data were analyzed using Microsoft Excel, Epi-Info, and ArcGIS 10.8 to generate descriptive statistics, epidemiological curves, attack rates, and spatial maps.</p></sec><sec><title>Results</title><p id="Par4">From 2019 to 2024, a total of 2,214 measles cases and 58 deaths were reported (case fatality rate: 2.6%), exceeding national rates. Children aged 5–14 years were most affected (42%), followed by those aged 15 years and older (33%). Geographically, Duhun and Garbo woredas had the highest attack rates (18 and 17 per 1,000 population, respectively). The outbreak peaked in 2023, with a decline thereafter.</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusions</title><p id="Par5">The study shows that Nogob Zone has faced a substantial measles burden, reporting 2,214 cases and a 2.6% case fatality rate between 2019 and 2024. The notably high attack rates observed in Garbo and Duhun woredas, along with a major outbreak surge in early 2023, point to persistent gaps in vaccination coverage and systemic barriers. Strengthening routine immunization, improving surveillance, and implementing targeted catch-up campaigns are recommended to prevent future outbreaks.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group xml:lang="en"><title>Keywords</title><kwd>Measles</kwd><kwd>Outbreak</kwd><kwd>Epidemiology</kwd><kwd>Investigation</kwd><kwd>Nogob</kwd><kwd>Somali regional state</kwd><kwd>Ethiopia</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-ND</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>© Springer Nature B.V 2026</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par6">Measles, caused by a highly contagious morbillivirus of the Paramyxoviridae family, remains a leading vaccine-preventable cause of childhood mortality worldwide [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>]. The virus transmits via respiratory droplets and persists in airborne particles for up to two hours, facilitating rapid outbreaks in under-immunized populations [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>]. Before widespread vaccination, measles caused an estimated 2.6 million deaths annually worldwide and led to 15,000–60,000 cases of blindness each year (mostly in children) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR4">4</xref>].</p><p id="Par7">Global efforts have achieved significant progress. Between 2000 and 2021, measles vaccination prevented an estimated 56 million deaths [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR5">5</xref>]. However, measles cases surged to an estimated 10.3 million worldwide in 2023 a 20% increase from 2022 resulting in approximately 107,500 deaths, mostly among unvaccinated or under‑vaccinated children under 5 years [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref>]. Despite vaccination averting 60.3 million deaths from 2000 to 2023 and WHO regional elimination pledges, no region sustained measles-free status by 2023; COVID-19 dropped first-dose measles-containing vaccine (MCV1) coverage to 81% (lowest since 2008) and second-dose measles-containing vaccine (MCV2) to 74%, with only partial recovery to 83% MCV1 and 74% MCV2 in 2022–2023 amid stalled progress and outbreaks in 57 countries [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref>].</p><p id="Par8">Ethiopia faces persistent measles endemicity, with annual outbreaks reported nationwide. There were an estimated 149,415 confirmed cases of measles in Ethiopia from 2000 to 2023 [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref>]. From August 2021 to May 2023, the country reported 16,814 laboratory-confirmed measles cases and 182 deaths, resulting in a case fatality ratio of 1.1%. Notably, the annual number of confirmed measles cases increased significantly from 1,953 in 2021 to 9,291 in 2022, indicating an almost fivefold rise. In 2022, the nationwide measles incidence rate was 82 cases per one million population. The highest reported rates were in the Somali region, which reported 540 cases per one million population. Factors contributing to this surge include low population immunity, concurrent epidemics, conflict, forced displacement, and other humanitarian crises that disrupt routine childhood vaccinations [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>].</p><p id="Par9">Between 1 January and 2 April 2023, the Somali Region reported 56 laboratory-confirmed measles cases and 364 epidemiologically linked cases. In 2022, the national measles incidence rate was 82 cases per one million population; however, the Somali Region reported the highest incidence, with 540 cases per one million population [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>].</p><p id="Par10">The region represents a clear example of regional vulnerability in the context of public health and infectious disease control. Limited health infrastructure, nomadic population movement, and recurring humanitarian challenges contribute to the amplification of measles outbreaks.</p><p id="Par11">A spatial analysis conducted between 2022 and 2023 demonstrated a marked geographic concentration of measles cases within the Somali Region. The Nogob zone was disproportionately affected, accounting for 37.7% of all reported cases, followed by the Erer zone (17.3%) and the Jarar zone (16.1%).</p><p id="Par12">Children under five years of age were the most affected group, representing 88.7% of all cases. Additionally, more than two-thirds of cases (82.6%) developed complications, highlighting the severe impact of measles outbreaks and the heightened vulnerability of young children in this setting [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>].</p><p id="Par13">Vaccination coverage in these areas remains alarmingly low. As reported in the aforementioned spatial analysis in the Somali Region shown that the MCV1 was administered to only 53.8% of the population, while MCV2 coverage reached 80.4%. Overall, the region’s measles vaccination coverage stood at 59.4%, with a measles incidence rate of 0.087 cases per 100 people [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>]. This is significantly below the 95% coverage threshold recommended by the WHO to achieve herd immunity and prevent measles transmission [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref>]. Nationally, Ethiopia struggles with MCV2 pooled coverage at 50.5% (95% CI: 39.0-61.9%), lowest in Somali (21.4%) and Afar regions [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref>]. These gaps leave populations susceptible, particularly in hard-to-reach pastoralist areas prone to outbreaks.</p><p id="Par14">Several factors contribute to the low vaccination coverage in Ethiopia generally. A qualitative study identified substantial health system barriers, including restricted availability of immunization services, vaccine stockouts, shortages of cold chain technologies, and data inaccuracies due to deliberate falsification or accidental manipulation [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>]. These systemic challenges undermine effective vaccination program delivery and compromise immunization data accuracy, complicating efforts to identify and reach unvaccinated children. Despite these efforts, challenges persist, underscoring the need for ongoing epidemiological investigations to inform targeted interventions, therefore, this study investigates epidemiological patterns of measles outbreaks in Nogob Zone, Somali Region, Eastern Ethiopia, from 2019 to 2024. Findings aim to guide targeted interventions, enhancing elimination strategies amid evolving threats.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2"><title>Methods and Materials</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>Study Area</title><p id="Par15">The study was conducted in Nogob, a zone in the Somali Region of Ethiopia. The Nogob Zone is bordered on the south by Gode Zone, on the southwest by Afder Zone, on the west and northwest by the Oromia Region, on the north by Fafan Zone, on the east by Jarar Zone, and on the southeast by Korahe Zone. The Erer River flows through this zone. Nogob has 7 woredas: Ayun, Segeg, Garbo, Horushagah, Elweyne, Dihun, and Hararey (Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>).</p><p id="Par16">
<fig id="Fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 1</label><caption><p>Nogob Zone Map</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e343" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="44197_2026_523_Fig1_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec4"><title>Study Design and Period</title><p id="Par17">A retrospective descriptive study was conducted using surveillance data collected from 2019 to 2024.</p></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Population</title><p id="Par18">The source population includes all individuals living in the Nogob zone, while the study population comprises all confirmed measles cases, epidemiologically linked and clinically compatible measles cases identified during the measles outbreak in the zone.</p></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Inclusion and Exclusion Criteria</title><p id="Par19">The study included completed measles outbreak line lists databases, whereas incomplete line lists were excluded from the study.</p></sec><sec id="Sec7"><title>Sample Size Determination</title><p id="Par20">The study included all measles outbreak surveillance line lists reported within the study period. As all eligible records were analyzed, no sampling technique or sample size calculation was applied. This complete inclusion of available surveillance data enhanced the validity and reliability of the findings.</p><sec id="Sec8"><title>Data Collection Tools</title><p id="Par21">Data were collected using a standardized measles outbreak line list tailored to the Ethiopian context, presented in English. The line list included various fields such as serial number, region, zone, woredas, country of origin, reporting HF, outpatient/inpatient, name of patient, sex, age (in years), age (in months), age group, Kebele/PA’s town, sub-kebele, Date for onset of rash, date seen at health facilities, Epi week, No. of valid measles doses (0, 1, 2, 3, 99), specimen taken (yes/no), lab results, complication (yes/no), outcome (alive or dead), fever (y/n), rash (y/n), cough (y/n), conjunctivitis, (red eyes) y/n, coryza(runny nose) y/n, year and along with any additional comments.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec9"><title>Data Quality Control</title><p id="Par22">Data quality was maintained through spot-checking and thorough review of the complete Line lists by the SMA, AMI and MAM, ensuring that all information was both complete and consistent.</p></sec><sec id="Sec10"><title>Operational Definition</title><sec id="FPar1"><title>Suspected Measles Case</title><p id="Par23">An illness in a patient with fever and generalized maculopapular (non-vesicular) rash, or in a patient whom a health care worker suspects has measles.</p></sec><sec id="FPar2"><title>Clinical Measles Case</title><p id="Par24">Any person in whom a clinician suspects measles infection; or Any person with fever and maculopapular rash (i.e., non-vesicular) and.</p><p>
<list list-type="bullet"><list-item><p id="Par26">Cough, or.</p></list-item><list-item><p id="Par27">Coryza (i.e., runny nose) or.</p></list-item><list-item><p id="Par28">Conjunctivitis (i.e., red eyes).</p></list-item></list>
</p></sec><sec id="FPar3"><title>Laboratory-confirmed Measles Case</title><p id="Par29">A suspected case of measles that has been confirmed positive by testing in a proficient laboratory, and vaccine-associated illness has been ruled out.</p></sec><sec id="FPar4"><title>Epidemiologically Linked Measles Case</title><p id="Par30">A clinical case of measles that has not been confirmed by a laboratory, but was geographically and temporally related, with dates of rash onset occurring 7–21 days apart from a laboratory-confirmed case or another epidemiologically linked measles case.</p></sec><sec id="Sec11"><title>Data Analysis</title><p id="Par31">Data were cleaned and analyzed using Microsoft Excel for descriptive statistics (frequencies, percentages, means). Attack rates (cases per 1,000 population) were calculated by woredas using population estimates. Epidemiological curves (weekly cases over time) were generated. Spatial distribution was mapped using ArcGIS 10.8 (spot maps of case counts by woredas). Age, sex, vaccination status, laboratory confirmation, and case fatality were summarized with tables.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec12"><title>Results</title><sec id="Sec13"><title>Overall Case Burden and Mortality</title><p id="Par32">From 2019 to 2024, a total of 2,214 measles cases were reported in the Nogob Zone, with 58 deaths, resulting in a case fatality rate (CFR) of 2.6%. The analysis excluded five incomplete line lists. While sporadic cases were reported throughout 2022, the region experienced a major epidemic wave in the first quarter of 2023. This was followed by a gradual tapering of the outbreak, with significantly lower and more stabilized case counts observed throughout the latter half of 2023 and into January 2024 (Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>).</p></sec><sec id="Sec14"><title>Trends in Measles Outbreak Epi Curve Analysis</title><p id="Par33">The epidemiological curve shows that the number of reported cases began to rise gradually in late 2022, with a marked surge in cases starting around November 2022. The outbreak reached its peak between January and February 2023, with the highest weekly case counts observed during this period.</p><p id="Par34">Following the peak, there was a noticeable decline in cases starting from March 2023, with sporadic smaller peaks occurring throughout the following months. By mid-2023 and into early 2024, the number of new cases continued to drop, stabilizing at much lower levels with only occasional cases reported (Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>).</p><p id="Par35">
<fig id="Fig2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 2</label><caption><p>Epidemiological Curve of Measles Outbreak in Nogob Zone, Somali Region (2019–2024)</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e430" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="44197_2026_523_Fig2_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec15"><title>Case Distribution by Age Group</title><p id="Par36">A children aged 5–14 years were the most affected, comprising 42% of cases, followed by those aged 15 years and older at 33% while only 5% of cases involved infants aged 0 to 11 months. This distribution underscores the vulnerability of school-aged children (Table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>).</p><p id="Par37">
<table-wrap id="Tab1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Measles case distribution by age group in nogob Zone, Somali region 2019 to 2024</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Age Group</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Number of cases reported</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Percentage of reported cases</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0–11 Months</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">110</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5%</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1–4 Years</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">450</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">20%</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5–14 Years</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">934</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">42%</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">≥ 15 Years</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">720</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">33%</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Total</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>2</bold>,<bold>214</bold></td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<bold>100%</bold>
</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec16"><title>Laboratory Confirmed Cases by Woreda</title><p id="Par38">A total of 21 samples were collected across from the woredas in which a total of 11 cases were IgM positive. Elweyne and Sagag woreda were the highest positivity rate among tasted samples followed by Horshagah woreda. Meanwhile, Garbo woreda shows low number of samples tested compared to the number of cases reported by the woreda (Table <xref rid="Tab2" ref-type="table">2</xref>).</p><p id="Par39">
<table-wrap id="Tab2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Laboratory confirmed cases by woreda in nogob Zone, Somali region 2019 to 2024</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Woreda</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Number of cases</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Number of samples collected</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Number of Cases IgM Positive</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Elweyne</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">16</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Garbo</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1249</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"/></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Horshagah</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">112</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sagag</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">164</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Total</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1541</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">21</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec17"><title>Vaccination Status by Woreda</title><p id="Par40">Vaccination coverage varied across the seven woredas in Nogob Zone from 2019 to 2024. Garbo and Duhun recorded the highest numbers for all antigens, while Hararey and Ayun had the lowest uptake. All woredas showed a consistent decline from Penta 1 to Penta 3 and further reductions through MCV1 and MCV2, with the sharpest drop‑offs observed in Hararey and Horshagah. Elweyne demonstrated the best continuity of vaccination, maintaining relatively small gaps between doses (Table <xref rid="Tab3" ref-type="table">3</xref>).</p><p id="Par41">
<table-wrap id="Tab3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3</label><caption><p>Vaccination status by woreda in nogob Zone, Somali region on five years of RI data</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Woreda</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Pentavalent 1st</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Pentavalent 3rd</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">MCV1</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">MCV2</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Ayun</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3274</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2944</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2444</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2362</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Elweyne</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4899</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4705</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4651</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4508</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Duhun</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8588</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7486</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5734</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4292</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Garbo</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10,062</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7610</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7279</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6655</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Hararey</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2830</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1944</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2108</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1478</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Horshagah</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2872</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2372</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2154</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1313</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sagag</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7319</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6142</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5132</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3715</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p><bold>Source</bold>: DHIS2 MoH</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec18"><title>Attack Rate by Woreda</title><p id="Par42">A geographic analysis revealed that Duhun woreda had the highest attack rate at 18 per 1,000 populations, followed closely by Garbo woreda with 17 per 1,000. In contrast, Elweyne woreda experienced the lowest impact, with an attack rate of 0.42 per 1,000 (Table <xref rid="Tab4" ref-type="table">4</xref>).</p><p id="Par43">
<table-wrap id="Tab4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 4</label><caption><p>Attack rate of the outbreak by woreda in nogob Zone, Somali region 2019 to 2024</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Woreda</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Total Population</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Number of cases</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Number of Deaths</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Attack Rate (per 1,000)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Ayun</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">25,457</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">211</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8.29</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Elweyne</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">37,799</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">16</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.42</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Duhun</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">21,916</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">400</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">18.25</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Garbo</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">72,323</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1249</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">31</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">17.27</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Hararey</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">24,574</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">62</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.52</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Horshagah</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">19,373</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">112</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5.78</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sagag</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">58,255</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">164</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.82</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Zonal</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>259</bold>,<bold>697</bold></td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><bold>2</bold>,<bold>214</bold></td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<bold>58</bold>
</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<bold>8.53</bold>
</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec19"><title>Case Distribution and Fatality Rates by Sex</title><p id="Par44">Among the reported measles cases, 1,164 (52.5%) were male and 1,053 (47.5%) were female. The case fatality rate (CFR) was 2.6% for males and 2.5% for females, indicating similar mortality outcomes between the two sexes (Table <xref rid="Tab5" ref-type="table">5</xref>).</p><p id="Par45">
<table-wrap id="Tab5" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 5</label><caption><p>Case distribution and fatality rates by sex of measles cases in nogob Zone, Somali region 2019 to 2024</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sex</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Number of cases</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Number of deaths</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">CFR</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Male</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1164</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">31</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.6</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Female</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1050</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">27</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.5</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Total</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2214</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">58</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.6</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec20"><title>Case Fatality by Age Group</title><p id="Par46">Out of 2,214 reported measles cases, a total of 58 deaths were documented, resulting in an overall CFR of 2.6%, which exceeds the WHO emergency threshold. The highest fatality occurred among infants (7.3%) and children aged 1–4 years (5.1%), reflecting the critical vulnerability of under-five children due to low immunization coverage and limited access to timely case management (Table <xref rid="Tab6" ref-type="table">6</xref>).</p><p id="Par47">
<table-wrap id="Tab6" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 6</label><caption><p>Case fatality by age group of measles cases in nogob Zone, Somali region 2019 to 2024</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Age Group</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cases</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Deaths</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">CFR %</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0–11 Months</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">110</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7.3%</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1–4 Years</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">450</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">23</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5.1%</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5–14 Years</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">934</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">19</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.0%</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">≥ 15 Years</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">720</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.1%</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Total</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2,214</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">58</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.6%</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec21"><title>Spatial Analysis of Measles Case Burden</title><p id="Par48">The spot map revealed that there are marked variations in the measles burden among the woredas, with the highest concentration of cases observed in Garbo woreda, which reported 1,249 cases. Dhuxun woreda also exhibited a high caseload, with 400 cases reported over the same period. Intermediate levels of cases were noted in Ayun (211 cases), Horashagah (112 cases), and Sagag (164 cases), while relatively low counts were observed in Hararey (62 cases) and Elweyne (16 cases).</p><p id="Par49">This spatial pattern indicates that the measles outbreak was particularly severe in central and northeastern Zone, especially Garbo and Dhuxun. The varying caseloads across woredas may reflect differences in population density, immunization coverage, or healthcare access (Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>).</p><p id="Par50">
<fig id="Fig3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 3</label><caption><p>Spot Map of Measles Cases in Nogob Zone, Somali Region (2019–2024)</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e986" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="44197_2026_523_Fig3_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec22"><title>Discussion</title><p id="Par51">In this outbreak investigation period from 2019 to 2024, a total of 2,214 cases were reported and 58 deaths occurred, resulting in a case fatality rate (CFR) of 2.6%. This substantial burden exceeds the national CFR of 1.1% reported between August 2021 and May 2023 (16,814 cases, 182 deaths) and the updated national CFR of 0.81% through December 2024 (78,106 cases, 633 deaths) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref>]. This CFR aligns with findings from other Ethiopian regions facing similar access barriers, such as Artuma Fursi woreda CFR 2.6%, and Tocha District CFR 2.72% [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR16">16</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR17">17</xref>].</p><p id="Par52">This elevated CFR may reflect limited healthcare access, delays in case detection, and challenges in managing complications, particularly among children under five, who accounted for 88.7% of cases in prior regional studies [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>]. The severity of outbreaks in Nogob Zone underscores the need for strengthened health system interventions to mitigate morbidity and mortality. This study reported attack rate (8.53 per 1,000) falls near the median of other Ethiopian outbreaks from the last decade, where rates have ranged between 4 and 12 per 1,000 in the region and nearby regions [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR20">20</xref>]. However, significant local variation was observed: Duhun and Garbo woredas experienced the highest attack rates (18 and 17 per 1,000, respectively). These findings are in line with previous analyses that identified heterogeneous attack rates across regions and woredas depending on local risk factors and immunity gaps [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR18">18</xref>].</p><p id="Par53">The age distribution revealed 42% of cases in children aged 5–14 years and 33% in individuals ≥ 15 years, diverging markedly from global patterns where 70–80% burden children under 5 years [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref>]. This atypical shift parallels Somali Region trends (Jarar: 45% in 5–14 years; Dollo Zone: 30% adults) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR21">21</xref>] and signals accumulated immunity debt from chronic MCV1 (53.8%) and MCV2 (80.4%) shortfalls below WHO’s 95% herd immunity threshold [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR22">22</xref>]. Expanding preventive and reactive campaigns to 15 years, as per updated WHO guidelines, becomes essential for catch-up strategies targeting school-age children and adolescents [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR23">23</xref>].</p><p id="Par54">Geographic analysis revealed significant variation in attack rates, with Duhun (18 per 1,000) and Garbo (17 per 1,000) woredas being the most affected. Garbo woreda, with 1,249 cases, was the epicenter of the outbreak, likely driven by higher population density or lower immunization coverage, as the region’s overall vaccination coverage of 59.4% falls well below the WHO-recommended 95% for herd immunity [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>]. These results are consistent with prior spatial analyses identifying Nogob Zone as a measles hotspot, contributing 37.7% of regional cases [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>]. The clustering of cases in Garbo and Duhun emphasizes the need for geographically targeted interventions.</p><p id="Par55">The epidemiological curve reveals a sharp increase in measles cases beginning in November 2022, reaching its peak between January and February 2023, and then gradually declining. This decline likely reflects the impact of reactive vaccination campaigns and/or a natural increase in population immunity. Despite the overall reduction, sporadic cases continued into 2024, indicating ongoing transmission risks and highlighting that the outbreak was not fully eliminated. This pattern suggests a large-scale outbreak with a distinct peak, followed by effective control measures or natural decline due to increased immunity, resulting in a significant reduction in new cases over time. The data emphasize the need for timely outbreak response and sustained surveillance to prevent future surges. However, systemic barriers such as vaccine stockouts, cold chain deficiencies, and data inaccuracies identified in previous studies continue to undermine immunization efforts [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref>]. The low MCV1 coverage (53.8%) and slightly higher MCV2 coverage (80.4%) in Nogob Zone further contribute to susceptibility [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref>].</p><p id="Par56">Males accounted for 52.5% of reported cases, while females accounted for 47.5%. The case fatality rates were similar between the two sexes, at 2.6% among males and 2.5% among females. The interplay of conflict, displacement, and concurrent epidemics, as noted in previous reports, likely disrupted routine immunization, exacerbating the outbreak [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref>, <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref>]. These findings underscore the need for comprehensive strategies to address both health system and contextual challenges.</p><sec id="Sec23"><title>Conclusion and Recommendations</title><p id="Par57">This study revealed that measles continues to pose a substantial public health challenge in Nogob Zone, Somali Region, Eastern Ethiopia, driven by persistent immunity gaps and health system constraints. The observed age distribution, geographic clustering, and temporal pattern of the outbreak emphasize the critical need to address vaccination coverage shortfalls, particularly among school-aged children and in high-burden woredas.</p><p id="Par58">To prevent future outbreaks, it’s recommended that public health authorities strengthen routine immunization, improve cold chain infrastructure, and improve surveillance. Targeted catch-up campaigns for children and adolescents, community engagement, and integrating measles vaccination into emergency responses are crucial.</p></sec></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher’s Note</bold></p><p>Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Author Contributions</title><p>S.M.A., A.B.A., and A.M.I. Conceptualization of the study, methodology, data collection, performed statistical analysis, interpretation and drafted the manuscript. S.M.A., A.B.A., and M.A.M. provided critical insights and revisions to the final manuscript. All authors reviewed and approved the final version prior to submission.</p></notes><notes notes-type="funding-information"><title>Funding</title><p>There is no funding provided.</p></notes><notes notes-type="data-availability"><title>Data Availability</title><p>The raw data supporting the conclusions of this article will be made available by the authors, without undue reservation.</p></notes><notes><title>Declarations</title><notes id="FPar5"><title>Consent for Publication</title><p id="Par59">Not applicable.</p></notes><notes id="FPar6" notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing interests</title><p id="Par60">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes><notes id="FPar7"><title>Ethical Approval</title><p id="Par61">Ethical approval was not required for this study. However, an exemption letter was obtained from Jigjiga University.</p></notes></notes><glossary><title>Abbreviations</title><def-list><def-item><term>CFR</term><def><p id="Par62">Case fatality rateEPI: Expanded Programme on ImmunizationMCV1:The first routine dose of the measles-containing vaccine</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>MCV2</term><def><p id="Par63">The second routine dose of the measles-containing vaccine</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>SRS</term><def><p id="Par64">Somali Regional State</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>WHO</term><def><p id="Par65">World Health Organization</p></def></def-item></def-list></glossary><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR1" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Douangboupha</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Binns</surname><given-names>PL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Khamphaphongphane</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Oulay</surname><given-names>VS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sengsaiya</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Boupphaphanh</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Factors contributing to a measles outbreak in a hard-to-reach rural village in Xaisomboun Province, Lao people’s Democratic Republic</article-title><source>Western Pac Surveillance Response Journal: WPSAR</source><year>2022</year><volume>13</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>1</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36313970</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.5365/wpsar.2022.13.3.874</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9583712</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR1" publication-type="journal">Douangboupha V, Binns PL, Khamphaphongphane B, Oulay VS, Sengsaiya K, Boupphaphanh T, et al. Factors contributing to a measles outbreak in a hard-to-reach rural village in Xaisomboun Province, Lao people’s Democratic Republic. Western Pac Surveillance Response Journal: WPSAR. 2022;13(3):1.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36313970</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.5365/wpsar.2022.13.3.874</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9583712</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Minta AA. Progress toward measles elimination—worldwide, 2000–2023. MMWR Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report. 2024;73.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.15585/mmwr.mm7345a4</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11576049</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39541251</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">WHO. Measles. WHO. (2024). Available online at: <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/measles">https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/measles</ext-link> 2024.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Measles W. rubella strategic framework: 2021–2030. Geneva: World Health Organization. 2020:1–34.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Newsroom C. Global progress against measles threatened amidst COVID-19 pandemic. Google Scholar. 2021.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Organization WH. Measles cases surge worldwide, infecting 10.3 million people in 2023. 2024.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11629650</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39658122</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">(WHO) WHO. Measles Key facts World Health Organization (WHO). 2024. Available from: https://wwwwhoint/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/measles. 2024.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR8" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Eshetu</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tosisa</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Regassa</surname><given-names>BT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hundie</surname><given-names>GB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mulu</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Epidemiology of measles outbreaks, incidence and associated risk factors in Ethiopia from 2000 to 2023: a systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title><source>BMC Infect Dis</source><year>2024</year><volume>24</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>914</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12879-024-09828-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39227789</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11370270</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR8" publication-type="journal">Eshetu D, Tosisa W, Regassa BT, Hundie GB, Mulu A. Epidemiology of measles outbreaks, incidence and associated risk factors in Ethiopia from 2000 to 2023: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Infect Dis. 2024;24(1):914.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39227789</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12879-024-09828-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11370270</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Organization WH. Measles – Ethiopia. Disease Outbreak News. 2023 May 4. Available from: https://wwwwhoint/emergencies/disease-outbreak-news/item/2023-DON460. 2023.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR10" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Auwal</surname><given-names>BM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Adegoke</surname><given-names>AA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zafar</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Noor</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Oduoye</surname><given-names>MO</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Breaking the vaccination challenges to fight measles in Ethiopia</article-title><source>IJS Global Health</source><year>2024</year><volume>7</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>e0382</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/GH9.0000000000000382</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR10" publication-type="journal">Auwal BM, Adegoke AA, Zafar H, Noor Z, Oduoye MO. Breaking the vaccination challenges to fight measles in Ethiopia. IJS Global Health. 2024;7(1):e0382.</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR11" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Muse</surname><given-names>AI</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kayat</surname><given-names>MY</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Aden</surname><given-names>MH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shuramu</surname><given-names>JB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mohammed</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ibrahim</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Spatial analysis of measles cases and vaccination coverage in the Somali region, Eastern Ethiopia</article-title><source>Front Epidemiol</source><year>2025</year><volume>5</volume><fpage>1498750</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fepid.2025.1498750</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40007934</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11847850</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR11" publication-type="journal">Muse AI, Kayat MY, Aden MH, Shuramu JB, Mohammed S, Ibrahim MA, et al. Spatial analysis of measles cases and vaccination coverage in the Somali region, Eastern Ethiopia. Front Epidemiol. 2025;5:1498750.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40007934</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fepid.2025.1498750</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11847850</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR12" publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alemayehu</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tefera</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name></person-group><source>Measles second dose vaccination coverage and associated factors in ethiopia: A systematic review and meta-analysis</source><year>2025</year><publisher-loc>Vaccine</publisher-loc><publisher-name>X</publisher-name><fpage>100675</fpage></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR12" publication-type="book">Alemayehu A, Tefera S. Measles second dose vaccination coverage and associated factors in ethiopia: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Vaccine: X; 2025. p. 100675.</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR13" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Addis</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mekonnen</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Estifanos</surname><given-names>AS</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Health system barriers to the first dose of measles immunization in ethiopia: a qualitative study</article-title><source>BMC Public Health</source><year>2024</year><volume>24</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>665</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12889-024-18132-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38429806</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10908078</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR13" publication-type="journal">Addis M, Mekonnen W, Estifanos AS. Health system barriers to the first dose of measles immunization in ethiopia: a qualitative study. BMC Public Health. 2024;24(1):665.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38429806</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12889-024-18132-6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10908078</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">(WHO). WHO. Measles – Ethiopia. Disease Outbreak News. Available from: https://wwwwhoint/emergencies/disease-outbreak-news/item/2023-DON460. 2023.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Institute EPH. Ethiopian Public Health Institute. Strategy for elimination of measles &amp; rubella diseases in Ethiopia. Available from: https://ephigovet/strategy-for-elimination-of-measles-rubella-diseases-in-ethiopia-led-to-success/. 2024.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR16"><label>16.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR16" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tefera</surname><given-names>SF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Admasu</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Abebe</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Feyisa</surname><given-names>GC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Midaksa</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Measles outbreak investigation in Tocha district, Southwestern ethiopia: an unmatched case–control study</article-title><source>Front Public Health</source><year>2024</year><volume>12</volume><fpage>1331798</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2024.1331798</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38689775</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11060179</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR16" publication-type="journal">Tefera SF, Admasu N, Abebe H, Feyisa GC, Midaksa G. Measles outbreak investigation in Tocha district, Southwestern ethiopia: an unmatched case–control study. Front Public Health. 2024;12:1331798.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38689775</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fpubh.2024.1331798</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11060179</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR17"><label>17.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR17" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tariku</surname><given-names>MK</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Misikir</surname><given-names>SW</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Measles outbreak investigation in Artuma fursi Woreda, oromia zone, Amhara region, Ethiopia, 2018: a case control study</article-title><source>BMC Res Notes</source><year>2019</year><volume>12</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>765</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s13104-019-4806-y</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31752989</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6873760</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR17" publication-type="journal">Tariku MK, Misikir SW. Measles outbreak investigation in Artuma fursi Woreda, oromia zone, Amhara region, Ethiopia, 2018: a case control study. BMC Res Notes. 2019;12(1):765.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31752989</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s13104-019-4806-y</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6873760</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR18"><label>18.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR18" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tariku</surname><given-names>MK</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Worede</surname><given-names>DT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Belete</surname><given-names>AH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bante</surname><given-names>SA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Misikir</surname><given-names>SW</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Attack rate, case fatality rate and determinants of measles infection during a measles outbreak in ethiopia: systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title><source>BMC Infect Dis</source><year>2023</year><volume>23</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>756</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12879-023-08757-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37919689</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10623867</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR18" publication-type="journal">Tariku MK, Worede DT, Belete AH, Bante SA, Misikir SW. Attack rate, case fatality rate and determinants of measles infection during a measles outbreak in ethiopia: systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Infect Dis. 2023;23(1):756.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37919689</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1186/s12879-023-08757-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10623867</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR19"><label>19.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR19" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Shimelis</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Asrat</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tadege</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Feleke</surname><given-names>SF</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Measles outbreak investigation in berhet District, North Shewa, Ethiopia</article-title><source>Front Public Health</source><year>2024</year><volume>12</volume><fpage>1330205</fpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2024.1330205</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38756880</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11097952</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR19" publication-type="journal">Shimelis Y, Asrat A, Tadege T, Feleke SF. Measles outbreak investigation in berhet District, North Shewa, Ethiopia. Front Public Health. 2024;12:1330205.<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38756880</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.3389/fpubh.2024.1330205</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11097952</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR20"><label>20.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Tsegaye G, Gezahegn Y, Tesfaye A, Mulatu G, Bulcha GG, Berhanu N. Measles outbreak investigation in Guradamole District of bale zone, South Eastern Ethiopia, 2021. Infection and drug resistance. 2022:669 – 83.<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.2147/IDR.S343270</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8893148</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35250282</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR21"><label>21.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Girma T. Five years measles prevalence in Fafan zone, Somali region, Eastern ethiopia: descriptive surveillance data analysis. Haramaya University; 2020.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR22"><label>22.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Organization WH. Eliminating measles and rubella: framework for the verification process in the WHO European region 2014. World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe; 2014.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR23"><label>23.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Organization WH. Measles and rubella strategic framework: 2021–2030. 2020.</mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>