<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article article-type="research-article" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Sci Rep</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Sci Rep</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">1579</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">scirep</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Scientific Reports</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2045-2322</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Nature Publishing Group</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC13046755</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC13046755.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">13046755</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">13046755</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">41760799</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-40983-9</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">40983</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Research on damage size effect of cemented paste backfill under high sand-cement ratio conditions</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Jiang</surname><given-names initials="D">Dongjie</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names initials="H">Hao</given-names></name><address><email>15762284597@163.com</email></address><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sun</surname><given-names initials="G">Guangzhong</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="Aff1"/></contrib><aff id="Aff1"><institution-wrap><institution-id institution-id-type="ROR">https://ror.org/007wym039</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="GRID">grid.494634.8</institution-id><institution-id institution-id-type="ISNI">0000 0004 7423 8329</institution-id><institution>School of Resources and Safety Engineering, </institution><institution>Henan University of Engineering, </institution></institution-wrap>Zhengzhou, 451191 Henan China </aff></contrib-group><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>27</day><month>2</month><year>2026</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2026</year></pub-date><volume>16</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">503847</issue-id><elocation-id>11215</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>8</day><month>12</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>17</day><month>2</month><year>2026</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>27</day><month>02</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>04</day><month>04</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2026-04-04 00:25:13.100"><day>04</day><month>04</month><year>2026</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>© The Author(s) 2026</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2026</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p><bold>Open Access</bold> This article is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License, which permits any non-commercial use, sharing, distribution and reproduction in any medium or format, as long as you give appropriate credit to the original author(s) and the source, provide a link to the Creative Commons licence, and indicate if you modified the licensed material. You do not have permission under this licence to share adapted material derived from this article or parts of it. The images or other third party material in this article are included in the article’s Creative Commons licence, unless indicated otherwise in a credit line to the material. If material is not included in the article’s Creative Commons licence and your intended use is not permitted by statutory regulation or exceeds the permitted use, you will need to obtain permission directly from the copyright holder. To view a copy of this licence, visit <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ext-link>.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="41598_2026_Article_40983.pdf"/><abstract id="Abs1" abstract-type="unstructured"><p id="Par1">Difficulty in accurately measuring uniaxial compressive strength (UCS) under high sand-cement ratios due to press range limitations. To facilitate the computation of the UCS value of the cemented paste backfill (CPB) under the condition of high sand-cement ratio, and to analyze the size effect of the CPB with high sand-cement ratio under varied height/width ratio, the CPB specimens with sand-cement ratios of 8:1–24:1 and height/width ratio of 0.5, 1, and 2 were prepared. Through response surface experiments and finite element analysis, the influence of three height/width ratio on the CPB strength was explored, and the failure characteristics and size effect mechanisms of CPB with various height/width ratio were analyzed. The results show that the UCS of the CPB decreases with the increase of the height/width ratio under the same mass concentration and sand-cement ratio. When the height/width ratio is 0.5 and 1, the splitting failure is the main factor, when the height/width ratio is 2, the shearing failure is the main factor. The three-dimensional stress caused by the end effect of the CPB is the main reason for the high strength when the height/width ratio is 0.5. Due to the one-dimensional stress zone generated in the middle of the CPB with a height/width ratio of 2 in the laboratory, its strength value is closer to the actual UCS value of the CPB. The UCS values of the CPB with height/width ratio of 0.5 and 1 were higher than the actual UCS values in the laboratory. The rationality of the theoretical analysis was verified by the ABAQUS analysis results. This study reveals the size effect mechanism and proposes a conversion model for different specimen geometries.</p></abstract><kwd-group xml:lang="en"><title>Keywords</title><kwd>High sand-cement ratio</kwd><kwd>Cemented paste backfill</kwd><kwd>Height/width ratio</kwd><kwd>Size effect</kwd></kwd-group><kwd-group kwd-group-type="npg-subject"><title>Subject terms</title><kwd>Engineering</kwd><kwd>Materials science</kwd></kwd-group><funding-group><award-group><funding-source><institution>Major science and technology projects in China</institution></funding-source><award-id>2024ZD1003700</award-id><principal-award-recipient><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Hao</given-names></name></principal-award-recipient></award-group></funding-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-ND</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>issue-copyright-statement</meta-name><meta-value>© Springer Nature Limited 2026</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="Sec1"><title>Introduction</title><p id="Par2">As a new green mining technology, backfill mining has been popularized and applied in mining<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR1">1</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR2">2</xref></sup>. The strength of the cemented paste backfill (CPB) determines the stability of the goaf. The strength of the CPB is not only related to the mass concentration of the backfill slurry, curing age, sand-cement ratio and other factors, but also to the size and shape of the CPB. The mechanical properties of the material will change with the size of the material, and this special property is called the size effect<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR3">3</xref>–<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR6">6</xref></sup>. Under the conditions of high sand-cement ratio and small-sized specimens, the CPB will have low strength accuracy because the test strength value of the CPB is less than 10% of the range of the press. Therefore, in order to facilitate the testing and computation of the strength value of the CPB under the condition of high sand-cement ratio, it is necessary to explore the size effect of the CPB under different sizes.</p><p id="Par3">At present, there have been some studies on the size effect of CPB at home and abroad. For the cube CPB specimens, Iasnii<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR7">7</xref></sup> conducted the laboratory measurements align with the findings from the literature, specifically, that compressive strength diminishes as the specimen size increases. In the case of the smallest, non-standardized specimens (cylinders with a height of 100 <italic toggle="yes">mm</italic> and a diameter of 50 <italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>), the deviation in compressive strength testing is higher compared to other specimens. Bayram et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR8">8</xref></sup> analyzed the strength properties and ultrasonic wave velocity of CPB with sizes of 10 <italic toggle="yes">cm</italic> and 20 <italic toggle="yes">cm</italic> respectively, and found that there is a very obvious size effect on the strength of CPB, and the strength of the 10 <italic toggle="yes">cm</italic> block is greater than that of the 20 <italic toggle="yes">cm</italic> block. Gan et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR9">9</xref></sup> tested the strength of different sizes of CPB specimens by preparing CPB specimens with a sand-cement ratio of 4:1. The experiment showed that the peak strength of CPB specimens with a size of 200 <italic toggle="yes">mm</italic> was only half of 70.7 <italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>. For cylinder backfill specimens, Xu et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR10">10</xref></sup> conducted experiments on the ratio of full tailings CPB of different sizes, and showed that the sand-cement ratio was 4:1–8:1, and under the same height-diameter ratio, the UCS of the CPB of the <italic toggle="yes">φ</italic>76.2<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>×152.4<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic> cylinder is greater than that of the <italic toggle="yes">φ</italic>50.8<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>×101.6<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic> cylinder. The conclusion is similar to that of the strength of the cube specimens, both of which show that the strength of the CPB specimens with smaller size is higher. Zhang et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR11">11</xref></sup> studied the pre-peak shear stiffness of concrete decreases with the increase in joint surface size. When the joint surface size increases from 35 mm to 95 mm, the pre-peak shear stiffness of specimens with JRC values of 0 ~ 2, 4 ~ 6, 8 ~ 10, 12 ~ 14, and 16 ~ 18 decreases by 66.96%, 63.87%, 71.67%, 64.57%, and 66.32%, respectively, with an average decrease of 66.68%. For the different shapes of CPB specimens, Ye et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR12">12</xref></sup> prepared cube and cylinder CPB specimens with a sand-ash ratio of 4:1–8:1 and a concentration of 65%-72%. Under the condition of and mass concentration, the strength test results show that the UCS of 70.7<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic> cube &gt; <italic toggle="yes">φ</italic>7.08<italic toggle="yes">cm</italic> × 14.2<italic toggle="yes">cm</italic> cylinder &gt; <italic toggle="yes">φ</italic>5.13<italic toggle="yes">cm</italic> × 10<italic toggle="yes">cm</italic> cylinder, that is, the shape of the specimen has a significant impact on the UCS of the CPB. For the CPB specimens with different height-diameter ratios, Wang et al.<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR13">13</xref></sup> conducted an experiment to test the UCS of cylinder CPB specimens with a sand-cement ratio of 4:1, φ50<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>, and a height-diameter ratio of 1:1–1:5. The results show that with the increase of the height-diameter ratio, the UCS of the CPB specimen shows an inversely proportional function and gradually decreases. The above studies show that size, shape, and height/width ratio (Hereinafter referred to as H/W) have a significant impact on the UCS of the CPB. Between 4:1–8:1. At present, many mines at home and abroad are filled with high sand-cement ratio due to filling methods or other factors. At this time, the UCS of high sand-cement ratio CPB is low, and its UCS cannot be accurately tested under the large range of ordinary servo presses in the laboratory. At the same time, there is no strength conversion model applicable to different sizes of backfills under high sand-to-cement ratio conditions.</p><p id="Par4">Based on this, in this paper, the CPB specimens with high sand-cement ratios of 8:1, 12:1, and 24:1, mass concentrations of 71%, 72%, and 73%, and H/W of 0.5, 1, and 2 were used to carry out a axial compression test. The significant effects of sand-cement ratio, mass concentration, and aspect ratio on the UCS of the CPB were investigated by the response surface design method, and the size effect and failure characteristics of the CPB were analyzed, the strength size effect mechanism of high sand-cement ratio CPB was revealed, and the UCS conversion model under different height-diameter ratios with high sand-cement ratio were established. It provides a theoretical basis for the design UCS parameters of mine CPB.</p></sec><sec id="Sec2"><title>Experimental design</title><sec id="Sec3"><title>Experimental materials and tools</title><p id="Par5">The filling materials include cement and tailings, with their chemical compositions shown in Table <xref rid="Tab1" ref-type="table">1</xref>. The tailings are all tailings of a copper mine. The particle gradation curve of the tailings is shown in Fig. <xref rid="Fig1" ref-type="fig">1</xref>, the characteristic parameters of tailings particle size, d10, d50, and d90, are 1.52 μm, 20.5 μm, and 165 μm, respectively, all of which belong to good gradation. The tailings density is 2600<italic toggle="yes">kg/m³</italic> and the average particle size is 0.04<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>. The cement adopts 32.5 slag Portland cement produced by a cement factory, and the mixing water is the water used in a mine dressing plant. No additives are added during the preparation of filling slurry. Two kinds of molds were used for the preparation of CPB, 70.7 <italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>×70.7 <italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>×70.7<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic> and 100 <italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>×100 <italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>×100<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic> cube molds.</p><p id="Par6">
<table-wrap id="Tab1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1</label><caption><p>Chemical contents and of backfill material (wt%).</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Element</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">SiO<sub>2</sub></th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Fe<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub></th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">CaO</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">MgO</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub></th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">SO<sub>3</sub></th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Others</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Tailing</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">50.63</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">25.54</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9.39</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5.39</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.72</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.92</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.40</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Cement</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">21.38</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3.58</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">66.49</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2.50</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4.23</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.05</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.70</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par7">
<fig id="Fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 1</label><caption><p>Particle size gradation curve of a mine.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e407" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2026_40983_Fig1_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec4"><title>Experimental design</title><p id="Par8">This paper mainly explores the size effect of CPB with different H/W. The Box-behnken in Response Surface Methodology (RSM for short) was used for experimental design. The experiment selects three independent variables and one dependent variable. The dependent variable is the 28<italic toggle="yes">d</italic> UCS (true uniaxial compressive strength under minimal end effect) of the CPB. The independent variables are the aspect ratio, mass concentration, and sand-cement ratio. The H/W of the CPB were 1:2 (100<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>×200<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>), 1:1 (100<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>×100<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>), 2:1 (200<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>×100<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>), and the mass concentrations are 71%, 72%, and 73%; and the sand-cement ratios were 8, 12, 24 respectively. According to Box-behnken, the experimental design is divided into 17 groups of experiments. Each group was tested three times.</p></sec><sec id="Sec5"><title>Experimental scheme</title><p id="Par9">After the preparation of test materials and tools, firstly, design the filling slurry sand-cement ratio (8, 12, 24) and mass concentration (71%, 72%, 73%). This setting is based on the actual working conditions on site. Secondly, four types of CPB were made, the 70.7<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic> infill was used as the reference specimen for the following analysis; the infill samples with H/W of 1 and 2 were prepared by a set of 100<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic> cube molds; the infill samples with an aspect ratio of 0.5 were prepared by two sets of 100<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic> cube test block splicing. Then, it is put into an environment with a temperature of 20<italic toggle="yes">°C</italic> and a humidity of more than 90% for curing after the preparation is completed, and the curing age is 28 days(<italic toggle="yes">d</italic>). Finally, due to the small loading size of the press, it is not suitable for the CPB with H/W of 1:2 in this experiment. Before uniaxial compression, the backing plate of the CPB needs to be remanufactured to ensure the same material as the loading backing plate of the equipment. The UCS test of the filling body is carried out with an electro-hydraulic servo press, and the loading rate is 0.1<italic toggle="yes">kN/s</italic>. The press has a load capacity of 100 kN with an accuracy of ± 0.5% and displacement control precision of ± 0.5 mm. The experimental scheme design table is shown in Table <xref rid="Tab2" ref-type="table">2</xref>.</p><p id="Par10">
<table-wrap id="Tab2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2</label><caption><p>Experimental Scheme Design.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Experimental Procedure</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Specific content</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Step 1- Fill slurry proportion design</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sand-cement ratio:8, 12, 24, mass concentration:71%, 72%, 73%</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Step 2- CPB preparation</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">H/W of 0.5,1, 2 and 70.0 mm cube benchmark</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Step 3- CPB Maintenance</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Temperature: 20 °C, humidity: 90%, duration: 28 days.</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Step 4- UCS test</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">loading rate : 0.1<italic toggle="yes">kN/s</italic>, accuracy: ±0.5%</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec6"><title>Analysis of RSM experimental results</title><p id="Par11">According to the test results of UCS of 17 groups of CPB, the influence law of sand-cement ratio and mass concentration on the UCS and size effect of CPB was analyzed respectively, and the three independent variables of H/W, mass concentration and sand-cement ratio on the CPB were analyzed. The degree of significant influence on 28<italic toggle="yes">d</italic> UCS. The results of the UCS test of the CPB are shown in Table <xref rid="Tab3" ref-type="table">3</xref>.</p><p id="Par12">
<table-wrap id="Tab3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 3</label><caption><p>RSM experimental UCS test results.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Group</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Variable A<break/>(H/W)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Variable B<break/>(Mass concentration /%)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Variable C<break/>(Sand-cement ratio)</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">UCS of 28d /MPa</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">73</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">24</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.52</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.5</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">71</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.07</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">71</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.24</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">4</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">71</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.84</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">5</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">72</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">24</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.42</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">6</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">72</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.96</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">7</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.5</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">72</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.29</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">72</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.96</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">9</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">72</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.96</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">10</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">71</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">24</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.46</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">11</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">73</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.87</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">72</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.96</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">13</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.5</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">72</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">24</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.53</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">73</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.26</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">15</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">72</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.96</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">16</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.5</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">73</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">12</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.27</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">17</td><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">72</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">8</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.20</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p><sec id="Sec7"><title>Analysis of the sand-cement ratio on the UCS and size effect of the CPB</title><p id="Par13">Under the conditions of the same slurry mass concentration, the relationship between the sand-cement ratio and UCS of the CPB of each size is shown in Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref>. It can be seen from Fig. <xref rid="Fig2" ref-type="fig">2</xref> that under the same slurry concentration, the common knowledge for the sand-cement ratio is that the UCS of the CPB decreases with the increase of the sand-cement ratio. In this experiment, the UCS of the CPB with three H/W decreases with the increase of the sand-cement ratio. When the sand-cement ratio increased from 8 to 24, the UCS of the CPB decreased by a maximum of 75%. Under the same slurry mass concentration, the order of the UCS of the CPB of each size is: the H/W is 0.5 &gt; the H/W is 1 &gt; the H/W is 2. There is a large difference in strength between different sizes, and the maximum difference in strength is 55%, which indicates that there is an obvious size effect in the CPB of each size, and the high sand-cement ratio has a greater impact on the size effect of the CPB.</p><p id="Par14">
<fig id="Fig2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 2</label><caption><p>Comparison of the UCS of CPB with different H/W as a function of sand-cement ratio.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e749" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2026_40983_Fig2_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par15">The sand-cement ratio directly determines the proportion and cementation state of the cement matrix in the CPB. Cement is the main source of providing cementation strength, while tailings mainly serve as a skeleton. A CPB with a low sand-cement ratio can fully encapsulate tailings particles, forming a continuous and dense network of calcium silicate hydrate (C-S-H) gel with strong cementation ability and high strength. Conversely, in a high sand-cement ratio, the cement content is significantly reduced, the cementation layer between tailings particles becomes thin or discontinuous, the porosity increases, and the number of weak cementation points increases, leading to a significant decrease in strength.</p></sec><sec id="Sec8"><title>Analysis of the mass concentration on the UCS and size of the CPB</title><p id="Par16">Under the conditions of the same sand-cement ratio, the relationship between the mass concentration of the CPB slurry and the UCS of each size is shown in Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref>. It can be seen from Fig. <xref rid="Fig3" ref-type="fig">3</xref> that under the same sand-cement ratio, the UCS of the CPB with the three H/W increases with the increase of the mass concentration. This can be explained as the phenomenon of segregation and stratification and uneven particle distribution in the slurry when the mass concentration is low<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR14">14</xref></sup>, resulting in an increase in the pores of the CPB and a decrease in the final UCS; as the mass concentration increases, the degree of segregation and stratification in the slurry decreases, the UCS increases gradually. In this experiment, when the mass concentration increased from 71% to 73%, the UCS of the CPB increased by 21% at the maximum, and the increasing trend was relatively slow. Under the same sand-cement ratio, the order of the UCS of the CPB of each size is as follows: the H/W is 0.5 &gt; the H/W is 1 &gt; the H/W is 2. The difference in UCS between each size is small, and the maximum difference in strength is 29%, which indicates that the mass concentration of the CPB has little effect on the size effect of the three high-to-width ratio CPB.</p><p id="Par17">
<fig id="Fig3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 3</label><caption><p>Comparison of the UCS of CPB with different H/W as a function of mass concentration.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e775" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2026_40983_Fig3_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par18">The mass concentration reflects the content of solid particles in the slurry, directly affecting the fluidity, compactness, and pore structure after hardening of the slurry. At low concentrations, there is more water, making the slurry prone to segregation and stratification, and resulting in lower strength after hardening. At high concentrations, the solid particles are more densely packed, improving the uniformity of the slurry, reducing segregation, and lowering the porosity after hardening. This leads to a denser structure and increased strength.</p></sec><sec id="Sec9"><title>Analysis of variance results</title><p id="Par19">
<table-wrap id="Tab4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 4</label><caption><p>RSM analysis of variance.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sourse</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Sum of squares</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">DF</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Mean Square</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">F-value</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1"><italic toggle="yes">P</italic>-value</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Model</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.50</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">3</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.5016</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">68.05</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt; 0.0001</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">A</italic>
</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.105</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.105</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">14.24</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.0023</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">B</italic>
</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.0066</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.0066</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.90</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.3608</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">C</italic>
</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.39</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.39</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">188.54</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">&lt; 0.0001</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p><p id="Par20">The UCS results measured according to the experimental design in Table <xref rid="Tab3" ref-type="table">3</xref> were input into the Design-Expert software, and the results of variance analysis were shown in Table <xref rid="Tab4" ref-type="table">4</xref>. It can be seen from Table <xref rid="Tab4" ref-type="table">4</xref> that the <italic toggle="yes">F</italic> value of the model is 68.05, and the <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value is less than 0.0001, which means that the model has a significant impact. Three independent variables have different degrees of significant influence on the 28<italic toggle="yes">d</italic> UCS of the CPB. Among them, the <italic toggle="yes">F</italic> value of the independent variable <italic toggle="yes">C</italic> (sand-cement ratio) is 188.54, and the <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value is less than 0.0001, which is a very significant influencing factor; the independent variable The <italic toggle="yes">F</italic> value of <italic toggle="yes">A</italic> (H/W) is 14.24, and the <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value is less than 0.005, which is a sub-significant factor; the <italic toggle="yes">F</italic> value of the independent variable <italic toggle="yes">B</italic> (mass concentration) is 0.90, and the <italic toggle="yes">P</italic> value is &gt; 0.1, which is a weakly significant factor. This conclusion also verifies the conclusions of Sect.  3.1 and 3.2. It was found that the direct interactions between various factors had minimal impact on the results of this study. This may be because under high sand-to-cement ratio conditions, the differences in the effects of factors on strength are minimal, thus the impact is not significant.</p><p id="Par21">The multiple linear regression analysis function of the Design-Expert software was used to carry out regression analysis on the UCS of the CPB. In order to make the regression equation fit well and control and predict variables accurately, a multiple linear regression model of the following formula (1) is established:<disp-formula id="Equ1"><label>1</label><tex-math id="d33e929">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\:f=-0.29497-0.14845{x}_{1}+0.022875{x}_{2}-0.04896{x}_{3}$$\end{document}</tex-math></disp-formula></p><p id="Par22">In the formula: f is the 28<italic toggle="yes">d</italic> UCS of the CPB of the dependent variable; <italic toggle="yes">x</italic><sub>1</sub> is the H/W of the CPB; <italic toggle="yes">x</italic><sub>2</sub> is the mass concentration of the CPB; <italic toggle="yes">x</italic><sub>3</sub> is the sand-cement ratio of the CPB slurry.</p><p id="Par23">
<fig id="Fig4" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 4</label><caption><p>Comparison chart of experimental and model strength.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e958" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2026_40983_Fig4_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par24">The model exhibits a good fitting effect with a high goodness of fit R<sup>2</sup> of 0.93, and it can effectively predict the 28d UCS values of the backfill under various conditions such as different aspect ratios, mass concentrations, and sand-cement ratios. Compare the experimental results in Table <xref rid="Tab3" ref-type="table">3</xref> with the predicted results of the model, as shown in Fig. <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>. The figure shows that the prediction model is consistent with the experimental results, with a maximum error within 6.7%. The coefficients of H/W <italic toggle="yes">x</italic><sub>1</sub> and sand-cement ratio <italic toggle="yes">x</italic><sub>3</sub> are negative, reflecting the patterns that UCS decreases with increasing sample height and decreases with decreasing cement content, respectively. The coefficient of mass concentration <italic toggle="yes">x</italic><sub>2</sub> is positive, indicating the positive effect of increased concentration on UCS. The absolute value of the sand-cement ratio coefficient is the largest, further corroborating the conclusion that it is the most critical influencing factor.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec10"><title>Size effect analysis of UCS of the CPB under the high sand-cement ratio backfill</title><p id="Par25">According to the results of the RSM test, the H/W is a significant factor affecting the UCS of the CPB. It is necessary to further analyze the UCS failure characteristics and size effect mechanism of the CPB under different H/W.</p><sec id="Sec11"><title>Size effect degree analysis of UCS</title><p id="Par26">In order to quantitatively analyze the size-effect relationship of the UCS of CPB, a 70.7 <italic toggle="yes">mm</italic> cube specimen was used as the reference size, and the H/W were 0.5 (100<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>/200<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>), 1 (100<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>/100<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>), 2 (200<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>/100<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>) specimens as non-reference dimensions. The concept of size effect degree in concrete size effect analysis was introduced to describe the size effect of the UCS of the CPB cube specimens<sup><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="CR15">15</xref></sup>, and the size effect degree was calculated according to formula (2):<disp-formula id="Equ2"><label>2</label><tex-math id="d33e1017">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\:{\gamma\:}_{a}=\frac{{f}_{s}-{f}_{a}}{{f}_{s}}\times\:100\%$$\end{document}</tex-math></disp-formula></p><p id="Par27">In the formula: <italic toggle="yes">γ</italic><sub><italic toggle="yes">a</italic></sub> represents the size effect degree; <italic toggle="yes">f</italic><sub><italic toggle="yes">s</italic></sub> is the UCS of the CPB of the reference size; <italic toggle="yes">f</italic><sub><italic toggle="yes">a</italic></sub> is the UCS of the CPB with size <italic toggle="yes">a</italic>.</p><p id="Par28">
<fig id="Fig5" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 5</label><caption><p>Size effect degree of UCS of the CPB.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e1052" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2026_40983_Fig5_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par29">Since the influence of the concentration is small, only 73% of the mass concentration is taken as an example, and the relationship between the size effect and the UCS of the CPB under the three sand-cement ratios is calculated as shown in Fig. <xref rid="Fig4" ref-type="fig">4</xref>. It can be seen from Fig. <xref rid="Fig5" ref-type="fig">5</xref> that the size effect of the CPB increases with the increase of the H/W, but the increasing trend gradually tends to be gentle, and the two show a logarithmic function relationship. The variation range of size effect degree under the condition of high sand-cement ratio is larger than that of low sand-cement ratio, and the maximum change range of size effect degree reaches 46%. Combined with the previous experimental results, it can be seen that the size effect degree of the H/W of 0.5 is the lowest, that is, the UCS is the largest, the H/W is 1, and the size effect degree of the H/W of 2 is the highest, that is, the UCS is the lowest.</p></sec><sec id="Sec12"><title>Analysis of UCS failure characteristics of CPB with different H/W</title><p id="Par30">The UCS failure characteristics of the three types of CPB with aspect ratios of 0.5, 1, and 2 are shown in Fig. <xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>. It can be seen from Fig. <xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref> that when the H/W is 0.5 and 1, there are 4 and 3 through main cracks (red dotted lines in the Fig. <xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>) that are approximately parallel to the loading direction on the surface of the specimen, respectively, showing the characteristics of splitting failure. When the H/W is 2, 2 main cracks appear on the surface of the specimen, which are obviously interlaced with each other, and continue to develop in an X shape. At the same time, there are many secondary cracks (blue dotted lines in the Fig. <xref rid="Fig6" ref-type="fig">6</xref>), showing the characteristics of splitting failure.</p><p id="Par31">
<fig id="Fig6" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 6</label><caption><p>The UCS failure characteristics of in CPB with different H/W.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e1086" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2026_40983_Fig6_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec13"><title>Mechanism analysis of size effect of UCS</title><p id="Par32">When the H/W is 0.5 and 1, under the condition of uniaxial compression, the stiffness of the upper and lower backing plates is much greater than that of the CPB, resulting in friction between the backing plate and the upper and lower ends of the backfill specimen. The lateral deformation under compression (Poisson’s ratio effect) is limited by the friction between the end face of the CPB and the backing plate, which can be called the end effect. Therefore, a three-dimensional conical compressive stress zone will be formed at the upper and lower ends of the specimen (Fig. <xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7</xref>a, b), and the area of the stress zone of the specimen with an H/W of 0.5 is larger than that of the CPB with an H/W of 1. Due to the low height, the conical stress zones at the upper and lower ends must be connected to each other, and the whole is close to the three-way stress state. Under this experimental condition, the measured UCS of the CPB must be greater than the actual UCS. Only the stiffness of the backing plate is exactly the same as that of the CPB can completely eliminate the above end effect. It is difficult to find pads with the same stiffness.</p><p id="Par33">When the H/W is 2, the height of the CPB is higher, and the upper and lower ends of the CPB are still subjected to the end effect brought by the backing plate, but the middle part of the CPB is in a one-dimensional compression state (as shown in Fig. <xref rid="Fig7" ref-type="fig">7</xref>c), the stress is more uniform, less affected by the end effect, and the UCS is low. Therefore, the UCS measured under the condition of this H/W is closer to the actual UCS of the CPB.</p><p id="Par34">
<fig id="Fig7" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 7</label><caption><p>Stress distribution of specimens with different H/W in the state of uniaxial compression.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e1108" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2026_40983_Fig7_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par35">According to the above theoretical results, the concrete damage criterion in the finite element analysis software ABAQUS is used for modeling and analysis. The size of the CPB model is 200<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>×100<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>×100<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>, 100<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>×100<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>×100<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>, and 100<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>×100<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>×200<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>, respectively. The constitutive model is a concrete damage plasticity model, calibrated based on experimental elastic modulus and Poisson’s ratio parameters, with damage evolution parameters derived from unconfined compressive strength (UCS) test data.</p><p id="Par36">The model parameters are as follows: the density of the CPB is 1900 <italic toggle="yes">kg/m³</italic>, the elastic modulus is 0.6<italic toggle="yes">GPa</italic>, and the Poisson’s ratio is 0.2; the upper and lower backing plates have a density of 7850<italic toggle="yes">kg/m³</italic>, an elastic modulus of 206<italic toggle="yes">GPa</italic>, and a Poisson’s ratio of 0.3. Constrain the bottom plate, apply displacement load to the upper plate, and reduce the displacement by 5<italic toggle="yes">mm</italic>. In order to facilitate data reading and analysis, the finite element analysis of the CPB only takes the concentration of 73% and the sand-cement ratio of 8 as an example. The stress field results are shown in Fig. <xref rid="Fig8" ref-type="fig">8</xref>.</p><p id="Par37">
<fig id="Fig8" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 8</label><caption><p>Stress field results of finite element analysis of the CPB.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e1169" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2026_40983_Fig8_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par38">According to the analysis results of the stress field in Fig. <xref rid="Fig8" ref-type="fig">8</xref>(a)(b), it can be seen that when the H/W of the CPB is 0.5 and 1, most of the three-dimensional stress compression zones appear at the upper and lower ends of the CPB, and the H/W is the area of the three-dimensional stress region of 0.5 is larger than that of the CPB with an H/W of 1. The three-dimensional stress regions at the upper and lower ends of the two are basically in a connected state, and there is no obvious one-dimensional stress region in the middle. The CPB with an H/W of 2, as shown in Fig. <xref rid="Fig8" ref-type="fig">8</xref>(c), has a small portion of stress compression zones at the upper and lower ends, and all of them are one-dimensional stress compression zones. From the stress field data, it can be seen that the UCS of the CPB with an H/W of 2 is the lowest, and the CPB with an H/W of 0.5 is the highest. The above analysis verifies the rationality of the theoretical analysis.</p></sec></sec><sec id="Sec14"><title>The conversion model of the UCS of the CPB between different H/W</title><p id="Par39">It can be seen from the above analysis that when the H/W is 2, the middle of the CPB is in a state of uniaxial compression, and the end effect is small. At this time, the UCS is closest to the actual UCS of the CPB. Therefore, taking the UCS of the CPB with an H/W of 2 as the reference value, in order to make the regression model fit the various parameters of the UCS calculation, the non-linear fitting method was used to establish the UCS conversion model of the CPB with an H/W of 2 and an H/W of 0.5 and 1, respectively. This conversion model adopts the power function product model, such as formula (3):<disp-formula id="Equ3"><label>3</label><tex-math id="d33e1183">\documentclass[12pt]{minimal}
				\usepackage{amsmath}
				\usepackage{wasysym} 
				\usepackage{amsfonts} 
				\usepackage{amssymb} 
				\usepackage{amsbsy}
				\usepackage{mathrsfs}
				\usepackage{upgreek}
				\setlength{\oddsidemargin}{-69pt}
				\begin{document}$$\:\left.\begin{array}{c}{F}_{m}=\:a\times\:{{F}_{n}}^{b}\\\:{F}_{m}=\:a\times\:{{F}_{z}}^{b}\end{array}\right\}$$\end{document}</tex-math></disp-formula></p><p id="Par40">In the formula: <italic toggle="yes">F</italic><sub><italic toggle="yes">m</italic></sub> represents the reference UCS of the CPB with an H/W of 2; <italic toggle="yes">F</italic><sub><italic toggle="yes">n</italic></sub> represents the UCS of the CPB with an H/W of 0.5; <italic toggle="yes">F</italic><sub><italic toggle="yes">z</italic></sub> represents the UCS of the CPB with an H/W of 1; <italic toggle="yes">a</italic> and <italic toggle="yes">b</italic> both represent regression coefficients. The <italic toggle="yes">a</italic> reflects the strength scaling factor due to stress distribution differences. The <italic toggle="yes">b</italic> represents the sensitivity of strength to H/W changes.</p><p id="Par41">The UCS of the CPB with an H/W of 0.5 and 1 is taken as the <italic toggle="yes">x</italic>-axis, and the UCS of the CPB with an H/W of 2 is taken as the <italic toggle="yes">y</italic>-axis. (<italic toggle="yes">F</italic><sub><italic toggle="yes">n</italic></sub>, <italic toggle="yes">F</italic><sub><italic toggle="yes">m</italic></sub>) and (<italic toggle="yes">F</italic><sub><italic toggle="yes">z</italic></sub>, <italic toggle="yes">F</italic><sub><italic toggle="yes">m</italic></sub>).</p><p id="Par42">
<fig id="Fig9" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Fig. 9</label><caption><p>Fitting diagram of UCS conversion function of H/W = 2 and H/W = 0.5 and 1.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="d33e1261" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="41598_2026_40983_Fig9_HTML.jpg"/></fig>
</p><p id="Par43">The fitting results of the UCS conversion function are shown in Fig. <xref rid="Fig8" ref-type="fig">8</xref>. It can be seen from Fig. <xref rid="Fig9" ref-type="fig">9</xref> that the UCS conversion functions of H/W 2 and H/W 0.5 and 1 are all in a power function relationship. The goodness of fit <italic toggle="yes">R</italic><sup><italic toggle="yes">2</italic></sup> of the two curves is greater than 0.95, and the curve fitting effect is good. Under the conditions of each concentration and sand-ash ratio, the UCS conversion points are staggered and distributed on both sides of the fitting curve, and the degree of dispersion is low. The parameters of the curve function expression are shown in Table <xref rid="Tab5" ref-type="table">5</xref>. Through the function conversion model, the sand-ash ratio 8–24 and the intensity conversion of different H/W under the experimental conditions of the mass concentration of 71%-73% can be converted, so that the conversion result is closer to the actual UCS of the CPB in the laboratory value. Scope of application of this model: and-cement ratio 8–24, mass concentration 71–73%, H/W is 0.5–2.</p><p id="Par44">
<table-wrap id="Tab5" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 5</label><caption><p>The UCS conversion function parameter table of H/W = 2 and H/W = 0.5 and 1.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">H/W</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Parameter a</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Parameter b</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">
<italic toggle="yes">R</italic>
<sup>2</sup>
</th><th align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">Residual sum of squares</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2 and 0.5</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.69313</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.70754</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.9908</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.0012</td></tr><tr><td align="left" colspan="1" rowspan="1">2 and 1</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.8145</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">1.4632</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.9674</td><td char="." align="char" colspan="1" rowspan="1">0.0043</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>
</p></sec><sec id="Sec15"><title>Conclusion</title><p id="Par45">This study systematically investigated the damage and size effect of CPB under high sand-cement ratio conditions (8:1–24:1). The main findings and their innovative contributions are summarized as follows:</p><p id="Par46">(1) Through the RSM experimental analysis, it can be seen that in the low sand-cement ratio 8:1–24:1, the mass concentration is in the range of 71%-73%, the sand-cement ratio and H/W have a significant impact on the UCS of the CPB, while the mass concentration of the CPB slurry has a weak significant effect on the UCS of the CPB. Under the conditions of the same slurry mass concentration and sand-cement ratio, the order of the UCS of the CPB of each size is as follows: the H/W is 0.5 &gt; the H/W is 1 &gt; the H/W is 2.</p><p id="Par47">(2)Under identical mix proportions, UCS decreases as H/W increases, exhibiting a distinct size effect. More importantly, the failure mode shifts from splitting-dominated failure at H/W = 0.5 and 1 to shear-dominated failure at H/W = 2, with the latter characterized by X-shaped crack propagation. This observation clarifies the intrinsic link between specimen geometry, stress state, and failure pattern in high sand-cement ratio CPB, which has rarely been addressed in previous studies.</p><p id="Par48">(3) The higher UCS of specimens with H/W = 0.5 and 1 is attributed to the pronounced “end effect,” which generates three-dimensional compressive stress zones at the specimen ends. In contrast, specimens with H/W = 2 develop a more uniform one-dimensional stress state in the middle region, thereby yielding a strength value closer to the true uniaxial compressive strength. This mechanistic explanation, supported by finite-element analysis, advances the theoretical understanding of size effects in CPB and highlights the importance of minimizing end effects in laboratory testing.</p><p id="Par49">(4) ABAQUS simulations of the stress distribution under uniaxial compression visually confirm the theoretical mechanism: three-dimensional stress concentrations dominate in short specimens (H/W = 0.5 and 1), while one-dimensional stress prevails in taller specimens (H/W = 2). The numerical results provide independent validation of the proposed size-effect mechanism, enhancing the reliability of the experimental conclusions. The UCS between different H/W follows a power function relationship. Within a certain applicable range, there is a conversion model for the strength of two sets of CPB.</p><p id="Par50">In summary, this research not only reveals the size-effect behavior and underlying mechanism of high sand-cement ratio CPB but also proposes a quantifiable conversion framework that bridges laboratory tests with engineering practice. The findings provide a theoretical basis and a practical methodology for the rational design and strength evaluation of CPB in high sand-cement ratio backfill operations.</p></sec></body><back><fn-group><fn><p><bold>Publisher’s note</bold></p><p>Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></fn></fn-group><notes notes-type="author-contribution"><title>Author contributions</title><p>**Dongjie Jiang: ** Funding acquisition, Resources, Writing–review &amp; editing. **Hao Li** : Writing–original draft, Visualization, Methodology, Formal analysis, Data curation, Conceptualization. **Guangzhong Sun** : Conceptualization, Project administration, Supervision, Writing–review &amp; editing.</p></notes><notes notes-type="funding-information"><title>Funding</title><p>This work was supported by the major science and technology projects in China (Grant No. 2024ZD1003700).</p></notes><notes notes-type="data-availability"><title>Data availability</title><p>The data presented in this study are available on request from the corresponding author. The data are not publicly available due to patent application issues.</p></notes><notes><title>Declarations</title><notes id="FPar1"><title>Ethics approval and consent to participate</title><p id="Par51">This research does not involve any ethical issues and all participants have agreed.</p></notes><notes id="FPar2"><title>Consent for publication</title><p id="Par52">All participants in the study have agreed to publish.</p></notes><notes id="FPar3" notes-type="COI-statement"><title>Competing interests</title><p id="Par53">The authors declare no competing interests.</p></notes></notes><ref-list id="Bib1"><title>References</title><ref id="CR1"><label>1.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Liu, D. W. Exploring the Progress of Key Technological Innovations in Intelligent Coal Mining. <italic toggle="yes">Inner Mongolia Coal Econ.</italic> (03), 56–58. 10.3969/j.issn.1008-0155.2025.03.020 (2025).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR2"><label>2.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR2" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Qin</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Progress in Green Coal Mining Technology in China</article-title><source>Min. Saf. EnvironmentalProtection</source><year>2023</year><volume>50</volume><issue>06</issue><fpage>7</fpage><lpage>15</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.19835/j.issn.1008-4495.2023.06.002</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR2" publication-type="journal">Liu, J. &amp; Qin, K. Progress in Green Coal Mining Technology in China. <italic toggle="yes">Min. Saf. EnvironmentalProtection</italic>. <bold>50</bold> (06), 7–15. 10.19835/j.issn.1008-4495.2023.06.002 (2023).</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR3"><label>3.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Larsson, J. et al. <italic toggle="yes">A Three-Factor Experimental Study on the Effect of Specimen Size on the Shear Strength of Rock Joints</italic> (Rock Mechanics and Rock Engineering, 2025). 10.1007/s00603-025-04954-2</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR4"><label>4.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yiouta-Mitra, P., Svourakis, K. &amp; Nomikos, P. Particle flow numerical study of size effect on uniaxial compressive strength of natural building stone. <italic toggle="yes">Geomech. Geophys. Geo-Energy Geo-Resources</italic>. <bold>10</bold> (1). 10.1007/s40948-023-00722-0 (2024).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR5"><label>5.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Farahani, A., Sharifi, M. &amp; Bayesteh, H. Effect of aggregate size on the slump and uniaxial compressive strength of concrete: a DEM study. <italic toggle="yes">Part. Sci. Technol.</italic>, <bold>2024</bold>:1–18. 10.1080/02726351.2024.2412655</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR6"><label>6.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Jiang, N. D. et al. Size effect on compressive strength of foamed concrete: Experimental and numerical studies. <italic toggle="yes">Mater. Des.</italic><bold>2024</bold>(240), 112841–112841. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135707</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR7"><label>7.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR7" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Iasnii</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mykytyshyn</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Specimen size and shape effect on the compressive strength of concrete</article-title><source>Sci. J. ternopil Natl. Tech. Univ.</source><year>2023</year><volume>111</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>97</fpage><lpage>105</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.33108/visnyk_tntu2023.03.097</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR7" publication-type="journal">Iasnii, V. &amp; Mykytyshyn, T. Specimen size and shape effect on the compressive strength of concrete. <italic toggle="yes">Sci. J. ternopil Natl. Tech. Univ.</italic><bold>111</bold> (3), 97–105. 10.33108/visnyk_tntu2023.03.097 (2023).</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR8"><label>8.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR8" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bayram</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tekin</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Kulekci</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Strength and ultrasonic properties of cemented paste backfill</article-title><source>Ultrasonics</source><year>2014</year><volume>54</volume><fpage>195</fpage><lpage>204</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ultras.2013.04.013</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23706262</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR8" publication-type="journal">Bayram, E., Tekin, Y. &amp; Kulekci, G. Strength and ultrasonic properties of cemented paste backfill. <italic toggle="yes">Ultrasonics</italic><bold>54</bold>, 195–204. 10.1016/j.ultras.2013.04.013 (2014).<pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23706262</pub-id>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.ultras.2013.04.013</pub-id></mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR9"><label>9.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR9" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gan</surname><given-names>DQ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Han</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhao</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Experimental study on size effect of compressive strength of cemented backfill</article-title><source>Metal Mines</source><year>2018</year><volume>1</volume><fpage>32</fpage><lpage>36</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.19614/j.cnki.jsks.201801006</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR9" publication-type="journal">Gan, D. Q., Han, L., Liu, Z. &amp; Zhao, H. Experimental study on size effect of compressive strength of cemented backfill. <italic toggle="yes">Metal Mines</italic>. <bold>1</bold>, 32–36. 10.19614/j.cnki.jsks.201801006 (2018).</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR10"><label>10.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR10" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>MF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jin</surname><given-names>AB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>LJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>GS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>WX</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Experimental study on size effect of full tailings cemented backfill specimen strength</article-title><source>China Min. Ind.</source><year>2016</year><volume>25</volume><fpage>87</fpage><lpage>92</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1004-4051.2016.05.022</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR10" publication-type="journal">Xu, M. F., Jin, A. B., Guo, L. J., Liu, G. S. &amp; Xu, W. X. Experimental study on size effect of full tailings cemented backfill specimen strength. <italic toggle="yes">China Min. Ind.</italic><bold>25</bold>, 87–92. 10.3969/j.issn.1004-4051.2016.05.022 (2016).</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR11"><label>11.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR11" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Guo</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhu</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zhong</surname><given-names>PB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Rong</surname><given-names>TL</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Experimental study on shear mechanical characteristics and its size effect of concrete joints based on BP neural network method[J]</article-title><source>Constr. Build. Mater.</source><year>2024</year><volume>442</volume><fpage>137583</fpage><lpage>137583</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137583</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR11" publication-type="journal">Zhang, Z., Guo, B., Zhu, C., Zhong, P. B. &amp; Rong, T. L. Experimental study on shear mechanical characteristics and its size effect of concrete joints based on BP neural network method[J]. <italic toggle="yes">Constr. Build. Mater.</italic><bold>442</bold>, 137583–137583. 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137583 (2024).</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR12"><label>12.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Ye, G. X., Xie, L. K., Guo, L. J., Liu, G. S. &amp; Wang, H. Research on the strength of filling samples with different shapes and sizes. <italic toggle="yes">China Min. Ind. </italic><bold>24</bold>, 128–131. 10.3969/j.issn.1004-4051.2015.10.026 2016.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR13"><label>13.</label><citation-alternatives><element-citation id="ec-CR13" publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname><given-names>LT</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Xiong</surname><given-names>ZQ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Su</surname><given-names>CD</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Analysis of size effect and failure characteristics of pillars filled with modified high-water materials</article-title><source>Coal Sci. Technol.</source><year>2021</year><volume>49</volume><fpage>82</fpage><lpage>88</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.13199/j.cnki.cst.2021.12.010</pub-id></element-citation><mixed-citation id="mc-CR13" publication-type="journal">Wang, L. T., Xiong, Z. Q. &amp; Su, C. D. Analysis of size effect and failure characteristics of pillars filled with modified high-water materials. <italic toggle="yes">Coal Sci. Technol.</italic><bold>49</bold>, 82–88. 10.13199/j.cnki.cst.2021.12.010 (2021).</mixed-citation></citation-alternatives></ref><ref id="CR14"><label>14.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Li, L. T. <italic toggle="yes">Research on the Segregation Mechanism and Control Technology of Jinchuan Coarse Aggregate Filling Slurry</italic> (University of Science and Technology Beijing, 2020).</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="CR15"><label>15.</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Yao, Z., Qiang, C., Jing, X. W. &amp; Zhang, J. Size Effect on Compressive Strength of High-Strength Concrete Cube. <italic toggle="yes">Res. Application Building Mater.</italic>, <bold>2016</bold>(1):4–6 10.3969/j.issn.1009-9441.2016.01.004</mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>