<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">Eur J Phys Rehabil Med</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">Eur J Phys Rehabil Med</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">4371</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">ejprm</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">EJPRM</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>European Journal of Physical and Rehabilitation Medicine</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">1973-9087</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1973-9095</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Edizioni Minerva Medica S.p.A.</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10077962</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC10077962.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">10077962</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">10077962</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">35904308</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.23736/S1973-9087.22.07457-3</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">7457</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Article</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Efficacy of telehealth core exercises during COVID-19 after bariatric surgery: a randomized controlled trial</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><name name-style="western"><surname>ALI</surname><given-names initials="OI">Olfat I.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp">*</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>ABDELRAOUF</surname><given-names initials="OR">Osama R.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">
<sup>2</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>EL-GENDY</surname><given-names initials="AM">Amira M.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">
<sup>1</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>ABDELGALIL</surname><given-names initials="AA">Abdelgalil A.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff">
<sup>3</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>ABDELAAL</surname><given-names initials="AK">Alshaimaa K.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">
<sup>2</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>DAHLAWI</surname><given-names initials="HA">Haytham A.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff4" ref-type="aff">
<sup>4</sup>
</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>SELIM</surname><given-names initials="AO">Ali O.</given-names></name><xref rid="aff5" ref-type="aff">
<sup>5</sup>
</xref></contrib><aff><target id="aff1" target-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></target><institution content-type="dept">Department of Basic Science for Physical Therapy, Faculty of Physical Therapy</institution>, <institution>Cairo University</institution>, <addr-line>Giza</addr-line>, <country country="eg">Egypt</country>; <target id="aff2" target-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></target><institution>Batterjee Medical College</institution>, <addr-line>Jeddah</addr-line>, <country country="sa">Saudi Arabia</country>; <target id="aff3" target-type="aff"><sup>3</sup></target><institution content-type="dept">Department of Physical Therapy for Musculoskeletal Disorders</institution>, <institution>Cairo University</institution>, <addr-line>Giza</addr-line>, <country country="eg">Egypt</country>; <target id="aff4" target-type="aff"><sup>4</sup></target><institution content-type="dept">Clinical Laboratory, Department of Sciences, College of Applied Medical Sciences, University of Taif, Taif</institution>, <country country="sa">Saudi Arabia</country>; <target id="aff5" target-type="aff"><sup>5</sup></target><institution content-type="dept">Department of Physical Therapy for Surgery, Faculty of Physical Therapy</institution>, <institution>Cairo University</institution>, <addr-line>Giza</addr-line>, <country country="eg">Egypt</country></aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="cor1"><label>*</label>Corresponding author: Olfat I. Ali, Department of Basic Science, Department for Physical Therapy, Faculty of Physical Therapy, Cairo University, 7 Ahmed Elzayad Street, 12611, Giza, Egypt. E-mail: <email xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="olfat_ib@yahoo.com">olfat_ib@yahoo.com</email></corresp><fn id="afn1" fn-type="COI-statement"><p><italic toggle="yes">Conflicts of interest.—</italic>The authors certify that there is no conflict of interest with any financial organization regarding the material discussed in the manuscript.</p></fn><fn id="afn2" fn-type="equal"><p><italic toggle="yes">Authors’ contributions</italic>.—All authors have given substantial contributions to the conception or the design of the manuscript, Olfat I. Ali, Osama R. Abdelraouf, Amira M. El-Gendy, Abdelgalil A. Abdelgalil, and Alshaimaa K. Abdelaal to the acquisition, analysis and interpretation of the data. All authors have participated to drafting the manuscript, all authors revised it critically. All authors read and approved the final version of the manuscript. All authors contributed equally to the manuscript and read and approved the final version of the manuscript.</p></fn><fn id="afn3"><p><italic toggle="yes">Acknowledgements.</italic>— The authors acknowledge Taif University researchers supporting project number (TURSP-2020/291), Taif University, Taif, Saudi Arabia.</p></fn></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>29</day><month>7</month><year>2022</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="collection"><month>12</month><year>2022</year></pub-date><volume>58</volume><issue>6</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">432945</issue-id><fpage>845</fpage><lpage>852</lpage><history><date date-type="accepted"><day>21</day><month>7</month><year>2022</year></date><date date-type="rev-recd"><day>09</day><month>6</month><year>2022</year></date><date date-type="received"><day>30</day><month>1</month><year>2022</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>29</day><month>07</month><year>2022</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>07</day><month>04</month><year>2023</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2023-04-11 06:10:14.553"><day>11</day><month>04</month><year>2023</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>2022 THE AUTHORS</copyright-statement><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial No Derivatives (CC BY-NC-ND) 4.0 License.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="11-7457-EJPRM_N.pdf"/><abstract><sec><title>BACKGROUND</title><p>Bariatric surgery (BS) is presently the most durable and effective intervention to address severe obesity. BS results in significant weight loss and body composition changes, with reductions in both fat mass and lean mass. Conequently, muscle tissue wasting and a reduction in muscle strength and endurance seem to take place. Some studies have evaluated the impact of resistance training on changes in lean body mass and muscle strength either alone or along with protein supplementation in the first year after BS. However, the effects of core stabilization training on core endurance, postural control, and aerobic capacity in patients after BS have not been evaluated.</p></sec><sec><title>AIM</title><p>This study assessed the effect of a home telehealth core stabilization exercise program on core stability, postural control, and aerobic capacity in patients after BS.</p></sec><sec><title>DESIGN</title><p>A single-blinded randomized controlled trial.</p></sec><sec><title>SETTING</title><p>Home-based exercise program.</p></sec><sec><title>POPULATION</title><p>Patients after BS.</p></sec><sec><title>METHODS</title><p>Fifty-four patients who underwent BS randomly assigned into study and control groups. The study group followed a telehealth supervised home core stabilization program for 8 weeks, while the control group did not receive any form of exercises. Core endurance tests, postural stability, and aerobic capacity were assessed at baseline and after 8 weeks in both groups.</p></sec><sec><title>RESULTS</title><p>No significant difference was noted between groups at baseline (P&gt;0.05). The outcome of the group comparisons showed significant improvement in core endurance tests, postural stability, and aerobic capacity in the study group. Between groups comparision showed that the study group scores significantly higher than the control group (P&lt;0.05). However, the control group showed non-significant changes in any measured variables after eight weeks (P&gt;0.05).</p></sec><sec><title>CONCLUSIONS</title><p>Eight weeks of a home-based telehealth core exercise program improves core endurance, postural stability, and aerobic capacity in patients after BS.</p></sec><sec><title>CLINICAL REHABILITATION IMPACT</title><p>The core stabilization exercise is an important rehabilitation program that should be implemented after BS. Telehealth is an alternative rehabilitation tool during the COVID -19 pandemic.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group kwd-group-type="author"><title>K<sc>ey</sc>
<sc>words</sc>: </title><kwd>Bariatric surgery</kwd><kwd>Telemedicine</kwd><kwd>Postural balance</kwd><kwd>COVID-19</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-ND</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><p>Over the last few decades, bariatric surgery (BS) has remained an enduring and effective clinical treatment for morbid obesity. The number of BS procedures has grown dramatically owing to its ability in reducing body weight and improving comorbidities and mortality associated with morbid obesity.<sup>1, 2</sup> BS plays a significant role in improving patients’ health outcomes, enhancing functional mobility, relieving musculoskeletal pain, and magnifying the patient’s quality of life.<sup>3.</sup></p><p>Despite the extreme fat mass loss after BS, a considerable loss of lean body mass<sup>4</sup> is noted which can increase the adverse effect on physical activities and muscle strength.<sup>5</sup> Nearly 30% of weight reduction after BS is attributed to a reduction in muscle mass,<sup>6</sup> which leads to a consequent decline in absolute muscle strength and has a direct negative impact on physical function.<sup>7, 8</sup></p><p>Studies have reported that weight loss after BS is associated with low back pain relief.<sup>9</sup> However, the opposite might occur with increasing pain severity and discomfort. A retrospective study found that 30 obese patients (BMI≥30 kg/m<sup>2</sup>) were presented with new-onset or exacerbation of pre-existing low back pain following BS.<sup>1</sup> The major factors associated with the back pain were the reduction in intra-abdominal pressure (IAP), spinal instability, and increased loading on the vertebral bodies and discs.<sup>10</sup> It is postulated that IAP improves lumbar stability through the activation of abdominal, diaphragmatic, and pelvic floor muscles.<sup>11</sup> Following BS, the IAP decreases, creating a disequilibrium state in the spine, uneven loading of the discs, and vertebral bodies,<sup>10</sup> leading to low back pain, disc herniation, and radiculopathy.<sup>12</sup></p><p>In the last few years, significant attention has been given to the efficacy of different exercise protocols for patients who have undergone BS. Positive effects of supervised resisted training on physical fitness, functional capacity, and muscle strength were reported.<sup>13, 14</sup> In addition, adding a protein supplement to resisted exercise was effective in enhancing the lower limb muscle strength in patients after gastric bypass surgery.<sup>2</sup> Arman <italic toggle="yes">et al.</italic>,<sup>15</sup> have concluded that 8-week of core stabilization exercise along with physical activities improves functional capacity, physical fitness, the quality of life and reduces fatigue, in obese individuals awaiting BS.</p><p>Barriers to healthcare access, such as distance, time, and expense, may be overcome with technological breakthroughs. COVID-19 had a striking effect on healthcare services globally, with many physiotherapy services rapidly transitioning to telehealth. Evidence has shown that telehealth is an effective delivery model to offer physiotherapy services with results equal to or even superior to face-to-face musculoskeletal care management.<sup>16</sup> Telehealth is a safe and beneficial mode of delivering physiotherapy to patients with various diseases.<sup>17</sup></p><p>Despite the benefits associated with telehealth for an exercise program, no previous studies have investigated the effects of supervised telehealth core stabilization exercise programs in patients who have undergone BS. This study aimed to assess the effect of a home telehealth core stabilization exercise program with supervision on core endurance, postural control, and aerobic capacity in patients after BS.</p><sec sec-type="materials|methods"><title>Materials and methods</title><sec><title>Study design</title><p>This is a single-blinded randomized controlled trial study.</p></sec><sec><title>Participants</title><p>In this study the inclusion criteria was at least 6 months after BS. Subjects who were involved in a structured physical activity program; subjects with systematic or visceral diseases, nerve root compression, spine disorders, previous surgery, lower limb injury, or pregnant females were excluded from the program.<sup>18</sup> This study was approved by BMC Ethical Board (UB-RES-2021-0021) with Clinical Registration No. (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="pmc:clinical-trial" xlink:href="NCT04932694">NCT04932694</ext-link>). Eligible subjects were randomly assigned with the study and control groups by a blinded independent researcher. Randomization was performed to allocate groups using generated computer numbers in sealed opaque envelopes. Informed consent was obtained from the eligible patients after being presented with a detailed description of the study’s aims and procedures. The study protocol was conducted according to the Declaration of Helsinki, and the sample size was calculated based on the core endurance test, which was the primary outcome of this study. The G power software (Universities, Dusseldorf, Germany) was used to estimate the sample size following the power of 80%, a P value of 0.05, and an effect size of 0.82. A sample size of 25 subjects in each group was required, and 61 subjects were initially included to account for dropouts (<xref rid="f1" ref-type="fig">Figure 1</xref>).</p><fig position="float" id="f1" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>—Study flow chart.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="7457-f1.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec><title>Outcome measure</title><p>Measurements were conducted by a blinded assessor on two occasions; baseline and after the study was completed.</p><sec><title>Primary outcome measures</title><sec><title>The core endurance tests</title><p>McGill’s tests were used to examine participants’ core endurance. The maximum duration was recorded in seconds when the person is attempting to hold four positions: sit-up position with trunk supported at 60° of trunk flexion (the trunk anterior flexor test), side-lying bridging while resting on the forearm with extended knees (the right and left lateral plank), and prone with the trunk, and upper extremities out of the table (the trunk posterior extensor test). The detailed procedures of these tests are fully described in a previous study.<sup>19</sup></p></sec></sec><sec><title>Secondary outcome measures</title><sec><title>Postural stability assessment</title><p>Biodex Balance System (BBS) (Biodex medical system, Shirley, NY, USA) is a valid and reliable method to assess dynamic balance and postural stability.<sup>20</sup> The measured postural stability indices comprised the Overall Stability Index (OSI) used to assess the postural control in all directions; the Anteroposterior Stability Index (APSI) assessed the postural control in the sagittal plane, and the Mediolateral Stability Index (MLSI) assessed the postural control in the frontal plane. All patients were tested on stability level 8 for 30 seconds. BBS assessment followed numerical values, where higher values indicated a lower level of stability, and a lower value was a higher level of stability.<sup>21</sup></p></sec><sec><title>Aerobics capacity</title><p>A 6-minute walking test (6MWT) is a valid and reliable method for assessing aerobic functional ability by measuring the distance covered within 6 minutes. A higher distance indicates better aerobic capacity.<sup>22</sup> The 6MWT test was performed following the standard protocol of the American Thoracic Society guidelines. Subjects were asked to walk for 6 min on a straight, flat, and hard surface hallway at their own pace with the encouragement of a physiotherapist. The 6MW distance covered during the test was recorded in meters and the heart rate was measured before and after the test.<sup>23</sup></p></sec></sec></sec><sec><title>Interventions</title><p>Subjects in the study group performed two equal phases of core stabilization exercises 3 days per week, for 8 weeks. The exercise program was adopted from the procedures developed by Narouei <italic toggle="yes">et al.</italic><sup>18</sup> Each phase consisted of five exercises repeated in 2 circuits with each exercise performed in 8-15 reps with 5-10 s hold based on the subject’s physical ability for each contraction. Thirty seconds of rest were allotted to the subjects after each exercise and two min rest between circuits. Subjects started the training with warm-up exercises in the form of low-intensity aerobic exercises, general stretching exercises for 5 minutes, and cool down for 5 minutes.<sup>18, 24</sup> Participants in the control group did not perform any core exercises.</p><p>Following the recommendation of the American Physical Therapy Association (APTA), the core program was conducted at home with remote supervision. APTA recommends that physical therapists should use telehealth services during the COVID-19 pandemic to limit the spread of the disease.<sup>25</sup> Patients were provided flyers with full descriptions and illustrations of the exercises to guide them about the exercise at home. Patients were asked to attend the physical therapy lab at the start and end of the exercise program. In the first session, the patients were evaluated and received a full demonstration of the exercise program. In addition, patients were asked to sign consent forms, which were collected. Once a week, a physical therapist supervised the exercise program remotely.<sup>26</sup></p><p>Exercises completed in Phase one were as follows:</p><p>1.1. Abdominal drawing: subjects pulled in the belly button without stopping the breathing from a crock lying position.</p><p>1.2. Alternate arm and leg lift: subjects elevated the upper and lower extremities to approximately 10 cm from a prone position with a pillow under the abdomen.</p><p>1.3. Unilateral glute bridging: from a supine lying position, the pelvis was elevated straight while one leg flexed to 90, and the second leg was positioned in neutral alignment on the ground. The exercise was conducted on right and left sides.</p><p>1.4. Quadruped contralateral arm and leg lift: subjects positioned in a quadruped position with erect trunk and elevated opposite upper and lower extremities simultaneously parallel to the ground.</p><p>1.5. Curl up: from a hook lying position, subjects placed both hands under the lumbar region to support the spine, pulled in the abdomen to flatten the lumbar spine, and raised the head and upper trunk straight to pull the inferior angle of the scapula off the ground.</p><p>Exercises completed in Phase two were as follows.</p><p>2.1. Sideway bridging: from the side-lying position, the weight was supported on one elbow while the other arm was placed across the chest, knees almost extended, and feet stacked over each other. The subject lifted the pelvis straight off the ground.</p><p>2.2. Diagonal curl up: subjects were placed on a hook lying with hands altogether, elevated head and upper trunk to raise the scapula lower angle to reach the opposite knee.</p><p>2.3. Sit back: subjects were positioned by sitting with the knee flexed 90<sup>0</sup>,feet on the floor, drawing the abdomen and elevating the upper trunk to an angle of 45<sup>0</sup> from the ground, and holding the position.</p><p>2.4. Single leg deadlift: subjects stood on a single limb with 30<sup>0</sup> flexion of the hip; knee joints and ipsilateral hand moved slowly to the lateral malleolus and extended the opposite hip.</p><p>2.5. Prone hip extension: from a prone position with a third of the lower extremity on a table, subjects held the edges of the table with their hands and moved both lower extremities up with their extended knee.<sup>27</sup> Exercises in both phases are shown in <xref rid="f2" ref-type="fig">Figure 2</xref>.</p><fig position="float" id="f2" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>—The core stabilization exercises in both phases.</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="7457-f2.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec><title>Statistical analysis</title><p>Shapiro-Wilk Test, drawing box blot and histogram, were used to check homogenity of the measured outcomes. All measured parameters (postural stability, back endurance tests, and 6 MWT) exhibited a parametric distribution. Two-way mixed model MANOVA was used to distinguish between and within the measured outcomes. Unpaired T-Test was applied to compare the participants’ demographic data, chi-square test was used for comparison of categorical data, and were. Quantitative data are displayed as mean and standard deviation. The significance level was set at P≤0.05 with a confidence level of 95%. All statistical analyses were performed with IBM<sup>®</sup> SPSS<sup>®</sup> Statistics Version 20.</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="results"><title>Results</title><p>A total of 54 individuals (35 females and 19 males) who were referred by surgeons from local hospitals and medical Private centers participated in the study. The study flowchart is presented in <xref rid="f1" ref-type="fig">Figure 1</xref>. The participant’s age was 18-40 years, and the demographic characteristics of the participants are shown in <xref rid="tI" ref-type="table">Table I</xref>. No significant difference was noted between the two groups regarding age, weight, height, BMI, duration after BS, sex, participants’ clinical characteristics, and the baseline values of the measured outcomes of P&gt;0.05, as displayed in <xref rid="tI" ref-type="table">Table I, II</xref><xref rid="tII" ref-type="table"/>.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="tI" orientation="portrait"><label>Table I</label><caption><title>—<italic toggle="yes">Demographic and clinical characteristics of both groups.</italic></title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><col width="45.37%" span="1"/><col width="21.43%" span="1"/><col width="21.43%" span="1"/><col width="11.77%" span="1"/><thead><tr><th valign="top" align="left" scope="col" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Characteristics</th><th valign="top" align="left" scope="col" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Study group <break/>(N.=28)<break/>(M±SD)</th><th valign="top" align="left" scope="col" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Control group <break/>(N.=26)<break/>(M±SD)</th><th valign="top" align="left" scope="col" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">P value</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Age (years)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">35.3±8.74</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">32.9±8.75</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.333</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Height (cm)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">168.8±9.2</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">170±7.13</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.625</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Weight (kg)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.8±7.6</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">90.1±7.2</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.270</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">BMI (kg/m)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">30.8</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">31.1</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.380</td></tr><tr><td colspan="4" valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="col" rowspan="1">Sex</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="2" valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" colspan="1">M (N. [%])<break/>F (N. [%])</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9 (32.1%)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10 (38.5%)</td><td rowspan="2" valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" colspan="1">0.627</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" colspan="1" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1">19 (67.9%)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">16 (61.5%)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Duration after BS (months)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9.79±1.8</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8.81±1.88</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.06</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Hypertension</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2 (7.1%)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 (11.5%)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.663</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">DM</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 (10.7%)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4 (15.4)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.699</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Dyspnea on exertion</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6 (21.4%)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5 (19.2%)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.414</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Medication for comorbidities</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4 (14.3%)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6 (23.1%)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.208</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>P value: significance level; M±SD: mean±standard deviation; N.: number; BMI: Body Mass Index; DM: diabetes mellitus; M: male; F: female; %: percentage; BS: bariatric surgery.</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><table-wrap position="float" id="tII" orientation="portrait"><label>Table II</label><caption><title>—<italic toggle="yes">Within and between groups’ comparisons of the outcome measures.</italic></title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><col width="37.74%" span="1"/><col width="23.49%" span="1"/><col width="25.05%" span="1"/><col width="13.72%" span="1"/><thead><tr><th valign="top" align="left" scope="col" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Variables</th><th valign="top" align="left" scope="col" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Study group<break/>(N.=28)<break/>(M±SD)</th><th valign="top" align="left" scope="col" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Control group<break/>(N.=26)<break/>(M±SD)</th><th valign="top" align="left" scope="col" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">P value</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td colspan="4" valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="col" rowspan="1">The trunk anterior flexor test (sec)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Baseline</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">60.8±12.55</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">62.5±14.6</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.645</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Post treatment</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">77.7±13.0</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">59.77±11.93</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">P value*</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.337</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MD (95% CI)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">16.93(22.4-11.5)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.73(2.93-8.38)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Percentage of treatment effect</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">31.14%</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.81%</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td colspan="4" valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="col" rowspan="1">The trunk posterior extensor test (s)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Baseline</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">50.86±11.76</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">46.62±9.5</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.153</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Post treatment</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">59.5±11.8</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">45.81±10.97</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">P value*</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.703</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MD (95% CI)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8.64(12.72-4.57)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.81(3.42-5.0.03)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Percentage of treatment effect</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">20.14%</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.03%</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td colspan="4" valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="col" rowspan="1">Right lateral plank test (s)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Baseline</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">36.7±8.6</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">37.1±4.83</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.836</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Post treatment</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">41.1±10</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">36.8±5.5</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.048</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">P value*</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.725</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MD (95% CI)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.36(6.25-2.5)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.35(1.61-2.31)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Percentage of treatment effect</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">13.13%</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.58%</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td colspan="4" valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="col" rowspan="1">Lt lateral plank test (s)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Baseline</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">33.9±4.4</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">35.23±4.64</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.269</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Post treatment</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">37.3±6.8</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">33.6±6</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.041</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">P value*</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.004</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.167</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MD (95% CI)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.4(5.7-1.11)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.65(4.02-0.71)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Percentage of treatment effect</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10.98%</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.52%</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td colspan="4" valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="col" rowspan="1">Overall Stability Index (OSI)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Baseline</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.6±0.38</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.73±0.52</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.278</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Post-treatment</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.5±0.45</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.61±0.37</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">P value*</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.207</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MD (95% CI)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.45(0.26-0.63)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.12(-0.31-0.07)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Percentage of treatment effect</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">27.34%</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.2%</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td colspan="4" valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="col" rowspan="1">Anteroposterior Stability Index (APSI)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Baseline</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.21±0.53</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.25±0.56</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.701</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Post treatment</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.88±0.35</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1.2±0.5</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.005</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">P value*</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.027</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.816</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MD (95% CI)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.31(0.36-0.58)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.03(0.25-0.32)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Percentage of treatment effect</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12.98%</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12.66%</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td colspan="4" valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="col" rowspan="1">Mediolateral Stability Index (MLSI)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Baseline</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.81±0.1</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.91±0.25</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.10</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Post treatment</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.67±90.25</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.96±0.26</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">P value*</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.001</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.124</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MD (95% CI)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.143(0.07-0.22)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.06(0.14-0.018)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Percentage of treatment effect</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">17.72%</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8.9%</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td colspan="4" valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="col" rowspan="1">6 MWT (m)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Baseline (% of max predicted HR)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">458±28.5 (67±9.3%)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">456.88±33.8 (66±10.4%)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.896</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Post treatment (% of max predicted HR)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">492.9±33.3 (56±7.5%)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">454.31±32.7 (64±11%)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">P value*</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">&lt;0.001</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.667</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">MD (95% CI)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">34.9(46.4-23.39)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2.58(9.36-14.51)</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr><tr><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" scope="row" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Percentage of treatment effect</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7.93%</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.5%</td><td valign="top" align="left" style="border-left: solid 1pt; border-top: solid 1pt; border-right: solid 1pt; border-bottom: solid 1pt" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><p>P value*: within group significance level; P value: between groups significance level; 6 MWT: 6 Minutes Walking Test; M±SD: mean±standard deviation; N.: number; CI: confidence interval; HR: heart rate.</p></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><p>After 8 weeks of core training, improvements were noted in the study group regarding the core endurance tests (P&lt;0.05), postural stability indices OSI, API, MLI, (P&lt;0.001, 0.027, and 0.001), respectively, and aerobic capacity (P&lt;0.001). However, within group comparisons of the control group showed a nonsignificant differences in measured outcomes (P&gt;0.05). When compared the study group with the control group, significant differences were displayed in measured outcomes (P&gt;0.05) after 8 weeks, as shown in <xref rid="tII" ref-type="table">Table II</xref>.</p></sec><sec sec-type="discussion"><title>Discussion</title><p>In the first six months after BS, patients experienced rapid weight loss and a significant decrease in fat-free mass, accounting for 30-35% of the total body weight loss. The weight loss peaks over a 2-year remain relatively stable from 2 to 20 years.<sup>28</sup> Excessive weight loss, malabsorption due to surgery, and insufficient protein intake contribute to muscle tissue wasting and a reduction in muscle strength and endurance<sup>2, 29</sup> Slow core muscles with predominantly oxidative metabolism are more susceptible to atrophy than muscles with fast-twitch fibers because of the severe effects on their oxidative enzyme content.<sup>29</sup> This previously mentioned study reveals that structured core stability programs that focus on muscle activation, neuromuscular control, and dynamic stability could improve core muscle endurance for functional demands associated with most daily living and sport activities.<sup>30</sup></p><p>This randomized controlled trial showed that 8 weeks of telehealth-supervised core stabilization exercise program (CSEP) improved core endurance, postural control, and 6 minutes walking test (6 MWT) in patients after BS compared with the controls who did not participate in the core training. The results would help in organizing effective programs to reduce the incidence of postoperative complications following BS. Core stability exercises are common component of musculoskeletal injury pervention programs. Previous studies have reported that impaired core stability is a risk factor for low back pain and lower extremity injury rates.<sup>31</sup></p><p>The improvement of core endurance in the study group could be explained by the fact that most of the type I core muscle fibers could benefit from the adopted high-repetition exercise program.<sup>32</sup> Other adaptations to core training increased blood supply to muscles, improved coordination of motor units, and increased the fuel storage in muscles, which ultimately enhanced endurance.<sup>33</sup> At the cellular level, the mitochondrial content increases rapidly after 6 weeks of training as reported by Henriksson.<sup>34</sup></p><p>Our results are consistent with those of Sandrey and Mitzel<sup>35</sup> who reported that after 6 weeks of a core stabilization program in high school track and field athletes, a significant increase in the core endurance tests was noted after conducting an abdominal fatigue test, back extensor test, and side bridge test for both the right and left side. Hoppes <italic toggle="yes">et al.</italic>,<sup>36</sup> found that an eight-week of core stabilization exercise program significantly improved three timed physical endurance tests, such as the horizontal side support, extensor endurance, and flexor endurance in active-duty US Service members.</p><p>Obesity is a risk factor for falls and fear of falls because of postural deviations and loss of balance.<sup>37</sup> Beside obesity, other risk factors for falls include demographic characteristics, physical health status, comorbidities, emotional status, cognitive function, and physical activity habits.<sup>38</sup> Ercan <italic toggle="yes">et al.</italic>,<sup>39</sup> investigated the effect of obesity using gender on balance, the risk of falls, and the fear of falls in a sample of 125 obese persons. The authors concluded that obese females had a high fear of falls and low confidence in daily activities. A significant inverse relationship was found between Body Mass Index and loss of balance. These balance-related problems may continue even after the weight loss surgery considering, almost 80% of patients who have undergone BS are women.<sup>40</sup> Our study also demonstrated that the OSI, APSI, and MLSI improved significantly following the CSEP. These improvements can explained by the positive effects of core stability exercise on the neuromuscular system specifically, ideal lumbar-pelvic-hip chain mobility, optimal movement acceleration and deceleration, proper muscle balance, and efficient proximal stability.<sup>15</sup></p><p>Additionally, gains in core muscle strength and endurance are vital because they maintain and stabilize the spinal segments against external stresses. Previous studies reported a positive correlation between core endurance and balance in different sex and age populations. It was hypothesized that a strong core structure allows less postural oscillations of the thoracolumbar fascia and distal body parts.<sup>41, 42</sup> These results agree with Lugo-Larcheveque <italic toggle="yes">et al.</italic>,<sup>43</sup> who find that core training improves core muscular strength and body movement stability during the limit of stability tests, which requires good upper and lower extremity limb coordination.</p><p>Finally, the significant improvement in 6 MWT can be attributed to an increase in blood flow, cardiac output, and VO<sub>2max</sub> that occur during exercises. During core strengthening exercises, the core muscles’ co-contraction and pressure changes by the diaphragm help supplying blood and oxygen that the body requires during exercises.<sup>44</sup> The results agreed with previous studies that reported improved aerobic activities such as long-distance running<sup>45</sup> and shuttle run performance<sup>46</sup> after core strengthening programs. The insignificant change in aerobic capacity of the control group found in this study, disagrees with Vargas <italic toggle="yes">et al.</italic>,<sup>47</sup> who reported that BS itself resulted in a significant improvement in physical performance. The study has used the self-reported Short Form 36-Item (SF-36) questionnaire to assess functional capacity while our study used the 6MWT.</p><p>This study highlighted the importance of telehealth in improving patients’ self-care management and reducing patient time and daily travel expenses. During the COVID-19 pandemic, telerehabilitation helps in continuing therapeutic services and monitoring patients’ performance during the treatment programs.<sup>48</sup> In Australia, Russell <italic toggle="yes">et al.</italic>,<sup>49</sup> found that a 6-week telerehabilitation intervention resulted in excellent patient satisfaction compared to normal outpatients’ treatment after total knee arthroplasty.</p><sec><title>Limitations of the study</title><p>This study has some limitations; only short-term effects were assessed. Future studies should investigate the long-term effects of core training in individuals after BS. Moreover, advanced core training using unstable surfaces was excluded from the established program because of the unavailability of training tools at the participants’ homes. Finally, the core program is designed to suit individuals after BS and should be revised before it is applied to another pathological population. The literature review showed a lack of consistency in core training programs that could be applied to all populations.<sup>30</sup></p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="conclusions"><title>Conclusions</title><p>Eight weeks of home-based telehealth core exercise program improves the core endurance, postural stability, and aerobic capacity in patients after BS.</p></sec></body><back><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="r1"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Skaf</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Elias</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nasser</surname><given-names>Z.</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Worsening Back Pain after Bariatric Surgery.</article-title>
<source>The Impact of Acute Weight Loss on the Spine.</source>
<year>2017</year>;<volume>2</volume>:<fpage>1</fpage>–<lpage>3</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r2"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Oppert</surname><given-names>JM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bellicha</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Roda</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bouillot</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Torcivia</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Clement</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Resistance Training and Protein Supplementation Increase Strength After Bariatric Surgery: A Randomized Controlled Trial.</article-title>
<source>Obesity (Silver Spring)</source>
<year>2018</year>;<volume>26</volume>:<fpage>1709</fpage>–<lpage>20</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=30358153&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=30358153&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/oby.22317</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30358153</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r3"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ryder</surname><given-names>JR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Edwards</surname><given-names>NM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gupta</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Khoury</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jenkins</surname><given-names>TM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bout-Tabaku</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Changes in functional mobility and musculoskeletal pain after bariatric surgery in teens with severe obesity teen-longitudinal assessment of bariatric surgery (LABS) study.</article-title>
<source>JAMA Pediatr</source>
<year>2016</year>;<volume>170</volume>:<fpage>871</fpage>–<lpage>7</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=27429076&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=27429076&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1001/jamapediatrics.2016.1196</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27429076</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5904853</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r4"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zalesin</surname><given-names>KC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Franklin</surname><given-names>BA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lillystone</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shamoun</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Krause</surname><given-names>KR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chengelis</surname><given-names>DL</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Differential loss of fat and lean mass in the morbidly obese after bariatric surgery.</article-title>
<source>Metab Syndr Relat Disord</source>
<year>2010</year>;<volume>8</volume>:<fpage>15</fpage>–<lpage>20</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=19929598&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=19929598&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1089/met.2009.0012</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19929598</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r5"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Alba</surname><given-names>DL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cawthon</surname><given-names>PM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mulligan</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lang</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Changes in Lean Mass, Absolute and Relative Muscle Strength, and Physical Performance After Gastric Bypass Surgery.</article-title>
<source>J Clin Endocrinol Metab</source>
<year>2019</year>;<volume>104</volume>:<fpage>711</fpage>–<lpage>20</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=30657952&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=30657952&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1210/jc.2018-00952</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30657952</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6339456</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r6"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ito</surname><given-names>MK</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gonçalves</surname><given-names>VS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Faria</surname><given-names>SL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Moizé</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Porporatti</surname><given-names>AL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Guerra</surname><given-names>EN</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Effect of Protein Intake on the Protein Status and Lean Mass of Post-Bariatric Surgery Patients: a Systematic Review.</article-title>
<source>Obes Surg</source>
<year>2017</year>;<volume>27</volume>:<fpage>502</fpage>–<lpage>12</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=27844254&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=27844254&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11695-016-2453-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27844254</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r7"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hue</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Berrigan</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Simoneau</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Marcotte</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Marceau</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Marceau</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Muscle force and force control after weight loss in obese and morbidly obese men.</article-title>
<source>Obes Surg</source>
<year>2008</year>;<volume>18</volume>:<fpage>1112</fpage>–<lpage>8</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=18584262&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=18584262&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11695-008-9597-5</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18584262</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r8"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Stegen</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Derave</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Calders</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Van Laethem</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pattyn</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Physical fitness in morbidly obese patients: effect of gastric bypass surgery and exercise training.</article-title>
<source>Obes Surg</source>
<year>2011</year>;<volume>21</volume>:<fpage>61</fpage>–<lpage>70</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=19997987&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=19997987&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11695-009-0045-y</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19997987</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r9"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Joaquim</surname><given-names>AF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Helvie</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Patel</surname><given-names>AA</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Bariatric Surgery and Low Back Pain: A Systematic Literature Review.</article-title>
<source>Global Spine J</source>
<year>2020</year>;<volume>10</volume>:<fpage>102</fpage>–<lpage>10</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=32002354&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=32002354&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/2192568219826935</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32002354</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6963354</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r10"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cresswell</surname><given-names>AG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Oddsson</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Thorstensson</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>The influence of sudden perturbations on trunk muscle activity and intra-abdominal pressure while standing.</article-title>
<source>Exp Brain Res</source>
<year>1994</year>;<volume>98</volume>:<fpage>336</fpage>–<lpage>41</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=8050518&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=8050518&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/BF00228421</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">8050518</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r11"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hodges</surname><given-names>PW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cresswell</surname><given-names>AG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Daggfeldt</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Thorstensson</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>In vivo measurement of the effect of intra-abdominal pressure on the human spine.</article-title>
<source>J Biomech</source>
<year>2001</year>;<volume>34</volume>:<fpage>347</fpage>–<lpage>53</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=11182126&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=11182126&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0021-9290(00)00206-2</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">11182126</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r12"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Koyanagi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Stickley</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Garin</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Miret</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ayuso-Mateos</surname><given-names>JL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Leonardi</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>The association between obesity and back pain in nine countries: a cross-sectional study.</article-title>
<source>BMC Public Health</source>
<year>2015</year>;<volume>15</volume>:<fpage>123</fpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=25886589&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=25886589&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12889-015-1362-9</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25886589</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4331391</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r13"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Huck</surname><given-names>CJ</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Effects of supervised resistance training on fitness and functional strength in patients succeeding bariatric surgery.</article-title>
<source>J Strength Cond Res</source>
<year>2015</year>;<volume>29</volume>:<fpage>589</fpage>–<lpage>95</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=25226310&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=25226310&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000000667</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25226310</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r14"><label>14</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Daniels</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Burns</surname><given-names>RD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Brusseau</surname><given-names>TA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hall</surname><given-names>MS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Davidson</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Adams</surname><given-names>TD</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Effect of a randomised 12-week resistance training programme on muscular strength, cross-sectional area and muscle quality in women having undergone Roux-en-Y gastric bypass.</article-title>
<source>J Sports Sci</source>
<year>2018</year>;<volume>36</volume>:<fpage>529</fpage>–<lpage>35</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=28467737&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=28467737&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/02640414.2017.1322217</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28467737</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r15"><label>15</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Arman</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tokgoz</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Seyit</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Karabulut</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>The effects of core stabilization exercise program in obese people awaiting bariatric surgery: A randomized controlled study.</article-title>
<source>Complement Ther Clin Pract</source>
<year>2021</year>;<volume>43</volume>:<elocation-id>101342</elocation-id>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=33684639&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=33684639&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link> https://doi.org/<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ctcp.2021.101342</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33684639</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r16"><label>16</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bennell</surname><given-names>KL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lawford</surname><given-names>BJ</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Metcalf</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mackenzie</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Russell</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>van den Berg</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Physiotherapists and patients report positive experiences overall with telehealth during the COVID-19 pandemic: a mixed-methods study.</article-title>
<source>J Physiother</source>
<year>2021</year>;<volume>67</volume>:<fpage>201</fpage>–<lpage>9</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=34147399&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=34147399&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jphys.2021.06.009</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34147399</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8188301</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r17"><label>17</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Raiszadeh</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tapicer</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Taitano</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Shahidi</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>In-clinic versus web-based multidisciplinary exercise-based rehabilitation for treatment of low back pain: prospective clinical trial in an integrated practice unit model.</article-title>
<source>J Med Internet Res</source>
<year>2021</year>;<volume>23</volume>:<elocation-id>e22548</elocation-id>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=33734088&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=33734088&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2196/22548</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33734088</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8074858</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r18"><label>18</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Narouei</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Barati</surname><given-names>AH</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Akuzawa</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Talebian</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ghiasi</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Akbari</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Effects of core stabilization exercises on thickness and activity of trunk and hip muscles in subjects with nonspecific chronic low back pain.</article-title>
<source>J Bodyw Mov Ther</source>
<year>2020</year>;<volume>24</volume>:<fpage>138</fpage>–<lpage>46</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=33218502&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=33218502&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jbmt.2020.06.026</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33218502</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r19"><label>19</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Waldhelm</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Endurance tests are the most reliable core stability related measurements.</article-title>
<source>J Sport Health Sci</source>
<year>2012</year>;<volume>1</volume>:<fpage>121</fpage>–<lpage>8</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jshs.2012.07.007</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r20"><label>20</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hinman</surname><given-names>MR</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Factors Affecting Reliability of the Biodex Balance System: A Summary of Four Studies.</article-title>
<source>J Sport Rehabil</source>
<year>2000</year>;<volume>9</volume>:<fpage>240</fpage>–<lpage>52</lpage>. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1123/jsr.9.3.240</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r21"><label>21</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book">Biodex MS, System B. 3 Pro Manual (#835-000) Applications/Operations. Shirley, NY: Biodex Medical System; 1998.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r22"><label>22</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Maniscalco</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Zedda</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Giardiello</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Faraone</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cerbone</surname><given-names>MR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cristiano</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Effect of bariatric surgery on the six-minute walk test in severe uncomplicated obesity.</article-title>
<source>Obes Surg</source>
<year>2006</year>;<volume>16</volume>:<fpage>836</fpage>–<lpage>41</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=16839479&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=16839479&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link> https://doi.org/<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1381/096089206777822331</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16839479</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r23"><label>23</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Crapo</surname><given-names>RO</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Casaburi</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Coates</surname><given-names>AL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Enright</surname><given-names>PL</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>MacIntyre</surname><given-names>NR</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>McKay</surname><given-names>RT</given-names></name><etal/><collab>ATS Committee on Proficiency Standards for Clinical Pulmonary Function Laboratories</collab></person-group>. <article-title>ATS statement: guidelines for the six-minute walk test.</article-title>
<source>Am J Respir Crit Care Med</source>
<year>2002</year>;<volume>166</volume>:<fpage>111</fpage>–<lpage>7</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=12091180&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=12091180&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1164/ajrccm.166.1.at1102</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">12091180</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r24"><label>24</label><mixed-citation publication-type="webpage">Günay S, Yildirim Y, Karadibak D. The effect of the muscle endurance training on the chronic low back pain. Fiz Rehabil 2014;25:28–34. <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7603/s40680-014-0004-y</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r25"><label>25</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Simkins</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Innovations in Telehealth.</article-title>
<source>PT Motion.</source>
<year>2017</year>;<volume>9</volume>:<fpage>30</fpage>–<lpage>5</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r26"><label>26</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname><given-names>AC</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>COVID-19 and the Advancement of Digital Physical Therapist Practice and Telehealth.</article-title>
<source>Phys Ther</source>
<year>2020</year>;<volume>100</volume>:<fpage>1054</fpage>–<lpage>7</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=32343836&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=32343836&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/ptj/pzaa079</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32343836</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7197535</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r27"><label>27</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Waseem</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Karimi</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Gilani</surname><given-names>SA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hassan</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Treatment of disability associated with chronic non-specific low back pain using core stabilization exercises in Pakistani population.</article-title>
<source>J Back Musculoskeletal Rehabil</source>
<year>2019</year>;<volume>32</volume>:<fpage>149</fpage>–<lpage>54</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=30248035&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=30248035&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3233/BMR-171114</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30248035</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r28"><label>28</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>O’Brien</surname><given-names>PE</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hindle</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Brennan</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Skinner</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Burton</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>Long-Term Outcomes After Bariatric Surgery: a Systematic Review and Meta-analysis of Weight Loss at 10 or More Years for All Bariatric Procedures and a Single-Centre Review of 20-Year Outcomes After Adjustable Gastric Banding.</article-title>
<source>Obes Surg</source>
<year>2019</year>;<volume>29</volume>:<fpage>3</fpage>–<lpage>14</lpage>. <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=30293134&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri">https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=30293134&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11695-018-3525-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">30293134</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6320354</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r29"><label>29</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Appell</surname><given-names>HJ</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Muscular atrophy following immobilisation. A review.</article-title>
<source>Sports Med</source>
<year>1990</year>;<volume>10</volume>:<fpage>42</fpage>–<lpage>58</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=2197699&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=2197699&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2165/00007256-199010010-00005</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2197699</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r30"><label>30</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Huxel Bliven</surname><given-names>KC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Anderson</surname><given-names>BE</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Core stability training for injury prevention.</article-title>
<source>Sports Health</source>
<year>2013</year>;<volume>5</volume>:<fpage>514</fpage>–<lpage>22</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=24427426&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=24427426&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/1941738113481200</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24427426</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3806175</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r31"><label>31</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>De Blaiser</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Roosen</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Willems</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Danneels</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bossche</surname><given-names>LV</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>De Ridder</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Is core stability a risk factor for lower extremity injuries in an athletic population? A systematic review.</article-title>
<source>Phys Ther Sport</source>
<year>2018</year>;<volume>30</volume>:<fpage>48</fpage>–<lpage>56</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=29246794&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=29246794&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2017.08.076</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">29246794</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r32"><label>32</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Romero-Franco</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Martínez-López</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Lomas-Vega</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hita-Contreras</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Martínez-Amat</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Effects of proprioceptive training program on core stability and center of gravity control in sprinters.</article-title>
<source>J Strength Cond Res</source>
<year>2012</year>;<volume>26</volume>:<fpage>2071</fpage>–<lpage>7</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=21997455&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=21997455&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31823b06e6</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21997455</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r33"><label>33</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Boyaci</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Tutar</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>The Effecet of the Quad-Core Training on Core Muscle Strength and Endurance.</article-title>
<source>Int J Sports Sci</source>
<year>2018</year>;<volume>8</volume>:<fpage>50</fpage>–<lpage>4</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r34"><label>34</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Henriksson</surname><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Effects of physical training on the metabolism of skeletal muscle.</article-title>
<source>Diabetes Care</source>
<year>1992</year>;<volume>15</volume>:<fpage>1701</fpage>–<lpage>11</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=1468304&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=1468304&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2337/diacare.15.11.1701</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">1468304</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r35"><label>35</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Sandrey</surname><given-names>MA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mitzel</surname><given-names>JG</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Improvement in dynamic balance and core endurance after a 6-week core-stability-training program in high school track and field athletes.</article-title>
<source>J Sport Rehabil</source>
<year>2013</year>;<volume>22</volume>:<fpage>264</fpage>–<lpage>71</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=23799868&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=23799868&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1123/jsr.22.4.264</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23799868</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r36"><label>36</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hoppes</surname><given-names>CW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sperier</surname><given-names>AD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hopkins</surname><given-names>CF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Griffiths</surname><given-names>BD</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Principe</surname><given-names>MF</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Schnall</surname><given-names>BL</given-names></name><etal/></person-group>
<article-title>The efficacy of an eight- week core stabilization program on core muscle function and endurance: A randomized trial.</article-title>
<source>Int J Sports Phys Ther</source>
<year>2016</year>;<volume>11</volume>:<fpage>507</fpage>–<lpage>19</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=27525175&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=27525175&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27525175</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4970841</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r37"><label>37</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bruce</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hunter</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Peters</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Davis</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Davis</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Fear of falling is common in patients with type 2 diabetes and is associated with increased risk of falls.</article-title>
<source>Age Ageing</source>
<year>2015</year>;<volume>44</volume>:<fpage>687</fpage>–<lpage>90</lpage>. <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=25739747&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri">https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=25739747&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/ageing/afv024</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25739747</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r38"><label>38</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Jung</surname><given-names>D.</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Fear of falling in older adults: comprehensive review.</article-title>
<source>Asian Nurs Res</source>
<year>2008</year>;<volume>2</volume>:<fpage>214</fpage>–<lpage>22</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=25029959&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=25029959&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S1976-1317(09)60003-7</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25029959</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r39"><label>39</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ercan</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Baskurt</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Baskurt</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cetin</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Balance disorder, falling risks and fear of falling in obese individuals: cross-sectional clinical research in Isparta.</article-title>
<source>J Pak Med Assoc</source>
<year>2020</year>;<volume>70</volume>:<fpage>17</fpage>–<lpage>23</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=31954018&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=31954018&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31954018</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.5455/JPMA.293668</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r40"><label>40</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Aly</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Hachey</surname><given-names>K</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pernar</surname><given-names>LI</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Gender disparities in weight loss surgery.</article-title>
<source>Mini-invasive Surg.</source>
<year>2020</year>;<volume>4</volume>:<fpage>21</fpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r41"><label>41</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ambegaonkar</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mettinger</surname><given-names>LM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Caswell</surname><given-names>SV</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Burtt</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cortes</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Relationships between core endurance, hip strength, and balance in collegiate female athletes.</article-title>
<source>Int J Sports Phys Ther</source>
<year>2014</year>;<volume>9</volume>:<fpage>604</fpage>–<lpage>16</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=25328823&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=25328823&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">25328823</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4196325</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r42"><label>42</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Barati</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Safarcherati</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Aghayari</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Azizi</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Abbasi</surname><given-names>H.</given-names></name></person-group>
<article-title>Evaluation of Relationship between Trunk Muscle Endurance and Static Balance in Male Students.</article-title>
<source>Asian J Sports Med</source>
<year>2013</year>;<volume>4</volume>:<fpage>289</fpage>–<lpage>94</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=24800004&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=24800004&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.5812/asjsm.34250</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24800004</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC3977213</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r43"><label>43</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lugo-Larcheveque</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Pescatello</surname><given-names>LS</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dugdale</surname><given-names>TW</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Veltri</surname><given-names>DM</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Roberts</surname><given-names>WO</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Management of lower extremity malalignment during running with neuromuscular retraining of the proximal stabilizers.</article-title>
<source>Curr Sports Med Rep</source>
<year>2006</year>;<volume>5</volume>:<fpage>137</fpage>–<lpage>40</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=16640949&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=16640949&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/01.CSMR.0000306303.87825.e0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16640949</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r44"><label>44</label><mixed-citation publication-type="other">Sorosky S, Sorosky BS. The Management of Low Back Pain: A Comprehensive Rehabilitation Program. 2009.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r45"><label>45</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Afyon</surname><given-names>YA</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mulazimoglu</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Boyaci</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>The effects of core trainings on speed and agility skills of soccer players.</article-title>
<source>Int J Sports Sci</source>
<year>2017</year>;<volume>7</volume>:<fpage>239</fpage>–<lpage>44</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r46"><label>46</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Okada</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Huxel</surname><given-names>KC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Nesser</surname><given-names>TW</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Relationship between core stability, functional movement, and performance.</article-title>
<source>J Strength Cond Res</source>
<year>2011</year>;<volume>25</volume>:<fpage>252</fpage>–<lpage>61</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=20179652&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=20179652&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181b22b3e</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">20179652</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r47"><label>47</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Vargas</surname><given-names>CB</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Picolli</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Dani</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Padoin</surname><given-names>AV</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Mottin</surname><given-names>CC</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Functioning of obese individuals in pre- and postoperative periods of bariatric surgery.</article-title>
<source>Obes Surg</source>
<year>2013</year>;<volume>23</volume>:<fpage>1590</fpage>–<lpage>5</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=23515976&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=23515976&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link> https://doi.org/<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11695-013-0924-0</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23515976</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r48"><label>48</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>De Cola</surname><given-names>MC</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>De Luca</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bramanti</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bertè</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bramanti</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Calabrò</surname><given-names>RS</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Tele-health services for the elderly: A novel southern Italy family needs-oriented model.</article-title>
<source>J Telemed Telecare</source>
<year>2016</year>;<volume>22</volume>:<fpage>356</fpage>–<lpage>62</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=26377125&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=26377125&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1177/1357633X15604290</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">26377125</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref><ref id="r49"><label>49</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Russell</surname><given-names>TG</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Buttrum</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Wootton</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Jull</surname><given-names>GA</given-names></name></person-group>. <article-title>Internet-based outpatient telerehabilitation for patients following total knee arthroplasty: a randomized controlled trial.</article-title>
<source>J Bone Joint Surg Am</source>
<year>2011</year>;<volume>93</volume>:<fpage>113</fpage>–<lpage>20</lpage>.<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=21248209&amp;dopt=Abstract" ext-link-type="uri"> https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=PubMed&amp;list_uids=21248209&amp;dopt=Abstract</ext-link>
<pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2106/JBJS.I.01375</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21248209</pub-id></mixed-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article></pmc-articleset>