<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37526793</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2199-1170</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine - open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Resistance Training and Weight Loss in Older Adults: A Scoping Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>67</StartPage><MedlinePgn>67</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">67</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40798-023-00613-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Resistance training (RT) is one of the most effective interventions available to older adults wishing to slow the progressive loss of muscle size and strength known to occur with age. Less is known about the ability of RT to resist the onset of an equally problematic condition related to increased age: obesity. The objective of this scoping review was to characterize current research associated with RT and weight loss in older adults, including protocols, feasibility, and gaps in current knowledge. We searched six databases using variations of the terms "resistance training," "weight loss," and "older adults" for experimental or quasi-experimental studies published in the year 2009 or later. Studies were included if they featured at least one treatment group with a mean age of&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;65&#xa0;years that engaged in an RT-only exercise protocol with no aerobic or high-intensity interval component. Of the 6102 references identified by the initial database search, 24 were retained for analysis. Older women and older adults with obesity or sarcopenic obesity were the most studied groups (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;13), followed by healthy community-dwelling older adults (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;11) and studies involving older adults and some aspect of either dietary control or pharmaceutical intervention (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;8). Significant between-study heterogeneity was observed in the RT characteristics researchers thought optimal for improving body composition measures in older adults. Changes in body composition, rather than total body mass, were found to be the essential variables to consider when evaluating the effectiveness of an RT intervention aimed at reducing chronic disease in older adults. Weight loss alone appears to be an incomplete and problematic outcome measure for older adults, with changes in body composition (ratio of fat mass to lean mass) being the more appropriate variable to emphasize in this population. However, it is important to note that only one study, showing questionably reproducible findings, found a significant lean body mass gain. The lack of abundant high-quality evidence demonstrating combined RT and a healthy diet can lead to significant fat loss and lean body mass gain, coupled with high attrition rates observed in many of the studies reviewed, highlight the need for further rigorous research.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buskard</LastName><ForeName>Andrew N L</ForeName><Initials>ANL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Practice, Faculty of Medicine, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Medicine, Mayo Clinic and Foundation, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Petrella</LastName><ForeName>Robert J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Practice, Faculty of Medicine, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, Canada. robert.petrella@ubc.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Studies in Family Medicine, Department of Family Medicine, Western University, London, ON, Canada. robert.petrella@ubc.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Western University, London, ON, Canada. robert.petrella@ubc.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Kinesiology, Faculty of Education, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, Canada. robert.petrella@ubc.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000098583">Scoping Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101662568</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2198-9761</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Older adults</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Weight loss</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests with the content of this review.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37526793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10393929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-023-00613-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40798-023-00613-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson DJ, Piasecki M, Atherton PJ. The age-related loss of skeletal muscle mass and function: measurement and physiology of muscle fibre atrophy and muscle fibre loss in humans. Ageing Res Rev. 2018;47:123&#x2013;132. doi: 10.1016/j.arr.2018.07.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2018.07.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6202460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30048806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell WK, Williams J, Atherton P, Larvin M, Lund J, Narici M. Sarcopenia, dynapenia, and the impact of advancing age on human skeletal muscle size and strength; a quantitative review. Front Physiol. 2012;3:260. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2012.00260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphys.2012.00260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3429036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22934016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira-Silva A, Dutra MT, de Moraes WMAM, Funghetto SS, Lopes de Farias D, dos Santos PHF, et al. Resistance training-induced gains in muscle strength, body composition, and functional capacity are attenuated in elderly women with sarcopenic obesity. Clin Interv Aging. 2018;13:411&#x2013;417. doi: 10.2147/CIA.S156174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CIA.S156174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5858549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29588579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Colditz GA. Prevalence of overweight and obesity in the United States, 2007&#x2013;2012. JAMA Intern Med. 2015;175(8):1412&#x2013;1413. doi: 10.1001/jamainternmed.2015.2405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2015.2405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4625533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26098405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J-M, Ye H, Zhu Q, Zhang J-H, Liu Q-Q, Xie H-Y, et al. Effects of resistance training on body composition and physical function in elderly patients with osteosarcopenic obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Osteoporos. 2022;17(1):82. doi: 10.1007/s11657-022-01120-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11657-022-01120-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9163017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35654981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Decaria JE, Sharp C, Petrella RJ. Scoping review report: obesity in older adults. Int J Obes. 2012;36(9):1141&#x2013;1150. doi: 10.1038/ijo.2012.29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ijo.2012.29</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22410960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arksey H, O&#x2019;Malley L. Scoping studies: towards a methodological framework. Int J Soc Res Methodol. 2005;8(1):19&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1080/1364557032000119616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1364557032000119616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gambassi BB, Rodrigues B, Feriani DJ, do Jesus-Furtado-Almeida F, Sauaia BA, Schwingel PA, et al. Effects of resistance training of moderate intensity on heart rate variability, body composition, and muscle strength in healthy elderly women. Sport Sci Health. 2016;12(3):389&#x2013;395. doi: 10.1007/s11332-016-0303-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11332-016-0303-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marriott CFS, Petrella AFM, Marriott ECS, Boa Sorte Silva NC, Petrella RJ. High-intensity interval training in older adults: a scoping review. Sports Med Open. 2021;7(1):49. doi: 10.1186/s40798-021-00344-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40798-021-00344-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8289951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34279765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell WW, Haub MD, Wolfe RR, Ferrando AA, Sullivan DH, Apolzan JW, et al. Resistance training preserves fat-free mass without impacting changes in protein metabolism after weight loss in older women. Obesity. 2009;17(7):1332&#x2013;1339. doi: 10.1038/oby.2009.2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/oby.2009.2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4299870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19247271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gylling AT, Eriksen CS, Garde E, Wimmelmann CL, Reislev NL, Bieler T, et al. The influence of prolonged strength training upon muscle and fat in healthy and chronically diseased older adults. Exp Gerontol. 2020;136:110939. doi: 10.1016/j.exger.2020.110939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2020.110939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32277977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dib MM, Tomeleri CM, Nunes JP, Cunha PM, Ribeiro AS, Schiavoni D, et al. Effects of three resistance exercise orders on muscular function and body composition in older women. Int J Sports Med. 2020;41(14):1024&#x2013;1031. doi: 10.1055/a-1192-5205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-1192-5205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32688414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe5;rdstu HB, Andersen V, Fimland MS, Aasdahl L, Raastad T, Cumming KT, et al. Effectiveness of a resistance training program on physical function, muscle strength, and body composition in community-dwelling older adults receiving home care: a cluster-randomized controlled trial. Eur Rev Aging Phys Act. 2020;17(1):11. doi: 10.1186/s11556-020-00243-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s11556-020-00243-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7414534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32782626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>dos Santos L, Ribeiro AS, Nunes JP, Tomeleri CM, Nabuco HCG, Nascimento MA, et al. Effects of pyramid resistance-training system with different repetition zones on cardiovascular risk factors in older women: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(17):6115&#x2013;6125. doi: 10.3390/ijerph17176115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17176115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7503540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32842644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brochu M, Malita MF, Messier V, Doucet E, Strychar I, Lavoie J-M, et al. Resistance training does not contribute to improving the metabolic profile after a 6-month weight loss program in overweight and obese postmenopausal women. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2009;94(9):3226&#x2013;3233. doi: 10.1210/jc.2008-2706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2008-2706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19567540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straight CR, Dorfman LR, Cottell KE, Krol JM, Lofgren IE, Delmonico MJ. Effects of resistance training and dietary changes on physical function and body composition in overweight and obese older adults. J Phys Act Health. 2012;9(6):875&#x2013;883. doi: 10.1123/jpah.9.6.875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jpah.9.6.875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21952180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gadelha AB, Paiva FML, Gauche R, de Oliveira RJ, Lima RM. Effects of resistance training on sarcopenic obesity index in older women: a randomized controlled trial. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2016;65:168&#x2013;173. doi: 10.1016/j.archger.2016.03.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.archger.2016.03.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27057600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguiar AF, Janu&#xe1;rio RSB, Junior RP, Gerage AM, Pina FLC, do Nascimento MA, et al. Long-term creatine supplementation improves muscular performance during resistance training in older women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113(4):987&#x2013;996. doi: 10.1007/s00421-012-2514-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-012-2514-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23053133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fragala MS, Cadore EL, Dorgo S, Izquierdo M, Kraemer WJ, Peterson MD, et al. Resistance training for older adults: position statement from the national strength and conditioning association. J Strength Cond Res. 2019;33(8):2019&#x2013;2052. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0000000000003230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31343601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theodorakopoulos C, Jones J, Bannerman E, Greig CA. Effectiveness of nutritional and exercise interventions to improve body composition and muscle strength or function in sarcopenic obese older adults: a systematic review. Nutr Res. 2017;43:3&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1016/j.nutres.2017.05.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nutres.2017.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28739051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ransdell LB, Wayment HA, Lopez N, Lorts C, Schwartz AL, Pugliesi K, et al. The impact of resistance training on body composition, muscle strength, and functional fitness in older women (45&#x2013;80 years): a systematic review (2010&#x2013;2020) Women Basel Switz. 2021;1(3):143&#x2013;168. doi: 10.3390/women1030014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/women1030014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9191851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35702064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas E, Gentile A, Lakicevic N, Moro T, Bellafiore M, Paoli A, et al. The effect of resistance training programs on lean body mass in postmenopausal and elderly women: a meta-analysis of observational studies. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2021;33(11):2941&#x2013;2952. doi: 10.1007/s40520-021-01853-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40520-021-01853-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8595144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33880736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindle RS, Metter EJ, Lynch NA, Fleg JL, Fozard JL, Tobin J, et al. Age and gender comparisons of muscle strength in 654 women and men aged 20&#x2013;93 yr. J Appl Physiol Bethesda Md. 1997;83(5):1581&#x2013;1587. doi: 10.1152/jappl.1997.83.5.1581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jappl.1997.83.5.1581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9375323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leenders M, Verdijk LB, van der Hoeven L, van Kranenburg J, Nilwik R, van Loon LJC. Elderly men and women benefit equally from prolonged resistance-type exercise training. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2013;68(7):769&#x2013;779. doi: 10.1093/gerona/gls241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/gls241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23223011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beard JR, Officer A, de Carvalho IA, Sadana R, Pot AM, Michel J-P, et al. The World report on ageing and health: a policy framework for healthy ageing. Lancet Lond Engl. 2016;387(10033):2145&#x2013;2154. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(15)00516-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(15)00516-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4848186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26520231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavalcante E, Ribeiro A, do Nascimento M, Silva A, Tomeleri C, Nabuco H, et al. Effects of different resistance training frequencies on fat in overweight/obese older women. Int J Sports Med. 2018;39(07):527&#x2013;534. doi: 10.1055/a-0599-6555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-0599-6555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29775988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha PM, Ribeiro AS, Tomeleri CM, Schoenfeld BJ, Silva AM, Souza MF, et al. The effects of resistance training volume on osteosarcopenic obesity in older women. J Sports Sci. 2018;36(14):1564&#x2013;1571. doi: 10.1080/02640414.2017.1403413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02640414.2017.1403413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29125017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avila JJ, Gutierres JA, Sheehy ME, Lofgren IE, Delmonico MJ. Effect of moderate intensity resistance training during weight loss on body composition and physical performance in overweight older adults. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;109(3):517&#x2013;525. doi: 10.1007/s00421-010-1387-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00421-010-1387-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20169360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beavers KM, Ambrosius WT, Rejeski WJ, Burdette JH, Walkup MP, Sheedy JL, et al. Effect of exercise type during intentional weight loss on body composition in older adults with obesity. Obesity. 2017;25(11):1823&#x2013;1829. doi: 10.1002/oby.21977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/oby.21977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5678994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29086504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bocalini DS, Lima LS, de Andrade S, Madureira A, Rica RL, dos Santos RN, et al. Effects of circuit-based exercise programs on the body composition of elderly obese women. Clin Interv Aging. 2012;7:551&#x2013;556. doi: 10.2147/CIA.S33893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CIA.S33893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3526879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23271901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verreijen AM, Engberink MF, Memelink RG, van der Plas SE, Visser M, Weijs PJM. Effect of a high protein diet and/or resistance exercise on the preservation of fat free mass during weight loss in overweight and obese older adults: a randomized controlled trial. Nutr J. 2017;16:10. doi: 10.1186/s12937-017-0229-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12937-017-0229-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5294725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28166780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balachandran A, Krawczyk SN, Potiaumpai M, Signorile JF. High-speed circuit training vs hypertrophy training to improve physical function in sarcopenic obese adults: a randomized controlled trial. Exp Gerontol. 2014;60:64&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1016/j.exger.2014.09.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2014.09.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25281504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen H-T, Chung Y-C, Chen Y-J, Ho S-Y, Wu H-J. Effects of different types of exercise on body composition, muscle strength, and igf-1 in the elderly with sarcopenic obesity. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2017;65(4):827&#x2013;832. doi: 10.1111/jgs.14722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jgs.14722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28205203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shea MK, Nicklas BJ, Marsh AP, Houston DK, Miller GD, Isom S, et al. The effect of pioglitazone and resistance training on body composition in older men and women undergoing hypocaloric weight loss. Obesity. 2011;19(8):1636&#x2013;1646. doi: 10.1038/oby.2010.327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/oby.2010.327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3091968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21233810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beavers KM, Beavers DP, Martin SB, Marsh AP, Lyles MF, Lenchik L, et al. Change in bone mineral density during weight loss with resistance versus aerobic exercise training in older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2017;72(11):1582&#x2013;1585. doi: 10.1093/gerona/glx048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glx048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5861903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28379325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coelho-J&#xfa;nior HJ, de Oliveira GI, Sampaio RAC, Sewo Sampaio PY, Cadore EL, Izquierdo M, et al. Periodized and non-periodized resistance training programs on body composition and physical function of older women. Exp Gerontol. 2019;121:10&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1016/j.exger.2019.03.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exger.2019.03.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30862526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson ED, Srivatsan SR, Agrawal S, Menon KS, Delmonico MJ, Wang MQ, et al. Effects of strength training on physical function: influence of power, strength, and body composition. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(9):2627&#x2013;2637. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181b2297b.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181b2297b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2966873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19910811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira DCL, Nascimento DC, Tajra V, Teixeira TG, Farias DL, Tibana RA, et al. High supervised resistance training in elderly women: the role of supervision ratio. Int J Exerc Sci. 2020;13(3):597&#x2013;606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7241618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32509119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fielding RA, LeBrasseur NK, Cuoco A, Bean J, Mizer K, Fiatarone Singh MA. High-velocity resistance training increases skeletal muscle peak power in older women. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2002;50(4):655&#x2013;662. doi: 10.1046/j.1532-5415.2002.50159.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1532-5415.2002.50159.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11982665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Concei&#xe7;&#xe3;o MS, Bonganha V, Vechin FC, Berton PdB, Lixandr&#xe3;o ME, Nogueira FRD, et al. Sixteen weeks of resistance training can decrease the risk of metabolic syndrome in healthy postmenopausal women. Clin Interv Aging. 2013;8:1221&#x2013;1228. doi: 10.2147/CIA.S44245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CIA.S44245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3783540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24072967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter GR, Wetzstein CJ, McLafferty CL, Zuckerman PA, Landers KA, Bamman MM. High-resistance versus variable-resistance training in older adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:1759&#x2013;1764. doi: 10.1097/00005768-200110000-00022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-200110000-00022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11581563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim I-Y, Park S, Jang J, Wolfe RR. Understanding muscle protein dynamics: technical considerations for advancing sarcopenia research. Ann Geriatr Med Res. 2020;24:157&#x2013;165. doi: 10.4235/agmr.20.0041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4235/agmr.20.0041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7533194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32752586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim I-Y, Schutzler S, Schrader A, Spencer H, Kortebein P, Deutz NEP, et al. Quantity of dietary protein intake, but not pattern of intake, affects net protein balance primarily through differences in protein synthesis in older adults. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2015;308:E21&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.00382.2014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.00382.2014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4280213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25352437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olaniyan ET, O&#x2019;Halloran F, McCarthy AL. Dietary protein considerations for muscle protein synthesis and muscle mass preservation in older adults. Nutr Res Rev Cambridge University Press. 2021;34:147&#x2013;157. doi: 10.1017/S0954422420000219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0954422420000219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32883378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>