<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">31794597</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2156-5376</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advances in nutrition (Bethesda, Md.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Protein Intake Greater than the RDA Differentially Influences Whole-Body Lean Mass Responses to Purposeful Catabolic and Anabolic Stressors: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>548</StartPage><EndPage>558</EndPage><MedlinePgn>548-558</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/advances/nmz106</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Under stressful conditions such as energy restriction (ER) and physical activity, the RDA for protein of 0.8&#xa0;g &#xb7; kg-1 &#xb7; d-1 may no longer be an appropriate recommendation. Under catabolic or anabolic conditions, higher protein intakes are proposed to attenuate the loss or increase the gain of whole-body lean mass, respectively. No known published meta-analysis compares protein intakes greater than the RDA with intakes at the RDA. Therefore, we conducted a systematic review and meta-analysis to assess the effects of protein intakes greater than the RDA, compared with at the RDA, on changes in whole-body lean mass. Three researchers independently screened 1520 articles published through August 2018 using the PubMed, Scopus, CINAHL, and Cochrane databases, with additional articles identified in published systematic review articles. Randomized, controlled, parallel studies &#x2265;6 wk long with apparently healthy adults (&#x2265;19 y) were eligible for inclusion. Data from 18 studies resulting in 22 comparisons of lean mass changes were included in the final overall analysis. Among all comparisons, protein intakes greater than the RDA benefitted changes in lean mass relative to consuming the RDA [weighted mean difference (95% CI): 0.32 (0.01, 0.64) kg, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;22 comparisons]. In the subgroup analyses, protein intakes greater than the RDA attenuated lean mass loss after ER [0.36 (0.06, 0.67) kg, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;14], increased lean mass after resistance training (RT) [0.77 (0.23, 1.31) kg, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;3], but did not differentially affect changes in lean mass [0.08 (-0.59, 0.75) kg, n&#xa0;=&#xa0;7] under nonstressed conditions (no ER&#xa0;+&#xa0;no RT). Protein intakes greater than the RDA beneficially influenced changes in lean mass when adults were purposefully stressed by the catabolic stressor of dietary ER with and without the anabolic stressor of RT. The RDA for protein is adequate to support lean mass in adults during nonstressed states. This review was registered at www.crd.york.ac.uk/prospero as CRD 42018106532.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; The Author(s) 2019.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hudson</LastName><ForeName>Joshua L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition Science, Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yu</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition Science, Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bergia Iii</LastName><ForeName>Robert E</ForeName><Initials>RE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition Science, Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campbell</LastName><ForeName>Wayne W</ForeName><Initials>WW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition Science, Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101540874</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2161-8313</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004044">Dietary Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004044" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dietary Proteins</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adults</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fat-free mass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">weight loss</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31794597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7231581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/advances/nmz106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2161-8313(22)00284-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Institute of Medicine. Dietary Reference Intakes for energy, carbohydrate, fiber, fat, fatty acids, cholesterol, protein and amino acids. Washington (DC): National Academies Press; 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scrimshaw NS, Sch&#xfc;rch B; International Dietary Energy Consultancy Group. Protein-energy interactions: proceedings of an I/D/E/C/G workshop, held in Waterville Valley, NH, USA, October 21 to 25, 1991. Lausanne, Switzerland: Nestl&#xe9; Foundation; 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elango R, Ball RO, Pencharz PB. Individual amino acid requirements in humans: an update. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2008;11(1):34&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18090656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traylor DA, Gorissen SHM, Phillips SM. Perspective: protein requirements and optimal intakes in aging: are we ready to recommend more than the recommended daily allowance?. Adv Nutr. 2018;9(3):171&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5952928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29635313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waterlow JC. The mysteries of nitrogen balance. Nutr Res Rev. 1999;12(1):25&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19087445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans W. Functional and metabolic consequences of sarcopenia. J Nutr. 1997;127(5):998S&#x2013;1003S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9164283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beasley JM, Shikany JM, Thomson CA. The role of dietary protein intake in the prevention of sarcopenia of aging. Nutr Clin Pract. 2013;28(6):684&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3928027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24163319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell WW, Leidy HJ. Dietary protein and resistance training effects on muscle and body composition in older persons. J Am Coll Nutr. 2007;26(6):696S&#x2013;703S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18187436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Zemel MB. Effect of protein, dairy components and energy balance in optimizing body composition. Nestle Nutr Inst Workshop Ser. 2011;69:97&#x2013;108.; discussion 108&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22301838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holloszy JO. Exercise-induced increase in muscle insulin sensitivity. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2005;99(1):338&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16036907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karpe F, Ehrenborg EE. PPAR&#x3b4; in humans: genetic and pharmacological evidence for a significant metabolic function. Curr Opin Lipidol. 2009;20(4):333&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19512923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM. A brief review of critical processes in exercise-induced muscular hypertrophy. Sports Med. 2014;44(Suppl 1):S71&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24791918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tipton KD, Phillips SM. Dietary protein for muscle hypertrophy. Nestle Nutr Inst Workshop Ser. 2013;76:73&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23899756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM. Higher dietary protein during weight loss: muscle sparing?. Obesity (Silver Spring). 2018;26(5):789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29687646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM. Higher protein during an energy deficit: muscle's guardian and fat's enemy?. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40(3):503&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18379213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW, Sitren HS, Daniels MJ, Langkamp-Henken B. Effects of variation in protein and carbohydrate intake on body mass and composition during energy restriction: a meta-regression. Am J Clin Nutr. 2006;83(2):260&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16469983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wycherley TP, Moran LJ, Clifton PM, Noakes M, Brinkworth GD. Effects of energy-restricted high-protein, low-fat compared with standard-protein, low-fat diets: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Am J Clin Nutr. 2012;96(6):1281&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23097268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JE, O'Connor LE, Sands LP, Slebodnik MB, Campbell WW. Effects of dietary protein intake on body composition changes after weight loss in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutr Rev. 2016;74(3):210&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4892287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26883880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. Ann Intern Med. 2009;151(4):264&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19622511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cermak NM, Res PT, de&#xa0;Groot LC, Saris WH, van&#xa0;Loon LJ. Protein supplementation augments the adaptive response of skeletal muscle to resistance-type exercise training: a meta-analysis. Am J Clin Nutr. 2012;96(6):1454&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23134885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finger D, Goltz FR, Umpierre D, Meyer E, Rosa LH, Schneider CD. Effects of protein supplementation in older adults undergoing resistance training: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2015;45(2):245&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25355074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrow JS, Summerbell CD. Meta-analysis: effect of exercise, with or without dieting, on the body composition of overweight subjects. Eur J Clin Nutr. 1995;49(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7713045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller PE, Alexander DD, Perez V. Effects of whey protein and resistance exercise on body composition: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Am Coll Nutr. 2014;33(2):163&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24724774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton RW, Murphy KT, McKellar SR, Schoenfeld BJ, Henselmans M, Helms E, Aragon AA, Devries MC, Banfield L, Krieger JW. A systematic review, meta-analysis and meta-regression of the effect of protein supplementation on resistance training-induced gains in muscle mass and strength in healthy adults. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(6):376&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5867436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28698222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naclerio F, Larumbe-Zabala E. Effects of whey protein alone or as part of a multi-ingredient formulation on strength, fat-free mass, or lean body mass in resistance-trained individuals: a meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2016;46(1):125&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26403469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nissen SL, Sharp RL. Effect of dietary supplements on lean mass and strength gains with resistance exercise: a meta-analysis. J Appl Physiol. 2003;94(2):651&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12433852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasiakos SM, McLellan TM, Lieberman HR. The effects of protein supplements on muscle mass, strength, and aerobic and anaerobic power in healthy adults: a systematic review. Sports Med. 2015;45(1):111&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25169440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Aragon AA, Krieger JW. The effect of protein timing on muscle strength and hypertrophy: a meta-analysis. J Int Soc Sport Nutr. 2013;10(1):53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3879660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24299050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwingshackl L, Hoffmann G. Long-term effects of low-fat diets either low or high in protein on cardiovascular and metabolic risk factors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutr J. 2013;12:48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3636027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23587198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DK, Quinn MA, Saunders DH, Greig CA. Protein supplementation does not significantly augment the effects of resistance exercise training in older adults: a systematic review. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2016;17(10):959.e1&#x2013;e9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5065619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27670605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergia RE III, Hudson JL, Campbell WW. Effect of whey protein supplementation on body composition changes in women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutr Rev. 2018;76(7):539&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29688559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldrich ND, Reicks MM, Sibley SD, Redmon JB, Thomas W, Raatz SK. Varying protein source and quantity do not significantly improve weight loss, fat loss, or satiety in reduced energy diets among midlife adults. Nutr Res. 2011;31(2):104&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3061831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21419314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claessens M, van&#xa0;Baak MA, Monsheimer S, Saris WH. The effect of a low-fat, high-protein or high-carbohydrate ad libitum diet on weight loss maintenance and metabolic risk factors. Int J Obes (Lond). 2009;33(3):296&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19153580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Josse AR, Atkinson SA, Tarnopolsky MA, Phillips SM. Increased consumption of dairy foods and protein during diet- and exercise-induced weight loss promotes fat mass loss and lean mass gain in overweight and obese premenopausal women. J Nutr. 2011;141(9):1626&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3159052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21775530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pal S, Ellis V, Dhaliwal S. Effects of whey protein isolate on body composition, lipids, insulin and glucose in overweight and obese individuals. Br J Nutr. 2010;104(5):716&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20377924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang M, Armstrong CL, Leidy HJ, Campbell WW. Normal vs. high-protein weight loss diets in men: effects on body composition and indices of metabolic syndrome. Obesity (Silver Spring). 2013;21(3):E204&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23592676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porter&#xa0;Starr KN, Pieper CF, Orenduff MC, McDonald SR, McClure LB, Zhou R, Payne ME, Bales CW. Improved function with enhanced protein intake per meal: a pilot study of weight reduction in frail, obese older adults. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2016;71(10):1369&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5018561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26786203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell WW, Crim MC, Young VR, Evans WJ. Increased energy requirements and changes in body composition with resistance training in older adults. Am J Clin Nutr. 1994;60(2):167&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8030593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layman DK, Evans EM, Erickson D, Seyler J, Weber J, Bagshaw D, Griel A, Psota T, Kris-Etherton P. A moderate-protein diet produces sustained weight loss and long-term changes in body composition and blood lipids in obese adults. J Nutr. 2009;139(3):514&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19158228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMillan-Price J, Petocz P, Atkinson F, O'Neill K, Samman S, Steinbeck K, Caterson I, Brand-Miller J. Comparison of 4 diets of varying glycemic load on weight loss and cardiovascular risk reduction in overweight and obese young adults: a randomized controlled trial. Arch Intern Med. 2006;166(14):1466&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16864756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melanson KJ, Summers A, Nguyen V, Brosnahan J, Lowndes J, Angelopoulos TJ, Rippe JM. Body composition, dietary composition, and components of metabolic syndrome in overweight and obese adults after a 12-week trial on dietary treatments focused on portion control, energy density, or glycemic index. Nutr J. 2012;11:57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3464127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22925169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reimer RA, Willis HJ, Tunnicliffe JM, Park H, Madsen KL, Soto-Vaca A. Inulin-type fructans and whey protein both modulate appetite but only fructans alter gut microbiota in adults with overweight/obesity: a randomized controlled trial. Mol Nutr Food Res. 2017;61(11):1700484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28730743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verreijen AM, Verlaan S, Engberink MF, Swinkels S, de&#xa0;Vogel-van&#xa0;den&#xa0;Bosch J, Weijs PJ. A high whey protein-, leucine-, and vitamin D-enriched supplement preserves muscle mass during intentional weight loss in obese older adults: a double-blind randomized controlled trial. Am J Clin Nutr. 2015;101(2):279&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25646324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wycherley TP, Buckley JD, Noakes M, Clifton PM, Brinkworth GD. Comparison of the effects of weight loss from a high-protein versus standard-protein energy-restricted diet on strength and aerobic capacity in overweight and obese men. Eur J Nutr. 2013;52(1):317&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22406907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhasin S, Apovian CM, Travison TG, Pencina K, Moore LL, Huang G, Campbell WW, Li Z, Howland AS, Chen R et al.. Effect of protein intake on lean body mass in functionally limited older men: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Intern Med. 2018;178(4):530&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5885156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29532075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layman DK, Boileau RA, Erickson DJ, Painter JE, Shiue H, Sather C, Christou DD. A reduced ratio of dietary carbohydrate to protein improves body composition and blood lipid profiles during weight loss in adult women. J Nutr. 2003;133(2):411&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12566476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leidy HJ, Carnell NS, Mattes RD, Campbell WW. Higher protein intake preserves lean mass and satiety with weight loss in pre-obese and obese women. Obesity (Silver Spring). 2007;15(2):421&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17299116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Milan AM, Mitchell SM, Zeng N, Ramzan F, Sharma P, Knowles SO, Roy NC, Sjodin A, Wagner KH et al.. The effects of dietary protein intake on appendicular lean mass and muscle function in elderly men: a 10-wk randomized controlled trial. Am J Clin Nutr. 2017;106(6):1375&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29092886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wycherley TP, Brinkworth GD, Clifton PM, Noakes M. Comparison of the effects of 52 weeks weight loss with either a high-protein or high-carbohydrate diet on body composition and cardiometabolic risk factors in overweight and obese males. Nutr Diabetes. 2012;2:e40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3432181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23448804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymsfield S. Human body composition. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heaney RP. The bone&#x2010;remodeling transient: implications for the interpretation of clinical studies of bone mass change. J Bone Miner Res. 1994;9(10):1515&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7817796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paddon-Jones D, Campbell WW, Jacques PF, Kritchevsky SB, Moore LL, Rodriguez NR, van&#xa0;Loon LJ. Protein and healthy aging. Am J Clin Nutr. 2015;101(6):1339s&#x2013;45s.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25926511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volpi E, Campbell WW, Dwyer JT, Johnson MA, Jensen GL, Morley JE, Wolfe RR. Is the optimal level of protein intake for older adults greater than the recommended dietary allowance?. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2013;68(6):677&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3660117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23183903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scrimshaw NS. Criteria for valid nitrogen balance measurement of protein requirements. Eur J Clin Nutr. 1996;50(Suppl 1):S196&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8641264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe RR, Miller SL. The recommended dietary allowance of protein: a misunderstood concept. JAMA. 2008;299(24):2891&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18577734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>USDA. Nutrient intakes from food: mean amounts consumed per individual, by gender and age, What We Eat in America, NHANES 2009&#x2013;2010. Beltsville, MD: Agricultural Research Service; 2012.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>