<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">28903957</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1938-3207</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>106</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2017</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The American journal of clinical nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Clin Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Within-day protein distribution does not influence body composition responses during weight loss in resistance-training adults who are overweight.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1190</StartPage><EndPage>1196</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1190-1196</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3945/ajcn.117.158246</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText><b>Background:</b> Emerging research suggests that redistributing total protein intake from 1 high-protein meal/d to multiple moderately high-protein meals improves 24-h muscle protein synthesis. Over time, this may promote positive changes in body composition.<b>Objective:</b> We sought to assess the effects of within-day protein intake distribution on changes in body composition during dietary energy restriction and resistance training.<b>Design:</b> In a randomized parallel-design study, 41 men and women [mean &#xb1; SEM age: 35 &#xb1; 2 y; body mass index (in kg/m<sup>2</sup>): 31.5 &#xb1; 0.5] consumed an energy-restricted diet (750 kcal/d below the requirement) for 16 wk while performing resistance training 3 d/wk. Subjects consumed 90 g protein/d (1.0 &#xb1; 0.03 g &#xb7; kg<sup>-1</sup> &#xb7; d<sup>-1</sup>, 125% of the Recommended Dietary Allowance, at intervention week 1) in either a skewed (10 g at breakfast, 20 g at lunch, and 60 g at dinner; <i>n</i> = 20) or even (30 g each at breakfast, lunch, and dinner; <i>n</i> = 21) distribution pattern. Body composition was measured pre- and postintervention.<b>Results:</b> Over time, whole-body mass (least-squares mean &#xb1; SE: -7.9 &#xb1; 0.6 kg), whole-body lean mass (-1.0 &#xb1; 0.2 kg), whole-body fat mass (-6.9 &#xb1; 0.5 kg), appendicular lean mass (-0.7 &#xb1; 0.1 kg), and appendicular fat mass (-2.6 &#xb1; 0.2 kg) each decreased. The midthigh muscle area (0 &#xb1; 1 cm<sup>2</sup>) did not change over time, whereas the midcalf muscle area decreased (-3 &#xb1; 1 cm<sup>2</sup>). Within-day protein distribution did not differentially affect these body-composition responses.<b>Conclusion:</b> The effectiveness of dietary energy restriction combined with resistance training to improve body composition is not influenced by the within-day distribution of protein when adequate total protein is consumed. This trial was registered at clinicaltrials.gov as NCT02066948.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2017 American Society for Nutrition.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hudson</LastName><ForeName>Joshua L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9356-693X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition Science, Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Jung Eun</ForeName><Initials>JE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3912-9042</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition Science, Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paddon-Jones</LastName><ForeName>Douglas</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Metabolism, University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, TX.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campbell</LastName><ForeName>Wayne W</ForeName><Initials>WW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7847-7242</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition Science, Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN; and campbeww@purdue.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT02066948</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2017</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Clin Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0376027</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0002-9165</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004044">Dietary Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="Y">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004032" MajorTopicYN="N">Diet</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004044" MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="Y">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D062407" MajorTopicYN="N">Meals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050177" MajorTopicYN="N">Overweight</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010349" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Compliance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064167" MajorTopicYN="N">Recommended Dietary Allowances</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015431" MajorTopicYN="Y">Weight Loss</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle mass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein patterning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">weight loss</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2017</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28903957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5657287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.117.158246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0002-9165(22)02672-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Jensen MD, Ryan DH, Apovian CM, Ard JD, Comuzzie AG, Donato KA, Hu FB, Hubbard VS, Jakicic JM, Kushner RF, et al. 2013 AHA/ACC/TOS guideline for the management of overweight and obesity in adults: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines and the Obesity Society. J Am Coll Cardiol 2014;63(Pt B):2985&#x2013;3023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24239920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leidy HJ, Carnell NS, Mattes RD, Campbell WW. Higher protein intake preserves lean mass and satiety with weight loss in pre-obese and obese women. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2007;15:421&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17299116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houston DK, Nicklas BJ, Ding JZ, Harris TB, Tylavsky FA, Newman AB, Lee JS, Sahyoun NR, Visser M, Kritchevsky SB, et al. Dietary protein intake is associated with lean mass change in older, community-dwelling adults: the Health, Aging, and Body Composition (Health ABC) Study. Am J Clin Nutr 2008;87:150&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18175749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layman DK, Evans E, Baum JI, Seyler J, Erickson DJ, Boileau RA. Dietary protein and exercise have additive effects on body composition during weight loss in adult women. J Nutr 2005;135:1903&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16046715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim JE, O&#x2019;Connor LE, Sands LP, Slebodnik MB, Campbell WW. Effects of dietary protein intake on body composition changes after weight loss in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutr Rev 2016;74:210&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4892287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26883880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW, Sitren HS, Daniels MJ, Langkamp-Henken B. Effects of variation in protein and carbohydrate intake on body mass and composition during energy restriction: a meta-regression. Am J Clin Nutr 2006;83:260&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16469983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>English KL, Paddon-Jones D. Protecting muscle mass and function in older adults during bed rest. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care 2010;13:34&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3276215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19898232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loenneke JP, Loprinzi PD, Murphy CH, Phillips SM. Per meal dose and frequency of protein consumption is associated with lean mass and muscle performance. Clin Nutr 2016;35:1506&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27086196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson BM, Axford S. Nutrition as a part of healthy aging and reducing cardiovascular risk: improving functionality in later life using quality protein, with optimized timing and distribution. Semin Thromb Hemost 2014;40:695&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25151523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mamerow MM, Mettler JA, English KL, Casperson SL, Arentson-Lantz E, Sheffield-Moore M, Layman DK, Paddon-Jones D. Dietary protein distribution positively influences 24-h muscle protein synthesis in healthy adults. J Nutr 2014;144:876&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4018950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24477298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thalacker&#x2010;Mercer AE, Drummond MJ. The importance of dietary protein for muscle health in inactive, hospitalized older adults. Ann N Y Acad Sci 2014;1328:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25118148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy CH, Churchward-Venne TA, Mitchell CJ, Kolar NM, Kassis A, Karagounis LG, Burke LM, Hawley JA, Phillips SM. Hypoenergetic diet-induced reductions in myofibrillar protein synthesis are restored with resistance training and balanced daily protein ingestion in older men. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 2015;308:E734&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4420900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25738784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farsijani S, Morais JA, Payette H, Gaudreau P, Shatenstein B, Gray-Donald K, Chevalier S. Relation between mealtime distribution of protein intake and lean mass loss in free-living older adults of the NuAge study. Am J Clin Nutr 2016;104:694&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27465379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell WW, Haub MD, Wolfe RR, Ferrando AA, Sullivan DH, Apolzan JW, Iglay HB. Resistance training preserves fat-free mass without impacting changes in protein metabolism after weight loss in older women. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2009;17:1332&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4299870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19247271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz ML, Watkins BA, Li Y, Anderson RA, Campbell WW. Chromium picolinate and conjugated linoleic acid do not synergistically influence diet- and exercise-induced changes in body composition and health indexes in overweight women. J Nutr Biochem 2008;19:61&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17531459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mojtahedi MC, Thorpe MP, Karampinos DC, Johnson CL, Layman DK, Georgiadis JG, Evans EM. The effects of a higher protein intake during energy restriction on changes in body composition and physical function in older women. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 2011;66:1218&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21798863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biolo G, Maggi SP, Williams BD, Tipton KD, Wolfe RR. Increased rates of muscle protein-turnover and amino-acid-transport after resistance exercise in humans. Am J Physiol 1995;268:E514&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7900797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chesley A, MacDougall JD, Tarnopolsky MA, Atkinson SA, Smith K. Changes in human muscle protein synthesis after resistance exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1992;73:1383&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1280254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Tipton KD, Aarsland A, Wolf SE, Wolfe RR. Mixed muscle protein synthesis and breakdown after resistance exercise in humans. Am J Physiol 1997;273:E99&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Tipton KD, Ferrando AA, Wolfe RR. Resistance training reduces the acute exercise-induced increase in muscle protein turnover. Am J Physiol 1999;276:E118&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9886957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rennie MJ, Wackerhage H, Spangenburg EE, Booth FW. Control of the size of the human muscle mass. Annu Rev Physiol 2004;66:799&#x2013;828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14977422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institute of Medicine. Dietary reference intakes for energy, carbohydrate, fiber, fat, fatty acids, cholesterol, protein and amino acids. Washington (DC): National Academies Press; 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim IY, Schutzler S, Schrader A, Spencer H, Kortebein P, Deutz NE, Wolfe RR, Ferrando AA. Quantity of dietary protein intake, but not pattern of intake, affects net protein balance primarily through differences in protein synthesis in older adults. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 2015;308:E21&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4280213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25352437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volpi E, Mittendorfer B, Rasmussen BB, Wolfe RR. The response of muscle protein anabolism to combined hyperaminoacidemia and glucose-induced hyperinsulinemia is impaired in the elderly. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2000;85:4481&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3192447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11134097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Churchward-Venne TA, Witard O, Breen L, Burd NA, Tipton KD, Phillips SM. Protein ingestion to stimulate myofibrillar protein synthesis requires greater relative protein intakes in healthy older versus younger men. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 2015;70:57&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25056502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell CJ, Churchward-Venne TA, Cameron-Smith D, Phillips SM. What is the relationship between the acute muscle protein synthesis response and changes in muscle mass? J Appl Physiol 2015;118:495&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25257869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnal MA, Mosoni L, Boirie Y, Houlier ML, Morin L, Verdier E, Ritz P, Antoine JM, Prugnaud J, Beaufrere B, et al. Protein pulse feeding improves protein retention in elderly women. Am J Clin Nutr 1999;69:1202&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10357740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouillanne O, Curis E, Hamon-Vilcot B, Nicolis I, Chretien P, Schauer N, Vincent JP, Cynober L, Aussel C. Impact of protein pulse feeding on lean mass in malnourished and at-risk hospitalized elderly patients: a randomized controlled trial. Clin Nutr 2013;32:186&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22992307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>