<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37184967</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nutrition, Training, Supplementation, and Performance-Enhancing Drug Practices of Male and Female Physique Athletes Peaking for Competition.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e444</StartPage><EndPage>e454</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e444-e454</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004462</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Escalante, G, Barakat, C, Tinsley, GM, and Schoenfeld, BJ. Nutrition, training, supplementation, and performance-enhancing drug practices of male and female physique athletes peaking for competition. J Strength Cond Res 37(8): e444-e454, 2023-The purpose of this descriptive investigation was threefold: (a) to assess the nutrition, training, supplement, and performance-enhancement drug practices of male and female physique competitors 30 days before competition; (b) to examine the specific water and macronutrient manipulation performed by competitors during the last 3 days before competition; and (c) to assess physiological responses to precontest preparation including body composition, body fluids, resting heart rate, and blood pressure. Competitors reported performing moderately high volume, moderate to high repetition, split-body resistance training programs performed on most days of the week; the programs included the use of a variety of advanced training methods. A majority of competitors included cardio to expedite fat loss, and most reported performing cardio in a fasted state despite a lack of objective evidentiary support for the practice. Competitors substantially restricted calories and consumed protein in amounts well above research-based guidelines (&gt;3 g&#xb7;kg -1 &#xb7;d -1 ); carbohydrate and lipid intake were highly variable. Water was substantially reduced in the final 3 days before competition. Competitors used a variety of dietary supplements throughout the study period, many of which are not supported by research. Both male and female competitors reported using performance enhancing drugs (&#x223c;48 and &#x223c;38%, respectively) including testosterone derivatives, selective androgen receptor modulators, and human growth hormone. More research is warranted to elucidate safer and more effective peak week practices for physique competitors.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Escalante</LastName><ForeName>Guillermo</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, California State University-San Bernardino, San Bernardino, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barakat</LastName><ForeName>Christopher</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Competitive Breed LLC, Department of Health Sciences and Human Performance, University of Tampa, Tampa, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tinsley</LastName><ForeName>Grant M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Sport Management, Texas Tech University, Lubbock, Texas; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schoenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Brad J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Sciences Department, CUNY Lehman College, Bronx, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D058573">Performance-Enhancing Substances</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058573" MajorTopicYN="Y">Performance-Enhancing Substances</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009752" MajorTopicYN="N">Nutritional Status</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019587" MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary Supplements</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="N">Water</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37184967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000004462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202308000-00023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Achar S, Rostamian A, Narayan SM. Cardiac and metabolic effects of anabolic-androgenic steroid abuse on lipids, blood pressure, left ventricular dimensions, and rhythm. Am J Cardiol 106: 893&#x2013;901, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamman MM, Hunter GR, Newton LE, Roney RK, Khaled MA. Changes in body composition, diet, and strength of bodybuilders during the 12 weeks prior to competition. J Sports Med Phys Fitness 33: 383&#x2013;391, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bone JL, Ross ML, Tomcik KA, et al. Manipulation of muscle creatine and glycogen changes dual X-ray absorptiometry estimates of body composition. Med Sci Sports Exerc 49: 1029&#x2013;1035, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bussau VA, Fairchild TJ, Rao A, Steele P, Fournier PA. Carbohydrate loading in human muscle: An improved 1 day protocol. Eur J Appl Physiol 87: 290&#x2013;295, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casa DJ, Armstrong LE, Hillman SK, et al. National Athletic Trainers' Association position statement: Fluid replacement for athletes. J Athl Train 35: 212&#x2013;224, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chappell AJ, Simper TN. Nutritional peak week and competition day strategies of competitive natural bodybuilders. Sports (Basel) 6: 1&#x2013;14, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chappell AJ, Simper T, Barker ME. Nutritional strategies of high level natural bodybuilders during competition preparation. Sports Nutr Rev J 15: 1&#x2013;12, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chappell AJ, Simper T, Helms E. Nutritional strategies of British professional and amateur natural bodybuilders during competition preparation. Sports Nutr Rev J 16: 1&#x2013;12, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole KS. Permeability and impermeability of cell membranes for IONS. Cold Spring Harbor Symp Quant Biol 8: 110&#x2013;122, 1940.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Moraes WMAM, de Almeida FN, Dos Santos LEA, et al. Carbohydrate loading practice in bodybuilders: Effects on muscle thickness, photo silhouette scores, mood states and gastrointestinal symptoms. J Sports Sci Med 18: 772&#x2013;779, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Souza D, Santos J, de Jesus D, Gentil P, Gentil P. Biochemical profile and body composition alteration of amateur bodybuilders during the pre-contest period. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 3: 1&#x2013;10, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xe9;combaz J. Nutrition and recovery of muscle energy stores after exercise. Swiss Magaz Sports Med Sports Traumatol 51: 31&#x2013;38, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escalante G, Barakat C. Fasted versus nonfasted aerobic exercise on body composition: Considerations for physique athletes. Strength Cond J 42: 71&#x2013;78, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escalante G, Stevenson SW, Barakat C, Aragon AA, Schoenfeld BJ. Peak week recommendations for bodybuilders: An evidence based approach. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil 13: 1&#x2013;24, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fyfe JJ, Bishop DJ, Stepto NK. Interference between concurrent resistance and endurance exercise: Molecular bases and the role of individual training variables. Sports Med 44: 743&#x2013;762, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentil P, de Lira CAB, Paoli A, et al. Nutrition, pharmacological and training strategies adopted by six bodybuilders: Case report and critical review. Eur J Transl Myol 27: 1&#x2013;16, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Lazinica B, Mikulic P, Krieger JW, Schoenfeld BJ. The effects of short versus long inter-set rest intervals in resistance training on measures of muscle hypertrophy: A systematic review. Eur J Sport Sci 17: 983&#x2013;993, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grgic J, Schoenfeld BJ, Orazem J, Sabol F. Effects of resistance training performed to repetition failure or non-failure on muscular strength and hypertrophy: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci 11: 202&#x2013;211, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett D, Hagstrom AD. Effect of overnight fasted exercise on weight loss and body composition: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 2: 1&#x2013;11, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA, Johnson NA, Chow C-M. Training practices and ergogenic aids used by male bodybuilders. J Strength Cond Res 27: 1609&#x2013;1617, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett DA. Training, supplementation, and pharmacological practices of competitive male bodybuilders across training phases. J Strength Cond Res 36: 963&#x2013;970, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halliday TM, Loenneke JP, Davy BM. Dietary intake, body composition, and menstrual cycle changes during competition preparation and recovery in a drug-free figure competitor: A case study. Nutrients 8: 1&#x2013;13, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanai T. Emulsion science. In: Electrical Properties in Emulsion Science. New York, NY: Sherman PH, 1968. pp. 353&#x2013;478.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson AS, Pollock ML, Gettman LR. Intertester reliability of selected skinfold and circumference measurements and percent fat estimates. Res Q 49: 546&#x2013;551, 1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keohane C, McMullin MF, Harrison C. The diagnosis and management of erythrocytosis. BMJ 347: 27&#x2013;31, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee G, Arcasoy MO. The clinical and laboratory evaluation of the patient with erythrocytosis. Eur J Intern Med 26: 297&#x2013;302, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenzi JL, Teixeira EL, de Jesus G, Schoenfeld BJ, de Salles Painelli V. Dietary strategies of modern bodybuilders during different phases of the competitive cycle. J Strength Cond Res 35: 2546&#x2013;2551, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malek MH, Nalbone DP, Berger DE, Coburn JW. Importance of health science education for personal fitness trainers. J Strength Cond Res 16: 19&#x2013;24, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manore MM, Thompson J, Russo M. Diet and exercise strategies of a world-class bodybuilder. Int J Sport Nutr 3: 76&#x2013;86, 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Burke LM, Dvorak J, et al. IOC consensus statement: Dietary supplements and the high-performance athlete. Br J Sports Med 52: 439&#x2013;455, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miclos-Balica M, Muntean P, Schick F, et al. Reliability of body composition assessment using A-mode ultrasound in a heterogeneous sample. Eur J Clin Nutr 75: 438&#x2013;445, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mifflin MD, St Jeor ST, Hill LA, et al. A new predictive equation for resting energy expenditure in healthy individuals. Am J Clin Nutr 51: 241&#x2013;247, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell L, Hackett D, Gifford J, Estermann F, O'Connor H. Do bodybuilders use evidence-based nutrition strategies to manipulate physique? Sports (Basel) 5: 1&#x2013;13, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell L, Slater G, Hackett D, Johnson N, O&#x2019;connor H. Physiological implications of preparing for a natural male bodybuilding competition. Eur J Sport Sci 18: 619&#x2013;629, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohlander SJ, Varghese B, Pastuszak AW. Erythrocytosis following testosterone therapy. Sex Med Rev 6: 77&#x2013;85, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richmond CR. ICRP report of the task group on reference man. J Appl Radiat Isot. 36, 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reale R, Slater G, Cox GR, Dunican IC, Burke LM. The effect of water loading on acute weight loss following fluid restriction in combat Sports athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metabol 28: 565&#x2013;573, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Aragon AA. How much protein can the body use in a single meal for muscle-building? Implications for daily protein distribution. Sports Nutr Rev J 15: 1&#x2013;6, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Grgic J, Ogborn D, Krieger JW. Strength and hypertrophy adaptations between low- vs. high-load resistance training: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Strength Cond Res 31: 3508&#x2013;3523, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld BJ, Alto A, Grgic J, et al. Alterations in body composition, resting metabolic rate, muscular strength, and eating behavior in response to natural bodybuilding competition preparation: A case study. J Strength Cond Res 34: 3124&#x2013;3138, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoenfeld B, Fisher J, Grgic J, et al. Resistance training recommendations to maximize muscle hypertrophy in an athletic population: Position stand of the IUSCA. Int J Strength Conditioning 1: 1&#x2013;30, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schumann M, Feuerbacher JF, S&#xfc;nkeler M, et al. Compatibility of concurrent aerobic and strength training for skeletal muscle size and function: An updated systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med 52: 601&#x2013;612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiose K, Yamada Y, Motonaga K, et al. Segmental extracellular and intracellular water distribution and muscle glycogen after 72-h carbohydrate loading using spectroscopic techniques. J Appl Physiol 121: 205&#x2013;211, 2112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith RW, Harty PS, Stratton MT, et al. Predicting adaptations to resistance training plus overfeeding using Bayesian regression: A preliminary investigation. J Funct Morphol Kinesiol 6: 1&#x2013;18, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinsley GM, Trexler ET, Smith-Ryan AE, et al. Changes in body composition and neuromuscular performance through preparation, 2 competitions, and a recovery period in an experienced female physique athlete. J Strength Cond Res 33: 1823&#x2013;1839, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinsley GM, Harty PS, Stratton MT, et al. Tracking changes in body composition: Comparison of methods and influence of pre-assessment standardisation. Br J Nutr 127: 1656&#x2013;1674, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner DR, Cain DL, Clark NW. Validity and reliability of A-mode ultrasound for body composition assessment of NCAA Division I athletes. PLoS One 11: 1&#x2013;12, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whelton PK, Carey RM, Aronow WS, et al. 2017 ACC/AHA/AAPA/ABC/ACPM/AGS/APhA/ASH/ASPC/NMA/PCNA guideline for the prevention, detection, evaluation, and management of high blood pressure in adults: Executive summary: A report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on clinical practice guidelines. Hypertension 71: 1269&#x2013;1324, 2018.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>