<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">25426472</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2288-176X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2014</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of exercise rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Exerc Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effect of weight loss by ketogenic diet on the body composition, performance-related physical fitness factors and cytokines of Taekwondo athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>326</StartPage><EndPage>331</EndPage><MedlinePgn>326-31</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12965/jer.140160</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The purpose of this study was to investigate the effects of the weight loss through 3 weeks of ketogenic diet on performance-related physical fitness and inflammatory cytokines in Taekwondo athletes. The subjects selected for this research were 20 Taekwondo athletes of the high schools who participated in a summer camp training program. The subjects were randomly assigned to 2 groups, 10 subjects to each group: the ketogenic diet (KD) group and the non-ketogenic diet (NKD) group. Body composition, performance-related physical fitness factors (2,000 m sprint, Wingate test, grip force, back muscle strength, sit-up, 100 m sprint, standing broad jump, single leg standing) and cytokines (Iinterleukin-6, Interferon-&#x3b3;, tumor necrosis factor-&#x3b1;) were analyzed before and after 3weeks of ketogenic diet. No difference between the KD and NKD groups in weight, %body fat, BMI and fat free mass. However, the KD group, compared to the NKD group, finished 2,000 m sprint in less time after weight loss, and also felt less fatigue as measured by the Wingate test and showed less increase in tumor necrosis factor-&#x3b1;. This result suggests that KD diet can be helpful for weight category athletes, such as Taekwondo athletes, by improving aerobic capacity and fatigue resistance capacity, and also by exerting positive effect on inflammatory response.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rhyu</LastName><ForeName>Hyun-Seung</ForeName><Initials>HS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Health Medicine, Jungwon University, Chungbuk, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cho</LastName><ForeName>Su-Youn</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Movement Science, Seoul Women's University, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>J Exerc Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101615171</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2288-176X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cytokines</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ketogenic diet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical fitness factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Taekwondo</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25426472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4237850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12965/jer.140160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jer-10-5-326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Astrup A, Meinert Larsen T, Harper A. Atkins and other low-carbohydrate diets: hoax or an effective tool for weight loss? Lancet. 2004;364:897&#x2013;899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15351198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar-Or O. The Wingate anaerobic test. An update on methodology, reliability and validity. Sports Med. 1987;4:381&#x2013;394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3324256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bravata DM, Sanders L, Huang J, et al. Efficacy and safety of lowcarbohydrate diets: a systematic review. JAMA. 2003;289:1837&#x2013;1850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12684364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brinkworth GD, Noakes M, Clifton PM, Buckley JD. Effects of a low carbohydrate weight loss diet on exercise capacity and tolerance in obese subjects. Obesity. 2009;17:1916&#x2013;1923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19373224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elsawy G, Abdelrahman O, Hamza A. Effect of choline supplementation on rapid weight loss and biochemical variables among female taekwondo and judo athletes. J Hum Kinet. 2014;40:77&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4096089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25031675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fantuzzi G. Adipose tissue, adipokines, and inflammation. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2005;115:911&#x2013;920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15867843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleeson M, Nieman D C, Pedersen BK. Exercise, nutrition and immune function. J Sports Sci. 2004;22:115&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14971437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger JW, Sitren HS, Daniels MJ, Langkamp-Henken B. Effects of variation in protein and carbohydrate intake on body mass and composition during energy restriction: a meta-regression. Am J Clin Nutr. 2006;83:260&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16469983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YW, Shin KW, Paik IY, Jung WM, Cho SY, Choi ST, Kim HD, Kim JY. Immunological impact of Taekwondo competitions. Int J Sports Med. 2012;33:58&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22113537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed HE, El-Swefy SE, Rashed LA, Abd El-Latif SK. Biochemical effect of a ketogenic diet on the brains of obese adult rats. J Clin Neurosci. 2010;17:899&#x2013;904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20395146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oppliger RA, Steen SN, Scott JR. Weight loss practices of college wrestlers. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metabol. 2003;13:29&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12660404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Canato M, Toniolo L, Bargossi AM, Neri M, Mediati M, Alesso D, Sanna G, Grimaldi KA, Fazzari AL, Bianco A. The ketogenic diet: an underappreciated therapeutic option? Clin Ter. 2011;162:145&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22041813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Grimaldi K, D&#x2019;Agostino D, Cenci L, Moro T, Bianco A, Palma A. Ketogenic diet does not affect strength performance in elite artistic gymnasts. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2012;9:34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3411406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22835211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen BK. Special feature for the Olympics: effects of exercise on the immune system: exercise and cytokines. Immunol Cell Biol. 2000;78:532&#x2013;535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11050536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pethick DW, Lindsay DB. Metabolism of ketone bodies in pregnant sheep. Br J Nutr. 1982;48:549&#x2013;563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6926736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phinney SD, Horton ES, Sims EA, et al. Capacity for moderate exercise in obese subjects after adaptation to a hypocaloric, ketogenic diet. J Clin Invest. 1980;66:1152&#x2013;1161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC371554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7000826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phinney SD, Bistrian BR, Evans WJ, Gervino E, Blackburn GL. The human metabolic response to chronic ketosis without caloric restriction: preservation of submaximal exercise capability with reduced carbohydrate oxidation. Metabolism. 1983;32:769&#x2013;776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6865776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu K, Aizawa K, Suzuki N, Masuchi K, Okada H, Akimoto T, Mesaki N, Kono I, Akama T. Influences of weight loss on monocytes and T-cell subpopulations in male judo athletes. J Strength Cond Res. 2011;25:1943&#x2013;1950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21499138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai ML, Chou KM, Chang CK, Fang SH. Changes of mucosal immunity and antioxidation activity in elite male Taiwanese taekwondo athletes associated with intensive training and rapid weight loss. Br J Sports Med. 2011;45:729&#x2013;734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19846424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White AM, Johnston CS, Swan PD, Tjonn SL, Sears B. Blood ketones are directly related to fatigue and perceived effort during exercise in over-weight adults adhering to low-carbohydrate diets for weight loss: a pilot study. J Am Diet Assoc. 2007;107:1792&#x2013;1796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17904939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>