<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">22174391</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1522-1601</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>112</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2012</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of applied physiology (Bethesda, Md. : 1985)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Appl Physiol (1985)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Aerobic exercise training conserves insulin sensitivity for 1 yr following weight loss in overweight women.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>688</StartPage><EndPage>693</EndPage><MedlinePgn>688-93</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1152/japplphysiol.00843.2011</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The objectives of this study were to 1) identify the independent effects of exercise (aerobic or resistance training) and weight loss on whole body insulin sensitivity and 2) determine if aerobic or resistance training would be more successful for maintaining improved whole body insulin sensitivity 1 yr following weight loss. Subjects were 97 healthy, premenopausal women, body mass index (BMI) 27-30 kg/m(2). Following randomized assignment to one of three groups, diet only, diet + aerobic, or diet + resistance training until a BMI &lt;25 kg/m(2) was achieved, body composition, fat distribution, and whole body insulin sensitivity were determined at baseline, in the weight reduced state, and at 1-yr follow up. The whole body insulin sensitivity index (S(I)) was determined using a frequently sampled intravenous glucose tolerance test. Results of repeated-measures ANOVA indicated a significant improvement in S(I) following weight loss. However, there were no group or group&#xd7;time interactions. At 1-yr follow up, there were no significant time or group interactions for S(I;) however, there was a significant group&#xd7;time interaction for S(I). Post hoc analysis revealed that women in the aerobic training group showed a significant increased S(I) from weight reduced to 1-yr follow up (P &lt; 0.05), which was independent of intra-abdominal adipose tissue and %fat. No significant differences in S(I) from weight reduced to 1-yr follow up were observed for diet only or diet + resistance groups. Additionally, multiple linear regression analysis revealed that change in whole body insulin sensitivity from baseline to 1-yr follow up was independently associated with the change in Vo(2max) from baseline to 1-yr follow up (P &lt; 0.05). These results suggest that long-term aerobic exercise training may conserve improvements in S(I) following weight loss and that maintaining cardiovascular fitness following weight loss may be important for maintaining improvements in S(I).</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fisher</LastName><ForeName>Gordon</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Nutrition Sciences, University of Alabama-Birmingham, Birmingham, AL 35294-3360, USA. grdnfs@uab.edu</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hunter</LastName><ForeName>Gary R</ForeName><Initials>GR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gower</LastName><ForeName>Barbara A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P60DK079626</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01DK49779</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01DK51684</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>P30-DK56336</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>T32 DK062710</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>P30 DK056336</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UL 1RR025777</GrantID><Acronym>RR</Acronym><Agency>NCRR NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>MO1-RR-00032</GrantID><Acronym>RR</Acronym><Agency>NCRR NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2T32DK062710-07</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Appl Physiol (1985)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8502536</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0161-7567</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007328">Insulin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004038" MajorTopicYN="N">Diet, Reducing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005500" MajorTopicYN="N">Follow-Up Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007328" MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007333" MajorTopicYN="Y">Insulin Resistance</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016014" MajorTopicYN="N">Linear Models</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050177" MajorTopicYN="N">Overweight</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015431" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Loss</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2011</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2012</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2013</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22174391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3289431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/japplphysiol.00843.2011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">japplphysiol.00843.2011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bergman R, Phillips L, Cobelli C. Physiologic evaluation of factors controlling glucose tolerance in man: measurement of insulin sensitivity and beta-cell glucose sensitivity from the response to intravenous glucose. J Clin Invest 68: 1456&#x2013;1467, 1981</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC370948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7033284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colman E, Katzel LI, Rogus E, Coon P, Muller D, Goldberg AP. Weight loss reduces abdominal fat and improves insulin action in middle-aged and older men with impaired glucose tolerance. Metabolism 44: 1502&#x2013;1508, 1995</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7476341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox KL, Burke V, Morton AR, Beilin LJ, Puddey IB. Independent and additive effects of energy restriction and exercise on glucose and insulin concentrations in sedentary overweight men. Am J Clin Nutr 80: 308&#x2013;316, 2004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15277150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dengel DR, Galecki AT, Hagberg JM, Pratley RE. The independent and combined effects of weight loss and aerobic exercise on blood pressure and oral glucose tolerance in older men. Am J Hypertens 11: 1405&#x2013;1412, 1998</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9880120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dengel DR, Pratley RE, Hagberg JM, Rogus EM, Goldberg AP. Distinct effects of aerobic exercise training and weight loss on glucose homeostasis in obese sedentary men. J Appl Physiol 81: 318&#x2013;325, 1996</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8828680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farin HM, Abbasi F, Reaven GM. Body mass index and waist circumference both contribute to differences in insulin-mediated glucose disposal in nondiabetic adults. Am J Clin Nutr 83: 47&#x2013;51, 2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16400048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodpaster BH, Kelley DE, Wing RR, Meier A, Thaete FL. Effects of weight loss on regional fat distribution and insulin sensitivity in obesity. Diabetes 48: 839&#x2013;847, 1999</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10102702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gower BA, Weinsier RL, Jordan JM, Hunter GR, Desmond R. Effects of weight loss on changes in insulin sensitivity and lipid concentrations in premenopausal African American and white women. Am J Clin Nutr 76: 923&#x2013;927, 2002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12399261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawley JA, Lessard SJ. Exercise training-induced improvements in insulin action. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 192: 127&#x2013;135, 2008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18171435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes TA, Gwynne JT, Switzer BR, Herbst C, White G. Effects of caloric restriction and weight loss on glycemic control, insulin release and resistance, and atherosclerotic risk in obese patients with type II diabetes mellitus. Am J Med 77: 7&#x2013;17, 1984</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6377892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes VA, Fiatarone MA, Fielding RA, Kahn BB, Ferrara CM, Shepherd P, Fisher EC, Wolfe RR, Elahi D, Evans WJ. Exercise increases muscle GLUT-4 levels and insulin action in subjects with impaired glucose tolerance. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 264: E855&#x2013;E862, 1993</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8333511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janssen I, Fortier A, Hudson R, Ross R. Effects of an energy-restrictive diet with or without exercise on abdominal fat, intermuscular fat, and metabolic risk factors in obese women. Diabetes Care 25: 431&#x2013;438, 2002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11874926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeffery RW, Drewnowski A, Epstein LH, Stunkard AJ, Wilson GT, Wing RR, Hill DR. Long-term maintenance of weight loss: current status. Health Psychol 19: 5&#x2013;16, 2000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10709944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein S, Burke LE, Bray GA, Blair S, Allison DB, Pi-Sunyer X, Hong Y, Eckel RH, and American Heart Association Council on Nutrition PyA, and Metabolism Clinical implications of obesity with specific focus on cardiovascular disease: a statement for professionals from the American Heart Association Council on Nutrition, Physical Activity, and Metabolism: endorsed by the American College of Cardiology Foundation. Circulation 110: 2952&#x2013;2967, 2004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15509809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuzuya T, Nakagawa S, Satoh J, Kanazawa Y, Iwamoto Y, Kobayashi M, Nanjo K, Sasaki A, Seino Y, Ito C, Shima K, Nonaka K, Kadowaki T, and Committee of the Japan Diabetes Society on the diagnostic criteria of diabetes mellitus Report of the Committee on the classification and diagnostic criteria of diabetes mellitus. Diabetes Res Clin Pract 55: 65&#x2013;85, 2002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11755481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvist H, Chowdhury B, Grang&#xe5;rd U, Tyl&#xe9;n U, Sj&#xf6;str&#xf6;m L. Total and visceral adipose-tissue volumes derived from measurements with computed tomography in adult men and women: predictive equations. Am J Clin Nutr 48: 1351&#x2013;1361, 1988</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3202084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larson-Meyer DE, Heilbronn LK, Redman LM, Newcomer BR, Frisard MI, Anton S, Smith SR, Alfonso A, Ravussin E. Effect of calorie restriction with or without exercise on insulin sensitivity, beta-cell function, fat cell size, and ectopic lipid in overweight subjects. Diabetes Care 29: 1337&#x2013;1344, 2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2677812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16732018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindstr&#xf6;m J, Ilanne-Parikka P, Peltonen M, Aunola S, Eriksson J, Hemi&#xf6; K, H&#xe4;m&#xe4;l&#xe4;inen H, H&#xe4;rk&#xf6;nen P, Kein&#xe4;nen-Kiukaanniemi S, Laakso M, Louheranta A, Mannelin M, Paturi M, Sundvall J, Valle T, Uusitupa M, Tuomilehto J, Group FDPS. Sustained reduction in the incidence of type 2 diabetes by lifestyle intervention: follow-up of the Finnish Diabetes Prevention Study. Lancet 368: 1673&#x2013;1679, 2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17098085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindstr&#xf6;m J, Louheranta A, Mannelin M, Rastas M, Salminen V, Eriksson J, Uusitupa M, Tuomilehto J, Group FDPS. The Finnish Diabetes Prevention Study (DPS): lifestyle intervention and 3-year results on diet and physical activity. Diabetes Care 26: 3230&#x2013;3236, 2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14633807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muoio DM, Newgard CB. Obesity-related derangements in metabolic regulation. Annu Rev Biochem 75: 367&#x2013;401, 2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16756496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neter JE, Stam BE, Kok FJ, Grobbee DE, Geleijnse JM. Influence of weight reduction on blood pressure: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Hypertension 42: 878&#x2013;884, 2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12975389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacini G, Bergman R. MINMOD: a computer program to calculate insulin sensitivity and pancreatic responsivity from the frequently sampled intravenous glucose tolerance test. Comput Methods Programs Biomed 23: 113&#x2013;122, 1986</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3640682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pi-Sunyer X, Blackburn G, Brancati FL, Bray GA, Bright R, Clark JM, Curtis JM, Espeland MA, Foreyt JP, Graves K, Haffner SM, Harrison B, Hill JO, Horton ES, Jakicic J, Jeffery RW, Johnson KC, Kahn S, Kelley DE, Kitabchi AE, Knowler WC, Lewis CE, Maschak-Carey BJ, Montgomery B, Nathan DM, Patricio J, Peters A, Redmon JB, Reeves RS, Ryan DH, Safford M, Van Dorsten B, Wadden TA, Wagenknecht L, Wesche-Thobaben J, Wing RR, Yanovski SZ, Group LAR. Reduction in weight and cardiovascular disease risk factors in individuals with type 2 diabetes: one-year results of the look AHEAD trial. Diabetes Care 30: 1374&#x2013;1383, 2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2665929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17363746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redman LM, Huffman KM, Landerman LR, Pieper CF, Bain JR, Muehlbauer MJ, Stevens RD, Wenner BR, Kraus VB, Newgard CB, Kraus WE, Ravussin E. Effect of caloric restriction with and without exercise on metabolic intermediates in nonobese men and women. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 96: E312&#x2013;E321, 2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3048325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21123443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter EA, Nielsen JN, J&#xf8;rgensen SB, Fr&#xf8;sig C, Birk JB, Wojtaszewski JF. Exercise signalling to glucose transport in skeletal muscle. Proc Nutr Soc 63: 211&#x2013;216, 2004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15294032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross R, Dagnone D, Jones PJ, Smith H, Paddags A, Hudson R, Janssen I. Reduction in obesity and related comorbid conditions after diet-induced weight loss or exercise-induced weight loss in men. A randomized, controlled trial. Ann Intern Med 133: 92&#x2013;103, 2000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10896648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross R, Freeman JA, Janssen I. Exercise alone is an effective strategy for reducing obesity and related comorbidities. Exerc Sport Sci Rev 28: 165&#x2013;170, 2000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11064850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas TR, Warner SO, Dellsperger KC, Hinton PS, WhaleyConnell AT, Rector RS, Liu Y, Linden MA, Chockalingam A, Thyfault JP, Huyette DR, Wang Z, Cox RH. Exercise and the metabolic syndrome with weight regain. J Appl Physiol 109: 3&#x2013;10, 2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2904200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20167668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turk MW, Yang K, Hravnak M, Sereika SM, Ewing LJ, Burke LE. Randomized clinical trials of weight loss maintenance: a review. J Cardiovasc Nurs 24: 58&#x2013;80, 2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2676575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19114803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallberg-Henriksson H, Holloszy JO. Contractile activity increases glucose uptake by muscle in severely diabetic rats. J Appl Physiol 57: 1045&#x2013;1049, 1984</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6389452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinsier RLWN, Morgan SL, Cornwell AR, Craig CB. EatRight lose weight: seven simple steps. Birmingham, AL: Oxmoor House, 1997</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Youn J, Bergman R. Modified protocols improve insulin sensitivity estimation using the minimal model. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 253: E595&#x2013;E602, 1987</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2892414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>