<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">20351587</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Strength exercise improves muscle mass and hepatic insulin sensitivity in obese youth.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1973</StartPage><EndPage>1980</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1973-80</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181df16d9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Data on the metabolic effects of resistance exercise (strength training) in adolescents are limited.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The objective of this study was to determine whether a controlled resistance exercise program without dietary intervention or weight loss reduces body fat accumulation, increases lean body mass, and improves insulin sensitivity and glucose metabolism in sedentary obese Hispanic adolescents.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twelve obese adolescents (age = 15.5 &#xb1; 0.5 yr, body mass index = 35.3 &#xb1; 0.8 kg&#xb7;m; 40.8% &#xb1; 1.5% body fat) completed a 12-wk resistance exercise program (two times 1 h&#xb7;wk, exercising all major muscle groups). At baseline and on completion of the program, body composition was measured by dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry, abdominal fat distribution was measured by magnetic resonance imaging, hepatic and intramyocellular fat was measured by magnetic resonance spectroscopy, peripheral insulin sensitivity was measured by the stable-label intravenous glucose tolerance test, and hepatic insulin sensitivity was measured by the hepatic insulin sensitivity index = 1000/(GPR &#xd7; fasting insulin). Glucose production rate (GPR), gluconeogenesis, and glycogenolysis were quantified using stable isotope gas chromatography/mass spectrometry techniques.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">All participants were normoglycemic. The exercise program resulted in significant strength gain in both upper and lower body muscle groups. Body weight increased from 97.0 &#xb1; 3.8 to 99.6 &#xb1; 4.2 kg (P &lt; 0.01). The major part (&#x223c;80%) was accounted for by increased lean body mass (55.7 &#xb1; 2.8 to 57.9 &#xb1; 3.0 kg, P &#x2264; 0.01). Total, visceral, hepatic, and intramyocellular fat contents remained unchanged. Hepatic insulin sensitivity increased by 24% &#xb1; 9% (P &lt; 0.05), whereas peripheral insulin sensitivity did not change significantly. GPR decreased by 8% &#xb1; 1% (P &lt; 0.01) because of a 12% &#xb1; 5% decrease in glycogenolysis (P &lt; 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">We conclude that a controlled resistance exercise program without weight loss increases strength and lean body mass, improves hepatic insulin sensitivity, and decreases GPR without affecting total fat mass or visceral, hepatic, and intramyocellular fat contents.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van Der Heijden</LastName><ForeName>Gert-Jan</ForeName><Initials>GJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, TX 77030, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zhiyue J</ForeName><Initials>ZJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chu</LastName><ForeName>Zili</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Toffolo</LastName><ForeName>Gianna</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manesso</LastName><ForeName>Erica</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sauer</LastName><ForeName>Pieter J J</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sunehag</LastName><ForeName>Agneta L</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>M01 RR000188</GrantID><Acronym>RR</Acronym><Agency>NCRR NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 HD044609</GrantID><Acronym>HD</Acronym><Agency>NICHD NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>M01-RR-00188-34</GrantID><Acronym>RR</Acronym><Agency>NCRR NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007328">Insulin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000273" MajorTopicYN="N">Adipose Tissue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007328" MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008099" MajorTopicYN="N">Liver</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009132" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscles</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="Y">Obesity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2010</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2010</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20351587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS203558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2944907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181df16d9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. 7th ed. Philadephia (Penn): 2006. American College of Sports Medicine; pp. 154&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23851406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avogaro A, Bristow JD, Bier DM, Cobelli C, Toffolo G. Stable-label intravenous glucose tolerance test minimal model. Diabetes. 1989;38(8):1048&#x2013;1055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2753235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar-Or O, Rowland T. Pediatric Exercise Medicine From Physiologic Principles to Health Care Application. 1st ed. Champaign (IL): Human Kinetics; 2004. pp. 35&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benson AC, Torode ME, Fiatarone Singh MA. The effect of high-intensity progressive resistance training on adiposity in children: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Obes (Lond) 2008;32(6):1016&#x2013;1027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18283282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benson AC, Torode ME, Singh MA. Muscular strength and cardiorespiratory fitness is associated with higher insulin sensitivity in children and adolescents. Int J Pediatr Obes. 2006;1(4):222&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17907329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks N, Layne JE, Gordon PL, Roubenoff R, Nelson ME, Castaneda-Sceppa C. Strength training improves muscle quality and insulin sensitivity in Hispanic older adults with type 2 diabetes. Int J Med Sci. 2007;4(1):19&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1752232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17211497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chacko SK, Sunehag AL, Sharma S, Sauer PJ, Haymond MW. Measurement of gluconeogenesis using glucose fragments and mass spectrometry after ingestion of deuterium oxide. J Appl Physiol. 2008;104(4):944&#x2013;951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18187615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis JN, Kelly LA, Lane CJ, Ventura EE, Byrd-Williams CE, Alexandar KA, et al. Randomized Control Trial to Improve Adiposity and Insulin Resistance in Overweight Latino Adolescents. Obesity (Silver Spring). (Epub ahead of print) 2009 PMID 19247280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2846423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19247280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Despres JP, Lemieux I. Abdominal obesity and metabolic syndrome. Nature. 2006;444(7121):881&#x2013;887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17167477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastaldelli A, Miyazaki Y, Pettiti M, Buzzigoli E, Mahankali S, Ferrannini E, et al. Separate contribution of diabetes, total fat mass, and fat topography to glucose production, gluconeogenesis, and glycogenolysis. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2004;89(8):3914&#x2013;3921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15292327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastaldelli A, Toschi E, Pettiti M, Frascerra S, Quinones-Galvan A, Sironi AM, et al. Effect of physiological hyperinsulinemia on gluconeogenesis in nondiabetic subjects and in type 2 diabetic patients. Diabetes. 2001;50(8):1807&#x2013;1812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11473042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutin B, Barbeau P, Owens S, Lemmon CR, Bauman M, Allison J, et al. Effects of exercise intensity on cardiovascular fitness, total body composition, and visceral adiposity of obese adolescents. Am J Clin Nutr. 2002;75(5):818&#x2013;826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11976154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutin B, Owens S. Role of exercise intervention in improving body fat distribution and risk profile in children. Am J Hum Biol. 1999;11(2):237&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11533947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heled Y, Shapiro Y, Shani Y, Moran DS, Langzam L, Barash V, et al. Physical exercise enhances hepatic insulin signaling and inhibits phosphoenolpyruvate carboxykinase activity in diabetes-prone Psammomys obesus. Metabolism. 2004;53(7):836&#x2013;841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15254873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holten MK, Zacho M, Gaster M, Juel C, Wojtaszewski JF, Dela F. Strength training increases insulin-mediated glucose uptake, GLUT4 content, and insulin signaling in skeletal muscle in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes. 2004;53(2):294&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14747278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishii T, Yamakita T, Sato T, Tanaka S, Fujii S. Resistance training improves insulin sensitivity in NIDDM subjects without altering maximal oxygen uptake. Diabetes Care. 1998;21(8):1353&#x2013;1355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9702447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley DE, Mandarino LJ. Fuel selection in human skeletal muscle in insulin resistance: a reexamination. Diabetes. 2000;49(5):677&#x2013;683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10905472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klimcakova E, Polak J, Moro C, Hejnova J, Majercik M, Viguerie N, et al. Dynamic strength training improves insulin sensitivity without altering plasma levels and gene expression of adipokines in subcutaneous adipose tissue in obese men. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2006;91(12):5107&#x2013;5112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16968804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopman R, Manders RJ, Jonkers RA, Hul GB, Kuipers H, van Loon LJ. Intramyocellular lipid and glycogen content are reduced following resistance exercise in untrained healthy males. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2006;96(5):525&#x2013;534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16369816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuczmarski RJ, Ogden CL, Grummer-Strawn LM, Flegal KM, Guo SS, Wei R, et al. CDC growth charts: United States. Adv Data. 2000;314:1&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11183293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonard MB, Elmi A, Mostoufi-Moab S, Shults J, Burnham JM, Thayu M, et al. Effects of sex, race, and puberty on cortical bone and the functional muscle bone unit in children, adolescents and young adults. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2010 February 15; [E-pub ahead of print]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2853999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20157194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuda M, DeFronzo RA. Insulin sensitivity indices obtained from oral glucose tolerance testing: comparison with the euglycemic insulin clamp. Diabetes Care. 1999;22(9):1462&#x2013;1470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10480510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCambridge TM, Stricker PR. Strength training by children and adolescents. Pediatrics. 2008;121(4):835&#x2013;840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18381549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuigan MR, Tatasciore M, Newton RU, Pettigrew S. Eight weeks of resistance training can significantly alter body composition in children who are overweight or obese. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23(1):80&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19130639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narayan KM, Boyle JP, Thompson TJ, Sorensen SW, Williamson DF. Lifetime risk for diabetes mellitus in the United States. JAMA. 2003;290(14):1884&#x2013;1890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14532317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naressi A, Couturier C, Devos JM, Janssen M, Mangeat C, de Beer R, et al. Java-based graphical user interface for the MRUI quantitation package. MAGMA. 2001;12(2&#x2013;3):141&#x2013;152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11390270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nassis GP, Papantakou K, Skenderi K, Triandafillopoulou M, Kavouras SA, Yannakoulia M, et al. Aerobic exercise training improves insulin sensitivity without changes in body weight, body fat, adiponectin, and inflammatory markers in overweight and obese girls. Metabolism. 2005;54(11):1472&#x2013;1479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16253636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Leary VB, Marchett CM, Krishnan RK, Stetzer BP, Gonzalez F, Kirwan JP. Exercise-induced reversal of insulin resistance in obese elderly is associated with reduced visceral fat. J Appl Physiol. 2006;100(5):1584&#x2013;1589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7037693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16373444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogden CL, Carroll MD, Curtin LR, McDowell MA, Tabak CJ, Flegal KM. Prevalence of overweight and obesity in the United States, 1999&#x2013;2004. JAMA. 2006;295(13):1549&#x2013;1555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16595758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Otten J, Pitzi Hellwig J, Meyers L. Dietary (DRI) Reference Intakes: The Essential Guide to Nutrient Requirements. Washington, DC: The National Academies Press; 2006. pp. 82&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwimmer JB, Deutsch R, Kahen T, Lavine JE, Stanley C, Behling C. Prevalence of fatty liver in children and adolescents. Pediatrics. 2006;118(4):1388&#x2013;1393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17015527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaibi GQ, Cruz ML, Ball GD, Weigensberg MJ, Salem GJ, Crespo NC, et al. Effects of resistance training on insulin sensitivity in overweight Latino adolescent males. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38(7):1208&#x2013;1215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16826016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sunehag AL, Toffolo G, Campioni M, Bier DM, Haymond MW. Effects of dietary macronutrient intake on insulin sensitivity and secretion and glucose and lipid metabolism in healthy, obese adolescents. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2005;90(8):4496&#x2013;4502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15928240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sunehag AL, Toffolo G, Treuth MS, Butte NF, Cobelli C, Bier DM, et al. Effects of dietary macronutrient content on glucose metabolism in children. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2002;87(11):5168&#x2013;5178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12414888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sunehag AL, Treuth MS, Toffolo G, Butte NF, Cobelli C, Bier DM, et al. Glucose production, gluconeogenesis, and insulin sensitivity in children and adolescents: an evaluation of their reproducibility. Pediatr Res. 2001;50(1):115&#x2013;123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11420428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szczepaniak LS, Babcock EE, Schick F, Dobbins RL, Garg A, Burns DK, et al. Measurement of intracellular triglyceride stores by H spectroscopy: validation in vivo. Am J Physiol. 1999;276(5 Pt 1):E977&#x2013;E989.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10329993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szczepaniak LS, Nurenberg P, Leonard D, Browning JD, Reingold JS, Grundy S, et al. Magnetic resonance spectroscopy to measure hepatic triglyceride content: prevalence of hepatic steatosis in the general population. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2005;288(2):462&#x2013;468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15339742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taksali SE, Caprio S, Dziura J, Dufour S, Cali AM, Goodman TR, et al. High visceral and low abdominal subcutaneous fat stores in the obese adolescent: a determinant of an adverse metabolic phenotype. Diabetes. 2008;57(2):367&#x2013;371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17977954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treuth MS, Hunter GR, Figueroa-Colon R, Goran MI. Effects of strength training on intra-abdominal adipose tissue in obese prepubertal girls. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1998;30(12):1738&#x2013;1743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9861608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treuth MS, Sunehag AL, Trautwein LM, Bier DM, Haymond MW, Butte NF. Metabolic adaptation to high-fat and high-carbohydrate diets in children and adolescents. Am J Clin Nutr. 2003;77(2):479&#x2013;489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12540411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Heijden G, Toffolo G, Manesso E, Sauer PJJ, Sunehag AL. Aerobic Exercise Increases Peripheral and Hepatic Insulin Sensitivity in Sedentary Adolescents. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2009;94(11):4292&#x2013;4299. E-pub Oct. 6, 2009 PMID 19808855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2775656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19808855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Heijden GJ, Wang ZJ, Sauer PJJ, Haymond MW, Rodriguez LM, Sunehag AL. A 12 Week Aerobic Exercise Program Reduces Hepatic Fat Accumulation and Insulin Resistance in Obese, Hispanic Adolescents. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2010;18:384&#x2013;390. E-pub Aug. 20, 2009 PMID 19696755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19696755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ventura E, Davis J, Byrd-Williams C, Alexander K, McClain A, Lane CJ, et al. Reduction in risk factors for type 2 diabetes mellitus in response to a low-sugar, high-fiber dietary intervention in overweight Latino adolescents. Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. 2009;163(4):320&#x2013;327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2850811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19349560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiggin M, Wilkinson K, Habetz S, Chorley J, Watson M. Percentile values of isokinetic peak torque in children six through thirteen years old. Pediatr Phys Ther. 2006;18(1):3&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16508529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilmore JH, Despres JP, Stanforth PR, Mandel S, Rice T, Gagnon J, et al. Alterations in body weight and composition consequent to 20 wk of endurance training: The HERITAGE family study. Am J Clin Nutr. 1999;70(3):346&#x2013;352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10479196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>