<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">25970664</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2016</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>47</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2015</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Prospective Association between Different Types of Exercise and Body Composition.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2535</StartPage><EndPage>2541</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2535-41</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000701</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Despite the widely accepted benefits of exercise on chronic disease risk, controversy remains on the role of exercise in weight loss. This study examined the effect of different exercise types on measures of adiposity across different fat categories.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 348 young adults (49% male; 28 &#xb1; 4 yr), participating in an ongoing observational study provided valid data over a period of 12 months. Fat mass (FM) and lean mass (LM) were measured via dual x-ray absorptiometry every 3 months. Percent body fat was calculated and used to differentiate between normal-fat, "overfat," and obese participants. At each measurement time point, participants reported engagement (min&#xb7;wk) in aerobic exercise, resistance exercise, and other forms of exercise.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Most participants (93%) reported some exercise participation during the observation period. Total exercise or specific exercise types did not significantly affect subsequent body mass index after adjusting for sex, ethnicity, age, and baseline values of adiposity and exercise. Resistance exercise affected LM (P &lt; 0.01) and FM (P &lt; 0.01), whereas aerobic exercise only affected FM (P &lt; 0.01). Any exercise type positively affected LM in normal-fat participants (P &lt; 0.04). In overfat and obese participants, FM was reduced with increasing resistance exercise (P &#x2264; 0.02) but not with aerobic exercise (P &#x2265; 0.09). Additionally adjusting for objectively assessed total physical activity level did not change these results.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Despite the limited effects on body mass index, exercise was associated with beneficial changes in body composition. Exercise increased LM in normal-fat participants and reduced FM in overfat and obese adults. Adults with excess body fat may benefit particularly from resistance exercise.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Drenowatz</LastName><ForeName>Clemens</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>1Department of Exercise Science, University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC; 2Department of Epidemiology, School of Public Health, West Virginia University, Morgantown, WV; 3European Society of Lifestyle Medicine, Paris, FRANCE; 4Department of Kinesiology, Iowa State University, Ames, IA; 5College of Nursing, University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC; and 6Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hand</LastName><ForeName>Gregory A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sagner</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shook</LastName><ForeName>Robin P</ForeName><Initials>RP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burgess</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blair</LastName><ForeName>Steven N</ForeName><Initials>SN</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>N01 HC045135</GrantID><Acronym>HC</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050154" MajorTopicYN="Y">Adiposity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="Y">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><u>Conflict of Interest</u>. The remaining authors have no conflict to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25970664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS687124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4643425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Andersen RE, Jakicic JM. Interpreting the physical activity guidelines for health and weight management. J Phys Act Health. 2009;6(5):651&#x2013;656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19953843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Archer E, Shook RP, Thomas DM, et al. 45-Year trends in women's use of time and household management energy expenditure. PLoS One. 2013;8(2):e56620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3577846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23437187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beavers KM, Lyles MF, Davis CC, Wang X, Beavers DP, Nicklas BJ. Is lost lean mass from intentional weight loss recovered during weight regain in postmenopausal women? Am J Clin Nutr. 2011;94(3):767&#x2013;774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3155932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21795437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernstein MS, Costanza MC, Morabia A. Association of physical activity intensity levels with overweight and obesity in a population-based sample of adults. Prev Med. 2004;38(1):94&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14672646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutcher SH. High-intensity intermittent exercise and fat loss. J Obes. 2011;2011:868305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2991639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21113312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catenacci VA, Ogden LG, Stuht J, et al. Physical activity patterns in the National Weight Control Registry. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2008;16(1):153&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4578963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18223628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Church TS, Thomas DM, Tudor-Locke C, et al. Trends over 5 decades in U.S. occupation-related physical activity and their associations with obesity. PLoS One. 2011;6(5):e19657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3102055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21647427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhurandhar EJ, Kaiser KA, Dawson JA, Alcorn AS, Keating KD, Allison DB. Predicting adult weight change in the real world: a systematic review and meta-analysis accounting for compensatory changes in energy intake or expenditure. Int J Obes (Lond) 2014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4516704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25323965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiPietro L. Physical activity in the prevention of obesity: current evidence and research issues. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31(11 Suppl):S542&#x2013;S546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10593525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly JE, Blair SN, Jakicic JM, et al. American College of Sports Medicine Position Stand. Appropriate physical activity intervention strategies for weight loss and prevention of weight regain for adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(2):459&#x2013;471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19127177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekelund U, S&#xe4;rnblad S, Brage S, Ryberg J, Wareham NJ, Aman J. Does physical activity equally predict gain in fat mass among obese and nonobese young adults? Int J Obes (Lond) 2007;31(1):65&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16652123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher D, Heymsfield SB, Heo M, Jebb SA, Murgatroyd PR, Sakamoto Y. Healthy percentage body fat ranges: an approach for developing guidelines based on body mass index. Am J Clin Nutr. 2000;72(3):694&#x2013;701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10966886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hand G, Shook R, Paluch A, et al. The Energy Balance Study: The design and baseline results for a longitudinal study of energy balance. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2013;84(3):275&#x2013;286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24261006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haskell WL, Lee IM, Pate RR, et al. Physical activity and public health: updated recommendation for adults from the American College of Sports Medicine and the American Heart Association. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39(8):1423&#x2013;1434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17762377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter GR, Fisher G, Neumeier WH, Carter SJ, Plaisance EP. Exercise Training and Energy Expenditure following Weight Loss. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015 epub ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4508245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25606816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter GR, Wetzstein CJ, Fields DA, Brown A, Bamman MM. Resistance training increases total energy expenditure and free-living physical activity in older adults. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2000;89(3):977&#x2013;984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10956341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeffery RW, Drewnowski A, Epstein LH, et al. Long-term maintenance of weight loss: current status. Health Psychol. 2000;19(1 Suppl):5&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10709944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johannsen DL, Calabro MA, Stewart J, Franke W, Rood JC, Welk GJ. Accuracy of armband monitors for measuring daily energy expenditure in healthy adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42(11):2134&#x2013;2140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20386334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King N, Caudwell P, Hopkins M, et al. Metabolic and behavioral compensatory responses to exercise interventions: barriers to weight loss. Obesity. 2007;15:1373&#x2013;1383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17557973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King NA, Horner K, Hills AP, et al. Exercise, appetite and weight management: understanding the compensatory responses in eating behaviour and how they contribute to variability in exercise-induced weight loss. Br J Sports Med. 2012;46(5):315&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21596715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirk EP, Donnelly JE, Smith BK, et al. Minimal resistance training improves daily energy expenditure and fat oxidation. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(5):1122&#x2013;1129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2862249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19346974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levinger I, Goodman C, Hare DL, Jerums G, Selig S. The effect of resistance training on functional capacity and quality of life in individuals with high and low numbers of metabolic risk factors. Diabetes Care. 2007;30(9):2205&#x2013;2210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17563342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin CK, Das SK, Lindblad L, et al. Effect of calorie restriction on the free-living physical activity levels of nonobese humans: results of three randomized trials. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2011;110(4):956&#x2013;963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3075130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21292847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maurer J, Taren DL, Teixeira PJ, et al. The psychosocial and behavioral characteristics related to energy misreporting. Nutr Rev. 2006;64(2 Pt 1):53&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16536182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekary RA, Gr&#xf8;ntved A, Despres JP, et al. Weight training, aerobic physical activities, and long-term waist circumference change in men. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2015;23(2):461&#x2013;467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4310793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25530447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melanson EL, Keadle SK, Donnelly JE, Braun B, King NA. Resistance to exercise-induced weight loss: compensatory behavioral adaptations. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2013;45(8):1600&#x2013;1609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3696411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23470300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller CT, Fraser SF, Levinger I, et al. The effects of exercise training in addition to energy restriction on functional capacities and body composition in obese adults during weight loss: a systematic review. PLoS One. 2013;8(11):e81692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3884087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24409219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohkawara K, Tanaka S, Miyachi M, Ishikawa-Takata K, Tabata I. A dose-response relation between aerobic exercise and visceral fat reduction: systematic review of clinical trials. Int J Obes (Lond) 2007;31(12):1786&#x2013;1797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17637702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveros E, Somers VK, Sochor O, Goel K, Lopez-Jimenez F. The concept of normal weight obesity. Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2014;56(4):426&#x2013;433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24438734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poslusna K, Ruprich J, de Vries JH, Jakubikova M, van't Veer P. Misreporting of energy and micronutrient intake estimated by food records and 24 hour recalls, control and adjustment methods in practice. Br J Nutr. 2009;101(Suppl.2):S73&#x2013;S85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19594967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pourhassan M, Bosy-Westphal A, Schautz B, Braun W, Gl&#xfc;er CC, M&#xfc;ller MJ. Impact of body composition during weight change on resting energy expenditure and homeostasis model assessment index in overweight nonsmoking adults. Am J Clin Nutr. 2014;99(4):779&#x2013;791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24500156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redman LM, Heilbronn LK, Martin CK, et al. Metabolic and behavioral compensations in response to caloric restriction: implications for the maintenance of weight loss. PLoS One. 2009;4(2):e4377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2634841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19198647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross R, Janiszewski PM. Is weight loss the optimal target for obesity-related cardiovascular disease risk reduction? Can J Cardiol. 2008;24(Suppl D):25D&#x2013;31D.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2794451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18787733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samitz G, Egger M, Zwahlen M. Domains of physical activity and all-cause mortality: systematic review and dose-response meta-analysis of cohort studies. Int J Epidemiol. 2011;40(5):1382&#x2013;1400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22039197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwingshackl L, Dias S, Strasser B, Hoffmann G. Impact of different training modalities on anthropometric and metabolic characteristics in overweight/obese subjects: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2013;8(12):e82853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3866267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24358230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slentz CA, Houmard JA, Kraus WE. Modest exercise prevents the progressive disease associated with physical inactivity. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2007;35(1):18&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17211189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St-Onge M, Mignault D, Allison DB, Rabasa-Lhoret R. Evaluation of a portable device to measure daily energy expenditure in free-living adults. Am J Clin Nutr. 2007;85(3):742&#x2013;749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17344495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser B, Schobersberger W. Evidence for resistance training as a treatment therapy in obesity. J Obes. 2011;2011:482564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2931407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swift DL, Johannsen NM, Lavie CJ, Earnest CP, Church TS. The role of exercise and physical activity in weight loss and maintenance. Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2014;56(4):441&#x2013;447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3925973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24438736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DM, Bouchard C, Church T, et al. Why do individuals not lose more weight from an exercise intervention at a defined dose? An energy balance analysis. Obes Rev. 2012;13(10):835&#x2013;847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3771367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22681398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DM, Schoeller DA, Redman LA, Martin CK, Levine JA, Heymsfield SB. A computational model to determine energy intake during weight loss. Am J Clin Nutr. 2010;92(6):1326&#x2013;1331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2980958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20962159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trapp EG, Chisholm DJ, Freund J, Boutcher SH. The effects of high-intensity intermittent exercise training on fat loss and fasting insulin levels of young women. Int J Obes (Lond) 2008;32(4):684&#x2013;691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18197184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wareham NJ, van Sluijs EM, Ekelund U. Physical activity and obesity prevention: a review of the current evidence. Proc Nutr Soc. 2005;64(2):229&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15960868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westerterp KR. Obesity and physical activity. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 1999;23(Suppl 1):59&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10193864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westerterp KR, Meijer GA, Janssen EM, Saris WH, Ten Hoor F. Long-term effect of physical activity on energy balance and body composition. Br J Nutr. 1992;68(1):21&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1390606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willey KA, Singh MA. Battling insulin resistance in elderly obese people with type 2 diabetes: bring on the heavy weights. Diabetes Care. 2003;26(5):1580&#x2013;1588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12716822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization W. Global recommendations on physical activity for health. Geneva, Switzerland: WHO Press; 2010. pp. 24&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26180873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>