<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">24772374</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2155-6156</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>4</Volume><PubDate><Year>2013</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of diabetes &amp; metabolism</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Diabetes Metab</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Treating Diabetes with Exercise - Focus on the Microvasculature.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>308</StartPage><MedlinePgn>308</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>The rising incidence of diabetes and the associated metabolic diseases including obesity, cardiovascular disease and hypertension have led to investigation of a number of drugs to treat these diseases. However, lifestyle interventions including diet and exercise remain the first line of defense. The benefits of exercise are typically presented in terms of weight loss, improved body composition and reduced fat mass, but exercise can have many other beneficial effects. Acute effects of exercise include major changes in blood flow through active muscle, an active hyperemia that increases the delivery of oxygen to the working muscle fibers. Longer term exercise training can affect the vasculature, improving endothelial health and possibly basal metabolic rates. Further, insulin sensitivity is improved both acutely after a single bout of exercise and shows chronic effects with exercise training, effectively reducing diabetes risk. Exercise-mediated improvements in endothelial function may also reduce complications associated with both diabetes and other metabolic disease. Thus, while drugs to improve microvascular function in diabetes continue to be investigated, exercise can also provide many similar benefits on endothelial function and should remain the first prescription when treating insulin resistance and diabetes. This review will investigate the effects of exercise on the blood vessel and the potential benefits of exercise on cardiovascular disease and diabetes.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kolka</LastName><ForeName>Cm</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, Diabetes and Obesity Research Institute, Cedars-Sinai Medical Center, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 DK027619</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 DK029867</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R37 DK027619</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Diabetes Metab</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101549907</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blood vessels</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vasculature</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2014</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2014</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24772374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS567754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4000229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. National Diabetes Fact Sheet: National estimates and general information on diabetes and prediabetes in the United States. 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reusch JE, Bridenstine M, Regensteiner JG. Type 2 diabetes mellitus and exercise impairment. Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2013;14:77&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3593997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23299658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haskell WL, Lee IM, Pate RR, Powell KE, Blair SN, et al. Physical activity and public health: updated recommendation for adults from the American College of Sports Medicine and the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2007;116:1081&#x2013;1093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17671237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wing RR, Bolin P, Brancati FL, Bray GA, et al. Look AHEAD Research Group. Cardiovascular effects of intensive lifestyle intervention in type 2 diabetes. N Engl J Med. 2013;369:145&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3791615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23796131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akazawa S, Sun F, Ito M, Kawasaki E, Eguchi K. Efficacy of troglitazone on body fat distribution in type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2000;23:1067&#x2013;1071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10937499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lottati M, Kolka CM, Stefanovski D, Kirkman EL, Bergman RN. Greater omentectomy improves insulin sensitivity in nonobese dogs. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2009;17:674&#x2013;680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3417107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19214178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MJ, Wu Y, Fried SK. Adipose tissue heterogeneity: implication of depot differences in adipose tissue for obesity complications. Mol Aspects Med. 2013;34:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3549425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23068073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirhosseini NZ, Shahar S, Ghayour-Mobarhan M, Parizadeh MR, Yusoff NA, et al. Body fat distribution and its association with cardiovascular risk factors in adolescent Iranian girls. Iran J Pediatr. 2012;22:197&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3446063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23056886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchonville M, Armamento-Villareal R, Shah K, Napoli N, Sinacore DR, et al. Weight loss, exercise or both and cardiometabolic risk factors in obese older adults: results of a randomized controlled trial. Int J Obes (Lond) 2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3835728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23823329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyner MJ, Green DJ. Exercise protects the cardiovascular system: effects beyond traditional risk factors. J Physiol. 2009;587:5551&#x2013;5558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2805367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19736305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeFronzo RA, Tripathy D. Skeletal muscle insulin resistance is the primary defect in type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2009;32:S157&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2811436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19875544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SP, Ellmerer M, Van Citters GW, Bergman RN. Primacy of hepatic insulin resistance in the development of the metabolic syndrome induced by an isocaloric moderate-fat diet in the dog. Diabetes. 2003;52:2453&#x2013;2460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14514627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virkam&#xe4;ki A, Korsheninnikova E, Sepp&#xe4;l&#xe4;-Lindroos A, Vehkavaara S, Goto T, et al. Intramyocellular lipid is associated with resistance to in vivo insulin actions on glucose uptake, antilipolysis, and early insulin signaling pathways in human skeletal muscle. Diabetes. 2001;50:2337&#x2013;2343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11574417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu C, Chen Y, Cline GW, Zhang D, Zong H, et al. Mechanism by which fatty acids inhibit insulin activation of insulin receptor substrate-1 (IRS-1)-associated phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase activity in muscle. J Biol Chem. 2002;277:50230&#x2013;50236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12006582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz-Peiffer C. Signalling aspects of insulin resistance in skeletal muscle: mechanisms induced by lipid oversupply. Cell Signal. 2000;12:583&#x2013;594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11080610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koopmans SJ, Maassen JA, Sips HC, Radder JK, Krans HM. Tissue-related changes in insulin receptor number and autophosphorylation induced by starvation and diabetes in rats. Metabolism. 1995;44:291&#x2013;297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7885272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laviola L, Perrini S, Cignarelli A, Natalicchio A, Leonardini A, et al. Insulin signaling in human visceral and subcutaneous adipose tissue in vivo. Diabetes. 2006;55:952&#x2013;961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16567516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolterman OG, Insel J, Saekow M, Olefsky JM. Mechanisms of insulin resistance in human obesity: evidence for receptor and postreceptor defects. J Clin Invest. 1980;65:1272&#x2013;1284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC371464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6997333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gogg S, Smith U, Jansson PA. Increased MAPK activation and impaired insulin signaling in subcutaneous microvascular endothelial cells in type 2 diabetes: the role of endothelin-1. Diabetes. 2009;58:2238&#x2013;2245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2750225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19581418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rask-Madsen C, Li Q, Freund B, Feather D, Abramov R, et al. Loss of insulin signaling in vascular endothelial cells accelerates atherosclerosis in apolipoprotein E null mice. Cell Metab. 2010;11:379&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3020149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20444418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vicent D, Ilany J, Kondo T, Naruse K, Fisher SJ, et al. The role of endothelial insulin signaling in the regulation of vascular tone and insulin resistance. J Clin Invest. 2003;111:1373&#x2013;1380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC154437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12727929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Akoum S, Cloutier I, Tanguay JF. Vascular smooth muscle cell alterations triggered by mice adipocytes: role of high-fat diet. J Atheroscler Thromb. 2012;19:1128&#x2013;1141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23047600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron AD, Steinberg HO, Chaker H, Leaming R, Johnson A, et al. Insulin-mediated skeletal muscle vasodilation contributes to both insulin sensitivity and responsiveness in lean humans. J Clin Invest. 1995;96:786&#x2013;792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC185264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7635973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu JD, Kolka CM, Richey JM, Harrison LN, Zuniga E, et al. Experimental hyperlipidemia dramatically reduces access of insulin to canine skeletal muscle. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2009;17:1486&#x2013;1492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3417110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19521354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolka CM, Harrison LN, Lottati M, Chiu JD, Kirkman EL, et al. Diet-induced obesity prevents interstitial dispersion of insulin in skeletal muscle. Diabetes. 2010;59:619&#x2013;626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2827487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19959760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eringa EC, Serne EH, Meijer RI, Schalkwijk CG, Houben AJ, et al. Endothelial dysfunction in (pre)diabetes: characteristics, causative mechanisms and pathogenic role in type 2 diabetes. Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2013;14:39&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23417760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansson PA. Endothelial dysfunction in insulin resistance and type 2 diabetes. J Intern Med. 2007;262:173&#x2013;183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17645585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watts GF, O&#x2019;Brien SF, Silvester W, Millar JA. Impaired endothelium-dependent and independent dilatation of forearm resistance arteries in men with diet-treated non-insulin-dependent diabetes: role of dyslipidaemia. Clin Sci (Lond) 1996;91:567&#x2013;573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8942395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldfine AB, Beckman JA, Betensky RA, Devlin H, Hurley S, et al. Family history of diabetes is a major determinant of endothelial function. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2006;47:2456&#x2013;2461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16781373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laughlin MH, Davis MJ, Secher NH, van Lieshout JJ, Arce-Esquivel AA, et al. Peripheral circulation. Compr Physiol. 2012;2:321&#x2013;447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23728977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honig CR, Odoroff CL, Frierson JL. Active and passive capillary control in red muscle at rest and in exercise. Am J Physiol. 1982;243:H196&#x2013;206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7114231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent MA, Clerk LH, Lindner JR, Price WJ, Jahn LA, et al. Mixed meal and light exercise each recruit muscle capillaries in healthy humans. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2006;290:E1191&#x2013;1197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16682488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong RB, Laughlin MH. Blood flows within and among rat muscles as a function of time during high speed treadmill exercise. J Physiol. 1983;344:189&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1193834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6655579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honig CR, Odoroff CL, Frierson JL. Capillary recruitment in exercise: rate, extent, uniformity, and relation to blood flow. Am J Physiol. 1980;238:H31&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7356032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laughlin MH, Armstrong RB. Muscular blood flow distribution patterns as a function of running speed in rats. Am J Physiol. 1982;243:H296&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7114239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong RB, Delp MD, Goljan EF, Laughlin MH. Distribution of blood flow in muscles of miniature swine during exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1987;62:1285&#x2013;1298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3106313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarelius I, Pohl U. Control of muscle blood flow during exercise: local factors and integrative mechanisms. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 2010;199:349&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3157959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20353492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas GD, Segal SS. Neural control of muscle blood flow during exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2004;97:731&#x2013;738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15247201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jendzjowsky NG, DeLorey DS. Short-term exercise training augments sympathetic vasoconstrictor responsiveness and endothelium-dependent vasodilation in resting skeletal muscle. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2012;303:R332&#x2013;339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22696575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straznicky NE, Grima MT, Eikelis N, Nestel PJ, Dawood T, et al. The effects of weight loss versus weight loss maintenance on sympathetic nervous system activity and metabolic syndrome components. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2011;96:E503&#x2013;508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21177786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straznicky NE, Lambert EA, Nestel PJ, McGrane MT, Dawood T, et al. Sympathetic neural adaptation to hypocaloric diet with or without exercise training in obese metabolic syndrome subjects. Diabetes. 2010;59:71&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2797947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19833893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheatley CM, Rattigan S, Richards SM, Barrett EJ, Clark MG. Skeletal muscle contraction stimulates capillary recruitment and glucose uptake in insulin-resistant obese Zucker rats. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2004;287:E804&#x2013;809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15213062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonne MP, Alibegovic AC, H&#xf8;jbjerre L, Vaag A, Stallknecht B, et al. Effect of 10 days of bedrest on metabolic and vascular insulin action: a study in individuals at risk for type 2 diabetes. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2010;108:830&#x2013;837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20110547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spier SA, Delp MD, Stallone JN, Dominguez JM, 2nd, Muller-Delp JM. Exercise training enhances flow-induced vasodilation in skeletal muscle resistance arteries of aged rats: role of PGI2 and nitric oxide. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2007;292:H3119&#x2013;3127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17337602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Womack L, Peters D, Barrett EJ, Kaul S, Price W, et al. Abnormal skeletal muscle capillary recruitment during exercise in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus and microvascular complications. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2009;53:2175&#x2013;2183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2722783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19497445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross RM, Wadley GD, Clark MG, Rattigan S, McConell GK. Local nitric oxide synthase inhibition reduces skeletal muscle glucose uptake but not capillary blood flow during in situ muscle contraction in rats. Diabetes. 2007;56:2885&#x2013;2892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17881613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinonen I, Saltin B, Kemppainen J, Sipil&#xe4; HT, Oikonen V, et al. Skeletal muscle blood flow and oxygen uptake at rest and during exercise in humans: a pet study with nitric oxide and cyclooxygenase inhibition. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2011;300:H1510&#x2013;1517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21257921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrett EJ, Rattigan S. Muscle perfusion: its measurement and role in metabolic regulation. Diabetes. 2012;61:2661&#x2013;2668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3478558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23093655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolka CM, Bergman RN. The barrier within: endothelial transport of hormones. Physiology (Bethesda) 2012;27:237&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4423824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22875454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majumdar S, Genders AJ, Inyard AC, Frison V, Barrett EJ. Insulin entry into muscle involves a saturable process in the vascular endothelium. Diabetologia. 2012;55:450&#x2013;456.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3270327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22002008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Wang AX, Liu Z, Barrett EJ. Insulin signaling stimulates insulin transport by bovine aortic endothelial cells. Diabetes. 2008;57:540&#x2013;547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17977956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi Y, Nagasaka S, Takahashi N, Kusaka I, Ishibashi S, et al. A single bout of exercise at higher intensity enhances glucose effectiveness in sedentary men. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2005;90:4035&#x2013;4040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15840752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinonen I, Saltin B, Kemppainen J, Nuutila P, Knuuti J, et al. Effect of nitric oxide synthase inhibition on the exchange of glucose and fatty acids in human skeletal muscle. Nutr Metab (Lond) 2013;10:43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3686616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23773265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishida Y, Higaki Y, Tokuyama K, Fujimi K, Kiyonaga A, et al. Effect of mild exercise training on glucose effectiveness in healthy men. Diabetes Care. 2001;24:1008&#x2013;1013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11375361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuart CA, Howell ME, Baker JD, Dykes RJ, Duffourc MM, et al. Cycle training increased GLUT4 and activation of mammalian target of rapamycin in fast twitch muscle fibers. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42:96&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2796589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20010125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Y, Sheng S, Fang P, Ma Y, Li J, et al. Exercise-induced galanin release facilitated GLUT4 translocation in adipocytes of type 2 diabetic rats. Pharmacol Biochem Behav. 2012;100:554&#x2013;559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22079346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;nn T, Volkov P, Daveg&#xe5;rdh C, Dayeh T, Hall E, et al. A six months exercise intervention influences the genome-wide DNA methylation pattern in human adipose tissue. PLoS Genet. 2013;9:e1003572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3694844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23825961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brechtel K, Dahl DB, Machann J, Bachmann OP, Wenzel I, et al. Fast elevation of the intramyocellular lipid content in the presence of circulating free fatty acids and hyperinsulinemia: a dynamic 1H-MRS study. Magn Reson Med. 2001;45:179&#x2013;183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11180422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perseghin G, Scifo P, De Cobelli F, Pagliato E, Battezzati A, et al. Intramyocellular triglyceride content is a determinant of in vivo insulin resistance in humans: a 1H-13C nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy assessment in offspring of type 2 diabetic parents. Diabetes. 1999;48:1600&#x2013;1606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10426379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greco AV, Mingrone G, Giancaterini A, Manco M, Morroni M, et al. Insulin resistance in morbid obesity: reversal with intramyocellular fat depletion. Diabetes. 2002;51:144&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11756334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krssak M, Falk Petersen K, Dresner A, DiPietro L, Vogel SM, et al. Intramyocellular lipid concentrations are correlated with insulin sensitivity in humans: a 1H NMR spectroscopy study. Diabetologia. 1999;42:113&#x2013;116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10027589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haus JM, Solomon TP, Lu L, Jesberger JA, Barkoukis H, et al. Intramyocellular lipid content and insulin sensitivity are increased following a short-term low-glycemic index diet and exercise intervention. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2011;301:E511&#x2013;516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3174532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21712533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pehm&#xf8;ller C, Brandt N, Birk JB, H&#xf8;eg LD, Sj&#xf8;berg KA, et al. Exercise alleviates lipid-induced insulin resistance in human skeletal muscle-signaling interaction at the level of TBC1 domain family member 4. Diabetes. 2012;61:2743&#x2013;2752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3478539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22851577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holland WL, Bikman BT, Wang LP, Yuguang G, Sargent KM, et al. Lipid-induced insulin resistance mediated by the proinflammatory receptor TLR4 requires saturated fatty acid-induced ceramide biosynthesis in mice. J Clin Invest. 2011;121:1858&#x2013;1870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3083776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21490391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nowotny B, Zahiragic L, Krog D, Nowotny PJ, Herder C, et al. Mechanisms underlying the onset of oral lipid-induced skeletal muscle insulin resistance in humans. Diabetes. 2013;62:2240&#x2013;2248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3712035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23454694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz-Peiffer C, Craig DL, Biden TJ. Ceramide generation is sufficient to account for the inhibition of the insulin-stimulated PKB pathway in C2C12 skeletal muscle cells pretreated with palmitate. J Biol Chem. 1999;274:24202&#x2013;24210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10446195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muoio DM. Revisiting the connection between intramyocellular lipids and insulin resistance: a long and winding road. Diabetologia. 2012;55:2551&#x2013;2554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22660796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coen PM, Goodpaster BH. Role of intramyocelluar lipids in human health. Trends Endocrinol Metab. 2012;23:391&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4908975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22721584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yudkin JS. Inflammation, obesity, and the metabolic syndrome. Horm Metab Res. 2007;39:707&#x2013;709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17952830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A, Bernatchez PN, de Haan JB. Targeting endothelial dysfunction in vascular complications associated with diabetes. Int J Vasc Med. 2012;2012:750126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3195347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22013533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberbach A, Bossenz Y, Lehmann S, Niebauer J, Adams V, et al. Altered fiber distribution and fiber-specific glycolytic and oxidative enzyme activity in skeletal muscle of patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2006;29:895&#x2013;900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16567834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowell BB, Shulman GI. Mitochondrial dysfunction and type 2 diabetes. Science. 2005;307:384&#x2013;387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15662004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoeks J, van Herpen NA, Mensink M, Moonen-Kornips E, van Beurden D, et al. Prolonged fasting identifies skeletal muscle mitochondrial dysfunction as consequence rather than cause of human insulin resistance. Diabetes. 2010;59:2117&#x2013;2125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2927932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20573749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shenouda SM, Widlansky ME, Chen K, Xu G, Holbrook M, et al. Altered mitochondrial dynamics contributes to endothelial dysfunction in diabetes mellitus. Circulation. 2011;124:444&#x2013;453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3149100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21747057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toledo FG, Goodpaster BH. The role of weight loss and exercise in correcting skeletal muscle mitochondrial abnormalities in obesity, diabetes and aging. Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2013;379:30&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23792186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rattigan S, Wallis MG, Youd JM, Clark MG. Exercise training improves insulin-mediated capillary recruitment in association with glucose uptake in rat hindlimb. Diabetes. 2001;50:2659&#x2013;2665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11723047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter GR, Wetzstein CJ, Fields DA, Brown A, Bamman MM. Resistance training increases total energy expenditure and free-living physical activity in older adults. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2000;89:977&#x2013;984.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10956341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilliat-Wimberly M, Manore MM, Woolf K, Swan PD, Carroll SS. Effects of habitual physical activity on the resting metabolic rates and body compositions of women aged 35 to 50 years. J Am Diet Assoc. 2001;101:1181&#x2013;1188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11678489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings AE, Alberga A, Sigal RJ, Jay O, Boul&#xe9; NG, et al. The effect of exercise training on resting metabolic rate in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:1558&#x2013;1565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19568205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stiegler P, Cunliffe A. The role of diet and exercise for the maintenance of fat-free mass and resting metabolic rate during weight loss. Sports Med. 2006;36:239&#x2013;262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16526835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Utsunomiya K. Treatment strategy for type 2 diabetes from the perspective of systemic vascular protection and insulin resistance. Vasc Health Risk Manag. 2012;8:429&#x2013;436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3402056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22910731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mather KJ. The vascular endothelium in diabetes--a therapeutic target? Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2013;14:87&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3593981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23397462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolka CM, Bergman RN. The endothelium in diabetes: its role in insulin access and diabetic complications. Rev Endocr Metab Disord. 2013;14:13&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3593803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23306780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonk AM, Houben AJ, de Jongh RT, Sern&#xe9; EH, Schaper NC, et al. Microvascular dysfunction in obesity: a potential mechanism in the pathogenesis of obesity-associated insulin resistance and hypertension. Physiology (Bethesda) 2007;22:252&#x2013;260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17699878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen PA, Nolte LA, Chen MM, Holloszy JO. Increased GLUT-4 translocation mediates enhanced insulin sensitivity of muscle glucose transport after exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1998;85:1218&#x2013;1222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9760308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeFronzo RA, Ferrannini E, Sato Y, Felig P, Wahren J. Synergistic interaction between exercise and insulin on peripheral glucose uptake. J Clin Invest. 1981;68:1468&#x2013;1474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC370949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7033285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slimani L, Oikonen V, H&#xe4;llsten K, Savisto N, Knuuti J, et al. Exercise restores skeletal muscle glucose delivery but not insulin-mediated glucose transport and phosphorylation in obese subjects. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2006;91:3394&#x2013;3403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2743828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16772346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satchell SC. The glomerular endothelium emerges as a key player in diabetic nephropathy. Kidney Int. 2012;82:949&#x2013;951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23064188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tremolada G, Del Turco C, Lattanzio R, Maestroni S, Maestroni A, et al. The role of angiogenesis in the development of proliferative diabetic retinopathy: impact of intravitreal anti-VEGF treatment. Exp Diabetes Res. 2012;2012:728325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3332167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22566995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szostak J, Laurant P. The forgotten face of regular physical exercise: a &#x2018;natural&#x2019; anti-atherogenic activity. Clin Sci (Lond) 2011;121:91&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21729002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolka CM, Rattigan S, Richards SM, Clark MG. Potential for endothelin-1-mediated impairment of contractile activity in hypertension. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol. 2007;34:217&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17250642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperandio PA, Oliveira MF, Rodrigues MK, Berton DC, Treptow E, et al. Sildenafil improves microvascular O2 delivery-to-utilization matching and accelerates exercise O2 uptake kinetics in chronic heart failure. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2012;303:H1474&#x2013;1480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23023868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley EA, Eringa EC, Stehouwer CD, Korstjens I, NieuwAmerongen GP, et al. Activation of AMP-activated protein kinase by 5-aminoimidazole-4-carboxamide-1-beta-D-ribofuranoside in the muscle microcirculation increases nitric oxide synthesis and microvascular perfusion. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2010;30:1137&#x2013;1142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20224051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGuire DK, Abdullah SM, See R, Snell PG, McGavock J, et al. Randomized comparison of the effects of rosiglitazone vs. placebo on peak integrated cardiovascular performance, cardiac structure, and function. Eur Heart J. 2010;31:2262&#x2013;2270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2938467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20601395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregg EW, Chen H, Wagenknecht LE, Clark JM, Delahanty LM, et al. Association of an intensive lifestyle intervention with remission of type 2 diabetes. JAMA. 2012;308:2489&#x2013;2496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4771522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23288372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solomon TP, Malin SK, Karstoft K, Haus JM, Kirwan JP. The influence of hyperglycemia on the therapeutic effect of exercise on glycemic control in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. JAMA Intern Med. 2013;173:1834&#x2013;1836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3837468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23817567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uusitupa M, Peltonen M, Lindstr&#xf6;m J, Aunola S, Ilanne-Parikka P, et al. Ten-year mortality and cardiovascular morbidity in the Finnish Diabetes Prevention Study--secondary analysis of the randomized trial. PLoS One. 2009;4:e5656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2682577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19479072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodpaster BH, Delany JP, Otto AD, Kuller L, Vockley J, et al. Effects of diet and physical activity interventions on weight loss and cardiometabolic risk factors in severely obese adults: a randomized trial. JAMA. 2010;304:1795&#x2013;1802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3082279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20935337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>