<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">30596808</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2156-5376</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advances in nutrition (Bethesda, Md.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Recent Advances in the Characterization of Skeletal Muscle and Whole-Body Protein Responses to Dietary Protein and Exercise during Negative Energy Balance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>70</StartPage><EndPage>79</EndPage><MedlinePgn>70-79</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/advances/nmy087</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In a review published in 2012, we concluded that higher-protein diets preserve muscle mass during energy deficit via stimulated mammalian target of rapamycin complex 1 signaling, coincident increased muscle protein synthesis (PS), inhibited ubiquitin-mediated proteolysis, and suppressed muscle protein breakdown (PB). Since then, there have been significant advances in understanding the fundamental effects of higher-protein diets, with or without exercise training, on muscle and whole-body protein homeostasis during negative energy balance. Therefore, an update on the evolution of this field of research is warranted to better inform recommendations on best practices for healthy weight loss and muscle preservation. We will review the most recent studies examining the effects of higher-protein diets and negative energy balance on body composition, muscle PS, muscle PB, associated intracellular regulatory pathway activities, and whole-body protein homeostasis. In addition to critically analyzing contemporary findings, knowledge gaps and opportunities for continued research will be identified. Overall, the newest research confirms that consuming higher-protein diets, particularly when coupled with resistance exercise, preserves muscle mass and maintains whole-body protein homeostasis during moderate energy deficits (i.e., normal weight loss). However, these newer findings also indicate that as the magnitude of energy deficit increases, the efficacy of higher-protein diets for mitigating losses of fat-free mass is diminished. Further, recent results suggest that alterations in muscle PS, more so than muscle PB, may be primarily responsible for changes in muscle mass that occur in response to negative energy balance.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carbone</LastName><ForeName>John W</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, Eastern Michigan University, Ypsilanti, MI.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McClung</LastName><ForeName>James P</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Military Nutrition Division, US Army Research Institute of Environmental Medicine, Natick, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pasiakos</LastName><ForeName>Stefan M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Military Nutrition Division, US Army Research Institute of Environmental Medicine, Natick, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101540874</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2161-8313</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004044">Dietary Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009124">Muscle Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073600" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diet, High-Protein</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004044" MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004734" MajorTopicYN="N">Energy Metabolism</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009124" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015431" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Loss</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2018</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30596808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6370268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/advances/nmy087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2161-8313(22)01288-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Carbone JW, McClung JP, Pasiakos SM. Skeletal muscle responses to negative energy balance: effects of dietary protein. Adv Nutr. 2012;3:119&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3648712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22516719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasiakos SM, Vislocky LM, Carbone JW, Altieri N, Konopelski K, Freake HC, Anderson JM, Ferrando AA, Wolfe RR, Rodriguez NR. Acute energy deprivation affects skeletal muscle protein synthesis and associated intracellular signaling proteins in physically active adults. J Nutr. 2010;140:745&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20164371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell WW, Haub MD, Wolfe RR, Ferrando AA, Sullivan DH, Apolzan JW, Iglay HB. Resistance training preserves fat-free mass without impacting changes in protein metabolism after weight loss in older women. Obesity. 2009;17:1332&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4299870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19247271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villareal DT, Smith GI, Shah K, Mittendorfer B. Effect of weight loss on the rate of muscle protein synthesis during fasted and fed conditions in obese older adults. Obesity. 2012;20:1780&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3291735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21938075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belkhou R, B&#xe9;chet D, Cherel Y, Galluser M, Ferrara M, le&#xa0;Maho Y. Effect of fasting and thyroidectomy on cysteine proteinase activities in liver and muscle. Biochim Biophys Acta. 1994;1199:195&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8123668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkes SC, Belcastro AN, McCargar LJ, McKenzie D. Effect of energy restriction on muscle function and calcium stimulated protease activity in recreationally active women. Can J Appl Physiol. 1998;23:279&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9615870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wohlgemuth SE, Lees HA, Marzetti E, Manini TM, Aranda JM, Daniels MJ, Pahor M, Perri MG, Leeuwenburgh C, Anton SD. An exploratory analysis of the effects of a weight loss plus exercise program on cellular quality control mechanisms in older overweight women. Rejuvenation Res. 2011;14:315&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3136739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21631380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbone JW, Margolis LM, McClung JP, Cao JJ, Murphy NE, Sauter ER, Combs GF, Young AJ, Pasiakos SM. Effects of energy deficit, dietary protein, and feeding on intracellular regulators of skeletal muscle proteolysis. FASEB J. 2013;27:5104&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23965841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hector AJ, Marcotte GR, Churchward-Venne TA, Murphy CH, Breen L, von&#xa0;Allmen M, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Whey protein supplementation preserves postprandial myofibrillar protein synthesis during short-term energy restriction in overweight and obese adults. J Nutr. 2015;145:246&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25644344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasiakos SM, Cao JJ, Margolis LM, Sauter ER, Whigham LD, McClung JP, Rood JC, Carbone JW, Combs GF, Young AJ. Effects of high-protein diets on fat-free mass and muscle protein synthesis following weight loss: a randomized controlled trial. FASEB J. 2013;27:3837&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23739654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasiakos SM, Margolis LM, McClung JP, Cao JJ, Whigham LD, Combs GF, Young AJ. Whole-body protein turnover response to short-term high-protein diets during weight loss: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Obes. 2014;38:1015&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24166063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbone JW, Pasiakos SM, Vislocky LM, Anderson JM, Rodriguez NR. Effects of short-term energy deficit on muscle protein breakdown and intramuscular proteolysis in normal-weight young adults. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2014;39:960&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24945715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karl JP, Smith TJ, Wilson MA, Bukhari AS, Pasiakos SM, McClung HL, McClung JP, Lieberman HR. Altered metabolic homeostasis is associated with appetite regulation during and following 48-h of severe energy deprivation in adults. Metabolism. 2016;65:416&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26975533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margolis LM, Murphy NE, Martini S, Spitz MG, Thrane I, McGraw SM, Blatny J-M, Castellani JW, Rood JC, Young AJ et al. Effects of winter military training on energy balance, whole-body protein balance, muscle damage, soreness, and physical performance. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2014;39:1395&#x2013;401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25386980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margolis LM, Murphy NE, Martini S, Gundersen Y, Castellani JW, Karl JP, Carrigan CT, Teien H-K, Madslien E-H, Montain SJ et al. Effects of supplemental energy on protein balance during 4-d Arctic military training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48:1604&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27054679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moberg M, Hendo G, Jakobsson M, Mattsson CM, Ekblom-Bak E, Flockhart M, Pont&#xe9;n M, S&#xf6;derlund K, Ekblom B. Increased autophagy signaling but not proteasome activity in human skeletal muscle after prolonged low-intensity exercise with negative energy balance. Physiol Rep. 2017;5:e13518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5727276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29208687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Areta JL, Burke LM, Camera DM, West DWD, Crawshay S, Moore DR, Stellingwerff T, Phillips SM, Hawley JA, Coffey VG. Reduced resting skeletal muscle protein synthesis is rescued by resistance exercise and protein ingestion following short-term energy deficit. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2014;306:E989&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24595305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berryman CE, Sepowitz JJ, McClung HL, Lieberman HR, Farina EK, McClung JP, Ferrando AA, Pasiakos SM. Supplementing an energy adequate, higher protein diet with protein does not enhance fat-free mass restoration after short-term severe negative energy balance. J Appl Physiol. 2017;122:1485&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28385919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hector AJ, McGlory C, Damas F, Mazara N, Baker SK, Phillips SM. Pronounced energy restriction with elevated protein intake results in no change in proteolysis and reductions in skeletal muscle protein synthesis that are mitigated by resistance exercise. FASEB J. 2018;32:265&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28899879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Josse AR, Atkinson SA, Tarnopolsky MA, Phillips SM. Increased consumption of dairy foods and protein during diet- and exercise-induced weight loss promotes fat mass loss and lean mass gain in overweight and obese premenopausal women. J Nutr. 2011;141:1626&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3159052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21775530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longland TM, Oikawa SY, Mitchell CJ, Devries MC, Phillips SM. Higher compared with lower dietary protein during an energy deficit combined with intense exercise promotes greater lean mass gain and fat mass loss: a randomized trial. Am J Clin Nutr. 2016;103:738&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26817506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy CH, Churchward-Venne TA, Mitchell CJ, Kolar NM, Kassis A, Karagounis LG, Burke LM, Hawley JA, Phillips SM. Hypoenergetic diet-induced reductions in myofibrillar protein synthesis are restored with resistance training and balanced daily protein ingestion in older men. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2015;308:E734&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4420900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25738784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smiles WJ, Areta JL, Coffey VG, Phillips SM, Moore DR, Stellingwerff T, Burke LM, Hawley JA, Camera DM. Modulation of autophagy signaling with resistance exercise and protein ingestion following short-term energy deficit. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2015;309:R603&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26136534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berryman CE, Young AJ, Karl JP, Kenefick RW, Margolis LM, Cole RE, Carbone JW, Lieberman HR, Kim I-Y, Ferrando AA et al. Severe negative energy balance during 21 d at high altitude decreases fat-free mass regardless of dietary protein intake: a randomized controlled trial. FASEB J. 2018;32:894&#x2013;905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29066613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margolis LM, Carbone JW, Berryman CE, Carrigan CT, Murphy NE, Ferrando AA, Young AJ, Pasiakos SM. Severe energy deficit at high altitude inhibits skeletal muscle mTORC1-mediated anabolic signaling without increased ubiquitin proteasome activity. FASEB J. 2018;32:5955&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29878853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margolis LM, Rivas DA, Pasiakos SM, McClung JP, Ceglia L, Fielding RA. Upregulation of circulating myomiR following short-term energy restriction is inversely associated with whole body protein synthesis. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2017;313:R298&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5625273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28659285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parr EB, Camera DM, Burke LM, Phillips SM, Coffey VG, Hawley JA. Circulating microRNA responses between &#x201c;high&#x201d; and &#x201c;low&#x201d; responders to a 16-wk diet and exercise weight loss intervention. PloS One. 2016;11:e0152545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4839646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27101373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layman DK, Boileau RA, Erickson DJ, Painter JE, Shiue H, Sather C, Christou DD. A reduced ratio of dietary carbohydrate to protein improves body composition and blood lipid profiles during weight loss in adult women. J Nutr. 2003;133:411&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12566476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berryman CE, Lieberman HR, Fulgoni VL, Pasiakos SM. Protein intake trends and conformity with the Dietary Reference Intakes in the United States: analysis of the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey, 2001&#x2013;2014. Am J Clin Nutr. 2018;108:405&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29931213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pikosky MA, Gaine PC, Martin WF, Grabarz KC, Ferrando AA, Wolfe RR, Rodriguez NR. Aerobic exercise training increases skeletal muscle protein turnover in healthy adults at rest. J Nutr. 2006;136:379&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16424115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips SM, Tipton KD, Aarsland A, Wolf SE, Wolfe RR. Mixed muscle protein synthesis and breakdown after resistance exercise in humans. Am J Physiol. 1997;273:E99&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasiakos SM, Carbone JW. Assessment of skeletal muscle proteolysis and the regulatory response to nutrition and exercise. IUBMB Life. 2014;66:478&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25052691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran A, Toffolo G, Schiavon M, Vella A, Klaus KA, Cobelli C, Nair KS. A novel triple-tracer approach to assess postprandial protein turnover. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2018;315:E469&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6230707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29870679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busch R, Kim Y-K, Neese RA, Schade-Serin V, Collins M, Awada M, Gardner JL, Beysen C, Marino ME, Misell LM et al. Measurement of protein turnover rates by heavy water labeling of nonessential amino acids. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2006;1760:730&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16567052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson MM, Turner SM, Hellerstein MK, Hamilton KL, Miller BF. Long-term synthesis rates of skeletal muscle DNA and protein are higher during aerobic training in older humans than in sedentary young subjects but are not altered by protein supplementation. FASEB J. 2011;25:3240&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3157680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21613572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy CH, Shankaran M, Churchward-Venne TA, Mitchell CJ, Kolar NM, Burke LM, Hawley JA, Kassis A, Karagounis LG, Li K et al. Effect of resistance training and protein intake pattern on myofibrillar protein synthesis and proteome kinetics in older men in energy restriction. J Physiol. 2018;596:2091&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5983154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29532476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasiakos SM. Exercise and amino acid anabolic cell signaling and the regulation of skeletal muscle mass. Nutrients. 2012;4:740&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3407992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22852061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margolis LM, Rivas DA, Berrone M, Ezzyat Y, Young AJ, McClung JP, Fielding RA, Pasiakos SM. Prolonged calorie restriction downregulates skeletal muscle mTORC1 signaling independent of dietary protein intake and associated microRNA expression. Front Physiol. 2016;7:445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5050214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27761114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atherton PJ, Etheridge T, Watt PW, Wilkinson D, Selby A, Rankin D, Smith K, Rennie MJ. Muscle full effect after oral protein: time-dependent concordance and discordance between human muscle protein synthesis and mTORC1 signaling. Am J Clin Nutr. 2010;92:1080&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20844073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Y, Tymen SD, Chen D, Fang ZJ, Zhao Y, Dragas D, Dai Y, Marucha PT, Zhou X. MicroRNA-99 family targets AKT/mTOR signaling pathway in dermal wound healing. PloS One. 2013;8:e64434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3665798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23724047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zacharewicz E, Della&#xa0;Gatta P, Reynolds J, Garnham A, Crowley T, Russell AP, Lamon S. Identification of microRNAs linked to regulators of muscle protein synthesis and regeneration in young and old skeletal muscle. PloS One. 2014;9:e114009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4252069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25460913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waterlow JC, Garlick PJ, Millward DJ. Protein Turnover in Mammalian Tissues and in the Whole Body. New York: Elsevier North-Holland; 1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim I-Y, Schutzler S, Schrader A, Spencer HJ, Azhar G, Ferrando AA, Wolfe RR. The anabolic response to a meal containing different amounts of protein is not limited by the maximal stimulation of protein synthesis in healthy young adults. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2016;310:E73&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4675798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26530155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>