<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40296814</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6519</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current opinion in clinical nutrition and metabolic care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sarcopenic obesity and weight loss-induced muscle mass loss.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>339</StartPage><EndPage>350</EndPage><MedlinePgn>339-350</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MCO.0000000000001131</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Sarcopenic obesity is a clinical condition characterized by the coexistence of excess adiposity and impaired muscle function, associated with heightened cardiometabolic risk and frailty. The emergence of new incretin-based obesity management medications (OMMs), which allow unprecedented weight loss, has raised concerns regarding weight loss-induced fat-free mass (FFM) reduction, including skeletal muscle mass (SMM). This review examines recent findings on the prevalence, diagnosis, and implications of sarcopenic obesity, explores the effects of weight-loss interventions on body composition and their impact on health, and discusses strategies to preserve muscle mass.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Weight loss induced by incretin-based OMMs results in a variable but significant reduction in FFM. The extent to which this loss affects SMM and function remains uncertain. Nutritional strategies, particularly adequate protein intake, and structured exercise interventions, especially resistance training, play a key role in mitigating FFM loss. Digital health interventions and telemedicine-based exercise programs offer promising approaches for maintaining muscle health during weight loss.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The clinical significance of FFM loss during weight reduction remains debated. Future research should refine sarcopenic obesity diagnostic criteria, assess the long-term impact of FFM/SMM reduction during intentional weight loss, and evaluate interventions that optimize body composition while preserving functional health.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caturano</LastName><ForeName>Alfredo</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Sciences and Promotion of the Quality of Life, San Raffaele Roma University, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amaro</LastName><ForeName>Anastassia</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Endocrinology, Diabetes and Metabolism, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berra</LastName><ForeName>Cesare C</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology and Metabolic Diseases, IRCCS MultiMedica, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Conte</LastName><ForeName>Caterina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Sciences and Promotion of the Quality of Life, San Raffaele Roma University, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology and Metabolic Diseases, IRCCS MultiMedica, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9804399</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1363-1950</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055948" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sarcopenia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="Y">Obesity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015431" MajorTopicYN="Y">Weight Loss</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GLP-1 receptor agonists</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fat-free mass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sarcopenic obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">weight loss</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>
<i>C.C. received speaker's honoraria from Therascience SAM, NewPenta srl, and Novo Nordisk, and speaker's and consultancy fees from Eli Lilly, outside the submitted work. A.A. has received grant support and consultant fees from NovoNordisk, grant support from Fractyl Laboratories, and is a steering committee member of Oxford Medical Products, outside the submitted work. For the remaining authors none were declared.</i>
</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40296814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12147736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCO.0000000000001131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00075197-990000000-00215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Neeland IJ, Linge J, Birkenfeld AL. Changes in lean body mass with glucagon-like peptide-1-based therapies and mitigation strategies. Diabetes Obes Metab 2024; 26: (Suppl 4): 16&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38937282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sylivris A, Mesinovic J, Scott D, Jansons P. Body composition changes at 12&#x200a;months following different surgical weight loss interventions in adults with obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized control trials. Obes Rev 2022; 23:e13442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9286475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35257480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conte C, Hall KD, Klein S. Is weight loss-induced muscle mass loss clinically relevant? JAMA 2024; 332:9&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38829659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prado CM, Phillips SM, Gonzalez MC, Heymsfield SB. Muscle matters: the effects of medically induced weight loss on skeletal muscle. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol 2024; 12:785&#x2013;787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39265590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linge J, Birkenfeld AL, Neeland IJ. Muscle mass and glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists: adaptive or maladaptive response to weight loss? Circulation 2024; 150:1288&#x2013;1298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39401279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinsley GM, Heymsfield SB. Fundamental body composition principles provide context for fat-free and skeletal muscle loss with GLP-1 RA treatments. J Endocr Soc 2024; 8:bvae164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11450469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39372917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirk B, Cawthon PM, Arai H, et al. The conceptual definition of sarcopenia: Delphi Consensus from the Global Leadership Initiative in Sarcopenia (GLIS). Age Ageing 2024; 53:afae052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10960072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38520141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voulgaridou G, Tyrovolas S, Detopoulou P, et al. Diagnostic criteria and measurement techniques of sarcopenia: a critical evaluation of the up-to-date evidence. Nutrients 2024; 16:436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10856900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38337720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prado CM, Batsis JA, Donini LM, et al. Sarcopenic obesity in older adults: a clinical overview. Nat Rev Endocrinol 2024; 20:261&#x2013;277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38321142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gengxin Y, Xuehan M, Xinyu W, et al. Association between sarcopenic obesity and risk of frailty in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Age Ageing 2025; 54:afae286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39775783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veronese N, Ragusa FS, Pegreffi F, et al. Sarcopenic obesity and health outcomes: an umbrella review of systematic reviews with meta-analysis. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 2024; 15:1264&#x2013;1274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11294015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38897937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirzai S, Carbone S, Batsis JA, et al. Sarcopenic obesity and cardiovascular disease: an overlooked but high-risk syndrome. Curr Obes Rep 2024; 13:532&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11306598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38753289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benz E, Pinel A, Guillet C, et al. Sarcopenia and sarcopenic obesity and mortality among older people. JAMA Netw Open 2024; 7:e243604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10964118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38526491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gortan Cappellari G, Semolic A, Zanetti M, et al. Sarcopenic obesity in free-living older adults detected by the ESPEN-EASO consensus diagnostic algorithm: validation in an Italian cohort and predictive value of insulin resistance and altered plasma ghrelin profile. Metabolism 2023; 145:155595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37245728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donini LM, Busetto L, Bischoff SC, et al. Definition and diagnostic criteria for sarcopenic obesity: ESPEN and EASO Consensus Statement. Obes Facts 2022; 15:321&#x2013;335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9210010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35196654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott D, Blyth F, Naganathan V, et al. Sarcopenia prevalence and functional outcomes in older men with obesity: comparing the use of the EWGSOP2 sarcopenia versus ESPEN-EASO sarcopenic obesity consensus definitions. Clin Nutr 2023; 42:1610&#x2013;1618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37481869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi S, Chon J, Yoo MC, et al. The impact of the physical activity level on sarcopenic obesity in community-dwelling older adults. Healthcare (Basel) 2024; 12:349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10855481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38338234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danielewicz AL, Marra A, Tringali G, et al. Analysis of sarcopenic obesity prevalence and diagnostic agreement according to the 2022 ESPEN and EASO Consensus in hospitalized older adults with severe obesity. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2024; 15:1366229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11222587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38966224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moll H, Frey E, Gerber P, et al. GLP-1 receptor agonists for weight reduction in people living with obesity but without diabetes: a living benefit-harm modelling study. EClinicalMedicine 2024; 73:102661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11154119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38846069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe JH, Kwon J, Nan B, Reikes A. Trends in glucagon-like peptide 1 receptor agonist use, 2014 to 2022. J Am Pharm Assoc 2024; 64:133&#x2013;138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37821008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymsfield SB. Advances in body composition: a 100-year journey. Int J Obes (Lond) 2025; 49:177&#x2013;181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11805704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38643327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymsfield SB, Brown J, Ramirez S, et al. Are lean body mass and fat-free mass the same or different body components? A critical perspective. Adv Nutr 2024; 15:100335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11625996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39510253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez C, Mota JD, Palmer TB, et al. Skeletal muscle estimation: a review of techniques and their applications. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging 2024; 44:261&#x2013;284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38426639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Bahat G, Bauer J, et al. Sarcopenia: revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing 2019; 48:16&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6322506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30312372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson J, Grimsgaard S, Strand BH, et al. Comparing associations of handgrip strength and chair stand performance with all-cause mortality-implications for defining probable sarcopenia: the Tromso Study. BMC Med 2023; 21:451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10659040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37981689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson J, Strand BH, Morseth B, et al. Differences in sarcopenia prevalence between upper-body and lower-body based EWGSOP2 muscle strength criteria: the Tromso study. BMC Geriatr 2020; 20:461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7654146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belfield AE, Wilkinson TJ, Henson J, et al. Sarcopenia prevalence using handgrip strength or chair stand performance in adults living with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Age Ageing 2024; 53:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11070724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38706394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira FT, Cai Y, Gonzalez MC, et al. Poor muscle quality: a hidden and detrimental health condition in obesity. Rev Endocr Metab Disord 2025; doi: 10.1007/s11154-025-09941-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39833502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xourafa G, Korbmacher M, Roden M. Inter-organ crosstalk during development and progression of type 2 diabetes mellitus. Nat Rev Endocrinol 2024; 20:27&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37845351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan Z, Stephan BCM, Donini LM, et al. Exploring the association between sarcopenic obesity and cardiovascular risk: a summary of findings from longitudinal studies and potential mechanisms. Proc Nutr Soc 2024; 1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39552359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moiz A, Filion KB, Toutounchi H, et al. Efficacy and safety of glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists for weight loss among adults without diabetes: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Ann Intern Med 2025; 178:199&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39761578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubin RL, Heymsfield SB, Ravussin E, Greenway FL. Glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonist-based agents and weight loss composition: filling the gaps. Diabetes Obes Metab 2024; 26:5503&#x2013;5518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39344838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao R, Lin C, Cai X, et al. Characterizing body composition modifying effects of a glucagon-like peptide 1 receptor-based agonist: a meta-analysis. Diabetes Obes Metab 2025; 27:259&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39431379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karakasis P, Patoulias D, Fragakis N, Mantzoros CS. Effect of glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists and co-agonists on body composition: systematic review and network meta-analysis. Metabolism 2025; 164:156113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39719170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Look M, Dunn JP, Kushner RF, et al. Body composition changes during weight reduction with tirzepatide in the SURMOUNT-1 study of adults with obesity or overweight. Diabetes Obes Metab 2025; 27:2720&#x2013;2729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11965027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39996356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beavers KM, Avery AE, Shankaran M, et al. Application of the D(3) -creatine muscle mass assessment tool to a geriatric weight loss trial: a pilot study. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 2023; 14:2350&#x2013;2358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10570063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37668075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, He L, Han S, et al. Sex differences in the efficacy of glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists for weight reduction: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Diabetes 2025; 17:e70063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11880690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40040445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaston TB, Dixon JB, O&#x2019;Brien PE. Changes in fat-free mass during significant weight loss: a systematic review. Int J Obes (Lond) 2007; 31:743&#x2013;750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17075583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymsfield SB, Yang S, McCarthy C, et al. Proportion of caloric restriction-induced weight loss as skeletal muscle. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2024; 32:32&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10872987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37807154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymsfield SB, Gonzalez MC, Shen W, et al. Weight loss composition is one-fourth fat-free mass: a critical review and critique of this widely cited rule. Obes Rev 2014; 15:310&#x2013;321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3970209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24447775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okobi OE, Khoury P, De la Vega RJ, et al. Impact of weight loss on testosterone levels: a review of BMI and testosterone. Cureus 2024; 16:e76139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11745839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39840189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiggs AG, Chandler JK, Aktas A, et al. The effects of diet and exercise on endogenous estrogens and subsequent breast cancer risk in postmenopausal women. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2021; 12:732255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8489575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34616366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soto Sauza KA, Ryan KK. FGF21 mediating the sex-dependent response to dietary macronutrients. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2024; 109:e1689&#x2013;e1696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11319005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38801670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zibellini J, Seimon RV, Lee CM, et al. Effect of diet-induced weight loss on muscle strength in adults with overweight or obesity - a systematic review and meta-analysis of clinical trials. Obes Rev 2016; 17:647&#x2013;663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27126087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibacache-Saavedra P, Martinez-Rosales E, Jerez-Mayorga D, et al. Effects of bariatric surgery on muscle strength and quality: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Obes Rev 2024; 25:e13790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38859617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crispim Carvalho NN, Martins VJB, Filho JM, et al. Effects of preoperative sarcopenia-related parameters on the musculoskeletal and metabolic outcomes after bariatric surgery: a one-year longitudinal study in females. Sci Rep 2023; 13:13373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10435473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37591922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gudzune KA, Stefanski A, Cao D, et al. Association between weight reduction achieved with tirzepatide and quality of life in adults with obesity: results from the SURMOUNT-1 study. Diabetes Obes Metab 2025; 27:539&#x2013;550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11701187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39497468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bliddal H, Bays H, Czernichow S, et al. Once-weekly semaglutide in persons with obesity and knee osteoarthritis. N Engl J Med 2024; 391:1573&#x2013;1583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39476339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosiborod MN, Abildstrom SZ, Borlaug BA, et al. Semaglutide in patients with heart failure with preserved ejection fraction and obesity. N Engl J Med 2023; 389:1069&#x2013;1084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37622681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer M, Zile MR, Kramer CM, et al. Tirzepatide for heart failure with preserved ejection fraction and obesity. N Engl J Med 2025; 392:427&#x2013;437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39555826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kosiborod MN, Verma S, Borlaug BA, et al. Effects of semaglutide on symptoms, function, and quality of life in patients with heart failure with preserved ejection fraction and obesity: a prespecified analysis of the STEP-HFpEF Trial. Circulation 2024; 149:204&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10782938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37952180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czernichow S, Rassy N, Carette C, et al. Nutritional and functional outcomes in trials of nutrient-stimulated hormone-based therapy: a systematic mapping review. Obes Rev 2025; e13890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11964801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39866032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen MC, Yoshino M, Smith GI, et al. Effect of weight loss on skeletal muscle bioactive lipids in people with obesity and Type 2 diabetes. Diabetes 2024; 73:2055&#x2013;2064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11579410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39264820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey A, Patel KV, Segar MW, et al. Effect of liraglutide on thigh muscle fat and muscle composition in adults with overweight or obesity: results from a randomized clinical trial. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 2024; 15:1072&#x2013;1083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11154779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38561962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Old VJ, Davies MJ, Papamargaritis D, et al. The effects of glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonists on mitochondrial function within skeletal muscle: a systematic review. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 2025; 16:e13677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11735953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39815782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giangregorio LM, Alexiuk MR, Tangri N, et al. Among people on osteoporosis medication, loss of appendicular or total body lean mass is an independent risk factor for hip and major osteoporotic fractures. Osteoporos Int 2024; 35:2025&#x2013;2035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39320415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bettis T, Kim BJ, Hamrick MW. Impact of muscle atrophy on bone metabolism and bone strength: implications for muscle-bone crosstalk with aging and disuse. Osteoporos Int 2018; 29:1713&#x2013;1720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7861141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29777277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardozo CP, Graham ZA. Muscle-bone interactions: movement in the field of mechano-humoral coupling of muscle and bone. Ann N Y Acad Sci 2017; 1402:10&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28763828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tagliaferri C, Wittrant Y, Davicco MJ, et al. Muscle and bone, two interconnected tissues. Ageing Res Rev 2015; 21:55&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25804855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawao N, Kaji H. Interactions between muscle tissues and bone metabolism. J Cell Biochem 2015; 116:687&#x2013;695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25521430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paccou J, Compston JE. Bone health in adults with obesity before and after interventions to promote weight loss. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol 2024; 12:748&#x2013;760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39053479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv F, Cai X, Lin C, et al. Effects of semaglutide and tirzepatide on bone metabolism in Type 2 diabetic mice. Pharmaceuticals (Basel) 2024; 17:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11728704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39770498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picoli CC, Tsibulnikov S, Ho M, et al. Vertical sleeve gastrectomy and semaglutide have distinct effects on skeletal health and heart function in obese male mice. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab 2025; 328:E555&#x2013;E566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12121371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40072928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Choi SA, Gu MS, et al. Effects of glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor agonist on bone mineral density and bone turnover markers: a meta-analysis. Diabetes Metab Res Rev 2024; 40:e3843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39311048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locatelli JC, Costa JG, Haynes A, et al. Incretin-based weight loss pharmacotherapy: can resistance exercise optimize changes in body composition? Diabetes Care 2024; 47:1718&#x2013;1730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38687506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Axelrod CL, Dantas WS, Kirwan JP. Sarcopenic obesity: emerging mechanisms and therapeutic potential. Metabolism 2023; 146:155639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11448314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37380015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozzetti F. Age-related and cancer-related sarcopenia: is there a difference? Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care 2024; 27:410&#x2013;418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38488242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gross DC, Cheever CR, Batsis JA. Understanding the development of sarcopenic obesity. Expert Rev Endocrinol Metab 2023; 18:469&#x2013;488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10842411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37840295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drucker DJ. Efficacy and safety of GLP-1 medicines for Type 2 diabetes and obesity. Diabetes Care 2024; 47:1873&#x2013;1888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38843460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tahrani AA, Morton J. Benefits of weight loss of 10% or more in patients with overweight or obesity: a review. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2022; 30:802&#x2013;840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35333446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodpaster BH, Park SW, Harris TB, et al. The loss of skeletal muscle strength, mass, and quality in older adults: the health, aging and body composition study. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 2006; 61:1059&#x2013;1064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17077199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss EP, Jordan RC, Frese EM, et al. Effects of Weight Loss on Lean Mass, Strength, Bone, and Aerobic Capacity. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2017; 49:206&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5161655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27580151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues PS, Mendonca FM, Neves JS, et al. Effects of bariatric surgery on sarcopenic obesity outcomes: a one-year prospective study in middle-aged women. Obes Surg 2024; 34:1674&#x2013;1683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38523172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zambon Azevedo V, Bel Lassen P, Aron-Wisnewsky J, et al. Metabolic and hepatic phenotypes in sarcopenic obesity and impact of bariatric surgery. Clin Nutr 2024; 43:254&#x2013;264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39536396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchai S, Andersen LF, Hopstock LA, Hjartaker A. Body mass index, waist circumference and prefrailty/frailty: the Tromso study. BMJ Open 2023; 13:e065707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9896186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36690391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchai S, Andersen LF, Johansson J, et al. Dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry derived adiposity measures and pre-frailty/frailty among Norwegian adults: the Tromso Study. J Nutr Health Aging 2023; 27:403&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37357322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A, Buckholz A, Kumar S, Newberry C. Implications of protein and sarcopenia in the prognosis, treatment, and management of metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease (MASLD). Nutrients 2024; 16:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10933907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38474786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobbie LJ, Coelho C, Crane J, McGowan B. Clinical evaluation of patients living with obesity. Intern Emerg Med 2023; 18:1273&#x2013;1285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10412477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37119384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavras A, Batsis JA. Medical weight loss in older persons with obesity. Clin Obes 2024; 14:e12684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11570349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38924367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wadden TA, Chao AM, Moore M, et al. The role of lifestyle modification with second-generation antiobesity medications: comparisons, questions, and clinical opportunities. Curr Obes Rep 2023; 12:453&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10748770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38041774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinel A, Guillet C, Capel F, et al. Identification of factors associated with sarcopenic obesity development: literature review and expert panel voting. Clin Nutr 2024; 43:1414&#x2013;1424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38701709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez PJ, Zhang V, Gratzl S, et al. Discontinuation and reinitiation of dual-labeled GLP-1 receptor agonists among US adults with overweight or obesity. JAMA Netw Open 2025; 8:e2457349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11786232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39888616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanaya N, Janusaite M, Dalamaga M, Magkos F. The physiological effects of weight-cycling: a review of current evidence. Curr Obes Rep 2024; 13:35&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38172475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, He W, Yang G, et al. The impact of weight cycling on health and obesity. Metabolites 2024; 14:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11205792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38921478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yates T, Biddle GJH, Henson J, et al. Impact of weight loss and weight gain trajectories on body composition in a population at high risk of type 2 diabetes: a prospective cohort analysis. Diabetes Obes Metab 2024; 26:1008&#x2013;1015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38093678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosy-Westphal A, Kahlhofer J, Lagerpusch M, et al. Deep body composition phenotyping during weight cycling: relevance to metabolic efficiency and metabolic risk. Obes Rev 2015; 16: (Suppl 1): 36&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25614202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turicchi J, O&#x2019;Driscoll R, Finlayson G, et al. Associations between the rate, amount, and composition of weight loss as predictors of spontaneous weight regain in adults achieving clinically significant weight loss: a systematic review and meta-regression. Obes Rev 2019; 20:935&#x2013;946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30925026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mechanick JI, Butsch WS, Christensen SM, et al. Strategies for minimizing muscle loss during use of incretin-mimetic drugs for treatment of obesity. Obes Rev 2025; 26:e13841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11611443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39295512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokura Y, Ueshima J, Saino Y, Maeda K. Enhanced protein intake on maintaining muscle mass, strength, and physical function in adults with overweight/obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Nutr ESPEN 2024; 63:417&#x2013;426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39002131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trommelen J, van Lieshout GAA, Nyakayiru J, et al. The anabolic response to protein ingestion during recovery from exercise has no upper limit in magnitude and duration in vivo in humans. Cell Rep Med 2023; 4:101324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10772463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38118410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchward-Venne TA, Pinckaers PJM, Smeets JSJ, et al. Dose-response effects of dietary protein on muscle protein synthesis during recovery from endurance exercise in young men: a double-blind randomized trial. Am J Clin Nutr 2020; 112:303&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7398777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32359142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DR, Robinson MJ, Fry JL, et al. Ingested protein dose response of muscle and albumin protein synthesis after resistance exercise in young men. Am J Clin Nutr 2009; 89:161&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19056590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witard OC, Jackman SR, Breen L, et al. Myofibrillar muscle protein synthesis rates subsequent to a meal in response to increasing doses of whey protein at rest and after resistance exercise. Am J Clin Nutr 2014; 99:86&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24257722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith GI, Yoshino J, Kelly SC, et al. High-protein intake during weight loss therapy eliminates the weight-loss-induced improvement in insulin action in obese postmenopausal women. Cell Rep 2016; 17:849&#x2013;861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5113728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27732859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batsis JA, Batchek DJ, Petersen CL, et al. Protein supplementation may dampen positive effects of exercise on glucose homeostasis: a pilot weight loss intervention. Nutrients 2023; 15:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10707998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38068805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James E, Kelsey RJ, Sargeant JA, et al. Nutritional supplementation to preserve healthy lean mass and function during periods of pharmacological and nonpharmacological-induced weight loss: protocol for a systematic review and meta-analysis. Health Sci Rep 2024; 7:e70219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11618885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39640031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Zhou H, Gong Y, et al. Clinical outcome changes in sarcopenic obesity: a meta-analysis of exercise training methods. BMC Geriatr 2025; 25:33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11734427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39815241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva Goncalves L, Santos Lopes da Silva L, Rodrigues Benjamim CJ, et al. The effects of different exercise training types on body composition and physical performance in older adults with sarcopenic obesity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Nutr Health Aging 2023; 27:1076&#x2013;1090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37997730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beals JW, Kayser BD, Smith GI, et al. Dietary weight loss-induced improvements in metabolic function are enhanced by exercise in people with obesity and prediabetes. Nat Metab 2023; 5:1221&#x2013;1235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10515726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37365374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serra-Prat M, Terradellas M, Lorenzo I, et al. Effectiveness of a weight-loss intervention in preventing frailty and functional decline in community-dwelling obese older people. A randomized controlled trial. J Frailty Aging 2022; 11:91&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35122096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendes C, Carvalho M, Bravo J, et al. Exercise interventions for the prevention of sarcopenia after bariatric surgery: a systematic review. J Sci Sport Exerc 2024; doi: 10.1007/s42978-024-00311-x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen SBK, Blond MB, Sandsdal RM, et al. Healthy weight loss maintenance with exercise, GLP-1 receptor agonist, or both combined followed by one year without treatment: a posttreatment analysis of a randomised placebo-controlled trial. EClinicalMedicine 2024; 69:102475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10965408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38544798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilsson MI, Xhuti D, de Maat NM, et al. Obesity and metabolic disease impair the anabolic response to protein supplementation and resistance exercise: a retrospective Analysis of a randomized clinical trial with implications for aging, sarcopenic obesity, and weight management. Nutrients 2024; 16:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11677392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39771028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian H, Li H, Zhang X, et al. Nonpharmacological treatment strategies for anthropometric, physical capacity and physiological indicators among sarcopenic obesity patients: a systematic review of rigorous randomized controlled trials. Age Ageing 2024; 53:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39709591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Protano C, De Giorgi A, Valeriani F, et al. Can digital technologies be useful for weight loss in individuals with overweight or obesity? A systematic review. Healthcare (Basel) 2024; 12:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10970199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38540634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spangler HB, Lynch DH, Gross DC, et al. Changes in weight or body composition by frailty status: a pilot study. J Nutr Gerontol Geriatr 2024; 43:83&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11213668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38470401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood BS, Batchek DJ, Lynch DH, et al. Impact of EASO/ESPEN-defined sarcopenic obesity following a technology-based weight loss intervention. Calcif Tissue Int 2024; 114:60&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11193940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37758867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromer FD, Lodberg A, Eijken M, et al. The effect of anti-activin receptor Type IIA and Type IIB antibody on muscle, bone and blood in healthy and osteosarcopenic mice. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle 2025; 16:e13718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11780395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39887865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunn E, Jaiswal N, Gavin M, et al. Antibody blockade of activin type II receptors preserves skeletal muscle mass and enhances fat loss during GLP-1 receptor agonism. Mol Metab 2024; 80:101880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10832506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38218536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanbay M, Siriopol D, Copur S, et al. Effect of Bimagrumab on body composition: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Aging Clin Exp Res 2024; 36:185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11385021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39251484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold C. After obesity drugs&#x2019; success, companies rush to preserve skeletal muscle. Nat Biotechnol 2024; 42:351&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38443623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Yan S, Banicki M, et al. 118-OR: the apelin receptor agonist azelaprag increases weight loss in diet-induced obese mice on incretin agonists and restores body composition and muscle function to that of lean controls. Diabetes Care 2024; 73:118-OR.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>BioAge Labs I. Efficacy and safety of oral azelaprag plus once weekly tirzepatide compared with tirzepatide alone in participants with obesity aged 55 years and over (STRIDES). https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT06515418?cond=azelaprag&amp;rank=2. [Accessed 9 February 2025].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbin KD, Carnero EA, Allerton TD, et al. Glucagon-like peptide-1/glucagon receptor agonism associates with reduced metabolic adaptation and higher fat oxidation: a randomized trial. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2023; 31:350&#x2013;362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9881753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36695055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wewer Albrechtsen NJ, Holst JJ, Cherrington AD, et al. 100&#x200a;years of glucagon and 100 more. Diabetologia 2023; 66:1378&#x2013;1394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37367959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>