<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36995998</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2471-254X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Hepatology communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Hepatol Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>American College of Sports Medicine (ACSM) International Multidisciplinary Roundtable report on physical activity and nonalcoholic fatty liver disease.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0108</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/HC9.0000000000000108</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND AIMS">We present findings from the inaugural American College of Sports Medicine (ACSM) International Multidisciplinary Roundtable, which was convened to evaluate the evidence for physical activity as a means of preventing or modifying the course of NAFLD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="APPROACH AND RESULTS">A scoping review was conducted to map the scientific literature and identify key concepts, research gaps, and evidence available to inform clinical practice, policymaking, and research. The scientific evidence demonstrated regular physical activity is associated with decreased risk of NAFLD development. Low physical activity is associated with a greater risk for disease progression and extrahepatic cancer. During routine health care visits, all patients with NAFLD should be screened for and counseled about physical activity benefits, including reduction in liver fat and improvement in body composition, fitness, and quality of life. While most physical activity benefits occur without clinically significant weight loss, evidence remains limited regarding the association between physical activity and liver fibrosis. At least 150&#xa0;min/wk of moderate or 75&#xa0;min/wk of vigorous-intensity physical activity are recommended for all patients with NAFLD. If a formal exercise training program is prescribed, aerobic exercise with the addition of resistance training is preferred.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The panel found consistent and compelling evidence that regular physical activity plays an important role in preventing NAFLD and improving intermediate clinical outcomes. Health care, fitness, and public health professionals are strongly encouraged to disseminate the information in this report. Future research should prioritize determining optimal strategies for promoting physical activity among individuals at risk and in those already diagnosed with NAFLD.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of the American Association for the Study of Liver Diseases.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stine</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan G</ForeName><Initials>JG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3352-6928</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Department of Medicine, The Pennsylvania State University-Milton S. Hershey Medical Center, Hershey, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health Sciences, The Pennsylvania State University-College of Medicine, Hershey, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Long</LastName><ForeName>Michelle T</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6131-3981</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Gastroenterology, Evans Department of Medicine, Boston University School of Medicine, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Corey</LastName><ForeName>Kathleen E</ForeName><Initials>KE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2882-7264</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Department of Medicine, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sallis</LastName><ForeName>Robert E</ForeName><Initials>RE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine and Sports Medicine, Kaiser Permanente Medical Center, Fontana, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Allen</LastName><ForeName>Alina M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8393-8410</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Department of Medicine, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Armstrong</LastName><ForeName>Matthew J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3425-1161</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Liver Transplant Unit, Queen Elizabeth University Hospitals Birmingham and NIHR Birmingham BRC, Birmingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Conroy</LastName><ForeName>David E</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0204-4093</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, The Pennsylvania State University, University Park, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cuthbertson</LastName><ForeName>Daniel J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular and Metabolic Medicine, Institute of Life Course and Medical Sciences, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duarte-Rojo</LastName><ForeName>Andres</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Northwestern University, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hallsworth</LastName><ForeName>Kate</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1860-6970</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Newcastle NIHR Biomedical Research Centre and the Liver Unit, Newcastle Upon Tyne Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, Newcastle Upon Tyne, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hickman</LastName><ForeName>Ingrid J</ForeName><Initials>IJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3205-9165</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Dietetics, Princess Alexandra Hospital, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kappus</LastName><ForeName>Matthew R</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3365-5903</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Duke University, Durham, North Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keating</LastName><ForeName>Shelley E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5357-2721</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Human Movement and Nutrition Sciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pugh</LastName><ForeName>Christopher J A</ForeName><Initials>CJA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiff School of Sport &amp; Health Sciences, Cardiff Metropolitan University, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rotman</LastName><ForeName>Yaron</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7549-8216</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Liver &amp; Energy Metabolism Section, Liver Diseases Branch, National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simon</LastName><ForeName>Tracey G</ForeName><Initials>TG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Department of Medicine, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vilar-Gomez</LastName><ForeName>Eduardo</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1435-4013</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Indiana University School of Medicine, Indianapolis, Indiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wong</LastName><ForeName>Vincent Wai-Sun</ForeName><Initials>VW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2215-9410</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Therapeutics, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, Hong Kong.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schmitz</LastName><ForeName>Kathryn H</ForeName><Initials>KH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2400-2935</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health Sciences, The Pennsylvania State University-College of Medicine, Hershey, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Hepatol Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101695860</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2471-254X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014481" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United States</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D065626" MajorTopicYN="Y">Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013178" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sports Medicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Jonathan G. Stine received research funding from the NIH and also from Astra Zeneca, Galectin, Grifols Inc., Noom Inc., Novo Nordisk, and Zydus. Michelle T. Long works full-time for Novo Nordisk; however, at the time of the roundtable, she worked full-time for Boston University. David E. Conroy received research funding from the NIH, NSF, and AICR; consulting fees unrelated to this work from WW International Inc. and InsideTracker LLC. Daniel J. Cuthbertson received research funding from BMS, Novo Nordisk, and Astra Zeneca; consulting fees from Astra Zeneca and Ipsen; educational support from Perspectum. Alina M. Allen received research funding from Pfizer, Novo Nordisk, Target Pharma; consulting fees from Novo Nordisk. Matthew J. Armstrong received consulting fees from Novo Nordisk and Norgine. Vincent Wai-Sun Wong received consulting fees from AbbVie, Boehringer Ingelheim, Echosens, Gilead Sciences, Intercept, Inventiva, Novo Nordisk, Pfizer, Sagimet Biosciences, and TARGET PharmaSolutions; research funding from Gilead Sciences; co-founder of Illuminatio Medical Technology Limited. Yaron Rotman was supported by the Intramural Research Program of NIDDK; received research funding from Gilead Sciences. Shelley E. Keating received research funding from National Health and Medical Research Council (NHMRC; Early Career Fellowship 1122190), Diabetes Australia, Exercise and Sports Science Australia. The remaining authors have no conflicts to report.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36995998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10069861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HC9.0000000000000108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">02009842-202304010-00029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Le MH, Yeo YH, Li X, Li J, Zou B, Wu Y, et al. 2019 Global NAFLD prevalence: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;20:2809&#x2013;2817.e28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34890795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheemerla S, Balakrishnan M. Global epidemiology of chronic liver disease. Clin Liver Dis (Hoboken). 2021;17:365&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8177826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34136143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen AM, Therneau TM, Larson JJ, Coward A, Somers VK, Kamath PS. Nonalcoholic fatty liver disease incidence and impact on metabolic burden and death: a 20 year-community study. Hepatology. 2018;67:1726&#x2013;1736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5866219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28941364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parikh ND, Marrero WJ, Wang J, Steuer J, Tapper EB, Konerman M, et al. Projected increase in obesity and non-alcoholic-steatohepatitis-related liver transplantation waitlist additions in the United States. Hepatology. 2019;70:487&#x2013;495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28833326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loomba R, Lim JK, Patton H, El-Serag HB. AGA clinical practice update on screening and surveillance for hepatocellular carcinoma in patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: expert review. Gastroenterology. 2020;158:1822&#x2013;1830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8012107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32006545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caspersen CJ, Powell KE, Christenson GM. Physical activity, exercise, and physical fitness: definitions and distinctions for health-related research. Public Health Rep. 1985;100:126&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1424733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3920711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Association for the Study of the Liver (EASL); European Association for the Study of Diabetes (EASD); European Association for the Study of Obesity (EASO). EASL-EASD-EASO Clinical Practice Guidelines for the management of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. J Hepatol. 2016;64:1388&#x2013;1402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27062661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chalasani N, Younossi Z, Lavine JE, Charlton M, Cusi K, Rinella M, et al. The diagnosis and management of nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: practice guidance from the American Association for the Study of Liver Diseases. Hepatology. 2018;67:328&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28714183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anstee QM, Hallsworth K, Lynch N, Hauvespre A, Mansour E, Kozma S, et al. Real-world management of non-alcoholic steatohepatitis differs from clinical practice guideline recommendations and across regions. JHEP Rep. 2022;4:100411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8686034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34977520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stine JG, Soriano C, Schreibman I, Rivas G, Hummer B, Yoo E, et al. Breaking down barriers to physical activity in patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Dig Dis Sci. 2021;66:3604&#x2013;3611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10321307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33098023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine (ACSM)&#x2014;Exercise is Medicine (EIM). Being active when you have NAFLD. Accessed July 7 2022. https://www.exerciseismedicine.org/assets/page_documents/EIM_Rx%20for%20Health_NAFLD.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buzzetti E, Pinzani M, Tsochatzis EA. The multiple-hit pathogenesis of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD). Metabolism. 2016;65:1038&#x2013;1048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26823198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes A, Dahmus J, Rivas G, Hummer B, Chen See JR, Wright JR, et al. Exercise training reverses gut dysbiosis in patients with biopsy-proven nonalcoholic steatohepatitis: a proof of concept study. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;19:1723&#x2013;1725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9067391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32882426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piguet AC, Guarino M, Potaczek DP, Garn H, Dufour JF. Hepatic gene expression in mouse models of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease after acute exercise. Hepatol Res. 2019;49:637&#x2013;652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30811073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melo L, Bilici M, Hagar A, Klaunig JE. The effect of endurance training on non-alcoholic fatty liver disease in mice. Physiol Rep. 2021;9:e14926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8329433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34342164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babu AF, Csader S, M&#xe4;nnist&#xf6; V, Tauriainen MM, Pentik&#xe4;inen H, Savonen K, et al. Effects of exercise on NAFLD using non-targeted metabolomics in adipose tissue, plasma, urine, and stool. Sci Rep. 2022;12:6485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9019539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35444259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorp A, Stine JG. Exercise as medicine: the impact of exercise training on nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Curr Hepatol Rep. 2020;19:402&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7987125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33767944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao H. Adipocytokines in obesity and metabolic disease. J Endocrinol. 2014;220:T47&#x2013;T59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3887367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24403378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giby VG, Ajith TA. Role of adipokines and peroxisome proliferator-activated receptors in nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. World J Hepatol. 2014;6:570&#x2013;579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4163740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25232450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashida R, Kawaguchi T, Bekki M, Omoto M, Matsuse H, Nago T, et al. Aerobic vs. resistance exercise in non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: a systematic review. J Hepatol. 2017;66:142&#x2013;152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27639843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diniz TA, de Lima Junior EA, Teixeira AA, Biondo LA, da Rocha LAF, Valad&#xe3;o IC, et al. Aerobic training improves NAFLD markers and insulin resistance through AMPK-PPAR-&#x3b1; signaling in obese mice. Life Sci. 2020;266:118868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33310034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi X, Yin H, Li J, Huang C, Chen Y, Chen Z, et al. Circulating branch chain amino acids and improvement in liver fat content in response to exercise interventions in NAFLD. Sci Rep. 2021;11:13415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8238945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34183740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng R, Wang L, Le S, Yang Y, Zhao C, Zhang X, et al. A randomized controlled trial for response of microbiome network to exercise and diet intervention in patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Nat Commun. 2022;13:2555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9091228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35538056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou J, Tripathi M, Sinha RA, Singh BK, Yen PM. Gut microbiota and their metabolites in the progression of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. Hepatoma Res. 2021;7:11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7116620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33490737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loomba R, Seguritan V, Li W, Long T, Klitgord N, Bhatt A, et al. Gut microbiome-based metagenomic signature for non-invasive detection of advanced fibrosis in human nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Cell Metab. 2017;25:1054&#x2013;1062.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5502730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28467925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D, Konyn P, Cholankeril G, Ahmed A. Physical activity is associated with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease and significant fibrosis measured by FibroScan. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2022;20:e1438&#x2013;e1455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34214678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D, Murag S, Cholankeril G, Cheung A, Harrison SA, Younossi ZM, et al. Physical activity, measured objectively, is associated with lower mortality in patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;19:1240&#x2013;1247.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32683103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zelber-Sagi S, Nitzan-Kaluski D, Goldsmith R, Webb M, Zvibel I, Goldiner I, et al. Role of leisure-time physical activity in nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: a population-based study. Hepatology. 2008;48:1791&#x2013;1798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18972405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider CV, Zandvakili I, Thaiss CA, Schneider KM. Physical activity is associated with reduced risk of liver disease in the prospective UK Biobank cohort. JHEP Rep. 2021;3:100263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8056270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33898961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnurr TM, Katz SF, Justesen JM, O&#x2019;Sullivan JW, Saliba-Gustafsson P, Assimes TL, et al. Interactions of physical activity, muscular fitness, adiposity, and genetic risk for NAFLD. Hepatol Commun. 2022;6:1516&#x2013;1526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9234625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35293152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwak JH, Jun DW, Lee SM, Cho YK, Lee KN, Lee HL, et al. Lifestyle predictors of obese and non-obese patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: a cross-sectional study. Clin Nutr. 2018;37:1550&#x2013;1557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28918170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sung K-C, Lee M-Y, Lee J-Y, Lee S-H, Kim Y-B, Song W-J, et al. Natural course of fatty liver in 36,195 South Korean adults. Sci Rep. 2019;9:9062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6629682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31308382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stine JG. Editorial: twenty minutes of moderate-to-vigorous physical activity a day keeps the NAFLD away. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2022;55:116&#x2013;117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34907567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsunoda K, Kitano N, Kai Y, Jindo T, Uchida K, Arao T. Dose-response relationships of accelerometer-measured sedentary behaviour and physical activity with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2021;54:1330&#x2013;1339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34633105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long MT, Pedley A, Massaro JM, Hoffmann U, Esliger DW, Vasan RS, et al. Hepatic steatosis is associated with lower levels of physical activity measured via accelerometry. Obesity (Silver Spring). 2015;23:1259&#x2013;1266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4446168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25959049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krasnoff JB, Painter PL, Wallace JP, Bass NM, Merriman RB. Health-related fitness and physical activity in patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Hepatology. 2008;47:1158&#x2013;1166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3096839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18266250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallsworth K, Thoma C, Moore S, Ploetz T, Anstee QM, Taylor R, et al. Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease is associated with higher levels of objectively measured sedentary behaviour and lower levels of physical activity than matched healthy controls. Frontline Gastroenterol. 2015;6:44&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4283712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25580206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowden Davies KA, Sprung VS, Norman JA, Thompson A, Mitchell KL, Harrold JOA, et al. Physical activity and sedentary time: association with metabolic health and liver fat. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51:1169&#x2013;1177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6542688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30694971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiJoseph K, Thorp A, Harrington A, Schmitz KH, Chinchilli VM, Stine JG. Physical activity and risk of hepatocellular carcinoma: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Dig Dis Sci. 2022. doi: 10.1007/s10620-022-07601-w[Epub ahead of print].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10620-022-07601-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35767138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore SC, Lee IM, Weiderpass E, Campbell PT, Sampson JN, Kitahara CM, et al. Association of Leisure-time physical activity with risk of 26 types of cancer in 1.44 million adults. JAMA Intern Med. 2016;176:816&#x2013;825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5812009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27183032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantovani A, Petracca G, Beatrice G, Csermely A, Tilg H, Byrne CD, et al. Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease and increased risk of incident extrahepatic cancers: a meta-analysis of observational cohort studies. Gut. 2022;71:778&#x2013;788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33685968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stine JGDK, Pattison Z, Harrington A, Chinchilli VM, Schmitz KH, Loomba R. Exercise training is associated with treatment response in liver fat content by magnetic resonance imaging independent of clinically significant body weight loss in patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Gastroenterol. 2022. doi: 10.14309/ajg.0000000000002098. [Epub ahead of print].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14309/ajg.0000000000002098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10287833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36705333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stine JG, Schreibman IR, Faust AJ, Dahmus J, Stern B, Soriano C, et al. NASHFit: a randomized controlled trial of an exercise training program to reduce clotting risk in patients with NASH. Hepatology. 2021;76:172&#x2013;185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9184303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34890063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vilar-Gomez E, Martinez-Perez Y, Calzadilla-Bertot L, Torres-Gonzalez A, Gra-Oramas B, Gonzalez-Fabian L, et al. Weight loss through lifestyle modification significantly reduces features of nonalcoholic steatohepatitis. Gastroenterology. 2015;149:367&#x2013;378.e5; quiz e14&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25865049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong VW, Chan RS, Wong GL, Cheung BH, Chu WC, Yeung DK, et al. Community-based lifestyle modification programme for non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: a randomized controlled trial. J Hepatol. 2013;59:536&#x2013;542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23623998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison SA, Fecht W, Brunt EM, Neuschwander-Tetri BA. Orlistat for overweight subjects with nonalcoholic steatohepatitis: a randomized, prospective trial. Hepatology. 2009;49:80&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19053049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babu AF, Csader S, Lok J, G&#xf3;mez-Gallego C, Hanhineva K, El-Nezami H, et al. Positive effects of exercise intervention without weight loss and dietary changes in NAFLD-related clinical parameters: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutrients. 2021;13:3135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8466505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34579012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker CJ, Martinez-Huenchullan SF, D&#x2019;Souza M, Xu Y, Li M, Bi Y, et al. Effect of exercise on hepatic steatosis: are benefits seen without dietary intervention? A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Diabetes. 2021;13:63&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32667128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battista F, Ermolao A, van Baak MA, Beaulieu K, Blundell JE, Busetto L, et al. Effect of exercise on cardiometabolic health of adults with overweight or obesity: Focus on blood pressure, insulin resistance, and intrahepatic fat&#x2014;a systematic review and meta-analysis. Obes Rev. 2021;22(suppl 4):e13269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8365642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33960110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hens W, Taeyman J, Cornelis J, Gielen J, Van Gaal L, Vissers D. The effect of lifestyle interventions on excess ectopic fat deposition measured by noninvasive techniques in overweight and obese adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Phys Act Health. 2016;13:671&#x2013;694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26694194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsagoni CN, Georgoulis M, Papatheodoridis GV, Panagiotakos DB, Kontogianni MD. Effects of lifestyle interventions on clinical characteristics of patients with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: a meta-analysis. Metabolism. 2017;68:119&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28183444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keating SE, Hackett DA, George J, Johnson NA. Exercise and non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Hepatol. 2012;57:157&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22414768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalafi M, Symonds ME. The impact of high intensity interval training on liver fat content in overweight or obese adults: a meta-analysis. Physiol Behav. 2021;236:113416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33823178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammad Rahimi GR, Attarzadeh, Hosseini SR. Effect of aerobic exercise alone or in conjunction with diet on liver function, insulin resistance and lipids in non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. Biol Res Nurs. 2022;24:259&#x2013;276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35130757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musso G, Cassader M, Rosina F, Gambino R. Impact of current treatments on liver disease, glucose metabolism and cardiovascular risk in non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD): a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised trials. Diabetologia. 2012;55:885&#x2013;904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22278337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orci LA, Gariani K, Oldani G, Delaune V, Morel P, Toso C. Exercise-based interventions for nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: a meta-analysis and meta-regression. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2016;14:1398&#x2013;1411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27155553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabag A, Barr L, Armour M, Armstrong A, Baker CJ, Twigg SM, et al. The effect of high-intensity interval training vs moderate-intensity continuous training on liver fat: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2022;107:862&#x2013;881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34724062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sargeant JA, Gray LJ, Bodicoat DH, Willis SA, Stensel DJ, Nimmo MA, et al. The effect of exercise training on intrahepatic triglyceride and hepatic insulin sensitivity: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Obes Rev. 2018;19:1446&#x2013;1459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30092609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smart NA, King N, McFarlane JR, Graham PL, Dieberg G. Effect of exercise training on liver function in adults who are overweight or exhibit fatty liver disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52:834&#x2013;843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6029644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27317790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez T, Vi&#xf1;uela M, Vidal C, Barrera F. Lifestyle changes in patients with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2022;17:e0263931.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8853532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35176096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golabi P, Locklear CT, Austin P, Afdhal S, Byrns M, Gerber L, et al. Effectiveness of exercise in hepatic fat mobilization in non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: systematic review. World J Gastroenterol. 2016;22:6318&#x2013;6327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4945989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27468220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stine JG, Munaganuru N, Barnard A, Wang JL, Kaulback K, Argo CK, et al. Change in MRI-PDFF and histologic response in patients with nonalcoholic steatohepatitis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;19:2274&#x2013;2283.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7914285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32882428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamaki N, Munaganuru N, Jung J, Yonan AQ, Loomba RR, Bettencourt R, et al. Clinical utility of 30% relative decline in MRI-PDFF in predicting fibrosis regression in non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. Gut. 2022;71:983&#x2013;990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8594562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33883248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Gorman P, Naimimohasses S, Monaghan A, Kennedy M, Melo AM, NF D, et al. Improvement in histological endpoints of MAFLD following a 12-week aerobic exercise intervention. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2020;52:1387&#x2013;1398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32717123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickman IJ, Jonsson JR, Prins JB, Ash S, Purdie DM, Clouston AD, et al. Modest weight loss and physical activity in overweight patients with chronic liver disease results in sustained improvements in alanine aminotransferase, fasting insulin, and quality of life. Gut. 2004;53:413&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1773957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14960526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckard C, Cole R, Lockwood J, Torres DM, Williams CD, Shaw JC, et al. Prospective histopathologic evaluation of lifestyle modification in nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: a randomized trial. Therap Adv Gastroenterol. 2013;6:249&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3667474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23814606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Promrat K, Kleiner DE, Niemeier HM, Jackvony E, Kearns M, Wands JR, et al. Randomized controlled trial testing the effects of weight loss on nonalcoholic steatohepatitis. Hepatology. 2010;51:121&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2799538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19827166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stine JG, Schmitz KH. Letter: proving the benefit of exercise intervention in non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2020;52:1424&#x2013;1425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33105976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon TG, Roelstraete B, Khalili H, Hagstr&#xf6;m H, Ludvigsson JF. Mortality in biopsy-confirmed nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: results from a nationwide cohort. Gut. 2021;70:1375&#x2013;1382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8185553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33037056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SB, Park GM, Lee JY, Lee BU, Park JH, Kim BG, et al. Association between non-alcoholic fatty liver disease and subclinical coronary atherosclerosis: an observational cohort study. J Hepatol. 2018;68:1018&#x2013;1024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29274406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green DJ, Jones H, Thijssen D, Cable NT, Atkinson G. Flow-mediated dilation and cardiovascular event prediction: does nitric oxide matter? Hypertension. 2011;57:363&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21263128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Paredes FJ, Hernandez Mesa G, Morales Arraez D, Marcelino Reyes R, Abrante B, Diaz-Flores F, et al. Contribution of cyclooxygenase end products and oxidative stress to intrahepatic endothelial dysfunction in early non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. PLoS One. 2016;11:e0156650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4882009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27227672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugh CJ, Spring VS, Kemp GJ, Richardson P, Shojaee-Moradie F, Umpleby AM, et al. Exercise training reverses endothelial dysfunction in nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2014;307:H1298&#x2013;H1306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25193471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugh CJ, Sprung VS, Jones H, Richardson P, Shojaee-Moradie F, Umpleby AM, et al. Exercise-induced improvements in liver fat and endothelial function are not sustained 12 months following cessation of exercise supervision in nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Int J Obes (Lond). 2016;40:1927&#x2013;1930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27439593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapmaz F, Uzman M, Basyigit S, Ozkan S, Yavuz B, Yeniova A, et al. Steatosis grade is the most important risk factor for development of endothelial dysfunction in NAFLD. Medicine (Baltimore). 2016;95:e3280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4998806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27057890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur ML, Sharma S, Kumar A, Bhatt SP, Luthra K, Guleria R, et al. Nonalcoholic fatty liver disease is associated with subclinical atherosclerosis independent of obesity and metabolic syndrome in Asian Indians. Atherosclerosis. 2012;223:507&#x2013;511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22748277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green DJ, Maiorana A, O&#x2019;Driscoll G, Taylor R. Effect of exercise training on endothelium-derived nitric oxide function in humans. J Physiol. 2004;561:1&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1665322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15375191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keating SE, Hackett DA, Parker HM, O&#x2019;Connor HT, Gerofi JA, Sainsbury A, et al. Effect of aerobic exercise training dose on liver fat and visceral adiposity. J Hepatol. 2015;63:174&#x2013;182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25863524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang HJ, He J, Pan LL, Ma ZM, Han CK, Chen CS, et al. Effects of moderate and vigorous exercise on nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Intern Med. 2016;176:1074&#x2013;1082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27379904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacchi E, Negri C, Targher G, Faccioli N, Lanza M, Zoppini G, et al. Both resistance training and aerobic training reduce hepatic fat content in type 2 diabetic subjects with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (the RAED2 Randomized Trial). Hepatology. 2013;58:1287&#x2013;1295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23504926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelbasset WK, Tantawy SA, Kamel DM, Alqahtani BA, Elnegamy TE, Soliman GS, et al. Effects of high-intensity interval and moderate-intensity continuous aerobic exercise on diabetic obese patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: a comparative randomized controlled trial. Medicine (Baltimore). 2020;99:e19471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7478706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32150108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuthbertson DJ, Shojaee-Moradie F, Sprung VS, Jones H, Pugh CJ, Richardson P, et al. Dissociation between exercise-induced reduction in liver fat and changes in hepatic and peripheral glucose homoeostasis in obese patients with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. Clin Sci (Lond). 2016;130:93&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26424731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez A, Valero-Breton M, Huerta-Salgado C, Achiardi O, Simon F, Cabello-Verrugio C. Impact of exercise training on the sarcopenia criteria in non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Transl Myol. 2021;31:9630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8056167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33709647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallsworth K, Fattakhova G, Hollingsworth KG, Thoma C, Moore S, Taylor R, et al. Resistance exercise reduces liver fat and its mediators in non-alcoholic fatty liver disease independent of weight loss. Gut. 2011;60:1278&#x2013;1283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3152868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21708823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houghton D, Thoma C, Hallsworth K, Cassidy S, Hardy T, Burt AD, et al. Exercise reduces liver lipids and visceral adiposity in patients with nonalcoholic steatohepatitis in a randomized controlled trial. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;15:96&#x2013;102.e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5196006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27521509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan S, Kirk EP, Mittendorfer B, Patterson BW, Klein S. Randomized trial of exercise effect on intrahepatic triglyceride content and lipid kinetics in nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Hepatology. 2012;55:1738&#x2013;1745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3337888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22213436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng S, Ge J, Zhao C, Le S, Yang Y, Ke D, et al. Effect of aerobic exercise and diet on liver fat in pre-diabetic patients with non-alcoholic-fatty-liver-disease: a randomized controlled trial. Sci Rep. 2017;7:15952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5698376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29162875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayiner M, Stepanova M, Pham H, Noor B, Walters M, Younossi ZM. Assessment of health utilities and quality of life in patients with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. BMJ Open Gastroenterol. 2016;3:e000106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5013331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27648297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Argo CK, Stine JG, Henry ZH, Lackner C, Patrie JT, Weltman AL, et al. Physical deconditioning is the common denominator in both obese and overweight subjects with nonalcoholic steatohepatitis. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2018;48:290&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7500226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29797529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clausen JSR, Marott JL, Holtermann A, Gyntelberg F, Jensen MT. Midlife cardiorespiratory fitness and the long-term risk of mortality: 46 years of follow-up. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2018;72:987&#x2013;995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30139444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser B, Burtscher M. Survival of the fittest: VO2max, a key predictor of longevity? Front Biosci. 2018;23:1505&#x2013;1516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29293447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams PT. Physical fitness and activity as separate heart disease risk factors: a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2001;33:754&#x2013;761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2821586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11323544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croci I, Coombes JS, Bucher Sandbakk S, Keating SE, Nauman J, Macdonald GA, et al. Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: prevalence and all-cause mortality according to sedentary behaviour and cardiorespiratory fitness. The HUNT Study. Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2019;62:127&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30796942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canada JM, Abbate A, Collen R, Billingsley H, Buckley LF, Carbone S, et al. Relation of hepatic fibrosis in nonalcoholic fatty liver disease to left ventricular diastolic function and exercise tolerance. Am J Cardiol. 2019;123:466&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6331258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30502049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golabi P, Otgonsuren M, Cable R, Felix S, Koenig A, Sayiner M, et al. Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) is associated with impairment of Health Related Quality of Life (HRQOL). Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2016;14:18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4746896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26860700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dan AA, Kallman JB, Wheeler A, Younoszai Z, Collantes R, Bondini S, et al. Health-related quality of life in patients with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2007;26:815&#x2013;820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17767465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raafs BM, Karssemeijer EGA, Van der Horst L, Aaronson JA, Olde Rikkert MGM, Kessels RPC. Physical exercise training improves quality of life in healthy older adults: a meta-analysis. J Aging Phys Act. 2020;28:81&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31629357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers VH, McVay MA, Brashear MM, Johannsen NM, Swift DL, Kramer K, et al. Exercise training and quality of life in individuals with type 2 diabetes: a randomized controlled trial. Diabetes Care 2013;36:1884&#x2013;1890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3687283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23404304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canadian Society for Exercise Physiology. Get Active Questionnaire; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig CL, Marshall AL, Sj&#xf6;str&#xf6;m M, Bauman AE, Booth ML, Ainsworth BE, et al. International physical activity questionnaire: 12-country reliability and validity. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35:1381&#x2013;1395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12900694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warburton DE, Jamnik VK, Bredin SS, McKenzie DC, Stone J, Shephard RJ, et al. Evidence-based risk assessment and recommendations for physical activity clearance: an introduction. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2011;36(suppl 1):S1&#x2013;S2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21800937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowen PG, Mankowski RT, Harper SA, Buford TW. Exercise is medicine as a vital sign: challenges and opportunities. Transl J Am Coll Sports Med. 2019;4:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6392189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30828640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallis R. Developing healthcare systems to support exercise: exercise as the fifth vital sign. Br J Sports Med. 2011;45:473&#x2013;474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21292925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office of National Drug Control Policy (ONDCP), Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA). Screening, Brief Intervention, and Referral to Treatment (SBIRT); 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Overcoming barriers to physical activity. 2022. Accessed July 7, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S, van Stralen MM, West R. The behaviour change wheel: a new method for characterising and designing behaviour change interventions. Implement Sci. 2011;6:42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3096582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21513547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buzzetti E, Linden A, Best LM, Madden AM, Roberts D, Chase TJG, et al. Lifestyle modifications for nonalcohol-related fatty liver disease: a network meta-analysis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2021;6:CD013156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8193812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34114650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora E, Babu AS, Vidhyasagar S, Maiya GA. Physical activity promotion program on physical activity and glycemic control in prediabetes. Crit Rev Phys Rehabil Med. 2018;30:181&#x2013;185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazarus JV, Kakalou C, Palayew A, Karamanidou C, Maramis C, Natsiavas P, et al. A Twitter discourse analysis of negative feelings and stigma related to NAFLD, NASH and obesity. Liver Int. 2021;41:2295&#x2013;2307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34022107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carol M, P&#xe9;rez-Guasch M, Sol&#xe0; E, Cervera M, Mart&#xed;nez S, Juanola A, et al. Stigmatization is common in patients with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease and correlates with quality of life. PLoS One. 2022;17:e0265153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8986095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35385510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallsworth K, Adams LA. Lifestyle modification in NAFLD/NASH: facts and figures. JHEP Rep. 2019;1:468&#x2013;479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7005657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32039399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Addo SF, Maiden K, Ehrenthal DB. Awareness of the 5 A&#x2019;s and motivational interviewing among community primary care providers. Del Med J. 2011;83:17&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21466014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vallabhan MK, Kong AS, Jimenez EY, Summers LC, DeBlieck CJ, Feldstein Ewing SW. Training primary care providers in the use of motivational interviewing for youth behavior change. Res Theory Nurs Pract. 2017;31:219&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5695044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28793946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzotti A, Caletti MT, Brodosi L, Di Domizio S, Forchielli ML, Petta S, et al. An internet-based approach for lifestyle changes in patients with NAFLD: Two-year effects on weight loss and surrogate markers. J Hepatol. 2018;69:1155&#x2013;1163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30290973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moscatiello S, Di Luzio R, Bugianesi E, Suppini A, Hickman IJ, Di Domizio S, et al. Cognitive-behavioral treatment of nonalcoholic Fatty liver disease: a propensity score-adjusted observational study. Obesity (Silver Spring). 2011;19:763&#x2013;770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20966900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montesi L, Caselli C, Centis E, Nuccitelli C, Moscatiello S, Suppini A, et al. Physical activity support or weight loss counseling for nonalcoholic fatty liver disease? World J Gastroenterol. 2014;20:10128&#x2013;10136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4123342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25110440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallsworth K, McPherson S, Anstee QM, Flynn D, Haigh L, Avery L. Digital intervention with lifestyle coach support to target dietary and physical activity behaviors of adults with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: systematic development process of VITALISE using intervention mapping. J Med Internet Res. 2021;23:e20491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7846439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33448929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Sousa D, Fogel A, Azevedo J, Padr&#xe3;o P. The effectiveness of web-based interventions to promote health behaviour change in adolescents: a systematic review. Nutrients. 2022;14:1258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8954163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35334915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamali T, Raasikh T, Bustamante G, Sisson A, Tandon P, Duarte-Rojo A, et al. Outcomes of exercise interventions in patients with advanced liver disease: a systematic review of randomized clinical trials. Am J Gastroenterol. 2022;117:1614&#x2013;1620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35973182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berzigotti A, Albillos A, Villanueva C, Genesc&#xe1; J, Ardevol A, August&#xed;n S, et al. Effects of an intensive lifestyle intervention program on portal hypertension in patients with cirrhosis and obesity: the SportDiet Study. Hepatology. 2017;65:1293&#x2013;1305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27997989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai JC, Dodge JL, Kappus MR, Wong R, Mohamad Y, Segev DL, et al. A multicenter pilot randomized clinical trial of a home-based exercise program for patients with cirrhosis: the Strength Training Intervention (STRIVE). Am J Gastroenterol. 2020;116:717&#x2013;722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8178511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33982941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte-Rojo A, Bloomer PM, Rogers RJ, Hassan MA, Dunn MA, Tevar AD, et al. Introducing EL-FIT (Exercise and Liver FITness): a smartphone app to prehabilitate and monitor liver transplant candidates. Liver Transpl. 2020;27:502&#x2013;512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10251157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33232547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faust A, Stine JG. Leveraging the coronavirus disease 2019 pandemic: is it time to consider incorporating mobile applications into standard clinical management of the liver transplantation patient? Liver Transpl. 2021;27:479&#x2013;481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8014121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33484229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mac&#xed;as-Rodr&#xed;guez RU, Ilarraza-Lomel&#xed; H, Ruiz-Marg&#xe1;in A, Ponce-de-Le&#xf3;n-Rosales S, Vargas-Vor&#xe1;ckov&#xe1; F, Garc&#xed;a-Flores O, et al. Changes in hepatic venous pressure gradient induced by physical exercise in cirrhosis: results of a pilot randomized open clinical trial. Clin Transl Gastroenterol. 2016;7:e180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5543482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27415618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zenith L, Meena N, Ramadi A, Yavari M, Harvey A, Carbonneau M, et al. Eight weeks of exercise training increases aerobic capacity and muscle mass and reduces fatigue in patients with cirrhosis. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2014;12:1920&#x2013;1926.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24768811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen HW, Ferrando A, White MG, Dennis RA, Xie J, Pauly M, et al. Home-based physical activity and diet intervention to improve physical function in advanced liver disease: a randomized pilot trial. Dig Dis Sci. 2020;65:3350&#x2013;3359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31907774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruger C, McNeely ML, Bailey RJ, Yavari M, Abraldes JG, Carbonneau M, et al. Home exercise training improves exercise capacity in cirrhosis patients: role of exercise adherence. Sci Rep. 2018;8:99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5758716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29311671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avery L, Exley C, McPherson S, Trenell MI, Anstee QM, Hallsworth K. Lifestyle behavior change in patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: a qualitative study of clinical practice. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;15:1968&#x2013;1971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28624648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson PD, Arena R, Riebe D, Pescatello LS. ACSM&#x2019;s new preparticipation health screening recommendations from ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription, ninth edition. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2013;12:215&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23851406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou BJ, Huang G, Wang W, Zhu LH, Deng YX, He YY, et al. Intervention effects of four exercise modalities on nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: a systematic review and Bayesian network meta-analysis. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2021;25:7687&#x2013;7697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34982430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh AK, Kaur N, Kaushal S, Tyagi R, Mathur D, Sivapuram MS, et al. Partitioning of radiological, stress and biochemical changes in pre-diabetic women subjected to Diabetic Yoga Protocol. Diabetes Metab Syndr. 2019;13:2705&#x2013;2713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31405697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keymasi Z, Sadeghi A, Pourrazi H. Effect of pilates training on hepatic fat content and liver enzymes in men with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. J Appl Health Stud Sport Physiol. 2017;4:49&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huber Y, Pfirrmann D, Gebhardt I, Labenz C, Gehrke N, Straub BK, et al. Improvement of non-invasive markers of NAFLD from an individualised, web-based exercise program. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2019;50:930&#x2013;939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31342533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motz V, Faust A, Dahmus J, Stern B, Soriano C, Stine JG. Utilization of a directly supervised telehealth-based exercise training program in patients with nonalcoholic steatohepatitis: feasibility study. JMIR Form Res. 2021;5:e30239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8408749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34402795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zelber-Sagi S, Buch A, Yeshua H, Vaisman N, Webb M, Harari G, et al. Effect of resistance training on non-alcoholic fatty-liver disease a randomized-clinical trial. World J Gastroenterol. 2014;20:4382&#x2013;4392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3989975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24764677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dulai PS, Singh S, Patel J, Soni M, Prokop LJ, Younossi Z, et al. Increased risk of mortality by fibrosis stage in nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: systematic review and meta-analysis. Hepatology. 2017;65:1557&#x2013;1565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5397356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28130788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Department of Health and Human Services. Food and Drug Administration. Noncirrhotic nonalcoholic steatohepatitis with liver fibrosis: developing drugs for treatment guidance for industry; 2018. Accessed July 7, 2022. https://www.fda.gov/media/119044/download.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>