<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40056334</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>12</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2161-3311</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current nutrition reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Nutr Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ketogenic Diet Intervention for Obesity Weight-Loss- A Narrative Review, Challenges, and Open Questions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>43</StartPage><MedlinePgn>43</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">43</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13668-025-00634-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The ketogenic diet (KD) has gained clinical attention for its potential benefits in weight loss and metabolic syndrome. By mimicking fasting through carbohydrate (CHO) restriction, KD shifts energy utilization to ketone bodies (KB) instead of glucose. Despite promising results, the effects on different weight loss indicators remain controversial, with challenges in monitoring adherence standards, optimal macronutrient composition, potential risks, and long-term sustainability. This article aims to review the different weight-loss outcomes of KD interventions for obesity, monitored by KB (adherence indication).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Current literature on KD interventions for obesity weight loss monitored by KB show reduction in different outcomes, including body weight, body mass index, waist circumference, visceral adipose tissue, fat mass, and body fat percentage. Minor decreases in lean body mass and skeletal muscle mass were noted without resistance training. Variability existed in adherence (KB markers), CHO intake (7-27% of daily energy), diet duration (28 days to 12 months), and follow-up frequency (weekly to biannual). KD, particularly accompanied by exercise, positively influenced appetite regulation. KD interventions improves weight-related outcomes in participants with obesity but presents challenges in lean body mass reduction without resistance training and adherence variability. Standardizing methodologies, refining interventions and suitability to sub-populations, setting KB markers, and defining clinical relevance are essential for optimizing KD effectiveness.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bachar</LastName><ForeName>Adina</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nutrition Department, Health Sciences Faculty, Ariel University, Ariel, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Birk</LastName><ForeName>Ruth</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5770-4277</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nutrition Department, Health Sciences Faculty, Ariel University, Ariel, Israel. ruthb@ariel.ac.il.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Nutr Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101587480</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2161-3311</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055423" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diet, Ketogenic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015431" MajorTopicYN="Y">Weight Loss</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="Y">Obesity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000178" MajorTopicYN="N">diet therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adherence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ketogenic diet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ketone bodies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lean body mass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Weight reduction</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Compliance with Ethical Standards. Ethical Statement: This article reviewed existing literature. It did not involve human or non-human participants, therefore obtaining ethical approval was not required. The article's publication is approved by all authors. Competing Interests: The authors declare no competing interests. Human and Animal Rights and Informed Consent: This article does not contain any studies with human or animal subjects performed by any of the authors.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40056334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11890254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13668-025-00634-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s13668-025-00634-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Li S, Du Y, Meireles C, Sharma K, Qi L, Castillo A, et al. Adherence to ketogenic diet in lifestyle interventions in adults with overweight or obesity and type 2 diabetes: a scoping review. Nutr Diabetes. 2023;13(1):16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41387-023-00246-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10502148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37709770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veneti S, Grammatikopoulou MG, Kintiraki E, Mintziori G, Goulis DG. Ketone Bodies in Diabetes Mellitus: Friend or Foe? Nutrients. 2023;15(20):4383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15204383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10609881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37892458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C, Wang M, Liang J, He G, Chen N. Ketogenic Diet Benefits to Weight Loss, Glycemic Control, and Lipid Profiles in Overweight Patients with Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus: A Meta-Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trails. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(16):10429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph191610429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9408028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36012064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Su X, Feng Y, Li R, Liao M, Fan L, et al. Ketogenic Diet and Multiple Health Outcomes: An Umbrella Review of Meta-Analysis. Nutrients. 2023;15(19):4161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15194161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10574428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37836444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowis K, Banga S. The Potential Health Benefits of the Ketogenic Diet: A Narrative Review. Nutrients. 2021;13(5):1654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13051654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8153354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34068325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firman CH, Mellor DD, Unwin D, Brown A. Does a Ketogenic Diet Have a Place Within Diabetes Clinical Practice? Review of Current Evidence and Controversies. Diabetes Ther Res Treat Educ Diabetes Relat Disord. 2024;15(1):77&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10786817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37966583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daria Go&#x142;&#x105;bek K, Regulska-Ilow B. Possible Nonneurological Health Benefits of Ketogenic Diet: Review of Scientific Reports over the Past Decade. Amirabdollahian F, editor. J Obes. 2022;7531518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9167021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35669612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Aamri KS, Alrawahi AH, Al Busaidi N, Al Githi MS, Al Jabri K, Al Balushi F, et al. The effect of low-carbohydrate ketogenic diet in the management of obesity compared with low caloric, low-fat diet. Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2022;49:522&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnesp.2022.02.110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35623861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu H, Bi D, Zhang Y, Kong C, Du J, Wu X, et al. Ketogenic diet for human diseases: the underlying mechanisms and potential for clinical implementations. Signal Transduct Target Ther. 2022;7(1):11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41392-021-00831-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8761750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35034957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dy&#x144;ka D, Kowalcze K, Ambrozkiewicz F, Paziewska A. Effect of the Ketogenic Diet on the Prophylaxis and Treatment of Diabetes Mellitus: A Review of the Meta-Analyses and Clinical Trials. Nutrients. 2023;15(3):500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15030500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9919384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36771207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi YJ, Jeon SM, Shin S. Impact of a Ketogenic Diet on Metabolic Parameters in Patients with Obesity or Overweight and with or without Type 2 Diabetes: A Meta-Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials. Nutrients. 2020;12(7):2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu12072005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7400909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32640608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Mancin L, Giacona MC, Bianco A, Caprio M. Effects of a ketogenic diet in overweight women with polycystic ovary syndrome. J Transl Med. 2020;18(1):104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-020-02277-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7045520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32103756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohorko N, &#x10c;erneli&#x10d;-Bizjak M, Poklar-Vatovec T, Grom G, Kenig S, Petelin A, et al. Weight loss, improved physical performance, cognitive function, eating behavior, and metabolic profile in a 12-week ketogenic diet in obese adults. Nutr Res. 2019;62:64&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nutres.2018.11.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30803508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valinejad A, Khodaei K. Does exercise during a ketogenic diet effectively alter appetite sensation, appetite-regulating hormones, and body composition? Exp Biol Med. 2022;247(21):1898&#x2013;906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15353702221113862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9742743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35920294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gershuni VM, Yan SL, Medici V. Nutritional Ketosis for Weight Management and Reversal of Metabolic Syndrome. Curr Nutr Rep. 2018;7(3):97&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13668-018-0235-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6472268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30128963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoli A, Bianco A, Moro T, Mota JF, Coelho-Ravagnani CDF. The Effects of Ketogenic Diet on Insulin Sensitivity and Weight Loss, Which Came First: The Chicken or the Egg? Nutrients. 2023;15(14):3120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15143120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10385501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37513538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luong TV, Pedersen MGB, Abild CB, Cunnane SC, Croteau E, Lauritsen KM, et al. A ketogenic diet lowers myocardial fatty acid oxidation but does not affect oxygen consumption: a study in overweight humans. Obesity. 2024;32(3):506&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/oby.23967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38258448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patikorn C, Saidoung P, Pham T, Phisalprapa P, Lee YY, Varady KA, et al. Effects of ketogenic diet on health outcomes: an umbrella review of meta-analyses of randomized clinical trials. BMC Med. 2023;21(1):196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-023-02874-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10210275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37231411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michalczyk MM, Klonek G, Maszczyk A, Zajac A. The Effects of a Low Calorie Ketogenic Diet on Glycaemic Control Variables in Hyperinsulinemic Overweight/Obese Females. Nutrients. 2020;12(6):1854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu12061854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7353458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32580282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim JM, Letchumanan V, Tan LTH, Hong KW, Wong SH, Ab Mutalib NS, et al. Ketogenic Diet: A Dietary Intervention via Gut Microbiome Modulation for the Treatment of Neurological and Nutritional Disorders (a Narrative Review). Nutrients. 2022;14(17):3566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu14173566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9460077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36079829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilyas Z, Perna S, Alalwan TA, Zahid MN, Spadaccini D, Gasparri C, Peroni G, Faragli A, Alogna A, La Porta E, et al. The Ketogenic Diet: Is It an Answer for Sarcopenic Obesity? Nutrients. 2022;14(3):620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu14030620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8838342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35276979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goss AM, Gower B, Soleymani T, Stewart M, Pendergrass M, Lockhart M, et al. Effects of weight loss during a very low carbohydrate diet on specific adipose tissue depots and insulin sensitivity in older adults with obesity: a randomized clinical trial. Nutr Metab. 2020;17(1):64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12986-020-00481-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7425171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32817749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheatley SD, Deakin TA, Arjomandkhah NC, Hollinrake PB, Reeves TE. Low Carbohydrate Dietary Approaches for People With Type 2 Diabetes&#x2014;A Narrative Review. Front Nutr. 2021;15(8):687658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2021.687658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8319397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34336909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kikuchi T, Kushiyama A, Yanai M, Kashiwado C, Seto T, Kasuga M. Comparison of Weight Reduction, Change in Parameters and Safety of a Very Low Carbohydrate Diet in Comparison to a Low Carbohydrate Diet in Obese Japanese Subjects with Metabolic Disorders. Nutrients. 2023;15(6):1342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu15061342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10052897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36986072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falkenhain K, Locke SR, Lowe DA, Reitsma NJ, Lee T, Singer J, et al. Keyto app and device versus WW app on weight loss and metabolic risk in adults with overweight or obesity: A randomized trial. Obesity. 2021;29(10):1606&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/oby.23242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8518592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34124856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falkenhain K, Locke SR, Lowe DA, Lee T, Singer J, Weiss EJ, et al. Use of an mHealth Ketogenic Diet App Intervention and User Behaviors Associated With Weight Loss in Adults With Overweight or Obesity: Secondary Analysis of a Randomized Clinical Trial. JMIR MHealth UHealth. 2022;10(3):e33940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/33940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8961343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35285809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sethi S, Wakeham D, Ketter T, Hooshmand F, Bjornstad J, Richards B, et al. Ketogenic Diet Intervention on Metabolic and Psychiatric Health in Bipolar and Schizophrenia: A Pilot Trial. Psychiatry Res. 2024;335:115866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2024.115866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38547601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charlot A, Zoll J. Beneficial Effects of the Ketogenic Diet in Metabolic Syndrome: A Systematic Review. Diabetology. 2022;3(2):292&#x2013;309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diabetology3020020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolb H, Kempf K, R&#xf6;hling M, Lenzen-Schulte M, Schloot NC, Martin S. Ketone bodies: from enemy to friend and guardian angel. BMC Med. 2021;19(1):313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-021-02185-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8656040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34879839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinsawas B, Surawit A, Mongkolsucharitkul P, Pongkunakorn T, Suta S, Manosan T, et al. Asian Low-Carbohydrate Diet with Increased Whole Egg Consumption Improves Metabolic Outcomes in Metabolic Syndrome: A 52-Week Intervention Study. J Nutr. 2024;154(11):3331&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tjnut.2024.08.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39245182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebbeling CB, Feldman HA, Klein GL, Wong JMW, Bielak L, Steltz SK, et al. Effects of a low carbohydrate diet on energy expenditure during weight loss maintenance: randomized trial. BMJ. 2018;14:k4583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.k4583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6233655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30429127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao T, Sun Y, Xu X, He K. Overview and Prospect of Nafld: Significant Roles of Nutrients and Dietary Patterns in Its Progression or Prevention. Hepatol Commun. 2023;7(10):e0234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HC9.0000000000000234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10531241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37756016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Bai W, Jiang B, Bai L, Gu B, Yan S, et al. Ketogenic diet in women with polycystic ovary syndrome and liver dysfunction who are obese: A randomized, open-label, parallel-group, controlled pilot trial. J Obstet Gynaecol Res. 2021;47(3):1145&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jog.14650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33462940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Lin G, Chen J, Chen Z, Xu F, Zhu F, et al. The effect of periodic ketogenic diet on newly diagnosed overweight or obese patients with type 2 diabetes. BMC Endocr Disord. 2022;22(1):34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12902-022-00947-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8811985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35115003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludwig DS, Aronne LJ, Astrup A, de Cabo R, Cantley LC, Friedman MI, Heymsfield SB, Johnson JD, King JC, Krauss RM, Lieberman DE, et al. The carbohydrate-insulin model: a physiological perspective on the obesity pandemic. Am J Clin Nutr. 2021;114:1873&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/nqab270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8634575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34515299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unwin DJ, Tobin SD, Murray SW, Delon C, Brady AJ. Substantial and Sustained Improvements in Blood Pressure, Weight and Lipid Profiles from a Carbohydrate Restricted Diet: An Observational Study of Insulin Resistant Patients in Primary Care. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019;16(15):2680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph16152680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6695889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31357547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimy KJ, Feldman HA, Klein GL, Bielak L, Ebbeling CB, Ludwig DS. Effects of Dietary Carbohydrate Content on Circulating Metabolic Fuel Availability in the Postprandial State. J Endocr Soc. 2020;4(7):bvaa062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jendso/bvaa062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7326475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32666008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansoor N, Vinknes KJ, Veier&#xf8;d MB, Retterst&#xf8;l K. Effects of low-carbohydrate diets <i>v</i> . low-fat diets on body weight and cardiovascular risk factors: a meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Br J Nutr. 2016;115(3):466&#x2013;79.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0007114515004699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26768850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenig S, Petelin A, Poklar Vatovec T, Mohorko N, Jenko-Pra&#x17e;nikar Z. Assessment of micronutrients in a 12-wk ketogenic diet in obese adults. Nutrition. 2019;67&#x2013;68:110522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2019.06.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31445313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perissiou M, Borkoles E, Kobayashi K, Polman R. The Effect of an 8 Week Prescribed Exercise and Low-Carbohydrate Diet on Cardiorespiratory Fitness, Body Composition and Cardiometabolic Risk Factors in Obese Individuals: A Randomised Controlled Trial. Nutrients. 2020;12(2):482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu12020482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7071220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32075010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iacovides S, Maloney SK, Bhana S, Angamia Z, Meiring RM. Could the ketogenic diet induce a shift in thyroid function and support a metabolic advantage in healthy participants? A pilot randomized-controlled-crossover trial. Pegoraro C, editor. PLoS One. 2022;17(6):e0269440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0269440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9165850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35658056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe M, Tuccinardi D, Ernesti I, Basciani S, Mariani S, Genco A, et al. Scientific evidence underlying contraindications to the ketogenic diet: An update. Obes Rev. 2020;21(10):e13053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.13053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7539910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32648647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshi S, Shi R, Patel J. Risks of the ketogenic diet in CKD &#x2013; the con part. Clin Kidney J. 2024;17(1):sfad274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ckj/sfad274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10768778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38186877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juraschek SP, McAdams-Demarco M, Gelber AC, Sacks FM, Appel LJ, White KJ, et al. Effects of Lowering Glycemic Index of Dietary Carbohydrate on Plasma Uric Acid Levels: The OmniCarb Randomized Clinical Trial. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2016;68(5):1281&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.39527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5532800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26636424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun S, Kong Z, Shi Q, Hu M, Zhang H, Zhang D, et al. Non-Energy-Restricted Low-Carbohydrate Diet Combined with Exercise Intervention Improved Cardiometabolic Health in Overweight Chinese Females. Nutrients. 2019;11(12):3051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu11123051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6950598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31847246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu W, Zhou Q, Yuan P, Qiao D, Deng S, Cheng H, et al. A Novel Multiphase Modified Ketogenic Diet: An Effective and Safe Tool for Weight Loss in Chinese Obese Patients. Diabetes Metab Syndr Obes Targets Ther. 2022;15:2521&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/DMSO.S365192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9393022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35999869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guevara-Cruz M, Hern&#xe1;ndez-G&#xf3;mez KG, Condado-Huerta C, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Salazar LE, Pe&#xf1;a-Flores AK, Pichardo-Ontiveros E, et al. Intermittent fasting, calorie restriction, and a ketogenic diet improve mitochondrial function by reducing lipopolysaccharide signaling in monocytes during obesity: A randomized clinical trial. Clin Nutr. 2024;43(8):1914&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2024.06.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39003957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Ding L, Xiao X. Comparing the Efficacy and Safety of Low-Carbohydrate Diets with Low-Fat Diets for Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus Patients: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Randomized Clinical Trials. Perez-Lopez FR, editor. Int J Endocrinol. 2021;2021:1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/8521756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8668312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34912453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tinguely D, Gross J, Kosinski C. Efficacy of Ketogenic Diets on Type 2 Diabetes: a Systematic Review. Curr Diab Rep. 2021;21(9):32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11892-021-01399-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8397683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34448957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross R, Neeland IJ, Yamashita S, Shai I, Seidell J, Magni P, et al. Waist circumference as a vital sign in clinical practice: a Consensus Statement from the IAS and ICCR Working Group on Visceral Obesity. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2020;16(3):177&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41574-019-0310-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7027970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32020062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson JC, Mattar SG, Greenway FL, Lindquist RJ. Measuring ketone bodies for the monitoring of pathologic and therapeutic ketosis. Obes Sci Pract. 2021;7(5):646&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/osp4.516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8488448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34631141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gnessi LWM. Scientific Evidence Underlying Contraindications to the Ketogenic Diet: An Update. Obes Rev. 2020;21(10):e13053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.13053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7539910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32648647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landry MJ, Crimarco A, Perelman D, Durand LR, Petlura C, Aronica L, et al. Adherence to Ketogenic and Mediterranean Study Diets in a Crossover Trial: The Keto-Med Randomized Trial. Nutrients. 2021;13(3):967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu13030967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8002540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33802709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>