<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40760444</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1743-7075</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>22</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nutrition &amp; metabolism</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nutr Metab (Lond)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effects of a home-based resistance training programme on body composition and muscle function during weight loss in people living with overweight or obesity: a randomised controlled pilot trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>90</StartPage><MedlinePgn>90</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">90</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12986-025-00986-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Obesity continues to grow as a public health concern and although dietary interventions can be effective at reducing body mass and improving cardiovascular risk factors, they also result in undesirable losses of lean tissue. The aim of this randomised controlled pilot trial was to investigate the effects of a home-based resistance training exercise programme on body composition and muscle function in people living with overweight or obesity undergoing dietary weight loss.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Participants (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;48) from Glasgow were randomly assigned to either a diet-induced weight loss group (WL) or a diet plus home-based resistance training exercise group (RT&#x2009;+&#x2009;WL) for 12-weeks. Body composition, muscle strength, and physical function were assessed at baseline and post-intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">There was no effect of the resistance exercise training programme (all p&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05) on body composition including body mass index, total body mass, fat mass, fat free mass or muscle thickness during weight loss. However, the resistance training group showed improvements in muscle and physical function compared to the weight loss only group, resulting in higher grip strength (RT&#x2009;+&#x2009;WL: &#x394;2.65, 95% CI: 0.44, 4.86; WL: &#x394;-0.26, 95% CI: -2.04, 1.51:p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.046), maximal voluntary contraction force (RT&#x2009;+&#x2009;WL:&#x394;23.61, 95% CI: 3.39, 43.84 WL: &#x394;-11.95, 95% CI: -35.37, 11.48;p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.019), and sit-to-stand test scores (RT&#x2009;+&#x2009;WL:&#x394;5.9, 95% CI: 4.27, 7.53 WL: &#x394;1.47, 95% CI: 0.13, 2.82; p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These findings suggest that incorporating home-based resistance training into weight loss programmes can preserve, or even enhance, muscle function without negatively impacting the effectiveness of dietary weight loss interventions, highlighting its potential to mitigate muscle function losses during weight loss in people living with overweight or obese.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Name of the registry: ClinicalTrials.gov. The registration number: NCT05702840. Date of Registry: 18/01/2023. The registration title: EXerCise wEight Loss (EXCEL).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Binmahfoz</LastName><ForeName>Ahmad</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Cardiovascular and Metabolic Health, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, College of Health Sciences at Al-Leith, Umm Al-Qura University, Al-Leith, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnston</LastName><ForeName>Lynsey</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Cardiovascular and Metabolic Health, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dunning</LastName><ForeName>Emma</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Cardiovascular and Metabolic Health, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gray</LastName><ForeName>Cindy M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Social and Political Sciences, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gray</LastName><ForeName>Stuart R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8969-9636</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Cardiovascular and Metabolic Health, University of Glasgow, Glasgow, UK. stuart.gray@glasgow.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Sports Science and Innovation, Lithuanian Sports University, Kaunus, Lithuania. stuart.gray@glasgow.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05702840</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nutr Metab (Lond)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101231644</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1743-7075</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Overweight</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resistance exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Weight loss</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study was approved by the College of Medical Veterinary and Life Sciences Ethics Committee at the University of Glasgow (Project No: 200220112) and all participants provided written informed consent. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40760444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12323239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12986-025-00986-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12986-025-00986-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Upadhyay J, Farr O, Perakakis N, Ghaly W, Mantzoros C. Obesity as a disease. Med Clin N Am. 2018;102(1):13&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29156181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An R, Ji M, Zhang S. Global warming and obesity: a systematic review. Obes Rev. 2018;19(2):150&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28977817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James PT, Leach R, Kalamara E, Shayeghi M. The worldwide obesity epidemic. Obes (Silver Spring Md). 2001;9(11S):S228&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11707546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siervo M, Montagnese C, Mathers JC, Soroka KR, Stephan BCM, Wells JCK. Sugar consumption and global prevalence of obesity and hypertension: an ecological analysis. Public Health Nutr. 2014;17(3):587&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10282320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23414749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge L, Sadeghirad B, Ball GDC, da Costa BR, Hitchcock CL, Svendrovski A, et al. Comparison of dietary macronutrient patterns of 14 popular named dietary programmes for weight and cardiovascular risk factor reduction in adults: systematic review and network meta-analysis of randomised trials. BMJ (Online). 2020;369:m696&#x2013;m.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7190064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32238384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lean MEJ, Leslie WS, Barnes AC, Brosnahan N, Thom G, McCombie L, et al. Primary care-led weight management for remission of type 2 diabetes (DiRECT): an open-label, cluster-randomised trial. Lancet (British edition). 2018;391(10120):541&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29221645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cava E, Yeat NC, Mittendorfer B. Preserving healthy muscle during weight loss. Advances in nutrition (Bethesda. Md). 2017;8(3):511&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5421125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28507015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enriquez Guerrero A, San Mauro Martin I, Garicano Vilar E, Camina Martin MA. Effectiveness of an intermittent fasting diet versus continuous energy restriction on anthropometric measurements, body composition and lipid profile in overweight and obese adults: a meta-analysis. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2021;75(7):1024&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33293678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellegrini M, Cioffi I, Evangelista A, Ponzo V, Goitre I, Ciccone G, et al. Effects of time-restricted feeding on body weight and metabolism. A systematic review and meta-analysis. Reviews Endocr Metabolic Disorders. 2019;21(1):17&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31808043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe RR. Underappreciated role of muscle in health and disease. Am J Clin Nutr. 2006;84(3):475&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16960159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sajoux I, Lorenzo PM, Gomez-Arbelaez D, Angeles Zulet M, Abete I, Castro A, et al. Effect of a Very-Low-Calorie ketogenic diet on Circulating myokine levels compared with the effect of bariatric surgery or a Low-Calorie diet in patients with obesity. Nutrients. 2019;11(10):2368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6835835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31590286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomlinson DJ, Erskine RM, Morse CI, Winwood K, Onamb&#xe9;l&#xe9;-Pearson G. The impact of obesity on skeletal muscle strength and structure through adolescence to old age. Biogerontology. 2016;17:467&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4889641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26667010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westcott WL. Resistance training is medicine: effects of strength training on health. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2012;11(4):209&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22777332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashton RE, Tew GA, Aning JJ, Gilbert SE, Lewis L, Saxton JM. Effects of short-term, medium-term and long-term resistance exercise training on cardiometabolic health outcomes in adults: systematic review with meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(6):341&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29934430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornelissen VA, Fagard RH, Coeckelberghs E, Vanhees L. Impact of resistance training on blood pressure and other cardiovascular risk factors: A Meta-Analysis of randomized, controlled trials. Hypertension (Dallas, Tex 1979). 2011;58(5):950&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21896934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avila JJ, Gutierres JA, Sheehy ME, Lofgren IE, Delmonico MJ. Effect of moderate intensity resistance training during weight loss on body composition and physical performance in overweight older adults. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2010;109(3):517&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20169360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter GR, Fisher G, Neumeier WH, Carter SJ, Plaisance EP. Exercise training and energy expenditure following weight loss. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015;47(9):1950&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4508245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25606816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strain T, Fitzsimons C, Kelly P, Mutrie N. The forgotten guidelines: cross-sectional analysis of participation in muscle strengthening and balance &amp; co-ordination activities by adults and older adults in Scotland. BMC Public Health. 2016;16:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5073826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27769211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley KS, Flippin KJ, Blom LC, Bolin JE, Hoover DL, Judge LW. Practices, perceived benefits, and barriers to resistance training among women enrolled in college. Int J Exerc Sci. 2018;11(5):226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5955292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29795737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters NA, Schlaff RA, Knous JL, Baruth M. Barriers to resistance training among college-aged women. J Am Coll Health. 2019;67(1):4&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29652602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burton E, Farrier K, Lewin G, Pettigrew S, Hill A-M, Airey P, et al. Motivators and barriers for older people participating in resistance training: a systematic review. J Aging Phys Act. 2017;25(2):311&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27620535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavill NA, Foster CEM. Enablers and barriers to older people&#x2019;s participation in strength and balance activities: A review of reviews. J Frailty Sarcopenia Falls. 2018;3(2):105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7155318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32300698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schvey NA, Sbrocco T, Bakalar JL, Ress R, Barmine M, Gorlick J, et al. The experience of weight stigma among gym members with overweight and obesity. Stigma Health. 2017;2(4):292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyenhuis SM, Greiwe J, Zeiger JS, Nanda A, Cooke A. Exercise and fitness in the age of social distancing during the COVID-19 pandemic. J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract. 2020;8(7):2152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7187829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32360185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur H, Singh T, Arya YK, Mittal S. Physical fitness and exercise during the COVID-19 pandemic: A qualitative enquiry. Front Psychol. 2020;11:590172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7673425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33250827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plotnikoff RC, Eves N, Jung M, Sigal RJ, Padwal R, Karunamuni N. Multicomponent, home-based resistance training for obese adults with type 2 diabetes: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Obes. 2010;34(12):1733&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20531348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikesky AE, Topp R, Wigglesworth JK, Harsha DM, Edwards JE. Efficacy of a home-based training program for older adults using elastic tubing. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1994;69:316&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7851367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zion AS, De Meersman R, Diamond BE, Bloomfield DM. A home-based resistance-training program using elastic bands for elderly patients with orthostatic hypotension. Clin Auton Res. 2003;13:286&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12955554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz KF, Altman DG, Moher D, the CG. CONSORT 2010 statement: updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomised trials. BMC Med. 2010;8(1):18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2860339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20334633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitehead AL, Julious SA, Cooper CL, Campbell MJ. Estimating the sample size for a pilot randomised trial to minimise the overall trial sample size for the external pilot and main trial for a continuous outcome variable. Stat Methods Med Res. 2016;25(3):1057&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4876429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26092476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman LM, Furberg CD, DeMets DL, Reboussin DM, Granger CB. Fundamentals of clinical trials: Springer; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gudzune KA, Doshi RS, Mehta AK, Chaudhry ZW, Jacobs DK, Vakil RM, et al. Efficacy of commercial weight-loss programs: an updated systematic review. Ann Intern Med. 2015;162(7):501&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4446719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25844997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagally KM, Robertson RJ. Construct validity of the OMNI resistance exercise scale. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2006;20(2):252&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16686549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institutes of Health. Office of Medical Applications of Research. Bioelectrical impedance analysis in body composition measurement: National Institutes of health technology assessment conference statement, December 12&#x2013;14, 1994: US Department of Health and Human Services, Public Health Service, National &amp;#8230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail AD, Alkhayl FFA, Wilson J, Johnston L, Gill JMR, Gray SR. The effect of short-duration resistance training on insulin sensitivity and muscle adaptations in overweight men. Exp Physiol. 2019;104(4):540&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30697876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huitema B. The analysis of covariance and alternatives: statistical methods for experiments, quasi-experiments, and single-case studies. Wiley; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conte C, Hall KD, Klein S. Is Weight Loss&#x2013;Induced Muscle Mass Loss Clinically Relevant? JAMA. 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38829659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell WW, Haub MD, Wolfe RR, Ferrando AA, Sullivan DH, Apolzan JW, et al. Resistance training preserves fat-free mass without impacting changes in protein metabolism after weight loss in older women. Obesity. 2009;17(7):1332&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4299870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19247271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller T, Mull S, Aragon AA, Krieger J, Schoenfeld BJ. Resistance training combined with diet decreases body fat while preserving lean mass independent of resting metabolic rate: a randomized trial. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2018;28(1):46&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28871849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straight CR, Dorfman LR, Cottell KE, Krol JM, Lofgren IE, Delmonico MJ. Effects of resistance training and dietary changes on physical function and body composition in overweight and obese older adults. J Phys Activity Health. 2012;9(6):875&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21952180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sardeli AV, Komatsu TR, Mori MA, G&#xe1;spari AF, Chacon-Mikahil MPT. Resistance training prevents muscle loss induced by caloric restriction in obese elderly individuals: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutrients. 2018;10(4):423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5946208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29596307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez P, Taaffe DR, Galv&#xe3;o DA, Newton RU, Nonemacher ER, Wendt VM, et al. Resistance training effectiveness on body composition and body weight outcomes in individuals with overweight and obesity across the lifespan: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Obes Rev. 2022;23(5):e13428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9285060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35191588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coleman M, Burke R, Benavente C, Pi&#xf1;ero A, Augustin F, Maldonado J, et al. Supervision during resistance training positively influences muscular adaptations in resistance-trained individuals. J Sports Sci. 2023;41(12):1207&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37789670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter GR, Byrne NM, Sirikul B, Fern&#xe1;ndez JR, Zuckerman PA, Darnell BE, et al. Resistance training conserves fat-free mass and resting energy expenditure following weight loss. Obesity. 2008;16(5):1045&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18356845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher J, Steele J, Wolf M, Korakakis PA, Smith D, Giessing J. The role of supervision in resistance training; an exploratory systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Strength Conditioning. 2022;2(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurst C, Robinson SM, Witham MD, Dodds RM, Granic A, Buckland C, et al. Resistance exercise as a treatment for sarcopenia: prescription and delivery. Age Ageing. 2022;51(2):afac003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8840798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35150587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunstan DW, Daly RM, Owen N, Jolley D, Vulikh E, Shaw J, et al. Home-based resistance training is not sufficient to maintain improved glycemic control following supervised training in older individuals with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2005;28(1):3&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15616225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Gao Y, Lu J, Ma Q, Shi Y, Liu J, et al. Effects of different resistance exercise forms on body composition and muscle strength in overweight and/or obese individuals: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Physiol. 2022;12:791999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8895240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35250604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orange ST, Madden LA, Vince RV. Resistance training leads to large improvements in strength and moderate improvements in physical function in adults who are overweight or obese: a systematic review. J Physiotherapy. 2020;66(4):214&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33069607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueroa A, Vicil F, Sanchez-Gonzalez MA, Wong A, Ormsbee MJ, Hooshmand S, et al. Effects of diet and/or Low-Intensity resistance exercise training on arterial stiffness, adiposity, and lean mass in obese postmenopausal women. Am J Hypertens. 2013;26(3):416&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23382493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hintze LJ, Messier V, Lavoie M-E, Brochu M, Lavoie J-M, Prud&#x2019;homme D, et al. A one-year resistance training program following weight loss has no significant impact on body composition and energy expenditure in postmenopausal women living with overweight and obesity. Physiol Behav. 2018;189:99&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29549030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folland JP, Williams AG. Morphological and neurological contributions to increased strength. Sports Med. 2007;37:145&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17241104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;karabot J, Brownstein CG, Casolo A, Del Vecchio A, Ansdell P. The knowns and unknowns of neural adaptations to resistance training. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2021;121:675&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7892509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33355714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hector AJ, Marcotte GR, Churchward-Venne TA, Murphy CH, Breen L, von Allmen M, et al. Whey protein supplementation preserves postprandial myofibrillar protein synthesis during short-term energy restriction in overweight and obese adults. J Nutr. 2015;145(2):246&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25644344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy C, Koehler K. Caloric restriction induces anabolic resistance to resistance exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2020;120:1155&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8233264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32236752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murlasits Z, Reed J. Muscular adaptations to periodized resistance-training in older adults. Sci Sports. 2020;35(4):216&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sale DG. Neural adaptation to resistance training. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1988;20(5 Suppl):S135&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3057313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verreijen AM, Verlaan S, Engberink MF, Swinkels S, de Vogel-van den Bosch J, Weijs PJM. A high Whey protein&#x2013;, leucine-, and vitamin D&#x2013;enriched supplement preserves muscle mass during intentional weight loss in obese older adults: a double-blind randomized controlled trial. Am J Clin Nutr. 2015;101(2):279&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25646324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koch B, Miller A, Glass NA, Owen E, Kirkpatrick T, Grossman R, et al. Reliability of multifrequency bioelectrical impedance analysis to quantify body composition in patients after musculoskeletal trauma. Iowa Orthop J. 2022;42(1):75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9210418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35821931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palacios AM, Lee AM, Parker C, Watts CQ, Dickinson SL, Henschel B et al. Effectiveness of a digital weight management program on diet quality: A randomized controlled trial. Am J Clin Nutr. 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40609748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weijs PJM, Wolfe RR. Exploration of the protein requirement during weight loss in obese older adults. Clin Nutr. 2016;35(2):394&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25788405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khodadad Kashi S, Mirzazadeh ZS, Saatchian V. A systematic review and meta-analysis of resistance training on quality of life, depression, muscle strength, and functional exercise capacity in older adults aged 60 years or more. Biol Res Nurs. 2023;25(1):88&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35968662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaughnessy KA, Hackney KJ, Clark BC, Kraemer WJ, Terbizan DJ, Bailey RR, et al. A narrative review of handgrip strength and cognitive functioning: bringing a new characteristic to muscle memory. J Alzheimers Dis. 2020;73(4):1265&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7063546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31929158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billot M, Calvani R, Urtamo A, S&#xe1;nchez-S&#xe1;nchez JL, Ciccolari-Micaldi C, Chang M et al. Preserving mobility in older adults with physical frailty and sarcopenia: opportunities, challenges, and recommendations for physical activity interventions. Clin Interv Aging. 2020: 15, 1675&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7508031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32982201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillsdon M, Foster C. What are the health benefits of muscle and bone strengthening and balance activities across life stages and specific health outcomes? J Frailty Sarcopenia Falls. 2018;3(2):66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7155322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32300695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abou Sawan S, Nunes EA, Lim C, McKendry J, Phillips SM. The health benefits of resistance exercise: beyond hypertrophy and big weights. Exerc Sport Mov. 2023;1(1):e00001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strasser B, Schobersberger W. Evidence for resistance training as a treatment therapy in obesity. J Obes. 2011;2011(1):482564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2931407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20847892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pesta DH, Goncalves RLS, Madiraju AK, Strasser B, Sparks LM. Resistance training to improve type 2 diabetes: working toward a prescription for the future. Nutr Metabolism. 2017;14:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5335813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28270856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santanasto AJ, Glynn NW, Newman MA, Taylor CA, Brooks MM, Goodpaster BH, et al. Impact of weight loss on physical function with changes in strength, muscle mass, and muscle fat infiltration in overweight to moderately obese older adults: a randomized clinical trial. J Obes. 2011;2011(1):516576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2952914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20953373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>