<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">24707505</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>1</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2013</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of physical therapy and health promotion</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Phys Ther Health Promot</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Community-Based Exercise and Support Group Program in African-American Breast Cancer Survivors (ABCs).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>15</StartPage><EndPage>24</EndPage><MedlinePgn>15-24</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>African-American (AA) women have higher rates of breast cancer (BCa) mortality than Caucasian women, and a recent study using data from the Surveillance, Epidemiology and End Results (SEER) registry suggests that this disparity may be due, in part, to the poorer health status of AAs at diagnosis and not treatment related issues. Randomized controlled trials involving supervised aerobic and resistance exercise have shown improved body composition and improvement in cancer-related biomarkers in BCa patients and may lead to improved recurrence and survival rates; however, most trials have focused on Caucasians and many have been conducted in academic- and clinic-based settings. We evaluated the feasibility of conducting a 20-week, supervised, resistance training, group exercise intervention coupled with a support group and home walking program utilizing facilities and personnel at a community cancer support center (The Gathering Place, Beachwood, Ohio) in AA Stage I-III BCa survivors who were within 12 months of completing treatment (surgery, chemotherapy, and/or breast irradiation); and, evaluated the potential effects of this intervention on physical measures and cancer-related biomarkers. 27 patients provided informed consent and 19 participated in the program. On average, attendance rates were 70.0% &#xb1; 19.1% for the exercise sessions and 63.1% &#xb1; 13.8% for the support group. We observed a significant decrease in circulating C-peptide levels (B: 893.9 &#xb1; 399.1 pg/mL; EOI: 723.9 &#xb1; 319.0 pg/mL; p=0.01). Although we did not observe a significant decrease in weight in the entire sample, there was a significant decrease in waist circumference and percent total body fat among those who attended 70% or more of the exercise sessions. In summary, we demonstrated that conducting lifestyle interventions in AA BCa survivors in a community setting is feasible. Future interventions should invoke strategies to enhance adherence and include a structured dietary intervention to enable greater weight loss.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nock</LastName><ForeName>Nora L</ForeName><Initials>NL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Owusu</LastName><ForeName>Cynthia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kullman</LastName><ForeName>Emily L</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Case Comprehensive Cancer Center, University Hospitals Case Medical Center, Cleveland, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Austin</LastName><ForeName>Kris</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathobiology, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roth</LastName><ForeName>Beth</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Gathering Place, Beachwood, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cerne</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Solid Tumor Oncology, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harmon</LastName><ForeName>Carl</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, MetroHealth Medical Center, Cleveland, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moore</LastName><ForeName>Halle</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, MetroHealth Medical Center, Cleveland, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vargo</LastName><ForeName>Mary</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Medicine, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hergenroeder</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology and Biochemistry, University of Vermont, Burlington, VT, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malone</LastName><ForeName>Hermione</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rocco</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tracy</LastName><ForeName>Russell</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lazarus</LastName><ForeName>Hillard M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kirwan</LastName><ForeName>John P</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heyman</LastName><ForeName>Ellen</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berger</LastName><ForeName>Nathan A</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K07 CA129162</GrantID><Acronym>CA</Acronym><Agency>NCI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U54 CA116867</GrantID><Acronym>CA</Acronym><Agency>NCI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Phys Ther Health Promot</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101626373</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">African-American</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Breast Cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Community-Based</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2014</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2014</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24707505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS552676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3975605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18005/pthp0101003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Siegel R, Naishadham D, Jemal A. Cancer statistics, 2012. CA Cancer J Clin. 2012 Jan;62(1):10&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22237781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Cancer Society. Cancer Facts and Figures for African-Americans 2011&#x2013;2012. American Cancer Society; Atlanta, GA: 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eley JW, Hill HA, Chen VW, Austin DF, Wesley MN, Muss HB, et al. Racial differences in survival from breast cancer. Results of the National Cancer Institute Black/White Cancer Survival Study. JAMA. 1994 Sep;272(12):947&#x2013;954.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8084062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tammemagi CM, Nerenz D, Neslund-Dudas C, Feldkamp C, Nathanson D. Comorbidity and survival disparities among black and white patients with breast cancer. JAMA. 2005 Oct;294(14):1765&#x2013;1772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16219879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuyahoga County Board of Health. The Cuyahoga County Comprehensive Cancer Report of 2011; A Detailed Look at Cancer Incidence and Mortality Data from 2002&#x2013;2006. 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ademuyiwa FO, Groman A, O&#x2019;Connor T, Ambrosone C, Watroba N, Edge SB. Impact of body mass index on clinical outcomes in triple-negative breast cancer. Cancer. 2011 Sep;117(18):4132&#x2013;4140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21387276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silber JH, Rosenbaum PR, Clark AS, Giantonio BJ, Ross RN, Teng Y, et al. Characteristics associated with differences in survival among black and white women with breast cancer. JAMA. 2013 Jul;310(4):389&#x2013;397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23917289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flegal KM, Carroll MD, Ogden CL, Curtin LR. Prevalence and trends in obesity among US adults, 1999&#x2013;2008. JAMA. 2010 Jan;303(3):235&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20071471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stolley MR, Sharp LK, Wells AM, Simon N, Schiffer L. Health behaviors and breast cancer: experiences of urban African American women. Health Educ Behav. 2006 Oct;33(5):604&#x2013;624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16923833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fong DY, Ho JW, Hui BP, Lee AM, Macfarlane DJ, Leung SS, et al. Physical activity for cancer survivors: meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. BMJ. 2012;344:e70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3269661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22294757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speck RM, Courneya KS, Masse LC, Duval S, Schmitz KH. An update of controlled physical activity trials in cancer survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Cancer Surviv. 2010 Jun;4(2):87&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20052559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nock NL, Berger NA. Exercise Associated Regulation of Tumor Promoters, Hormones and Cytokines in Cancer Control. In: Ulrich C, Steindorf K, Berger NA, editors. In Exercise, Energy Balance and Cancer. New York: Springer; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin ML. Benefits of Aerobic and Resistance Exercise in Cancer Survivors. In: Berger NA, Steindorf K, Ulrich C, editors. In Exercise, Energy Balance and Cancer. New York: Springer; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Des Jarlais DC, Lyles C, Crepaz N. Improving the reporting quality of nonrandomized evaluations of behavioral and public health interventions: the TREND statement. Am J Public Health. 2004 Mar;94(3):361&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1448256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14998794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. ACSM resource manual for guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. 5. Baltimore, MD: 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz KH, Courneya KS, Matthews C, Demark-Wahnefried W, Galvao DA, Pinto BM, et al. American College of Sports Medicine roundtable on exercise guidelines for cancer survivors. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010 Jul;42(7):1409&#x2013;1426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20559064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sander A. Safe and effective upper extremity resistive exercise program for women post breast cancer treatment. Rehabilitation Oncology. 2008;26(2):3&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swank AM, Hagerman P. In Resistant Training for Special Populations. Clifton Park, NY: DELMAR Cengage Learning; 2010. Resistance training strategies for individuals with cancer; pp. 305&#x2013;324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cummings B, Fink K. Estimation of one repetition maximum bench press for untrained women. J Strength Conditioning Assoc. 2011;12:262&#x2013;265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapiro JP, McCue K, Heyman EN, Dey T, Haller HS. A naturalistic evaluation of psychosocial interventions for cancer patients in a community setting. J Psychosoc Oncol. 2010 Jan;28(1):23&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20391064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butland RJ, Pang J, Gross ER, Woodcock AA, Geddes DM. Two-, six-, and 12-minute walking tests in respiratory disease. Br Med J (Clin Res Ed) 1982 May;284(6329):1607&#x2013;1608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1498516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6805625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper KH. A means of assessing maximal oxygen intake. Correlation between field and treadmill testing. JAMA. 1968 Jan;203(3):201&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5694044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens MA. EDF Statistics for Goodness of Fit and Some Comparisons. Journal of American Statistical Association. 1974;69:730&#x2013;737.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization (WHO) 2000</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman AB, Simonsick EM, Naydeck BL, Boudreau RM, Kritchevsky SB, Nevitt MC, et al. Association of long-distance corridor walk performance with mortality, cardiovascular disease, mobility limitation, and disability. JAMA. 2006 May;295(17):2018&#x2013;2026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16670410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calle EE, Kaaks R. Overweight, obesity and cancer: epidemiological evidence and proposed mechanisms. Nat Rev Cancer. 2004 Aug;4(8):579&#x2013;591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15286738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin ML, Varma K, Alvarez-Reeves M, Cadmus L, Wiley A, Chung GG, et al. Randomized controlled trial of aerobic exercise on insulin and insulin-like growth factors in breast cancer survivors: the Yale Exercise and Survivorship study. Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev. 2009 Jan;18(1):306&#x2013;313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2841479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19124513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ligibel JA, Campbell N, Partridge A, Chen WY, Salinardi T, Chen H, et al. Impact of a mixed strength and endurance exercise intervention on insulin levels in breast cancer survivors. J Clin Oncol. 2008 Feb;26(6):907&#x2013;912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18281663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairey AS, Courneya KS, Field CJ, Bell GJ, Jones LW, Mackey JR. Effects of exercise training on fasting insulin, insulin resistance, insulin-like growth factors, and insulin-like growth factor binding proteins in postmenopausal breast cancer survivors: a randomized controlled trial. Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev. 2003 Aug;12(8):721&#x2013;727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12917202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitz KH, Ahmed RL, Hannan PJ, Yee D. Safety and efficacy of weight training in recent breast cancer survivors to alter body composition, insulin, and insulin-like growth factor axis proteins. Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev. 2005 Jul;14(7):1672&#x2013;1680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16030100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McTiernan A, Sorensen B, Yasui Y, Tworoger SS, Ulrich CM, Irwin ML, et al. No effect of exercise on insulin-like growth factor 1 and insulin-like growth factor binding protein 3 in postmenopausal women: a 12-month randomized clinical trial. Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev. 2005 Apr;14(4):1020&#x2013;1021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15824183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenlee HA, Crew KD, Mata JM, McKinley PS, Rundle AG, Zhang W, et al. A Pilot Randomized Controlled Trial of a Commercial Diet and Exercise Weight Loss Program in Minority Breast Cancer Survivors. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2012 Jun;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4705911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23505170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodwin PJ, Ennis M, Pritchard KI, Trudeau ME, Koo J, Madarnas Y, Hartwick W, Hoffman B, Hood N. Fasting insulin and outcome in early-stage breast cancer: results of a prospective cohort study. J Clin Oncol. 2002 Jan;20(1):42&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11773152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irwin ML, Duggan C, Wang CY, Smith AW, McTiernan A, Baumgartner RN, et al. Fasting C-peptide levels and death resulting from all causes and breast cancer: the health, eating, activity, and lifestyle study. J Clin Oncol. 2011 Jan;29(1):47&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3055859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21115859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nock NL, Berger NA. Obesity and Cancer: Overview of Mechanisms. In: Berger NA, editor. In Cancer and Energy Balance, Epidemiology and Overview. New York: Springer; 2010. pp. 129&#x2013;179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baratta M. Leptin--from a signal of adiposity to a hormonal mediator in peripheral tissues. Med Sci Monit. 2002 Dec;8(12):RA282&#x2013;RA292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12503048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X, Juneja SC, Maihle NJ, Cleary MP. Leptin--a growth factor in normal and malignant breast cells and for normal mammary gland development. J Natl Cancer Inst. 2002 Nov;94(22):1704&#x2013;1711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12441326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hursting SD, Nunez NP, Varticovski L, Vinson C. The obesity-cancer link: lessons learned from a fatless mouse. Cancer Res. 2007 Mar;67(6):2391&#x2013;2393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17363554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ligibel JA, Giobbie-Hurder A, Olenczuk D, Campbell N, Salinardi T, Winer EP, et al. Impact of a mixed strength and endurance exercise intervention on levels of adiponectin, high molecular weight adiponectin and leptin in breast cancer survivors. Cancer Causes Control. 2009 Oct;20(8):1523&#x2013;1528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19434504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winzer BM, Whiteman DC, Reeves MM, Paratz JD. Physical activity and cancer prevention: a systematic review of clinical trials. Cancer Causes Control. 2011 Jun;22(6):811&#x2013;826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21461921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson KA, Singh MA. Effects of exercise on adiponectin: a systematic review. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2008 Feb;16(2):241&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18239630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Salles BF, Simao R, Fleck SJ, Dias I, Kraemer-Aguiar LG, Bouskela E. Effects of resistance training on cytokines. Int J Sports Me. 2010 Jul;31(7):441&#x2013;450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20432196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wren AM, Bloom SR. Gut hormones and appetite control. Gastroenterology. 2007 May;132(6):2116&#x2013;2130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17498507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rock CL, McEligot AJ, Flatt SW, Sobo EJ, Wilfley DE, Jones VE, et al. Eating pathology and obesity in women at risk for breast cancer recurrence. Int J Eat Disord. 2000 Mar;27(2):172&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10657890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>