<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">31714457</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-4287</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of strength and conditioning research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Strength Cond Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Combined Resistance Plus Aerobic Training on Body Composition, Muscle Strength, Aerobic Capacity, and Renal Function in Kidney Transplantation Subjects.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3243</StartPage><EndPage>3250</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3243-3250</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003274</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Lima, PS, de Campos, AS, de Faria Neto, O, Ferreira, TCA, Amorim, CEN, Stone, WJ, Prestes, J, Garcia, AMC, and Urtado, CB. Effects of combined resistance plus aerobic training on body composition, muscle strength, aerobic capacity, and renal function in kidney transplantation subjects. J Strength Cond Res 35(11): 3243-3250, 2021-Immunosuppression and a sedentary lifestyle may exacerbate complications such as early graft dysfunction and muscle loss, and reduce patient survival after kidney transplantation (KT). Therefore, the purpose of this study was to evaluate changes in body composition (BC), muscular strength, aerobic, and renal function in KT subjects submitted to combined resistance plus aerobic training. Twelve KT subjects were randomly assigned into groups: (G1) 12 weeks of combined training (3 males and 4 females, 54 &#xb1; 3 years); or (G2) nonexercise control (5 females, 43 &#xb1; 18 years). The subjects were evaluated for BC (dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry), estimated V&#x307;o2peak, right-hand maximal grip strength (RHMGS) and left-hand maximal grip strength (LHMGS), and renal function. Post-training revealed that G1 reduced body fat percentage (p = 0.046), uric acid (&#x394; = -0.87; p = 0.023), urea (&#x394; = -9.43; p = 0.032), and creatinine (&#x394; = -0.15; p = 0.045), increased fat-free mass, estimated V&#x307;o2peak, RHMGS, LHMGS (p &lt; 0.05), and estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) (&#x394; = 11.64; p = 0.017). G2 increased urea (&#x394; = 8.20; p = 0.017), creatinine (&#x394; = 0.37; p = 0.028), and decreased eGFR (&#x394; = -16.10; p = 0.038). After 12 weeks, urea (&#x394; = 24.94; p = 0.013), uric acid (&#x394; = 1.64; p = 0.044), and creatinine (&#x394; = 0.9; p = 0.011) were lower, whereas eGFR (&#x394; = 36.51; p = 0.009) was higher in G1. These data indicate that combined training instigates positive changes in BC, muscular strength, aerobic capacity, and renal function after KT.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2019 National Strength and Conditioning Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lima</LastName><ForeName>Paulo S</ForeName><Initials>PS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Program on Physical Education, Department of Physical Education, Federal University of Maranhao (UFMA), S&#xe3;o Luis, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Campos</LastName><ForeName>Alexandre S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Multiprofessional Program of Internship in Health, Kidney Health Care Unit, University Hospital of the Federal University of Maranhao (HU-UFMA), S&#xe3;o Luis, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Faria Neto</LastName><ForeName>Omar</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Program on Physical Education, Department of Physical Education, Catholic University of Brasilia, Brasilia, Federal District, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferreira</LastName><ForeName>Teresa C A</ForeName><Initials>TCA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kidney Transplant Unit, University Hospital of the Federal University of Maranhao (HU-UFMA), S&#xe3;o Luis, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Federal University of Maranh&#xe3;o (UFMA), Pinheiro, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amorim</LastName><ForeName>Carlos E N</ForeName><Initials>CEN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Federal University of Maranhao (UFMA), S&#xe3;o Luis, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stone</LastName><ForeName>Whitley J</ForeName><Initials>WJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nutrition, Kinesiology, and Psychological Sciences, University of Central Missouri, Missouri; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prestes</LastName><ForeName>Jonato</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduation Program on Physical Education, Department of Physical Education, Catholic University of Brasilia, Brasilia, Federal District, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garcia</LastName><ForeName>Alessandra M C</ForeName><Initials>AMC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Federal University of Maranhao (UFMA), S&#xe3;o Luis, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Urtado</LastName><ForeName>Christiano B</ForeName><Initials>CB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education, Federal University of Maranhao (UFMA), S&#xe3;o Luis, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Strength Cond Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9415084</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1064-8011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007668" MajorTopicYN="N">Kidney</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016030" MajorTopicYN="Y">Kidney Transplantation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Resistance Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31714457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0000000000003274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124278-202111000-00039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American Thoracic Society Committee. Proficiency standards for clinical pulmonary function laboratories. ATS statement: Guidelines for the six minute walk test. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 166: 111&#x2013;117, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong KA, Campbell SB, Hawley CM, et al. Obesity is associated with worsening cardiovascular risk factor profiles and proteinuria progression in renal transplant recipients. Am J Transpl 5: 2710&#x2013;2718, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barroso R, Silva-Filho AC, Dias CJ, et al. Effect of exercise training in heart rate variability, anxiety, depression, and sleep quality in kidney recipients: A preliminary study. J Health Psychol 24: 299&#x2013;308, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baum CL. Weight gain and cardiovascular risk after organ transplantation. JPEN 25: 114&#x2013;119, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bechtol CO. Grip test: The use of a dynamometer with adjustable handle spacings. J Bone Joint Surg Am 36A: 820&#x2013;824, 1954.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bottomley MJ, Harden PN. Update on the long-term complications of renal transplantation. Br Med Bull 106: 117&#x2013;134, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clunk JM, Lin CY, Curtis JJ. Variables affecting weight gain in renal transplant recipients. Am J Kidney Dis 38: 349&#x2013;353, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekstrand A, Schalin-J&#xe4;ntti C, L&#xf6;fman M, et al. The effect of (steroid) immunosuppression on skeletal muscle glycogen metabolism in subjects after kidney transplantation. Transplantation 61: 889&#x2013;893, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franz MJ, van Wormer JJ, Crain AL, et al. Weight-loss outcomes: A systematic review and meta-analysis of weight-loss clinical trials with a minimum 1-year follow-up. J Am Diet Assoc 107: 1755&#x2013;1767, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, et al. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, muscle skeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: Guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc 7: 1334&#x2013;1359, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon EJ, Prohaska T, Siminoff LA, Minich PJ, Sehgal AR. Needed: Tailored exercise regimens for kidney transplant recipients. Am J Kidney Dis 45: 769&#x2013;774, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon EJ, Prohaska TR, Gallant MP, et al. Longitudinal analysis of physical activity, fluid intake, and graft function among kidney transplant recipients. Transpl Int 22: 990&#x2013;998, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gore JL, Pham PT, Danovitch GM, et al. Obesity and outcome following renal transplantation. Am J Transpl 6: 357&#x2013;363, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isiklar I, Akin O, Demirag A, Niron EA. Effects of renal transplantation on body composition. Transpl Proc 30: 831&#x2013;832, 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan B, Meier-Kriesche HU. Renal transplantation: A half century of success and the long road ahead. J Am Soc Nephrol 15: 3270&#x2013;3271, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasiske BL, Vazquez MA, Harmon WE, et al. Recommendations for the outpatient surveillance of renal transplant recipients. American Society of Transplantation. J Am Soc Nephrol 11: S1&#x2013;S86, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kempeneers G, Noakes TD, van Zyl-Smit R, et al. Skeletal muscle limits the exercise tolerance of renal transplant recipients: Effects of a graded exercise training program. Am J Kidney Dis 16: 57&#x2013;65, 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovacs AZ, Molnar MZ, Szeifert L, et al. Sleep disorders, depressive symptoms and health-related quality of life: A cross-sectional comparison between kidney transplant recipients and waitlisted subjects on maintenance dialysis. Nephrol Dial Transpl 26: 1058&#x2013;1065, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagally KM, Robertson RJ. Construct validity of the OMNI resistance exercise scale. J Strength Cond Res 20: 252&#x2013;256, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levey AS, Stevens LA, Schmid CH, et al.; CKD-EPI (Chronic Kidney Disease Epidemiology Collaboration). A new equation to estimate glomerular filtration rate. Ann Intern Med 150: 604&#x2013;612, 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima PS, Campos ASD, Corr&#xea;a CS, et al. Effects of chronic physical activity on glomerular filtration rate, creatinine, and the markers of anemia of kidney transplantation subjects. Transpl Proc 50: 746&#x2013;749, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marinho SM, Moraes C, Barbosa JE, et al. Exercise training alters the bone mineral density of hemodialysis subjects. J Strength Cond Res 30: 2918&#x2013;2923, 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitch WE, Medina R, Grieber S, et al. Metabolic acidosis stimulates muscle protein degradation by activating the adenosine triphosphate-dependent pathway involving ubiquitin and proteasomes. J Clin Invest 93: 2127&#x2013;2133, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitch WE. Insights into the abnormalities of chronic renal disease attributed to malnutrition. J Am Soc Nephrol 13: S22&#x2013;S27, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyberg L, Hallste L, Nord&#xe9;n L, Hadimeri H, Wramner L. Physical performance does not improve in elderly subjects following successful kidney transplantation. Nephrol Dial Transpl 10: 86&#x2013;90, 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oguchi H, Tsujita M, Yazawa M, et al. The efficacy of exercise training in kidney transplant recipients: A meta-analysis and systematic review. Clin Exp Nephrol 23: 275&#x2013;284, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oterdoom LH, van Ree RM, de Vries APJ, et al. Urinary creatinine excretion reflecting muscle mass is a predictor of mortality and graft loss in renal transplant recipients. Transplantation 86: 391&#x2013;398, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Painter PL, Hector L, Ray K, et al. A randomized trial of exercise training after renal transplantation. Transplantation 74: 42&#x2013;48, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Painter PL, Hector L, Ray K, et al. Effects of exercise training on coronary heart disease risk factors in renal transplant recipients. Am J Kidney Dis 42: 362&#x2013;369, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Painter PL, Topp KS, Krasnoff JB, et al. Health-related fitness and quality of life following steroid withdrawal in renal transplant recipients. Kidney Int 63: 2309&#x2013;2316, 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Program TTPP. Realistic Expectations: A Guide for Post-transplant Kidney Subjects. Basel, Switzerland: Nutley, Roche Laboratories, Inc, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rengel M. Obesity and arterial hypertension in renal transplant patients. Nefrolog&#xed;a 22: 30, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Revanur VK, Jardine AG, Kingsmore DB, Jaques BC, Hamilton DH, Jindal RM. Influence of diabetes mellitus on patient and graft survival in recipients of kidney transplantation. Clin Transpl 15: 89&#x2013;94, 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhea MR. Determining the magnitude of treatment effects in strength training research through the use of the effect size. J Strength Cond Res 18: 918&#x2013;920, 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romano G, Simonella R, Falleti E, et al. Physical training effects in renal transplant recipients. Clin Transpl 24: 510&#x2013;514, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;tz T, Hudjetz H, Roske AE, et al. Weight gain in long-term survivors of kidney or liver transplantation: Another paradigm of sarcopenic obesity? Nutrition 28: 378&#x2013;383, 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirali AC, Bia MJ. Management of cardiovascular disease in renal transplant recipients. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 3: 491&#x2013;504, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stehman-Breen CO, Sherrard D, Walker A, Sadler R, Alem A, Lindberg J. Racial differences in bone mineral density and bone loss among end-stage renal disease subjects. Am J Kidney Dis 33: 941&#x2013;946, 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ting SM, Iqbal H, Kanji H, et al. Functional cardiovascular reserve predicts survival pre-kidney and post-kidney transplantation. J Am Soc Nephrol 25: 187&#x2013;195, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Ham EC, Kooman JP, Christiaans MH, Leunissen KM, van Hooff JP. Posttransplantation weight gain is predominantly due to an increase in body fat mass. Transplantation 70: 241&#x2013;242, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Ham EC, Kooman JP, Christiaans MH, van Hooff JP. Relation between steroid dose, body composition and physical activity in renal transplant subjects. Transplantation 69: 1591&#x2013;1598, 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Ham EC, Kooman JP, Schols AM, et al. Similarities in skeletal muscle strength and exercise capacity between renal transplant and hemodialysis subjects. Am J Transpl 5: 1957&#x2013;1965, 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vega J, Huidobro J, Barraa S, Haro D. Influence of weight gain during the first year of renal transplantation in graft survival and patients. Rev Med Chile 143: 961&#x2013;970, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K, Qu Q, Miao S, Zhang Y, Jing X. Discussion on the risk factors of developing cardiovascular diseases (CVD) after the kidney transplantation. Pak J Pharm Sci 30: 241&#x2013;246, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zelle DM, Corpeleijn E, Stolk RP, et al. Low physical activity and risk of cardiovascular and all-cause mortality in renal transplant recipients. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 6: 898&#x2013;905, 2011.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>