<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article article-type="case-report" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">JACC Case Rep</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">JACC Case Rep</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">4067</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">jacccasereps</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>JACC Case Reports</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">2666-0849</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Elsevier</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC13045555</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC13045555.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">13045555</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">13045555</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">41906561</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jaccas.2026.107150</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pii">S2666-0849(26)00298-6</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">107150</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Heart Failure and Cardiomyopathies</subject><subj-group><subject>Clinical Case</subject></subj-group></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Syncope in an Athlete With Apical Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy</article-title><subtitle>Ominous or Orthostatic?</subtitle></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" id="au1"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tatapudi</surname><given-names initials="S">Suhas</given-names></name><degrees>DO</degrees><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">a</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="au2"><name name-style="western"><surname>Dean</surname><given-names initials="JHL">John-Henry L.</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><email>johnhenry.l.dean.mil@health.mil</email><ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://twitter.com/JohnHenryDean">@JohnHenryDean</ext-link><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">b</xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp">∗</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="au3"><name name-style="western"><surname>Pabba</surname><given-names initials="K">Krishna</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff">c</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="au4"><name name-style="western"><surname>Martinez</surname><given-names initials="MW">Matthew W.</given-names></name><degrees>MD</degrees><xref rid="aff4" ref-type="aff">d</xref></contrib><aff id="aff1"><label>a</label>Department of Internal Medicine, University of Houston/HCA Kingwood Medical Center, Kingwood, Texas, USA</aff><aff id="aff2"><label>b</label>Division of Cardiology, Brooke Army Medical Center, San Antonio, Texas, USA</aff><aff id="aff3"><label>c</label>Department of Cardiovascular Medicine, Baylor Scott &amp; White Medical Center, Temple, Texas, USA</aff><aff id="aff4"><label>d</label>Department of Cardiovascular Medicine, Morristown Medical Center, Morristown, New Jersey, USA</aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="cor1"><label>∗</label><bold>Address for correspondence:</bold> Dr John-Henry L. Dean, Brooke Army Medical Center, 3551 Roger Brooke Drive, JBSA-Fort Sam, Houston, Texas 78234, USA. <email>johnhenry.l.dean.mil@health.mil</email><ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://twitter.com/JohnHenryDean">@JohnHenryDean</ext-link></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><day>25</day><month>3</month><year>2026</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>25</day><month>3</month><year>2026</year></pub-date><volume>31</volume><issue>12</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">510833</issue-id><elocation-id>107150</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>29</day><month>11</month><year>2025</year></date><date date-type="rev-recd"><day>27</day><month>1</month><year>2026</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>27</day><month>1</month><year>2026</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>25</day><month>03</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>03</day><month>04</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2026-04-03 10:25:15.667"><day>03</day><month>04</month><year>2026</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncndlicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open access article under the CC BY-NC-ND license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/).</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="main.pdf"/><abstract id="abs0010"><sec><title>Background</title><p>Syncope in athletes with hypertrophic cardiomyopathy (HCM) requires careful evaluation, as etiologies range from benign to life-threatening. Guidelines emphasize individualized risk stratification and shared decision-making.</p></sec><sec><title>Case Summary</title><p>A 20-year-old basketball player experienced a syncopal episode when rising from a seated position, preceded by progressive lightheadedness and visual dimming, without chest discomfort or palpitations. Electrocardiogram abnormalities prompted further imaging, confirming the diagnosis of apical HCM. Evaluation demonstrated no left ventricular outflow tract obstruction at rest or with maximal-effort stress testing, and no exertional arrhythmias were observed. The episode was attributed to orthostatic syncope in a preload-dependent structurally abnormal left ventricle. He continued sports participation with hydration counseling, annual imaging, rhythm monitoring, and genetic evaluation, without recurrent events.</p></sec><sec><title>Discussion</title><p>This case highlights the importance of accurately identifying the etiology of syncope in athletes with HCM and supports individualized, risk informed sport participation rather than universal restriction.</p></sec><sec><title>Take-Home Message</title><p>Syncope in athletes with HCM warrants comprehensive evaluation and tailored return-to-play decisions.</p></sec></abstract><abstract abstract-type="graphical" id="abs0015"><title>Visual Summary</title><fig id="undfig1" position="anchor" orientation="portrait"><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="ga1.jpg"/></fig></abstract><kwd-group id="kwrds0010"><title>Key Words</title><kwd>athlete</kwd><kwd>hypertrophic cardiomyopathy</kwd><kwd>sudden cardiac death</kwd><kwd>syncope</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-ND</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta><def-list><title>Abbreviations and Acronyms</title><def-item><term id="kwrd0035">ECG</term><def><p>electrocardiogram</p></def></def-item><def-item><term id="kwrd0045">HCM</term><def><p>hypertrophic cardiomyopathy</p></def></def-item><def-item><term id="kwrd0055">LV</term><def><p>left ventricular</p></def></def-item><def-item><term id="kwrd0065">LVOT</term><def><p>left ventricular outflow tract</p></def></def-item><def-item><term id="kwrd0075">SCD</term><def><p>sudden cardiac death</p></def></def-item></def-list></front><body><p id="p0010">
<fig id="dfig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Visual Summary</label><caption><p>Diagnostic Considerations in the Evaluation of Athletes With Syncope</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gr4.jpg"/></fig>
</p><sec id="sec1"><title>History of Presentation</title><p id="p0015">A previously healthy 20-year-old man is evaluated in the Sports Cardiology Clinic after experiencing a brief syncopal episode while playing basketball. While walking to the bench in between games, he began to experience progressive lightheadedness, dizziness, and visual dimming. He did not have chest discomfort or palpitations. Upon standing from the bench, he fell to the floor with syncope that lasted for a few seconds. After regaining consciousness, he continued to feel lightheaded and fatigued until he drank water. After appropriate rehydration, he resumed play without recurrence of symptoms. During his clinical evaluation, he reported a several-year history of similar prodromal symptoms without syncope during basketball games. He also described intermittent, nonexertional, pressure-like chest discomfort lasting minutes to hours. Vital signs demonstrated elevated blood pressure (149/82 mm Hg), and cardiovascular examination was otherwise unremarkable, with no murmurs elicited even with dynamic maneuvers.<boxed-text id="dtbox1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><sec id="dtbox1sec1"><title>Take-Home Messages</title><p id="p0020"><list list-type="simple" id="ulist0010"><list-item id="u0010"><label>•</label><p id="p0025">Syncope in athletes with apical hypertrophic cardiomyopathy requires a meticulous, multimodality evaluation to distinguish benign causes from potential arrhythmic mechanisms with implications for sudden cardiac death risk.</p></list-item><list-item id="u0015"><label>•</label><p id="p0030">Contemporary sports cardiology guidelines support individualized, risk-based return-to-play decisions, and athletes with hypertrophic cardiomyopathy may safely participate when high-risk features are absent and expert-directed surveillance is in place.</p></list-item></list></p></sec></boxed-text></p></sec><sec id="sec2"><title>Past Medical History</title><p id="p0035">He had no medical comorbidities, no family history of hypertrophic cardiomyopathy (HCM) or sudden cardiac death (SCD), and no substance use. He consumed energy drinks occasionally but was actively reducing intake.</p></sec><sec id="sec3"><title>Differential Diagnosis</title><p id="p0040">The differential diagnosis for exertional syncope in this young athlete included orthostatic syncope, reflex syncope, vasovagal syncope, HCM with dynamic left ventricular (LV) outflow tract (LVOT) obstruction, ventricular arrhythmias, and valvular pathology such as aortic stenosis.</p></sec><sec id="sec4"><title>Investigations</title><p id="p0045">An electrocardiogram (ECG) demonstrated normal sinus rhythm with marked ST-T wave abnormalities concerning for apical HCM (<xref rid="fig1" ref-type="fig">Figure 1</xref>). Transthoracic echocardiography revealed normal LV systolic function with moderately increased septal wall thickness without significant apical tapering, further supporting the diagnosis of apical HCM. There was no LVOT obstruction with rest or Valsalva.<fig id="fig1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>12-Lead Electrocardiogram Demonstrating Normal Sinus Rhythm With Sinus Arrhythmia and Marked ST-T Wave Abnormalities Concerning for Apical Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gr1.jpg"/></fig></p><p id="p0050">An exercise stress echocardiogram was performed for further evaluation. The stress ECG portion was nondiagnostic because of resting ST-T wave abnormalities, though there was no echocardiographic evidence of ischemia or LVOT obstruction with maximal exertion. In addition, no arrhythmias were observed.</p><p id="p0055">Cardiac magnetic resonance demonstrated findings consistent with apical HCM with diffusely increased LV myocardial wall thickness (<xref rid="fig2" ref-type="fig">Figure 2</xref>) and normal biventricular systolic function. Focal midmyocardial late gadolinium enhancement was noted within the mid-to-distal anteroseptal LV wall (<xref rid="fig3" ref-type="fig">Figure 3</xref>). T<sub>1</sub> mapping times and extracellular volume were within normal limits throughout the remainder of the myocardium.<fig id="fig2" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>4-Chamber Long-Axis View at End Diastole Showing Increased Myocardial Wall Thickness Without Apical Tapering Consistent With Apical Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gr2.jpg"/></fig><fig id="fig3" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>Short-Axis Slice Highlighting the Focal Midmyocardial Late Gadolinium Enhancement Localized to the Apical and Apical-Septal Segments</p></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="gr3.jpg"/></fig></p></sec><sec id="sec5"><title>Management</title><p id="p0060">After comprehensive evaluation and structured risk stratification, his syncope was attributed to orthostatic syncope in the context of a preload-dependent structurally susceptible ventricle sensitive to intravascular volume depletion. Through shared decision-making, he continued to play basketball with education on appropriate hydration and stimulant avoidance, annual transthoracic echocardiography, ambulatory rhythm monitoring, and referral for genetic counseling and testing per the 2024 multisociety Guideline on the Management of HCM.</p></sec><sec id="sec6"><title>Outcome and Follow-Up</title><p id="p0065">With attention to sufficient fluid intake and vigilance for prodromal symptoms, he has had no recurrent episodes of syncope and continues participating in basketball. Annual SCD risk stratification is ongoing, and genetic testing results are pending.</p></sec><sec id="sec7"><title>Discussion</title><p id="p0070">This case illustrates the nuanced evaluation of syncope in an athlete with apical HCM and the evolving landscape of risk assessment and sports participation in individuals with genetic cardiomyopathies. An important initial observation is that historical features that may suggest benign etiologies in the general population can carry different diagnostic implications in patients with structural heart disease. Orthostatic or reflex syncope is classically preceded by prodromal symptoms such as lightheadedness, visual dimming, or dizziness, whereas arrhythmogenic syncope more often presents as an abrupt loss of consciousness without prodromal symptoms and in the absence of positional triggers. Accordingly, a detailed history and physical examination are central to the initial assessment of syncope and to differentiating between cardiac and noncardiac causes.<xref rid="bib1" ref-type="bibr"><sup>1</sup></xref> Key historical elements include the timing of symptoms in relation to exertion, the absence or presence of prodromal symptoms, associated symptoms (eg, palpitations, chest pain, and shortness of breath), and a family history of SCD. This is where a collaborative team approach, including a sports cardiologist, can be helpful.</p><p id="p0075">Importantly, syncope is relatively common in HCM, reported in approximately 15.8% of patients, and the underlying mechanism remains unexplained in the majority (91%) of cases.<xref rid="bib2" ref-type="bibr"><sup>2</sup></xref> This highlights the diagnostic uncertainty that often surrounds syncope in HCM and underscores the importance of careful clinical adjudication in athletes rather than reflexively attributing symptoms to malignant etiologies and restricting from sport. In this athlete, several features strongly supported a more benign clinical diagnosis consistent with orthostatic syncope, including the presence of prodromal symptoms and the positional trigger of standing from a seated position. Nevertheless, although the historical features were quite reassuring in this case, comprehensive evaluation of syncope in athletes requires integration with structured risk stratification to appropriately contextualize symptoms and guide management.</p><p id="p0080">Initial studies in the evaluation of syncope in athletes with HCM include a 12-lead ECG, echocardiogram, and an exercise stress test, commonly performed as an exercise stress echocardiogram to assess for dynamic LV outflow tract obstruction. If nondiagnostic or if high-risk features are present, advanced imaging (eg, cardiac magnetic resonance) should be considered.<xref rid="bib1" ref-type="bibr"><sup>1</sup></xref> To rule out underlying arrhythmia as a cause, ambulatory ECG monitoring and implantable loop recorders may also be used.<xref rid="bib3" ref-type="bibr"><sup>3</sup></xref><sup>,</sup><xref rid="bib4" ref-type="bibr"><sup>4</sup></xref> Genetic testing may be helpful to exclude other types of arrhythmic risk such as catecholaminergic polymorphic ventricular tachycardia.</p><p id="p0085">As in all patients with HCM, athletes must also undergo risk stratification for SCD, considering any history of unexplained syncope, a family history of SCD, maximal LV wall thickness, the presence of nonsustained ventricular tachycardia, and imaging findings such as apical aneurysm or extensive fibrosis.<xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr"><sup>5</sup></xref><sup>,</sup><xref rid="bib6" ref-type="bibr"><sup>6</sup></xref> A strong predictor of SCD is when a recent syncopal episode is thought to be arrhythmogenic, which then may warrant consideration of implantable cardioverter-defibrillator implantation.<xref rid="bib3" ref-type="bibr"><sup>3</sup></xref><sup>,</sup><xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr"><sup>5</sup></xref> This risk assessment for SCD should be repeated every 1 to 2 years, especially in the younger population whose phenotype may evolve over time.<xref rid="bib1" ref-type="bibr"><sup>1</sup></xref><sup>,</sup><xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr"><sup>5</sup></xref></p><p id="p0090">Historically, athletes with HCM were uniformly advised to restrict or avoid sports participation. Now, individualized, risk-based recommendations are in place. Those with phenotype-positive HCM may compete in sports in the setting of appropriate therapy, expert assessment, and emergency action planning (access to automated external defibrillator), as long as the athlete shows no signs of high-risk features (eg, exercise-induced syncope or documented ventricular arrhythmias).<xref rid="bib1" ref-type="bibr"><sup>1</sup></xref><sup>,</sup><xref rid="bib7" ref-type="bibr"><sup>7</sup></xref><sup>,</sup><xref rid="bib8" ref-type="bibr"><sup>8</sup></xref> The LIVE-HCM and Return-to-Play in Elite Athlete studies further support this approach. In this prospective cohort study, the risk of death or life-threatening arrhythmia was not higher among individuals with HCM or genotype-positive/phenotype-negative patients who continue vigorous exercise compared with those who were sedentary or engaging in moderate intensity exercise.<xref rid="bib9" ref-type="bibr"><sup>9</sup></xref><sup>,</sup><xref rid="bib10" ref-type="bibr"><sup>10</sup></xref> These findings reinforce the role of shared decision-making in this population and suggest that appropriately evaluated and monitored athletes with HCM may safely engage in higher-intensity sports.</p><p id="p0095">In summary, the evaluation and management of syncope in athletic patients with HCM requires a multidisciplinary, evidence-based approach. Careful history-taking, targeted diagnostics, and ongoing risk assessment are essential for optimizing outcomes and guiding safe return-to-play decisions.<xref rid="bib1" ref-type="bibr"><sup>1</sup></xref><sup>,</sup><xref rid="bib5" ref-type="bibr"><sup>5</sup></xref><sup>,</sup><xref rid="bib7" ref-type="bibr"><sup>7</sup></xref></p></sec><sec id="sec8"><title>Conclusions</title><p id="p0100">This case highlights the importance of comprehensive evaluation, multimodality imaging, and individualized risk stratification in athletes with apical HCM and syncope. Etiologies range from benign orthostatic intolerance to ventricular arrhythmias, each necessitating unique management strategies and shared decision-making regarding sports participation.</p></sec><sec sec-type="COI-statement" id="coi0010"><title>Funding Support and Author Disclosures</title><p id="p0105">The authors have reported that they have no relationships relevant to the contents of this paper to disclose.</p></sec></body><back><ref-list id="cebib0010"><title>References</title><ref id="bib1"><label>1</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref1"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lampert</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Chung</surname><given-names>E.H.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ackerman</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>2024 HRS expert consensus statement on arrhythmias in the athlete: evaluation, treatment, and return to play</article-title><source>Heart Rhythm</source><volume>21</volume><issue>10</issue><year>2024</year><fpage>e151</fpage><lpage>e252</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.hrthm.2024.05.018</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38763377</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib2"><label>2</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref2"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Mascia</surname><given-names>G.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Crotti</surname><given-names>L.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Groppelli</surname><given-names>A.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Syncope in hypertrophic cardiomyopathy (part I): an updated systematic review and meta-analysis</article-title><source>Int J Cardiol</source><volume>357</volume><year>2022</year><fpage>88</fpage><lpage>94</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2022.03.028</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35304190</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib3"><label>3</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref3"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Shen</surname><given-names>W.K.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Sheldon</surname><given-names>R.S.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Benditt</surname><given-names>D.G.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>2017 ACC/AHA/HRS guideline for the evaluation and management of patients with syncope: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on clinical practice guidelines and the heart rhythm society</article-title><source>J Am Coll Cardiol</source><volume>70</volume><issue>5</issue><year>2017</year><fpage>e39</fpage><lpage>e110</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2017.03.003</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28286221</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib4"><label>4</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref4"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ommen</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Semsarian</surname><given-names>C.</given-names></name></person-group><article-title>Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy: a practical approach to guideline directed management</article-title><source>Lancet</source><volume>398</volume><issue>10316</issue><year>2021</year><fpage>2102</fpage><lpage>2108</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(21)01205-8</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34600606</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib5"><label>5</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref5"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Steinberg</surname><given-names>J.S.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Varma</surname><given-names>N.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Cygankiewicz</surname><given-names>I.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>2017 ISHNE-HRS expert consensus statement on ambulatory ECG and external cardiac monitoring/telemetry</article-title><source>Heart Rhythm</source><volume>14</volume><issue>7</issue><year>2017</year><fpage>e55</fpage><lpage>e96</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.hrthm.2017.03.038</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">28495301</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib6"><label>6</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref6"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Zampieri</surname><given-names>M.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Saberi</surname><given-names>S.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>D'Ascenzi</surname><given-names>F.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy: changing the paradigm of exercise prescription and competitive sport participation</article-title><source>Eur Heart J</source><year>2025</year><object-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">ehaf770</object-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehaf770</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">41065586</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib7"><label>7</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref7"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ommen</surname><given-names>S.R.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ho</surname><given-names>C.Y.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Asif</surname><given-names>I.M.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>2024 AHA/ACC/AMSSM/HRS/PACES/SCMR guideline for the management of hypertrophic cardiomyopathy: a report of the American Heart Association/American College of Cardiology Joint Committee on clinical practice guidelines</article-title><source>J Am Coll Cardiol</source><volume>83</volume><issue>23</issue><year>2024</year><fpage>2324</fpage><lpage>2405</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2024.02.014</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38727647</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib8"><label>8</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref8"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kim</surname><given-names>J.H.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Baggish</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Levine</surname><given-names>B.D.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Clinical considerations for competitive sports participation for athletes with cardiovascular abnormalities: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association and American College of Cardiology</article-title><source>J Am Coll Cardiol</source><volume>85</volume><issue>10</issue><year>2025</year><fpage>1059</fpage><lpage>1108</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2024.12.025</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39976316</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12145891</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib9"><label>9</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref9"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lampert</surname><given-names>R.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Ackerman</surname><given-names>M.J.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Marino</surname><given-names>B.S.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Vigorous exercise in patients with hypertrophic cardiomyopathy</article-title><source>JAMA Cardiol</source><volume>8</volume><issue>6</issue><year>2023</year><fpage>595</fpage><lpage>605</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1001/jamacardio.2023.1042</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37195701</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10193262</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="bib10"><label>10</label><element-citation publication-type="journal" id="sref10"><person-group person-group-type="author"><name name-style="western"><surname>Martinez</surname><given-names>K.A.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Bos</surname><given-names>J.M.</given-names></name><name name-style="western"><surname>Baggish</surname><given-names>A.L.</given-names></name><etal/></person-group><article-title>Return-to-play for elite athletes with genetic heart diseases predisposing to sudden cardiac death</article-title><source>J Am Coll Cardiol</source><volume>82</volume><issue>8</issue><year>2023</year><fpage>661</fpage><lpage>670</lpage><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37587576</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="doi" assigning-authority="pmc">10.1016/j.jacc.2023.05.059</pub-id></element-citation></ref></ref-list><fn-group><fn id="d36e32"><p id="ntpara0015aa">The authors attest they are in compliance with human studies committees and animal welfare regulations of the authors’ institutions and Food and Drug Administration guidelines, including patient consent where appropriate. For more information, visit the <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.jacc.org/author-center" id="interref1">Author Center</ext-link>.</p></fn></fn-group></back></article></pmc-articleset>