<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40316640</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Real-time prediction of early concrete compressive strength using AI and hydration monitoring.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>15463</StartPage><MedlinePgn>15463</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">15463</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-97060-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The continuous evolution of construction technologies, particularly in reinforced concrete production, demands advanced, reliable, and efficient methodologies for real-time monitoring and prediction of concrete compressive strength. Traditional laboratory methods for assessing compressive strength are time-intensive and can introduce delays in construction workflows. This study introduces a comprehensive framework for a system designed to predict early-age compressive strength of concrete through continuous monitoring of the cement hydration process using a custom artificial intelligence (AI) model. The system integrates a network of temperature sensors, communication modules, and a centralized database server to collect, transmit, and analyze real-time data during the concrete curing process. The AI model, a deep neural network leverages this data to generate accurate strength predictions. The system architecture emphasizes scalability, robustness, and integration with existing construction management systems. Empirical results indicate that the proposed system achieves high predictive accuracy, with an R<sup>2</sup> value of 0.996 and RMSE of 0.143&#xa0;MPa, offering a robust tool for real-time decision-making in construction. This study also critically evaluates the system's performance, identifying key strengths such as predictive accuracy and real-time processing capabilities, and addresses challenges related to wireless communication reliability and sensor power supply. Recommendations are provided for enhancing system precision, improving communication technologies, optimizing power management, and ensuring scalability across diverse construction contexts. The developed system, which is part of the "CONCRESENSE" project and protected under European patent number 245107 (2024), represents a significant advancement in construction technology, with substantial implications for enhancing the safety, efficiency, and quality of reinforced concrete structures.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marchewka</LastName><ForeName>Adam</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Telecommunications and Computer Sciences, University of Science and Technology, Bydgoszcz, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ziolkowski</LastName><ForeName>Patryk</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Civil and Environmental Engineering, Gdansk University of Technology, Gabriela Narutowicza 11/12, 80-233, Gdansk, Poland. patziolk@pg.edu.pl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garc&#xed;a Gal&#xe1;n</LastName><ForeName>Sebasti&#xe1;n</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Telecommunication Department, University of Ja&#xe9;n, Linares, Ja&#xe9;n, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>CONCRESENS_CTWT_II.4.0_1</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Education and Science (MEiN)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40316640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12048722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-97060-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-97060-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Asmara, Y. P. <i>Concrete Reinforcement Degradation and Rehabilitation: Damages, Corrosion and Prevention</i> (Springer Nature, 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mas&#x117;nas, V., Me&#x161;k&#x117;nas, A. &amp; Valivonis, J. Analysis of the bearing capacity of reinforced concrete dapped-end beams. <i>Appl. Sci.</i><b>13</b>, 5228 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app13095228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litzner, H.-U. &amp; Becker, A. Design of concrete structures for durability and strength to Eurocode 2. <i>Mater. Struct.</i><b>32</b>, 323&#x2013;330 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02479623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilimaa, J., Gamil, Y. &amp; Zhaka, V. Formwork engineering for sustainable concrete construction. <i>CivilEng</i><b>4</b>, 1098&#x2013;1120 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/civileng4040060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akber, M. Z. Improving the experience of machine learning in compressive strength prediction of industrial concrete considering mixing proportions, engineered ratios and atmospheric features. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>444</b>, 137884 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, L. et al. Prediction of concrete strength considering thermal damage using a modified strength-maturity model. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>400</b>, 132779 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mostafaei, H., Badarloo, B., Chamasemani, N. F., Rostampour, M. A. &amp; Lehner, P. Investigating the effects of concrete mix design on the environmental impacts of reinforced concrete structures. <i>Buildings</i><b>13</b>, 1313 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings13051313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamada, H., Alattar, A., Tayeh, B., Yahaya, F. &amp; Almeshal, I. Influence of different curing methods on the compressive strength of ultra-high-performance concrete: A comprehensive review. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater.</i><b>17</b>, e01390 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziolkowski, P., Niedostatkiewicz, M. &amp; Kang, S.-B. Model-based adaptive machine learning approach in concrete mix design. <i>Materials</i><b>14</b>, 1661 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma14071661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8036661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33800672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziolkowski, P. &amp; Niedostatkiewicz, M. Machine learning techniques in concrete mix design. <i>Materials</i><b>12</b>, 1256 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma12081256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6515295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30999557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziolkowski, P. Computational complexity and its influence on predictive capabilities of machine learning models for concrete mix design. <i>Materials</i><b>16</b>, 5956 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16175956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10489033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37687648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reichenbach, S. &amp; Kromoser, B. State of practice of automation in precast concrete production. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>43</b>, 102527 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2021.102527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, H., Vu, T., Vo, T. P. &amp; Thai, H.-T. Efficient machine learning models for prediction of concrete strengths. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>266</b>, 120950 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyngdoh, G. A., Zaki, M., Krishnan, N. M. A. &amp; Das, S. Prediction of concrete strengths enabled by missing data imputation and interpretable machine learning. <i>Cem. Concr. Compos.</i><b>128</b>, 104414 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji, Y., Zhang, X., Pel, L. &amp; Sun, Z. NMR investigations on Cl<sup>&#x2212;</sup> and Na <sup>+</sup> ion binding during the early hydration process of C<sub>3</sub>S, C<sub>3</sub>A and cement paste: a combined modelling and experimental study. <i>Compos B Eng</i> 111624 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, H. et al. Mechanical and durability properties of blended OPC mortar modified by low-carbon belite (C<sub>2</sub>S) nanoparticles. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>305</b>, 127087 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.127087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pyzalski, M. et al. The effect of biological corrosion on the hydration processes of synthetic tricalcium aluminate (C<sub>3</sub>A). <i>Materials</i><b>16</b>, 2225 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16062225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10058350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36984110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H., De Leon, D. &amp; Farzam, H. C<sub>4</sub>AF reactivity&#x2013;chemistry and hydration of industrial cement. <i>ACI Mater. J.</i><b>111</b> (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pichler, C., Schmid, M., Traxl, R. &amp; Lackner, R. Influence of curing temperature dependent microstructure on early-age concrete strength development. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>102</b>, 48&#x2013;59 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2017.08.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krstulovi&#x107;, R. &amp; Dabi&#x107;, P. A conceptual model of the cement hydration process. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>30</b>, 693&#x2013;698 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0008-8846(00)00231-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>John, E. &amp; Lothenbach, B. Cement hydration mechanisms through time&#x2013;a review. <i>J. Mater. Sci.</i><b>58</b>, 9805&#x2013;9833 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10853-023-08651-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, T., Ma, B., Jiang, D., Jiang, Q. &amp; Jin, Z. Comparative research on the effect of various mineral admixtures on the early hydration process of cement. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>301</b>, 124372 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor, H. F. W. <i>Cement Chemistry</i> Vol. 2 (Thomas Telford, 1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neville, A. M. <i>Properties of Concrete</i> 58&#x2013;661 (Pearson Education Limited, 2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin, J. et al. Environmental impact and thermal cracking resistance of low heat cement (LHC) and moderate heat cement (MHC) concrete at early ages. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>32</b>, 101668 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H. et al. Gradient microstructure and strain field at interfacial zone between cement-based repair and concrete substrate. <i>Compos. B Eng.</i><b>260</b>, 110775 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2023.110775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gajda, J. <i>Mass concrete for buildings and bridges</i> (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacGregor, J. G., Wight, J. K., Teng, S. &amp; Irawan, P. <i>Reinforced Concrete: Mechanics and Design</i> Vol. 3 (Prentice Hall, 1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang, Y., Xie, Y., Long, G. &amp; He, F. Hydration phase and pore structure evolution of hardened cement paste at elevated temperature. <i>J. Cent. South Univ.</i><b>28</b>, 1665&#x2013;1678 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11771-021-4725-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espinosa, R. M. &amp; Franke, L. Influence of the age and drying process on pore structure and sorption isotherms of hardened cement paste. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>36</b>, 1969&#x2013;1984 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2006.06.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escalante-Garcia, J. I. &amp; Sharp, J. H. The effect of temperature on the early hydration of Portland cement and blended cements. <i>Adv. Cem. Res.</i><b>12</b>, 121&#x2013;130 (2000).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1680/adcr.2000.12.3.121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scrivener, K., Ouzia, A., Juilland, P. &amp; Mohamed, A. K. Advances in understanding cement hydration mechanisms. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>124</b>, 105823 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dung, N. T. &amp; Unluer, C. Advances in the hydration of reactive MgO cement blends incorporating different magnesium carbonates. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>294</b>, 123573 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seleem, H. E. H., Rashad, A. M. &amp; Elsokary, T. Effect of elevated temperature on physico-mechanical properties of blended cement concrete. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>25</b>, 1009&#x2013;1017 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2010.06.078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z. &amp; Ding, Z. Property improvement of Portland cement by incorporating with metakaolin and slag. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>33</b>, 579&#x2013;584 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0008-8846(02)01025-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schindler, A. K. &amp; Folliard, K. J. Heat of hydration models for cementitious materials. <i>ACI Mater. J.</i><b>102</b>, 24 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chidiac, S. E. &amp; Shafikhani, M. Cement degree of hydration in mortar and concrete. <i>J. Therm. Anal. Calorim.</i><b>138</b>, 2305&#x2013;2313 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10973-019-08800-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skibsted, J. Characterization of supplementary cementitious materials and their quantification in cement blends by solid-state NMR. In <i>Ind. Waste Charact. Modif. Appl. Residues</i> 1st edn 3&#x2013;32 (De Gruyter, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson, I. G., Skibsted, J., Black, L. &amp; Kirkpatrick, R. J. Characterisation of cement hydrate phases by TEM, NMR and Raman spectroscopy. <i>Adv. Cem. Res.</i><b>22</b>, 233&#x2013;248 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1680/adcr.2010.22.4.233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pargar, F., Koleva, D. A., Koenders, E. A. B. &amp; van Breugel, K. Monitoring the electrochemical response of chloride sensors embedded in cement paste. <i>MRS Online Proc. Libr. OPL</i><b>1768</b>, imrc2014-6d (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J., Qin, L. &amp; Li, Z. Hydration monitoring of cement-based materials with resistivity and ultrasonic methods. <i>Mater. Struct.</i><b>42</b>, 15&#x2013;24 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1617/s11527-008-9363-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta, P. K. Concrete, microstructure, properties, and materials (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran, D.-L., Mouret, M. &amp; Cassagnab&#xe8;re, F. Impact of the porosity and moisture state of coarse aggregates, and binder nature on the structure of the paste-aggregate interface: Elementary model study. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>319</b>, 126112 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.126112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ndahirwa, D., Zmamou, H., Lenormand, H. &amp; Leblanc, N. The role of supplementary cementitious materials in hydration, durability and shrinkage of cement-based materials, their environmental and economic benefits: A review. <i>Clean. Mater.</i><b>5</b>, 100123 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clema.2022.100123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Biajawi, M. I., Embong, R., Muthusamy, K., Ismail, N. &amp; Obianyo, I. I. Recycled coal bottom ash as sustainable materials for cement replacement in cementitious Composites: A review. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>338</b>, 127624 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.127624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang, X. et al. Influence of curing temperature on the hydration and strength development of Class G Portland cement. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>156</b>, 106776 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2022.106776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ndekugri, I., Braimah, N. &amp; Gameson, R. Delay analysis within construction contracting organizations. <i>J. Constr. Eng. Manag.</i><b>134</b>, 692&#x2013;700 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)0733-9364(2008)134:9(692)</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winters, J. B. &amp; Dolan, C. W. Concrete breakout capacity of cast-in-place concrete anchors in early-age concrete. <i>PCI J.</i><b>59</b> (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, W., Lin, X., Bao, D. W. &amp; Xie, Y. M. A review of formwork systems for modern concrete construction. In <i>Structures</i> Vol. 38 52&#x2013;63 (Elsevier, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaaban, I. G., Hosni, A. H., Montaser, W. M. &amp; El-Sayed, M. M. Effect of premature loading on punching resistance of reinforced concrete flat slabs. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater.</i><b>12</b>, e00320 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, S. W., Yao, Y., Andrade, C. &amp; Li, Z. J. Recent durability studies on concrete structure. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>78</b>, 143&#x2013;154 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2015.05.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>John, S. T., Roy, B. K., Sarkar, P. &amp; Davis, R. IoT enabled real-time monitoring system for early-age compressive strength of concrete. <i>J. Constr. Eng. Manag.</i><b>146</b>, 05019020 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)CO.1943-7862.0001754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeh, I.-C. Modeling of strength of high-performance concrete using artificial neural networks. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>28</b>, 1797&#x2013;1808 (1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0008-8846(98)00165-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou, J.-S. &amp; Tsai, C.-F. Concrete compressive strength analysis using a combined classification and regression technique. <i>Autom. Constr.</i><b>24</b>, 52&#x2013;60 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autcon.2012.02.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, F. et al. Compressive strength prediction of recycled concrete based on deep learning. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>175</b>, 562&#x2013;569 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.04.169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, H., Yang, J. &amp; Chen, X. A convolution-based deep learning approach for estimating compressive strength of fiber reinforced concrete at elevated temperatures. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>313</b>, 125437 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.125437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, H., Yang, J., Chen, X., Zhang, D. &amp; Gan, V. J. L. Tempnet: A graph convolutional network for temperature field prediction of fire-damaged concrete. <i>Expert Syst. Appl.</i><b>238</b>, 121997 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eswa.2023.121997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhilwade, V., Delhi, V. S. K., Nanthagopalan, P., Das, A. K. &amp; Modi, K. Predicting labour productivity for formwork activities in high-rise building construction: a case study. <i>Asian J. Civ. Eng.</i><b>24</b>, 959&#x2013;968 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s42107-022-00545-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pronk, A., Brancart, S. &amp; Sanders, F. Reusing timber formwork in building construction: Testing, redesign, and socio-economic reflection. <i>Urban Plan.</i><b>7</b>, 81&#x2013;96 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17645/up.v7i2.5117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham, V. H. S., Dau, T. D. &amp; Tran, L. A. Application of multi-criteria analysis in the selection of formwork material for high-rise building construction projects. <i>Cogent Eng.</i><b>11</b>, 2367121 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23311916.2024.2367121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elansary, A., Mabrouk, A. &amp; El-Attar, A. Staged-construction analysis of high-rise buildings: A literature review and future perspectives. <i>Struct. Design Tall Spec. Build.</i><b>32</b>, e2043 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/tal.2043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allam, A., Elbeltagi, E., Abouelsaad, M. N. &amp; E. El Madawy, M. Integrated BIM-GA approach for slab formwork design optimization. <i>Constr. Innov.</i> (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awad, T., Guardiola, J. &amp; Fra&#xed;z, D. Sustainable construction: Improving productivity through lean construction. <i>Sustainability</i><b>13</b>, 13877 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su132413877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vipulanandan, C. <i>Smart Cement: Development, Testing</i> (Modeling and Real-Time Monitoring. CRC Press, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, Z., Zhong, B. &amp; Xiong, R. Sensor design based on wireless measurement of corrosion monitoring of reinforced concrete structure. <i>Wirel. Commun. Mob. Comput.</i><b>2022</b>, 2608490 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/2608490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sofi, A., Regita, J. J., Rane, B. &amp; Lau, H. H. Structural health monitoring using wireless smart sensor network&#x2013;An overview. <i>Mech. Syst. Signal Process.</i><b>163</b>, 108113 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ymssp.2021.108113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdulkarem, M., Samsudin, K., Rokhani, F. Z. &amp; Rasid, A. Wireless sensor network for structural health monitoring: A contemporary review of technologies, challenges, and future direction. <i>Struct. Health Monit.</i><b>19</b>, 693&#x2013;735 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1475921719854528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asteris, P. G. &amp; Mokos, V. G. Concrete compressive strength using artificial neural networks. <i>Neural Comput. Appl.</i><b>32</b>, 11807&#x2013;11826 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00521-019-04663-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, S.-J., Ahn, D., You, I., Yoo, D.-Y. &amp; Kang, Y.-S. Wireless cement-based sensor for self-monitoring of railway concrete infrastructures. <i>Autom. Constr.</i><b>119</b>, 103323 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autcon.2020.103323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik, M., Bhattacharyya, S. K. &amp; Barai, S. V. Thermal and mechanical properties of concrete and its constituents at elevated temperatures: A review. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>270</b>, 121398 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kako, S. A comparative study about accuracy levels of resistance temperature detectors RTDs composed of platinum, copper, and nickel. <i>Al Nahrain J. Eng. Sci.</i><b>26</b>, 216&#x2013;225 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29194/NJES.26030216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claggett, T. J., Worrall, R. W., Clayton, W. A. &amp; Lipt&#xe1;k, B. G. Resistance temperature detectors (RTDs). In <i>Temperature Measurement</i> 75&#x2013;84 (CRC Press, 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amirinasab Nasab, M., Shamshirband, S., Chronopoulos, A. T., Mosavi, A. &amp; Nabipour, N. Energy-efficient method for wireless sensor networks low-power radio operation in internet of things. <i>Electronics</i><b>9</b>, 320 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics9020320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho, M.-H., Yen, H.-C., Lai, M.-Y. &amp; Liu, Y.-T. Implementation of dds cloud platform for real-time data acquisition of sensors. In <i>2021 International Symposium on Intelligent Signal Processing and Communication Systems (ISPACS)</i> 1&#x2013;2 (IEEE, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seddiki, D. et al. Enhanced virtual machine migration for energy sustainability optimization in cloud computing through knowledge acquisition. <i>Comput. Electr. Eng.</i><b>119</b>, 109506 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compeleceng.2024.109506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang, W. et al. Design of MIMO-PDMA in 5G mobile communication system. <i>IET Commun.</i><b>14</b>, 76&#x2013;83 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1049/iet-com.2018.5837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinar, N. J. &amp; Brinkmann, M. Development of a sensor and measurement platform for water quality observations: Design, sensor integration, 3D printing, and open-source hardware. <i>Environ. Monit. Assess.</i><b>194</b>, 207 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10661-022-09825-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35190903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristiani, E., Yang, C.-T., Huang, C.-Y., Ko, P.-C. &amp; Fathoni, H. On construction of sensors, edge, and cloud (iSEC) framework for smart system integration and applications. <i>IEEE Internet Things J.</i><b>8</b>, 309&#x2013;319 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/JIOT.2020.3004244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morales-Velazquez, L., de Jesus Romero-Troncoso, R., Herrera-Ruiz, G., Morinigo-Sotelo, D. &amp; Osornio-Rios, R. A. Smart sensor network for power quality monitoring in electrical installations. <i>Measurement</i><b>103</b>, 133&#x2013;142 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.measurement.2017.02.032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodia, A., Shah, P., Sekhar, R. &amp; Murugesan, D. Smart sensors in industry 4.0. In <i>2023 4th International Conference for Emerging Technology (INCET)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalil, N., Abid, M. R., Benhaddou, D. &amp; Gerndt, M. Wireless sensors networks for Internet of Things. In <i>2014 IEEE ninth international conference on Intelligent sensors, sensor networks and information processing (ISSNIP)</i> 1&#x2013;6 (IEEE, 2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, C. C., Wong, K. K., Cheng, W. C., Li, S. P. &amp; Li, H. C. Smart control system on electrical safety in Testing Laboratories. In <i>IECON 2019&#x2013;45th Annual Conference of the IEEE Industrial Electronics Society</i> Vol. 1, 3031&#x2013;3036 (IEEE, 2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barroca, N. et al. Wireless sensor networks for temperature and humidity monitoring within concrete structures. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>40</b>, 1156&#x2013;1166 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2012.11.087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farhan, K. Z., Shihata, A. S., Anwar, M. I. &amp; Demirbo&#x11f;a, R. Temperature and humidity sensor technology for concrete health assessment: A review. <i>Innov. Infrast. Solut.</i><b>8</b>, 276 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabello-Solorzano, K., Ortigosa de Araujo, I., Pe&#xf1;a, M., Correia, L. &amp; J. Tall&#xf3;n-Ballesteros, A. The impact of data normalization on the accuracy of machine learning algorithms: a comparative analysis. In <i>International Conference on Soft Computing Models in Industrial and Environmental Applications</i> 344&#x2013;353 (Springer, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen, Q. H. et al. Influence of data splitting on performance of machine learning models in prediction of shear strength of soil. <i>Math. Probl. Eng.</i><b>2021</b>, 4832864 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/4832864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, Z.-H. <i>Machine Learning</i> (Springer Nature, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakshmanan, V., Robinson, S. &amp; Munn, M. <i>Machine Learning Design Patterns</i> (O&#x2019;Reilly Media, 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirtaheri, S. L. &amp; Shahbazian, R. <i>Machine Learning: Theory to Applications</i> (CRC Press, 2022).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>