<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40702035</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Microscopic mechanism of calcium silicate hydrate(C-S-H) freeze-thaw cycle based on molecular dynamics.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>26851</StartPage><MedlinePgn>26851</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">26851</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-11739-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In order to study the microstructure changes of C-S-H under the freeze-thaw cycling, the freeze-thaw cycle simulation of C-S-H is carried out based on molecular dynamics in this paper. It was found that the density of C-S-H gradually increased with time during the freezing process and gradually decreased with time during the thawing process. The larger the temperature difference, the greater the change of the density of C-S-H, and the more obvious the movement of molecules during the freeze-thaw cycle. The increase of temperature rise and fall rate will increase the density change rate and the stress of the system. As the number of freeze-thaw cycle increases, the atomic motion in C-S-H becomes more intense, and the degree of atomic motion during freeze-thaw cycle also increases with the increase of the ratio of calcium and silicon atoms (C/S) and the ratio of water molecule and silicon atoms (W/S) in C-S-H. These research results provide theoretical guidance for further exploring the freeze-thaw failure mechanism of cement-based materials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Xiaotian</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Wuyi University, Nanping, 354300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center of Prevention and Control of Geological Disasters in Northern Fujian, Fujian Province Higher Education Institutes, Nanping, 354300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Smart Town Construction Technology in Hills and Mountains of Fujian Province, Nanping, 354300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yulin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Wuyi University, Nanping, 354300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center of Prevention and Control of Geological Disasters in Northern Fujian, Fujian Province Higher Education Institutes, Nanping, 354300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Smart Town Construction Technology in Hills and Mountains of Fujian Province, Nanping, 354300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Henggan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Wuyi University, Nanping, 354300, China. lhg@wuyiu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center of Prevention and Control of Geological Disasters in Northern Fujian, Fujian Province Higher Education Institutes, Nanping, 354300, China. lhg@wuyiu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Smart Town Construction Technology in Hills and Mountains of Fujian Province, Nanping, 354300, China. lhg@wuyiu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Zihan</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Wuyi University, Nanping, 354300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center of Prevention and Control of Geological Disasters in Northern Fujian, Fujian Province Higher Education Institutes, Nanping, 354300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Smart Town Construction Technology in Hills and Mountains of Fujian Province, Nanping, 354300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zuo</LastName><ForeName>Huixin</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Wuyi University, Nanping, 354300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center of Prevention and Control of Geological Disasters in Northern Fujian, Fujian Province Higher Education Institutes, Nanping, 354300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Smart Town Construction Technology in Hills and Mountains of Fujian Province, Nanping, 354300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Dehong</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Wuyi University, Nanping, 354300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center of Prevention and Control of Geological Disasters in Northern Fujian, Fujian Province Higher Education Institutes, Nanping, 354300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Smart Town Construction Technology in Hills and Mountains of Fujian Province, Nanping, 354300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hou</LastName><ForeName>Jiacan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Wuyi University, Nanping, 354300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center of Prevention and Control of Geological Disasters in Northern Fujian, Fujian Province Higher Education Institutes, Nanping, 354300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Smart Town Construction Technology in Hills and Mountains of Fujian Province, Nanping, 354300, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024XQ025</GrantID><Agency>Fujian Provincial Department of Industry and Information Technology technology innovation key research and industrialization projects</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023-K-25</GrantID><Agency>Science and technology project of Fujian Provincial Department of Housing and Construction</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>N2021Z008</GrantID><Agency>Nanping City resources industry science and technology innovation joint funding project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Calcium silicate hydrate(C-S-H)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Freeze-thaw cycle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mean square displacement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular dynamics</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40702035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12287256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-11739-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-11739-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Qiu, J. et al. Damage constitutive model of coal gangue concrete under freeze-thaw cycles. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>264</b>, 120720 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, B., Wang, F. &amp; Wang, Q. Damage constitutive models of concrete under the coupling action of freeze&#x2013;thaw cycles and load based on lemaitre assumption. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>173</b>, 332&#x2013;341 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesbah, A. et al. Crystal structure of kuzel&#x2019;s salt 3CaO center Dot Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> center Dot 1/2CaSO<sub>4</sub>center Dot 1/2CaCl<sub>2</sub> center Dot 11H<sub>2</sub>O determined by synchrotron powder diffraction. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>41</b> (5), 504 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, W. Behavior of aged reinforced concrete columns under high sustained concentric and eccentric loads (Doctoral dissertation, University of Nevada, Las Vegas). (University of Nevada, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. et al. Elastic modulus damage model of cement mortar under salt freezing circumstance based on X-ray CT scanning. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>191</b>, 1201&#x2013;1209 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez, D. C. et al. Influence of air-entraining agent and freeze-thaw action on pore structure in high-strength concrete by using CT-Scan technology. <i>Cold Reg. Sci. Technol.</i><b>192</b>, 103397 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sokhansefat, G. et al. Using X-ray computed tomography to investigate mortar subjected to freeze-thaw cycles. <i>Cem. Concr. Compos.</i><b>108</b>, 103520 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, F. et al. Experimental investigation on the effect of sulfate attack on chloride diffusivity of cracked concrete subjected to composite solution. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>237</b>, 117643 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. et al. Resistance of recycled aggregate concrete containing low-and high-volume fly Ash against the combined action of freeze&#x2013;thaw cycles and sulfate attack. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>166</b>, 23&#x2013;34 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, L. et al. Durability of concrete under sulfate attack exposed to freeze&#x2013;thaw cycles. <i>Cold Reg. Sci. Technol.</i><b>112</b>, 112&#x2013;117 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nili, M., Ramezanianpour, A. A. &amp; Sobhani, J. Evaluation of the effects of silica fume and air-entrainment on deicer salt scaling resistance of concrete pavements: microstructural study and modeling. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>308</b>, 124972 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao, C. et al. Petrographically quantifying the damage to field and lab-cast mortars subject to freeze-thaw cycles and deicer application. <i>J. Infrastructure Preservation Resil.</i><b>2</b>, 1&#x2013;12 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu, D., Jiang, L. &amp; Fei, Q. Deterioration mechanism of sulfate attack on concrete under freeze-thaw cycles. <i>J. Wuhan Univ. Technology-Mater Sci. Ed.</i><b>28</b> (6), 1172&#x2013;1176 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, D. et al. Durability of concrete containing fly Ash and silica fume against combined freezing-thawing and sulfate attack. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>147</b>, 398&#x2013;406 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, X. et al. Multiscale freezing-thaw in concrete: A numerical study. <i>Compos. Struct.</i><b>309</b>, 116758 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, W. et al. Mesoscopic simulation of thermo-mechanical behaviors in concrete under Frost action. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>157</b>, 117&#x2013;131 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv, Y. et al. Performance degradation of fatigue-damaged concrete under the combined effect of freeze-thaw cycles and chloride-sulfate attack. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>470</b>, 140585 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, Y. et al. Mechanism of concrete damage under the coupled action of freeze-thaw cycle and low-stress impact fatigue load: from pore structure to energy dissipation. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>436</b>, 136980 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J. et al. Experimental and theoretical investigations on the damage evolution of the basalt fiber reinforced concrete under freeze-thaw cycles. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>422</b>, 135703 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, T. et al. Freezing mechanism of NaCl solution ultra-confined on surface of calcium-silicate-hydrate: A molecular dynamics study. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>154</b>, 106722 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang, T. et al. Molecular dynamics simulation investigation on the anti-freezing mechanisms of CSH-GS/GO interfaces. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>369</b>, 130581 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>An, Y. et al. Microcosmic mechanism of asphalt-aggregate interface adhesion failure under freeze-thaw cycles based on molecular dynamics. <i>Australian J. Civil Eng.</i> 1&#x2013;16. (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Z. et al. Freezing of water confined between calcium-silicate-hydrate layers: a coarse-grained molecular dynamics study. <i>J. Sustain. Cem-Based Mater.</i><b>13</b> (6), 799&#x2013;814 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21650373.2023.2297381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, S. et al. Unraveling the molecular freezing behavior of water on a calcium silicate hydrate matrix. <i>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys.</i><b>26</b> (6), 5115&#x2013;5127 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38259173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chai, S. et al. Freezing behavior of ionic solutions within calcium silicate hydrate gel pores. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>192</b>, 107841 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chai, S. et al. Atomistic exploration of unfrozen water film connection modes in CSH gel pores. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>422</b>, 135798 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamid, S. A. The crystal structure of the 11&#xc5; natural tobermorite Ca<sub>2.25</sub>[Si<sub>3</sub>O<sub>7.5</sub> (OH)<sub>1.5</sub>]&#xb7;1H<sub>2</sub>O. Z. <i>Z. F&#xfc;r Kristallographie - Crystalline Mater.</i><b>154</b>, 189&#x2013;198 (1981).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkar, P. K. &amp; Mitra, N. Molecular level study of uni/multi-axial deformation response of tobermorite 11 &#xc5;: A force field comparison study. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>145</b>, 106451 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou, D. et al. Modified Lucas-Washburn function of capillary transport in the calcium silicate hydrate gel pore: A coarse-grained molecular dynamics study. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>136</b>, 106166 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, J. et al. Insights on the capillary transport mechanism in the sustainable cement hydrate impregnated with graphene oxide and epoxy composite. <i>Compos. Part. B: Eng.</i><b>173</b>, 106907 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellenq, Roland, J-M. et al. A realistic molecular model of cement hydrates. <i>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci.</i><b>106</b> (38), 16102&#x2013;16107. (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2739865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19805265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cygan, R. T., Liang, J. J. &amp; Kalinichev, A. G. Molecular models of hydroxide, oxyhydroxide, and clay phases and the development of a general force field. <i>J. Phys. Chem. B</i>. <b>108</b> (4), 1255&#x2013;1266 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdolhosseini Qomi, M. J. et al. <i>Comb. Mol. Optim. Cem. Hydrates Nat. Commun.</i>, <b>5</b>(1): 4960. (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4200522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25248305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babaei, S., Ghasemzadeh, H. &amp; Tesson, S. Methane adsorption of nanocomposite shale in the presence of water: insights from molecular simulations. <i>Chem. Eng. J.</i><b>475</b>, 146196 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babaei Saeed, and Hasan Ghasemzadeh. From rigidity to flexibility: Understanding ethane adsorption and diffusion in shale under moist and saline conditions. <i>Energy</i><b>314</b> 134235. (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalinichev, A. G., Wang, J. &amp; Kirkpatrick, R. J. Molecular dynamics modeling of the structure, dynamics and energetics of mineral&#x2013;water interfaces: application to cement materials. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>37</b> (3), 337&#x2013;347 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnan, N. M. A. et al. Confined water in layered silicates: the origin of anomalous thermal expansion behavior in calcium-silicate-hydrates. <i>ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces</i>. <b>8</b> (51), 35621&#x2013;35627 (2016).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27977137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cygan, R. T., Greathouse, J. A. &amp; Kalinichev, A. G. Advances in clayff molecular simulation of layered and nanoporous materials and their aqueous interfaces. <i>J. Phys. Chem. C</i>. <b>125</b> (32), 17573&#x2013;17589 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murashima, T., Urata, S. &amp; Li, S. Coupling finite element method with large scale atomic/molecular massively parallel simulator (LAMMPS) for hierarchical multiscale simulations: modeling and simulation of amorphous polymeric materials. <i>Eur. Phys. J. B</i>. <b>92</b>, 1&#x2013;8 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stukowski, A. Visualization and analysis of atomistic simulation data with OVITO&#x2013;the open visualization tool. <i>Modell. Simul. Mater. Sci. Eng.</i><b>18</b> (1), 015012. (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, X. et al. Upscaling degradation of cementitious calcium (aluminate) silicate hydrate upon ultra-low temperature attack: a multiscale insight and a bottom-up enhancement route. <i>Compos. Part. B: Eng.</i><b>243</b>, 110122 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LI Yan, Y. U. et al. Random distribution structure characteristics for a calcium silicate hydrate coarse grained model. <i>Petroleum Sci. Bull.</i><b>03</b>, 474&#x2013;480 (2021).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>