<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39459803</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>20</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Recycled Asphalt Mixture and Solid Waste-Based Solidification Materials on Performance of Cold-Regenerated Asphalt Mixture.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5099</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma17205099</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In this study, an aging asphalt mixture was regenerated by a waste-based rejuvenator and cemented by solid waste-based solidification materials (SSMs). A splitting test, wheel tracking test, and three-point bending test were conducted to evaluate the properties of the regenerated asphalt mixture (RAM). The results reveal that the properties of the asphalt mixture were not diminished or were moderately enhanced by the 30% substitution of RAP. With the substitution of RAP to 100%, the splitting tensile strength, dynamic stability, and splitting strength ratio were decreased by 13%, 15%, and 5%, respectively. With the 100% substitution of SSMs for cement, the compressive strength, dynamic stability, flexural strain, and splitting strength ratios of the RAM were increased by 40%, 32%%, 14%, and 8%, respectively. The lightweight components can be supplemented, and low-temperature deformation and interlayer flowability can be improved by the incorporation of the rejuvenator. The generation of hydrated calcium silicate and ettringite for SSMs is greater than those of cement. The massive generation of ettringite has been observed to increase the solid phase volume by 120%, which may facilitate a more complete filling of the remaining pores in the RAM due to water evaporation. The regeneration and cement on green and the high performance of the rejuvenator and the SSM markedly enhanced RAM performance.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shu</LastName><ForeName>Benan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9926-0966</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Engineering Research Center of Highway Maintenance Technology, Changsha University of Science &amp; Technology, Changsha 410114, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Foshan Transportation Science and Technology Co., Ltd., Foshan 528000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Guodong</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Foshan Transportation Science and Technology Co., Ltd., Foshan 528000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Yunlong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fojiaoke Tiannuo (Guangdong) Materials Co., Ltd., Foshan 528000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Yanfei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0769-6648</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Foshan Transportation Science and Technology Co., Ltd., Foshan 528000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Maocong</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Foshan Transportation Science and Technology Co., Ltd., Foshan 528000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>kfj230202</GrantID><Agency>Open Fund of National Engineering Research Center of Highway Maintenance Technology (Changsha University of Science &amp; Technology)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>HGKFYBP20</GrantID><Agency>Open Project Funding of Key Laboratory of Intelligent Health Perception and Ecological Restoration of Rivers and Lakes, Ministry of Education, Hubei University of Technology</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">material properties</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">property</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recycled asphalt mixture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">regeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">solid waste</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">solidification materials</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Authors Benan Shu, Guodong Zeng, Yanfei Ren and Maocong Zhu were employed by the company Foshan Transportation Science and Technology Co. Ltd. Author Yunlong Ma was employed by the company Fojiaoke Tiannuo (Guangdong) Materials Co. Ltd. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39459803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11509320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17205099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma17205099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pei Z., Xu M., Cao J., Feng D., Hu W., Ren J., Jing R., Yi J. Analysis of the microcharacteristics of different kinds of asphalt based on different aging conditions. Mater. Struct. 2022;55:250. doi: 10.1617/s11527-022-02088-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1617/s11527-022-02088-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Feng J., Yang F., Wu S., Liu Q., Bai T., Liu Z., Li C., Gu D., Chen A., et al. Gradient aging behaviors of asphalt aged by ultraviolet lights with various intensities. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;295:123618. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y., Chen A., Wu S., Li Y., Song Y. Laboratory and field performance investigation of anti-ultraviolet aging of warm-mixed asphalt concretes. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;409:134032. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y., Wu S., Chen A., Li Y. Physical, Rheological, and Anti-Ultraviolet Aging Performance of Layered Double Hydroxides + Styrene Block Copolymer-Modified Asphalt Binders. Sustainability. 2023;15:15246. doi: 10.3390/su152115246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su152115246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Feng J., Chen A., Wu S., Bai T., Liu Q., Zhu H. Development mechanism of aging depth of bitumen with increasing UV aging time. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2022;17:e01057. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen A., Hu Z., Li M., Bai T., Xie G., Zhang Y., Li Y., Li C. Investigation on the mechanism and performance of asphalt and its mixture regenerated by waste engine oil. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;313:125411. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.125411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.125411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpani C., Bocci E., Bocci M. Characterization of Cold Recycled Asphalt Mixtures including Reinforcing Fibers. Sustainability. 2023;15:16209. doi: 10.3390/su152316209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su152316209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng P., Qiao P., Zheng C., Liu Z., Zhang Z., Li Y. Study on the Performance and Mechanism of Cold-Recycled Asphalt Based on Permeable Recycling Agent. Materials. 2023;16:6464. doi: 10.3390/ma16196464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16196464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10573666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37834600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araneda M.E., Pradena M., Silva R., Pardo M. Sustainable paving alternative for low-volume roads using cold recycled asphalt. Proceeding Inst. Civ. Eng.-Eng. Sustain. 2022;175:293&#x2013;301. doi: 10.1680/jensu.21.00036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1680/jensu.21.00036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aker S.N.A., Ozer H. Aggregate packing characterisation of cold recycled mixtures. Int. J. Pavement Eng. 2022;24:1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1080/10298436.2022.2078977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10298436.2022.2078977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arafat S., Wasiuddin N.M., Mohammad L.N. Evaluation of bio-based and petroleum-based rejuvenator based on cracking susceptibility of hot mix asphalt with high RAP content. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;371:130725. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.130725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.130725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Memon A.M., Sutanto M.H., Memon Z.A., Khahro S.H., Memon R.A. Valorization of petroleum sludge as rejuvenator for recycled asphalt binder and mixture. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2024;20:e03318. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2024.e03318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2024.e03318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samara M., Offenbacker D., Mehta Y., Ali A., Elshaer M., Decarlo C. Performance Evaluation and Characterization of Extracted Recycled Asphalt Binder with Rejuvenators. Transp. Res. Rec. 2022;2676:714&#x2013;727. doi: 10.1177/03611981221097091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03611981221097091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwettmann K., Nytus N., Weigel S., Radenberg M., Stephan D. Effects of rejuvenators on bitumen ageing during simulated cyclic reuse: A review. Resour. Conserv. Recycl. 2023;190:106776. doi: 10.1016/j.resconrec.2022.106776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resconrec.2022.106776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro T., Freire A.C., S&#xe1;-da-Costa M., Canejo J., Cordeiro V., Micaelo R. Investigating Asphalt Self-Healing with Colorless Binder and Pigmented Rejuvenator. Sustainability. 2023;15:4556. doi: 10.3390/su15054556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su15054556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwama M., Hayano K. Influence of combined aging on the mechanical and physical properties of reclaimed asphalt pavement mixtures blended with rejuvenator agents. J. Mater. Cycles Waste Manag. 2023;25:1417&#x2013;1433. doi: 10.1007/s10163-023-01619-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10163-023-01619-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwettmann K., Nytus N., Radenberg M., Stephan D. Ageing behaviour of naturally and artificially aged bitumen samples after the addition of rejuvenators. Road Mater. Pavement Des. 2023;24:471&#x2013;485. doi: 10.1080/14680629.2023.2181006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14680629.2023.2181006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almusawi A., Jaleel M.M., Shoman S., Lupanov A.P. Field and Laboratory Performance Evaluation of Cement Treated Cold Recycled Asphalt Pavement Mixtures. J. Transp. Eng. Part B-Pavements. 2024;150:1373. doi: 10.1061/JPEODX.PVENG-1373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/JPEODX.PVENG-1373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Y., Yi Y., Tian T., Fan J., Bai C., Tan Y., Fang J., Deng C. Laboratory and Field Research on Using Cement and Polyester Fiber to Enhance the Performance of Emulsified Asphalt Cold Recycled Mixture. Arab. J. Sci. Eng. 2023;48:4937&#x2013;4951. doi: 10.1007/s13369-022-07260-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13369-022-07260-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mignini C., Cardone F., Graziani A. Complex modulus of cement-bitumen treated materials produced with different reclaimed asphalt gradations. Mater. Struct. 2022;55:169. doi: 10.1617/s11527-022-02009-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1617/s11527-022-02009-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X., Ma B. Microstructure in Adhesion Development Process and Strength Formation Mechanism in Early Stage of Cold Recycled Mixture with Emulsified Asphalt. Adv. Civ. Eng. 2024;2024:7940655. doi: 10.1155/2024/7940655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2024/7940655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fedrigo W., Kleinert T.R., N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez W.P., Graef G., Filho L.C.P.d.S., Brito L.A.T. Shrinkage of Cold Recycled Cement- Treated Mixtures of Asphalt Pavement Materials. J. Test. Eval. 2023;51:2230&#x2013;2244. doi: 10.1520/JTE20220260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1520/JTE20220260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji J., Li J., Wang J., Suo Z., Li H., Yao H. Early Strength of Cold Recycled Emulsified Asphalt Mixtures. J. Mater. Civ. Eng. 2023;35:14647. doi: 10.1061/JMCEE7.MTENG-14647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/JMCEE7.MTENG-14647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong Z., Xu G., Xu S., Ma S., Ma T., Luan Y., Liu J. Study on the strength composition mechanism and interface microscopic characteristics of cold recycling asphalt mixture. Front. Mater. 2024;11:1397335. doi: 10.3389/fmats.2024.1397335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmats.2024.1397335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu B., Gong H., Chen S., Ren Y., Li Y., Yang T., Zeng G., Zhou M., Barbieri D.M., Li Y. Case Study of Solid Waste Based Soft Soil Solidifying Materials Applied in Deep Mixing Pile. Buildings. 2022;12:1193. doi: 10.3390/buildings12081193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings12081193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu B., Yang T., Li Y., Ren Y., Zhen L., Chen J. Effect of alkali-activated steel slag powder on solidification performance of silt soil. New Build. Mater. 2022;49:83&#x2013;86+94. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu B., Chen W., Yang T., Xie Z., Ren Y., Li Y., Zheng L., Zeng G., Li M., Barbieri D.M. Study on laboratory and engineering application of multi source solid waste based soft soil solidification materials. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2022;17:e01465. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hajiebrahimi M., Hosseini S.A., Fariman M.R. Experimental Evaluation of Mechanical Characteristics of Roller-Compacted Concrete Containing Crumb Rubber, RAP and Slag. Arab. J. Sci. Eng. 2024;49:14459&#x2013;14471. doi: 10.1007/s13369-024-09038-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13369-024-09038-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X., Xie C., Chen J., Luo J., Wei D. Study on preparation of light oil regenerant and performance of cold recycled mixture. Mater.-Rio Jan. 2023;28:e20230101. doi: 10.1590/1517-7076-rmat-2023-0101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1517-7076-rmat-2023-0101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao J., Wang T., Hong J., Ruan C., Zhang Y., Yuan D., Wu W. Experimental Study of Permeable Asphalt Mixture Containing Reclaimed Asphalt Pavement. Sustainability. 2023;15:10676. doi: 10.3390/su151310676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su151310676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Zhang Y., Chen J., Liu W., Wang W. Effect of Desulfurization Process Variables on the Properties of Crumb Rubber Modified Asphalt. Polymers. 2022;14:1365. doi: 10.3390/polym14071365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym14071365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9002867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35406239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W., Xu Y., Wang H., Shu B., Barbieri D.M., Norambuena-Contreras J. Enhanced Storage Stability and Rheological Properties of Asphalt Modified by Activated Waste Rubber Powder. Materials. 2021;14:2693. doi: 10.3390/ma14102693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma14102693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8160994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34065577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farahani H.Z., Palassi M., Galooyak S.S. Using response surface methodology to optimize rubber and LDPE contents in bitumen at low-temperature performance. Pet. Sci. Technol. 2022;41:139&#x2013;158. doi: 10.1080/10916466.2022.2052092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10916466.2022.2052092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong P., Tang J., Zhou F., Guo R., Yan J., Yang T. Performance analysis of graphene modified asphalt and pavement performance of SMA mixture. PLoS ONE. 2022;17:e0267225. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0267225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0267225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9126367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35604930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J., Zou Y., Zhang Y., Yu H., Zou G. Adhesion Characteristics of Graphene-Modified Asphalt Using Surface-Free Energy Method. J. Mater. Civ. Eng. 2023;35:15104. doi: 10.1061/JMCEE7.MTENG-15104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/JMCEE7.MTENG-15104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>