<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41570493</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-8171</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>102</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The American journal of emergency medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Emerg Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exertional and classic heat stroke: A narrative review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>49</StartPage><EndPage>54</EndPage><MedlinePgn>49-54</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ajem.2026.01.008</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0735-6757(26)00008-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Exertional (EHS) and classic heat stroke (CHS) share similarities in pathophysiology, progression, and potential sequelae. Further, quick recognition and management demonstrate favorable outcomes. Limited publications have examined parallels between types of heat stroke. Therefore, the purpose of this review was to search available literature and critically outline current evidence-informed clinical management of heat stroke. Our result was a thorough search and analysis of related literature that answers questions related to heat stroke. The pathophysiology of heat stroke is similar between EHS and CHS, with the only difference being onset predisposition and typical affected population. The main driver toward EHS includes exercise intensity inconsistent with environmental demands. CHS often presents in geriatric or pediatric populations and in patients with predisposing thermoregulatory limitations. Although debate continues in diagnostic criteria, both EHS and CHS are diagnosed with concomitant hyperpyrexia and central nervous system dysfunction. Following initial onset, the progression of cell death, tissue and organ failure, and potentially fatal outcome remains consistent between EHS and CHS. Emergency management of EHS has resulted in 100% survival when prompt diagnosis and effective treatment are administered. Results are not as favorable with CHS, albeit with a lack of robust data. The available evidence suggests similar management protocols would potentially improve outcomes with CHS. A potential addition to successful cooling may include hemodynamic support. Lastly, recommendations for enhanced data and documentation for heat stroke in emergency management could help foster consistent, updated clinical guidelines.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perez</LastName><ForeName>Rosie I</ForeName><Initials>RI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Arkansas, Heat &amp; Hydration Optimization (H(2)O) Lab, Department of Health, Human Performance and Recreation; 155 Stadium Drive, Fayetteville, AR 72701, USA. Electronic address: rosiep@uark.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Londono</LastName><ForeName>Maria J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Texas at San Antonio, Department of Biomedical &amp; Chemical Engineering; 1 UTSA Circle, San Antonio, TX 78249, USA; University of Texas at San Antonio, Department of Emergency Medicine; 7703 Floyd Curl Drive; San Antonio, TX 78229, USA. Electronic address: mariajose.londonojaramillo@my.utsa.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Everitt</LastName><ForeName>Bryan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Texas at San Antonio, Department of Emergency Medicine; 7703 Floyd Curl Drive; San Antonio, TX 78229, USA. Electronic address: Everitt@uthscsa.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Young</LastName><ForeName>Douglas</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Texas at San Antonio, Department of Emergency Medicine; 7703 Floyd Curl Drive; San Antonio, TX 78229, USA. Electronic address: youngd1@uthscsa.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hood</LastName><ForeName>R Lyle</ForeName><Initials>RL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Texas at San Antonio, Department of Biomedical &amp; Chemical Engineering; 1 UTSA Circle, San Antonio, TX 78249, USA; University of Texas at San Antonio, Department of Emergency Medicine; 7703 Floyd Curl Drive; San Antonio, TX 78229, USA; University of Texas at San Antonio, Department of Mechanical, Aerospace, and Industrial Engineering; 1 UTSA Circle, San Antonio, TX 78249, USA. Electronic address: lyle.hood@utsa.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Lorenzo</LastName><ForeName>Robert A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Texas at San Antonio, Department of Biomedical &amp; Chemical Engineering; 1 UTSA Circle, San Antonio, TX 78249, USA; University of Texas at San Antonio, Department of Emergency Medicine; 7703 Floyd Curl Drive; San Antonio, TX 78229, USA; University of Texas at San Antonio, Department of Mechanical, Aerospace, and Industrial Engineering; 1 UTSA Circle, San Antonio, TX 78249, USA. Electronic address: delorenzo@uthscsa.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McDermott</LastName><ForeName>Brendon P</ForeName><Initials>BP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Arkansas, Heat &amp; Hydration Optimization (H(2)O) Lab, Department of Health, Human Performance and Recreation; 155 Stadium Drive, Fayetteville, AR 72701, USA. Electronic address: brendonm@uark.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Emerg Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8309942</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0735-6757</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018883" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heat Stroke</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005082" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Exertion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heat illness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hyperthermia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Whole-body cooling</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest This manuscript was not a result of funding from any of the co-authors. The authors also claim no conflict of interest in the preparation of this manuscript.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41570493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajem.2026.01.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0735-6757(26)00008-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>