<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40851871</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-302X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Optimizing <i>Bacillus pasteurii</i> spore germination and unveiling impermeability mechanisms in microbial self-healing concrete.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1653557</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1653557</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1653557</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fmicb.2025.1653557</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study investigated the impact of key factors on spore germination of <i>Bacillus pasteurii</i>, a self-healing bacterium for concrete, and elucidated its impermeability mechanism to provide theoretical and practical guidance for advanced self-healing concrete development. Controlled experiments determined optimal germination conditions: 2 g/L microcapsule concentration, pH 8, and 1 g/L inosine, yielding peak germination efficiency that highlights parameter synergies. Thermal stimulation for 3 minutes effectively triggered germination, presenting a practical activation approach. MIP and SEM analyses were employed to characterize concrete microstructure. Results showed the alkaline concrete matrix facilitated <i>B. pasteurii physiology</i>, while Ca<sup>2+</sup> had no inhibitory effect, enabling calcium-based additives in formulations. <i>B. pasteurii</i>-containing mortar enhanced cement hydration stability; MIP revealed self-healing concrete had an infiltration fractal cone number of 2.832 and trunk fractal dimension of 2.306, similar to conventional materials, indicating no increased structural complexity. Environmental erosion primarily affects 300-10,000 nm pores, pinpointing durability targets. SEM and MIP analyses confirmed <i>B. pasteurii</i>-induced vaterite and aragonite calcium carbonate crystals integrated with tobermorite, reducing porosity and enhancing mechanical strength. These findings indicate the bacterium's potential in self-healing systems, though future research should address complex physicochemical influences and bacterial gradient domestication to improve environmental adaptability.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Hu, Liu, Zhang and Hu.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Yingying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong Key Laboratory of Eco-Environmental Science for the Yellow River Delta, Shandong University of Aeronautics, Binzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Weitao</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Energy and Mining Engineering, Shandong University of Science and Technology, Qingdao, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yutao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shandong Key Laboratory of Eco-Environmental Science for the Yellow River Delta, Shandong University of Aeronautics, Binzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Xuelong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Safety and High-Efficiency Coal Mining, Ministry of Education, Anhui University of Science and Technology, Huainan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101548977</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-302X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bacillus pasteurii</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">concrete durability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">germination conditions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">impermeability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-healing concrete</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spore germination</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40851871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12367450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2025.1653557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ahmad B., Shabbir F., Raza A., Shaheen N., Ahmed M. (2025). Enhancing self-healing in bio-mineralized concrete with steel slag aggregates and <i>Bacillus subtilis</i>. Struct. Concr.
26, 2526&#x2013;2547. doi: 10.1002/suco.202400171</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/suco.202400171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akhtar J. N., Khan R. A., Khan R. A., Akhtar M. N. (2025). Investigation of microstructural characterization, strength and durability of self-healing self-compacting conventional concrete. Structure 71:108059. doi: 10.1016/j.istruc.2024.108059</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2024.108059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C., Habert G., Bouzidi Y., Jullien A. (2010). Environmental impact of cement production: detail of the different processes and cement plant variability evaluation. J. Clean. Prod. 18, 478&#x2013;485. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2009.12.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2009.12.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng M., Jiang L., Hu S., Zhao X., Wang W., Zhang Y., et al. (2025). Mechanism and application of a coating-free microbial self-healing agent in cement-based composites. Cem. Concr. Compos. 163:106213. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2025.106213</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2025.106213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong Z. H., Pan X. H., Tang C. S., Wang D. L., Wang R., Shi B. (2023). An efficient microbial sealing of rock weathering cracks using bio-carbonation of reactive magnesia cement. Constr. Build. Mater. 366:130038. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.130038</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.130038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galano S., Calabrese A., Asvapathanagul P., Shadravan S., Ly M., Flores D., et al. (2025). Innovative approaches to enhancing concrete compressive strength: an extensive investigation of biochar-embedded and self-repairing techniques. J. Mater. Civ. Eng. 37:04025112. doi: 10.1061/JMCEE7.MTENG-19564</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/JMCEE7.MTENG-19564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo W., Li L., Yang J., Yu K., Sun X., Wang Z., et al. (2025). Mechanism investigation and safety evaluation towards flame-retardant structural thermoplastic polyurethane composites inspired via interfacial synergy strategy. Polym. Degrad. Stab. 238:111355. doi: 10.1016/j.polymdegradstab.2025.111355</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.polymdegradstab.2025.111355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo W., Yang J., Li L., Zhang J., Wang Z. r., Wang J., et al. (2024). Boron nitride based nanostructure inspired flame retarded thermoplastic polyurethane composites: comprehensive evaluation and mechanism investigation. Constr. Build. Mater. 457:139478. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.139478</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.139478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He C., Wei Y., Wang Z., Wang J., Richard Y. K. K. (2024). Catalytic chemistry inspired hollow carbon nanofibers loaded with NiS/NiAs high-performance and safe Li+ reservoir. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 664, 156&#x2013;167. doi: 10.1016/j.jcis.2024.02.212, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2024.02.212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38471188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y., Zhao Y., Bai W., Cao Y., Wang T., Xu W., et al. (2024). Study on the influence of high rate charge and discharge on thermal runaway behavior of lithium-ion battery. Process. Saf. Environ. Prot. 191, 1483&#x2013;1494. doi: 10.1016/j.psep.2024.09.054</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2024.09.054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javeed Y., Goh Y., Mo K. H., Yap S. P., Leo B. F. (2024). Microbial self-healing in concrete: a comprehensive exploration of bacterial viability, implementation techniques, and mechanical properties. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 29, 2376&#x2013;2395. doi: 10.1016/j.jmrt.2024.01.261</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2024.01.261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jongvivatsakul P., Janprasit K., Nuaklong P., Pungrasmi W., Likitlersuang S. (2019). Investigation of the crack healing performance in mortar using microbially induced calcium carbonate precipitation (MICP) method. Constr. Build. Mater. 212, 737&#x2013;744. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.04.035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.04.035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Lv Z., Xiao J., Xu X., Nong X., Liu H. (2021). On the mechanism of cl diffusion transport in self-healing concrete based on recycled coarse aggregates as microbial carriers. Cem. Concr. Compos. 124:104232. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2021.104232</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2021.104232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Zhou L., Zhang Y., Wang J., Wang Z. (2023). Aging behavior and mechanisms of lithium-ion battery under multi-aging path. J. Clean. Prod. 423:138678, 1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.138678</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.138678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Zhuge Y., Fan W., Duan W., Wang L. (2022). Recycling industrial wastes into self- healing concrete: a review. Environ. Res. 214:113975. doi: 10.1016/j.envres.2022.113975, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2022.113975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35995228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metwally G. A. M., Mahdy M., Ahmed El Raheem H., El Raheem A. (2020). Performance of bio concrete by using <i>Bacillus Pasteurii</i> Bacteria. Civ. Eng. J.
6, 1443&#x2013;1456. doi: 10.28991/cej-2020-03091559, PMID: 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.28991/cej-2020-03091559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nodehi M., Ozbakkaloglu T., Gholampour A. (2022). A systematic review of bacteria- based self-healing concrete: biomineralization, mechanical, and durability properties. J. Build. Eng. 49:104038. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104038, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Reilly M., Lafikes J., Farshadfar O., Grayli P. V., Al-Qassag O., Darwin D. (2022). Effect of concrete settlement cracks on corrosion initiation. ACI Mater. J. 119, 117&#x2013;124. doi: 10.14359/51734729</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14359/51734729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian C., Zhang Y., Xie Y. (2021). Effect of ion concentration in crack zone on healing degree of microbial self-healing concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 286:122969. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122969</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramachandran S. K., Ramakrishnan V., Bang S. S. (2001). Remediation of concrete using microorganisms. Mater. J. 98, 3&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathore R., Mostavi E., Asadi S., Hassan M. M., Alansari M., Khaliq W., et al. (2021). A review of bacteria-based self-healing concrete. ACADEMICIA: Int. Multidiscip. Res. J. 11:839&#x2013;844. doi: 10.5958/2249-7137.2021.02674.4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5958/2249-7137.2021.02674.4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rollakanti C. R., Srinivasu K. (2022). Experimental investigations on self-healing concrete with <i>Pseudomonas Fluorescens</i> Bacteria and calcium lactate. Math. Stat. Eng. Appl.
71, 803&#x2013;816.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafi P. M. (2022). Poor construction techniques in small construction works: a case study in the valley of Kashmir. Int. J. Res. Publ. Rev. 2582:7421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Son Y., Min J., Jang I., Yi C., Park W. (2022). Development of a novel compressed tablet- based bacterial agent for self-healing cementitious material. Cem. Concr. Compos. 129:104514. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104514</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;ovljanski O., Tomi&#x107; A., Markov S. (2022). Relationship between bacterial contribution and self-healing effect of cement-based materials. Microorganisms 10:1399. doi: 10.3390/microorganisms10071399</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/microorganisms10071399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9322135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35889117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun D., Cao Z., Huang C., Wu K., De Schutter G., Zhang L. (2022). Degradation of concrete in marine environment under coupled chloride and sulfate attack: a numerical and experimental study. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 17:e01218. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01218, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thurairajah A. (2022). The overload behaviour of reinforced concrete flexural members. Int. J. Struct. Constr. Eng. 16, 259&#x2013;268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Yang J., Bai W., Wang Z., Yu K., Lu Y., et al. (2025). Thermal runaway and jet flame features of LIBs undergone high-rate charge/discharge: an investigation. J. Energy Chem. 103, 826&#x2013;837. doi: 10.1016/j.jechem.2024.12.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jechem.2024.12.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin J., Liu Y., Zhang G., Wang Z., Wang J., Yang N., et al. (2022). Evaluation of early- age thermal cracking resistance of high w/b, high volume fly ash (HVFA) concrete using temperature stress testing machine. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 16:e00825. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00825</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi H., Zheng T., Jia Z., Su T., Wang C. (2021). Study on the influencing factors and mechanism of calcium carbonate precipitation induced by urease bacteria. J. Cryst. Growth 564:126113. doi: 10.1016/j.jcrysgro.2021.126113</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcrysgro.2021.126113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaerkabeh R., Sadeghi A. M., Afshin H., Majdani R. (2022). Crack healing and mechanical properties of bacteria-based self-healing cement. Period. Polytech. Civ. Eng. 66, 581&#x2013;592. doi: 10.3311/PPci.18803</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3311/PPci.18803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Jin Z., Li M., Qian C. (2021). Effects of carrier on the performance of bacteria- based self-healing concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 305:124771. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124771</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L. V., Suleiman A. R., Allaf M. M., Marani A., Tuyan M., Nehdi M. L. (2022). Crack self-healing in alkali-activated slag composites incorporating immobilized bacteria. Constr. Build. Mater. 326:126842. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.126842</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.126842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H., Ma Y., Zhang J., Hu Z., Li H., Wang Y., et al. (2022). Effect of clay content on plastic shrinkage cracking of cementitious materials. Constr. Build. Mater. 342:127989. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.127989</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.127989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>