<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40979646</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2193-9616</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>In silico pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>In Silico Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>In silico ligand self-assembly drives binding recognition of natural products into <i>Anopheles gambiae</i> cytosolic sulfotransferases (AgSULT-001425) protein.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>138</StartPage><MedlinePgn>138</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">138</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40203-025-00403-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">Malaria remains one of the most devastating diseases affecting humanity, generating a significant interest in developing effective and reliable interventions. Synthetic insecticides widely used for vector control face limitations due to increased insect resistance and toxicity to humans and non-target species. Indole alkaloids, recognized for their insecticidal properties, have emerged as promising alternatives, however, their molecular mechanisms and efficacy for malaria vector control have not been fully explored or documented. AgSULT-001425, a sulfotransferase enzyme crucial for mosquito development and reproductive success, represents a key target for disrupting mosquito survival. To investigate this, molecular docking, dynamics, and MMPBSA analyses were employed to explore the binding mechanisms, stability, and self-assembly of indole alkaloids with AgSULT-001425. The binding affinity was ranked as EP4&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;ST6&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;AS4&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;SP4. Hydrated docking indicated that EP4-7R0U binding affinity improved significantly to&#x2009;-&#x2009;10.41&#xa0;kcal/mol, surpassing the binding affinity of the co-crystallized ligand by&#x2009;-&#x2009;1.0&#xa0;kcal/mol. ADME/T analysis confirmed drug-like properties and high bioavailability with adherence to Lipinski's rule of five. Stability analyses demonstrated minimal structural deviations, compact protein structures ensuring stable interactions. MMPBSA identified EP4 (-&#x2009;94.83&#xa0;kJ/mol) and ST6 (-&#x2009;91.67&#xa0;kJ/mol) as exhibiting the strongest binding energies. During self-assembly, SP4 achieved the shortest distance to the protein, whereas the free energy surface emphasized stable interactions for both EP4 and SP4. Based on these findings, the identified natural inhibitors demonstrate potential as lead compounds for developing more potent insecticides. However, experimental validation is needed to confirm their efficacy and optimize their properties for practical use.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1007/s40203-025-00403-8.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature 2025. Springer Nature or its licensor (e.g. a society or other partner) holds exclusive rights to this article under a publishing agreement with the author(s) or other rightsholder(s); author self-archiving of the accepted manuscript version of this article is solely governed by the terms of such publishing agreement and applicable law.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Makaye</LastName><ForeName>Angelina I</ForeName><Initials>AI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, College of Natural and Mathematical Sciences, University of Dodoma, P. O. Box 338, Dodoma, Tanzania.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/009n8zh45</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.442459.a</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 1998 2954</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paul</LastName><ForeName>Lucas</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Dar es Salaam University College of Education, P. O. Box 2329, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/0479aed98</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.8193.3</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0648 0244</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vuai</LastName><ForeName>Said A H</ForeName><Initials>SAH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, College of Natural and Mathematical Sciences, University of Dodoma, P. O. Box 338, Dodoma, Tanzania.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/009n8zh45</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.442459.a</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 1998 2954</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shadrack</LastName><ForeName>Daniel M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Faculty of Natural and Applied Sciences, St. John's University of Tanzania, P. O. Box 47, Dodoma, Tanzania.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="ROR">https://ror.org/02jmk1h66</Identifier><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.442456.5</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0484 1130</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>In Silico Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101623954</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2193-9616</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-mosquito agent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">In silico</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Indole alkaloids</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interestsThe authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40979646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12446164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40203-025-00403-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abraham MJ, Murtola T, Schulz R, P&#xe1;ll S, Smith JC, Hess B et al (2015) GROMACS: high performance molecular simulations through multi-level parallelism from laptops to supercomputers. SoftwareX 1&#x2013;2:19&#x2013;25. 10.1016/j.softx.2015.06.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.softx.2015.06.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aghdam AG, Vossoughi M, Almzadeh I, Zeinali M (2008) Bioconjugation of interferon-alpha molecules to lysine-capped gold nanoparticles for further drug delivery applications. J Dispers Sci Technol 29(8):1062&#x2013;1065. 10.1080/01932690701815762</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01932690701815762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed N, Alam M, Saeed M, Ullah H, Iqbal T, Al-Mutairi KA et al (2021) Botanical insecticides are a non-toxic alternative to conventional pesticides for controlling insects and pests. In: Global decline of insects, pp 1&#x2013;19. 10.5772/intechopen.100416</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen LR, Krivov SV, Paci E (2009) Analysis of the free-energy surface of proteins from reversible folding simulations. PLoS Comput Biol 5(7):e1000428. 10.1371/journal.pcbi.1000428</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1000428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2700257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19593364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaro RE, Baron R, McCammon JA (2008) An improved relaxed complex scheme for receptor flexibility in computer-aided drug design. J Comput Aided Mol Des 22:693&#x2013;705. 10.1007/s10822-007-9159-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10822-007-9159-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2516539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18196463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amod L, Mohunlal R, Teixeira N, Egan TJ, Wicht KJ (2023) Identifying inhibitors of &#x3b2;-haematin formation with activity against chloroquine-resistant <i>Plasmodium falciparum</i> malaria parasites via virtual screening approaches. Sci Rep 13(1):2648. 10.1038/s41598-023-29273-w
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-29273-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9929333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36788274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ausaf Ali S, Imtaiyaz Hassan M, Islam A, Ahmad F (2014) A review of methods available to estimate solvent-accessible surface areas of soluble proteins in the folded and unfolded states. Curr Protein Pept Sci 15(5):456&#x2013;476. 10.2174/1389203715666140327114232</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1389203715666140327114232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24678666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagewadi ZK, Khan TY, Gangadharappa B, Kamalapurkar A, Shamsudeen SM, Yaraguppi DA (2023) Molecular dynamics and simulation analysis against superoxide dismutase (SOD) target of <i>Micrococcus luteus</i> with secondary metabolites from <i>Bacillus licheniformis</i> recognized by genome mining approach. Saudi J Biolo Sci 30(9):103753. 10.1016/j.sjbs.2023.103753</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sjbs.2023.103753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10424208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37583871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnes CE, English DM, Cowley SM (2019) Acetylation &amp; co: an expanding repertoire of histone acylations regulates chromatin and transcription. Essays Biochem 63(1):97&#x2013;107. 10.1042/EBC20180061</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/EBC20180061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6484784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30940741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baum B, Mohamed M, Zayed M, Gerlach C, Heine A, Hangauer D et al (2009) More than a simple lipophilic contact: a detailed thermodynamic analysis of nonbasic residues in the S1 pocket of thrombin. J Mol Biol 390(1):56&#x2013;69. 10.1016/j.jmb.2009.04.051</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmb.2009.04.051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19409395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baum B, Muley L, Smolinski M, Heine A, Hangauer D, Klebe G (2010) Non-additivity of functional group contributions in protein&#x2013;ligand binding: a comprehensive study by crystallography and isothermal titration calorimetry. J Mol Biol 397(4):1042&#x2013;1054</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmb.2010.02.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20156458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekheit MS, Panda SS, Kariuki BM, Mahmoud SH, Mostafa A, Girgis AS (2023) Spiroindole-containing compounds bearing phosphonate group of potential Mpro-SARS-CoV-2 inhibitory properties. Eur J Med Chem 258:115563. 10.1016/j.ejmech.2023.115563</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejmech.2023.115563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10257517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37329713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berendsen HJC, Postma JPM, van Gunsteren WF, DiNola A, Haak JR (1984) Molecular dynamics with coupling to an external bath. J Chem Phys 81(8):3684&#x2013;3690. 10.1063/1.448118</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.448118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernard M, Qing Y (2022) Bioinsecticides as future mainstream pest control agents: opportunities and challenges. Front Agric Sci Eng 9(1):82&#x2013;97. 10.15302/j-fase-2021404</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15302/j-fase-2021404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogoch II, Watts A, Thomas-Bachli A, Huber C, Kraemer MU, Khan K (2020) Pneumonia of unknown aetiology in wuhan, china: potential for international spread via commercial air travel. J Travel Med 27(2):taaa008. 10.1093/jtm/taaa008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jtm/taaa008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7107534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31943059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bronowska AK (2011) Thermodynamics of ligand-protein interactions: implications for molecular design. In: Thermodynamics-interaction studies-solids, liquids and gases: IntechOpen. 10.1007/s10822-007-9159-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burley SK, Berman HM, Bhikadiya C, Bi C, Chen L, Di Costanzo L et al (2019) RCSB protein data bank: biological macromolecular structures enabling research and education in fundamental biology, biomedicine, biotechnology and energy. Nucleic Acids Res 47(D1):D464&#x2013;D474. 10.1093/nar/gky1004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gky1004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6324064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30357411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bussi G, Donadio D, Parrinello M (2007) Canonical sampling through velocity rescaling. J Chem Phys 126(1):014101</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.2408420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17212484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butu M, Stef R, Grozea I, Corneanu M, Butnariu M (2020) Biopesticides: clean and viable technology for healthy environment. In: Bioremediation and biotechnology: sustainable approaches to pollution degradation, pp 107&#x2013;151. 10.1007/978-3-030-35691-0_6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chanda E (2016) Optimizing strategic insecticide resistance management planning in malaria vectors. Insectic Resist. 10.5772/61301</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5772/61301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman E, Best MD, Hanson SR, Wong CH (2004) Sulfotransferases: structure, mechanism, biological activity, inhibition, and synthetic utility. Angew Chem Int Ed Engl 43(27):3526&#x2013;3548. 10.1002/anie.200300631</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.200300631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15293241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Li H, Tian L, Li Q, Luo J, Zhang Y (2020) Analysis of the physicochemical properties of acaricides based on Lipinski&#x2019;s rule of five. J Comput Biol 27(9):1397&#x2013;1406. 10.1089/cmb.2019.032</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cmb.2019.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32031890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chierrito TPC, Aguiar ACC, de Andrade IM, Ceravolo IP, Gon&#xe7;alves RAC, de Oliveira AJB et al (2014) Anti-malarial activity of indole alkaloids isolated from aspidosperma olivaceum. Malar J 13(1):142. 10.1186/1475-2875-13-142</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1475-2875-13-142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4006081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24731256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarkson CS, Miles A, Harding NJ, Lucas ER, Battey CJ, Amaya-Romero JE et al (2020) Genome variation and population structure among 1142 mosquitoes of the african malaria vector species <i>Anopheles gambiae</i> and <i>Anopheles coluzzii</i>. Genome Res 30(10):1533&#x2013;1546. 10.1101/gr.262790.120
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/gr.262790.120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7605271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32989001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cozzini P, Fornabaio M, Mozzarelli A, Spyrakis F, Kellogg GE, Abraham DJ (2006) Water: how to evaluate its contribution in protein&#x2013;ligand interactions. Int J Quantum Chem 106(3):647&#x2013;651. 10.1002/qua.20812</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/qua.20812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daina A, Michielin O, Zoete V (2017) SwissADME: a free web tool to evaluate pharmacokinetics, drug-likeness and medicinal chemistry friendliness of small molecules. Sci Rep 7(1):42717. 10.1038/srep42717</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep42717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5335600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28256516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das A, Rajkhowa S, Sinha S, Zaki ME (2024) Unveiling potential repurposed drug candidates for <i>Plasmodium falciparum</i> through in silico evaluation: a synergy of structure-based approaches, structure prediction, and molecular dynamics simulations. Comput Biol Chem 110:108048. 10.1016/j.compbiolchem.2024.108048
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compbiolchem.2024.108048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38471353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Beer S, Vermeulen NP, Oostenbrink C (2010) The role of water molecules in computational drug design. Curr Top Med Chem 10(1):55&#x2013;66. 10.2174/156802610790232288</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/156802610790232288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19929830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeLano WL (2002) Pymol: an open-source molecular graphics tool. CCP4 Newsl Protein Crystallogr 40(1):82&#x2013;92</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di S, Wang Z, Cang T, Xie Y, Zhao H, Qi P et al (2021) Enantioselective toxicity and mechanism of chiral fungicide penflufen based on experiments and computational chemistry. Ecotoxicol Environ Saf 222:112534. 10.1016/j.ecoenv.2021.112534</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoenv.2021.112534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34311429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinner AR, &#x160;ali A, Smith LJ, Dobson CM, Karplus M (2000) Understanding protein folding via free-energy surfaces from theory and experiment. Trends Biochem Sci 25(7):331&#x2013;339</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0968-0004(00)01610-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10871884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodda LS, Cabeza de Vaca I, Tirado-Rives J, Jorgensen WL (2017a) LigParGen web server: an automatic OPLS-AA parameter generator for organic ligands. Nucleic Acids Res 45(W1):W331&#x2013;W336. 10.1093/nar/gkx312</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkx312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5793816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28444340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodda LS, Vilseck JZ, Tirado-Rives J, Jorgensen WL (2017b) 1.14* CM1A-LBCC: localized bond-charge corrected CM1A charges for condensed-phase simulations. J Phys Chem B 121(15):3864&#x2013;3870. 10.1021/acs.jpcb.7b00272</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcb.7b00272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5813481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28224794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eberhardt J, Santos-Martins D, Tillack AF, Forli S (2021) AutoDock Vina 1.2.0: new docking methods, expanded force field, and python bindings. J Chem Inf Model 61(8):3891&#x2013;3898. 10.1021/acs.jcim.1c00203</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jcim.1c00203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10683950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34278794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eichenseer H, Mullin CA, Chyb S (1998) Antifeedant discrimination thresholds for two populations of western corn rootworm. Physiol Entomol 23(3):220&#x2013;226. 10.1046/j.1365-3032.1998.233078.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-3032.1998.233078.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Hachem N, Haibe-Kains B, Khalil A, Kobeissy FH, Nemer G (2017) AutoDock and AutoDockTools for protein-ligand docking: beta-site amyloid precursor protein cleaving enzyme 1 (BACE1) as a case study. Neuroproteomics Methods Protoc. 10.1007/978-1-4939-6952-4_20</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-4939-6952-4_20</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28508374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Essmann U, Perera L, Berkowitz ML, Darden T, Lee H, Pedersen LG (1995) A smooth particle mesh Ewald method. J Chem Phys 103(19):8577&#x2013;8593. 10.1063/1.470117</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.470117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiorentino F, Castiello C, Mai A, Rotili D (2022) Therapeutic potential and activity modulation of the protein lysine deacylase sirtuin 5. J Med Chem 65(14):9580&#x2013;9606. 10.1021/acs.jmedchem.2c00687</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jmedchem.2c00687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9340778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35802779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forli S, Huey R, Pique ME, Sanner MF, Goodsell DS, Olson AJ (2016) Computational protein&#x2013;ligand docking and virtual drug screening with the AutoDock suite. Nat Protoc 11(5):905&#x2013;919. 10.1038/nprot.2016.051</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nprot.2016.051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4868550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27077332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamage NU, Tsvetanov S, Duggleby RG, McManus ME, Martin JL (2005) The structure of human SULT1A1 crystallized with estradiol: an insight into active site plasticity and substrate inhibition with multi-ring substrates*. J Biol Chem 280(50):41482&#x2013;41486. 10.1074/jbc.M508289200</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M508289200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16221673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genheden S, Ryde U (2015) The MM/PBSA and MM/GBSA methods to estimate ligand-binding affinities. Expert Opin Drug Discov 10(5):449&#x2013;461. 10.1517/17460441.2015.1032936</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1517/17460441.2015.1032936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4487606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25835573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glatt H (2000) Sulfotransferases in the bioactivation of xenobiotics. Chem Biol Interact 129(1&#x2013;2):141&#x2013;170. 10.1016/s0009-2797(00)00202-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0009-2797(00)00202-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11154739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta SK, Mandal A, Ghosh A, Kundu A, Saha S, Singh A et al (2024) Evaluating the insecticidal potential of alkaloids for the management of thrips palmi: in vivo and in silico perspectives. Sci Rep 14(1):28045. 10.1038/s41598-024-77236-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-77236-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11564808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39543116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haines LR, Trett A, Rose C, Garc&#xed;a N, Sterkel M (2025) Anopheles mosquito survival and pharmacokinetic modeling show the mosquitocidal activity of nitisinone. Sci Transl Med 17(791):eadr4827. 10.1126/scitranslmed.adr4827</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/scitranslmed.adr4827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40138457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halgren TA (1996) Merck molecular force field. I basis, form, scope, parameterization, and performance of MMFF94. J Comput Chem 17(5&#x2013;6):490&#x2013;519. 10.1002/(SICI)1096-987X(199604)17:5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1096-987X(199604)17:5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamann PR, Hinman LM, Hollander I, Beyer CF, Lindh D, Holcomb R et al (2002) Gemtuzumab ozogamicin, a potent and selective anti-CD33 antibody&#x2212;calicheamicin conjugate for treatment of acute myeloid leukemia. Bioconjug Chem 13(1):47&#x2013;58. 10.1021/bc010021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/bc010021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11792178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Q, Wong DM, Robinson H, Ding H, Lam PC, Totrov MM et al (2018) Crystal structure of acetylcholinesterase catalytic subunits of the malaria vector <i>Anopheles gambiae</i>. Insect Sci 25(4):721. 10.1111/1744-7917.12450
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1744-7917.12450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5581290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28247978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haug EJ, Arora JS, Matsui K (1976) A steepest-descent method for optimization of mechanical systems. J Optim Theory Appl 19(3):401&#x2013;424. 10.1007/BF00941484</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00941484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hess B, Bekker H, Berendsen HJC, Fraaije JGEM (1997) LINCS: a linear constraint solver for molecular simulations. JCC 18(12):1463&#x2013;1472. 10.1002/(SICI)1096987X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1096987X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho TC, Chan AH, Ganesan A (2020) Thirty years of HDAC inhibitors: 2020 insight and hindsight. J Med Chem 63(21):12460&#x2013;12484. 10.1021/acs.jmedchem.0c00830</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jmedchem.0c00830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32608981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holliday GL, Mitchell JB, Thornton JM (2009) Understanding the functional roles of amino acid residues in enzyme catalysis. J Mol Biol 390(3):560&#x2013;577. 10.1016/j.jmb.2009.05.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmb.2009.05.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19447117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horn HW, Swope WC, Pitera JW, Madura JD, Dick TJ, Hura GL et al (2004) Development of an improved four-site water model for biomolecular simulations: TIP4P-Ew. J Chem Phys 120(20):9665&#x2013;9678. 10.1063/1.1683075</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.1683075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15267980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ippolito MM, Moser KA, Kabuya J-BB, Cunningham C, Juliano JJ (2021) Antimalarial drug resistance and implications for the WHO global technical strategy. Curr Epidemiol Rep 8:46&#x2013;62. 10.1007/s40471-021-00266-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40471-021-00266-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7955901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33747712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwaloye O, Ottu PO, Olawale F, Babalola OO, Elekofehinti OO, Kikiowo B et al (2023) Computer-aided drug design in anti-cancer drug discovery: what have we learnt and what is the way forward? Inform Med Unlocked 41:101332. 10.1016/j.imu.2023.101332</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.imu.2023.101332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jejurikar BL, Rohane SH (2021) Drug designing in discovery studio. 10.1007/s10822-007-9159-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez-D&#xed;az M-B, M&#xf6;hrle JJ, Angulo-Barturen I, Demarta-Gatsi C (2023) Using cryopreserved <i>Plasmodium falciparum</i> sporozoites in a humanized mouse model to study early malaria infection processes and test prophylactic treatments. Microorganisms 11(9):2209. 10.3390/microorganisms11092209
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/microorganisms11092209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10536749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37764054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorgensen WL, Tirado-Rives J (2005) Potential energy functions for atomic-level simulations of water and organic and biomolecular systems. Proc Natl Acad Sci 102(19):6665&#x2013;6670. 10.1073/pnas.0408037102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.0408037102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1100738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15870211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakuta Y, Pedersen LG, Carter CW, Negishi M, Pedersen LC (1997) Crystal structure of estrogen sulphotransferase. Nat Struct Biol 4(11):904&#x2013;908. 10.1038/nsb1197-904</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nsb1197-904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9360604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaminski GA, Friesner RA, Tirado-Rives J, Jorgensen WL (2001) Evaluation and reparametrization of the OPLS-AA force field for proteins via comparison with accurate quantum chemical calculations on peptides. J Phys Chem B 105(28):6474&#x2013;6487. 10.1021/jp003919d</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp003919d</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasai S, Komagata O, Itokawa K, Shono T, Ng LC, Kobayashi M et al (2014) Mechanisms of pyrethroid resistance in the dengue mosquito vector, aedes aegypti: target site insensitivity, penetration, and metabolism. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 8(6):e2948. 10.1371/journal.pntd.0002948</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0002948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4063723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24945250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan P, Parkash A, Islam A, Ahmad F, Hassan MI (2016) Molecular basis of the structural stability of hemochromatosis factor E: a combined molecular dynamic simulation and GdmCl-induced denaturation study. Biopolymers 105(3):133&#x2013;142. 10.1002/bip.22760</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bip.22760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26537310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landrum G (2013) Rdkit documentation. Release 1(1&#x2013;79):4. 10.1007/s00894-022-05359-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00894-022-05359-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis Phillips GD, Li G, Dugger DL, Crocker LM, Parsons KL, Mai E et al (2008) Targeting HER2-positive breast cancer with trastuzumab-DM1, an antibody&#x2013;cytotoxic drug conjugate. Can Res 68(22):9280&#x2013;9290. 10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-08-1776</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-08-1776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19010901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Managi S (2022) Global malaria infection risk from climate change. Environ Res 214:114028. 10.1016/j.envres.2022.114028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2022.114028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35940231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Zhao F, Zhao B, Yang J, Ferrara J, Sankaran B et al (2021) Structural basis of the stereoselective formation of the spirooxindole ring in the biosynthesis of citrinadins. Nat Commun 12(1):4158. 10.1038/s41467-021-24421-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-24421-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8260726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34230497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matowo N (2020) Dynamics of insecticide resistance in <i>Anopheles arabiensis</i> and <i>culex pipiens</i> complex, and its associations to agricultural practices in southern Tanzania. University of Basel, Report</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mbare O (2015)Novel insecticides and application strategies for malaria vector control 10.17037/pubs.02374462</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monroe A, Williams NA, Ogoma S, Karema C, Okumu F (2022) Reflections on the 2021 world malaria report and the future of malaria control. BioMed Cent. 10.1186/s12936-022-04178-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12936-022-04178-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9137259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35624483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris GM, Huey R, Olson AJ (2008) Using AutoDock for ligand-receptor docking. Curr Protoc Bioinform 24(1):8&#x2013;14. 10.1002/0471250953.bi0814s24</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/0471250953.bi0814s24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19085980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muegge I, Rarey M (2001) Small molecule docking and scoring. Rev Comput Chem 17:1&#x2013;60. 10.1002/0471224413.ch1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/0471224413.ch1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negishi M, Pedersen LG, Petrotchenko E, Shevtsov S, Gorokhov A, Kakuta Y et al (2001) Structure and function of sulfotransferases. Arch Biochem Biophys 390(2):149&#x2013;157. 10.1006/abbi.2001.2368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/abbi.2001.2368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11396917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nkungli NK, Fouegue ADT, Tasheh SN, Bine FK, Hassan AU, Ghogomu JN (2024) In silico investigation of falcipain-2 inhibition by hybrid benzimidazole-thiosemicarbazone antiplasmodial agents: a molecular docking, molecular dynamics simulation, and kinetics study. Mol Divers 28(2):475&#x2013;549. 10.1007/s11030-022-10594-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11030-022-10594-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9838286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36622482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Boyle NM, Banck M, James CA, Morley C, Vandermeersch T, Hutchison GR (2011) Open Babel: an open chemical toolbox. J Cheminformatics 3(1):33</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1758-2946-3-33</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3198950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21982300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okombo J, Fidock DA (2024) Towards next-generation treatment options to combat <i>Plasmodium falciparum</i> malaria. Nat Rev Microbiol. 10.1038/s41579-024-01099-x
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41579-024-01099-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11832322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39367132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okumu F (2020) The fabric of life: what if mosquito nets were durable and widely available but insecticide-free? Malar J 19(1):1&#x2013;29. 10.1186/s12936-020-03321-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12936-020-03321-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7370456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32690016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Leary DP (1979) Conjugate gradient algorithms in the solution of optimization problems for nonlinear elliptic partial differential equations. Computing 22(1):59&#x2013;77. 10.1007/BF02246559</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02246559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orozco MI, Moreno P, Guevara M, Abonia R, Quiroga J, Insuasty B et al (2024) In silico prediction and in vitro assessment of novel heterocyclics with antimalarial activity. Parasitol Res 123(1):75. 10.1007/s00436-023-08089-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00436-023-08089-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10754745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38155300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oshiokhayamhe I, Israel I, Agumeile K (2021) Assessment of the prevalence of malaria and typhoid fever among apparently healthy undergraduates. Int J Med Sci Public Health 7(2):13&#x2013;17. 10.32861/IJHMS.72.13.17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32861/IJHMS.72.13.17</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panda SK, Saxena S, Gupta PSS, Rana MK (2021) Inhibitors of plasmepsin X <i>Plasmodium falciparum</i>: structure-based pharmacophore generation and molecular dynamics simulation. J Mol Liq 340:116851. 10.1016/j.molliq.2021.116851</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2021.116851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parrinello M, Rahman A (1981) Polymorphic transitions in single crystals: a new molecular dynamics method. J Appl Phys 52(12):7182&#x2013;7190. 10.1063/1.328693</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.328693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei Z (2024) Computer-aided drug discovery: from traditional simulation methods to language models and quantum computing. Cell Rep Phys Sci 5(12):102334. 10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.102334</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.102334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng X, Baxa M, Faruk N, Sachleben JR, Pintscher S, Gagnon IA et al (2022) Prediction and validation of a protein&#x2019;s free energy surface using hydrogen exchange and (importantly) its denaturant dependence. J Chem Theory Comput 18(1):550&#x2013;561. 10.1021/acs.jctc.1c00960</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jctc.1c00960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8757463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34936354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pludowski P, Holick MF, Pilz S, Wagner CL, Hollis BW, Grant WB et al (2013) Vitamin D effects on musculoskeletal health, immunity, autoimmunity, cardiovascular disease, cancer, fertility, pregnancy, dementia and mortality&#x2014;a review of recent evidence. Autoimmun Rev 12(10):976&#x2013;989. 10.1016/j.autrev.2013.02.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autrev.2013.02.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23542507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rai P (2021) Study of resistance and underlying mechanisms against common insecticides in <i>culex quinquefasciatus</i> say, from different districts of northern part of West Bengal, India. University of North Bengal. https://ir.nbu.ac.in/handle/123456789/4325</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramadhan DSF, Siharis F, Abdurrahman S, Isrul M, Fakih TM (2022) In silico analysis of marine natural product from sponge for (<i>Clathria</i> sp.) their activity as inhibitor of SARS-CoV-2 main protease. J Biomol Struct Dyn 40(22):11526&#x2013;11532. 10.1080/07391102.2021.1959405
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07391102.2021.1959405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34338602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodier F, Bahadur RP, Chakrabarti P, Janin J (2005) Hydration of protein&#x2013;protein interfaces. Proteins Struct Funct Bioinform 60(1):36&#x2013;45. 10.1002/prot.20478</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/prot.20478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15856483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rottmann M, McNamara C, Yeung BK, Lee MC, Zou B, Russell B et al (2010) Spiroindolones, a potent compound class for the treatment of malaria. Science 329(5996):1175&#x2013;1180. 10.1126/science.1193225</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1193225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3050001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20813948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakthivel S, Mohideen HS, Raman C, Mohamad SB (2022) Potential Acetylcholinesterase inhibitor acting on the pesticide-resistant and susceptible cotton pests. ACS Omega 7(24):20515&#x2013;20527. 10.1021/acsomega.1c07359</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.1c07359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9219083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35755373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salawu EO (2018) In silico study reveals how E64 approaches, binds to, and inhibits falcipain-2 of <i>Plasmodium falciparum</i> that causes malaria in humans. Sci Rep 8(1):16380. 10.1038/s41598-018-34622-1
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-018-34622-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6219542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30401806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkhel S, Desiraju GR (2004) N&#x2013;H&#x2026; O, O&#x2013;H&#x2026; O, and C&#x2013;H&#x2026; O hydrogen bonds in protein&#x2013;ligand complexes: Strong and weak interactions in molecular recognition. Proteins Struct Funct Bioinform 54(2):247&#x2013;259. 10.1002/PROT.10567</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/PROT.10567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14696187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarnpitak P, Mujumdar P, Taylor P, Cross M, Coster MJ, Gorse A-D et al (2015) Panel docking of small-molecule libraries&#x2014;prospects to improve efficiency of lead compound discovery. Biotechnol Adv 33(6):941&#x2013;947. 10.1016/j.biotechadv.2015.05.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biotechadv.2015.05.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26025037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiebel J, Gaspari R, Wulsdorf T, Ngo K, Sohn C, Schrader TE et al (2018) Intriguing role of water in protein-ligand binding studied by neutron crystallography on trypsin complexes. Nat Commun 9(1):3559. 10.1038/s41467-018-05769-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-018-05769-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6120877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30177695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seeliger D, de Groot BL (2010) Ligand docking and binding site analysis with PyMOL and Autodock/Vina. J Comput Aided Mol des 24(5):417&#x2013;422. 10.1007/s10822-010-9352-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10822-010-9352-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2881210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20401516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15e;eng&#xfc;l Demirak M&#x15e;, Canpolat E (2022) Plant-based bioinsecticides for mosquito control: impact on insecticide resistance and disease transmission. InseCts 13(2):162. 10.3390/insects13020162</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/insects13020162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8878986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35206735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sgro J-Y (2017) UCSF Chimaera-I-Introduction</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shadrack DM, Deogratias G, Kiruri LW, Onoka I, Vianney J-M, Swai H et al (2021a) Luteolin: a blocker of SARS-CoV-2 cell entry based on relaxed complex scheme, molecular dynamics simulation, and metadynamics. J Mol Model 27:1&#x2013;15. 10.1007/s00894-021-04833-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00894-021-04833-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8264176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34236507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shadrack DM, Deogratias G, Kiruri LW, Swai HS, Vianney J-M, Nyandoro SS (2021b) Ensemble-based screening of natural products and FDA-approved drugs identified potent inhibitors of SARS-CoV-2 that work with two distinct mechanisms. J Mol Graph Model 105:107871. 10.1016/j.jmgm.2021.107871</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmgm.2021.107871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7901283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33684603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapovalov MV, Dunbrack RL (2011) A smoothed backbone-dependent rotamer library for proteins derived from adaptive kernel density estimates and regressions. Structure 19(6):844&#x2013;858. 10.1016/j.str.2011.03.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.str.2011.03.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3118414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21645855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sikaala C (2014) Community-based monitoring of vector control interventions impact upon mosquito population dynamics in rural zambia. University of Liverpool, Report</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Souto AL, Sylvestre M, T&#xf6;lke ED, Tavares JF, Barbosa-Filho JM, Cebri&#xe1;n-Torrej&#xf3;n G (2021) Plant-derived pesticides as an alternative to pest management and sustainable agricultural production: prospects, applications and challenges. Molecules 26(16):4835. 10.3390/molecules26164835</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules26164835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8400533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34443421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stavrou-Dowd ZT, Parsons G, Rose C, Brown F, Lees RS, Acosta-Serrano A et al (2025) The beta-triketone, nitisinone, kills insecticide-resistant mosquitoes through cuticular uptake. <i>bioRxiv</i>, 2025.2001. 2029.635148</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12315382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40745331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tafesse T, Tolera C, Amenu D (2023) A retrospective analysis of malaria trends in leka dulecha health center over the last ten years (2013&#x2013;2022), western oromia east wollega zone. BioMed Res Int 2023(1):6635249. 10.1155/2023/6635249</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2023/6635249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10425245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37583960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeshita A, Yamakage N, Shinjo K, Ono T, Hirano I, Nakamura S et al (2009) CMC-544 (inotuzumab ozogamicin), an anti-CD22 immuno-conjugate of calicheamicin, alters the levels of target molecules of malignant B-cells. Leukemia 23(7):1329&#x2013;1336. 10.1038/leu.2009.77</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/leu.2009.77</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19369961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka S, Nishiyori T, Kojo H, Otsubo R, Tsuruta M, Kurogi K, Kakuta Y (2017) Structural basis for the broad substrate specificity of the human tyrosylprotein sulfotransferase-1. Sci Rep 7(1):8776. 10.1038/s41598-017-07141-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-07141-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5562738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28821720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teder T, Knapp M (2019) Sublethal effects enhance detrimental impact of insecticides on non-target organisms: a quantitative synthesis in parasitoids. Chemosphere 214:371&#x2013;378. 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2018.09.132</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2018.09.132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30267910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toropov AA, Toropova AP, Mukhamedzhanoval DV, Gutman I (2005) Simplified molecular input line entry system (SMILES) as an alternative for constructing quantitative structure-property relationships (QSPR). Indian J Chem Sect A Inorg Phys Theor Anal Chem 44(8):1545&#x2013;1552</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trott O, Olson AJ (2010) AutoDock Vina: improving the speed and accuracy of docking with a new scoring function, efficient optimization, and multithreading. J Comput Chem 31(2):455&#x2013;461. 10.1002/jcc.21334</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcc.21334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3041641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19499576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vadakkan K, Aravoor SS, Mundanttu MR, Devanooru BK, Puthiyamadathil VM (2024) Acetylcholinesterase inhibition mediated the larvicidal activity of mangifera indica extract against culex quinquefasciatus. Clin Phytoscience 10(1):12. 10.1186/s40816-024-00379-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40816-024-00379-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Pelt-Koops J, Pett H, Graumans W, Van Der Vegte-Bolmer M, Van Gemert G, Rottmann M et al (2012) The spiroindolone drug candidate NITD609 potently inhibits gametocytogenesis and blocks <i>Plasmodium falciparum</i> transmission to anopheles mosquito vector. Antimicrob Agents Chemother 56(7):3544&#x2013;3548. 10.1128/aac.06377-11
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/aac.06377-11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3393464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22508309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vennelakanti V, Qi HW, Mehmood R, Kulik HJ (2021) When are two hydrogen bonds better than one? Accurate first-principles models explain the balance of hydrogen bond donors and acceptors found in proteins. Chem Sci 12(3):1147&#x2013;1162. 10.1039/d0sc05084a</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d0sc05084a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8908278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35382134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vergaray Ramirez MA, Sterkel M, Martins AJ, Lima BPJ, Oliveira PL (2022) On the use of inhibitors of 4-hydroxyphenylpyruvate dioxygenase as a vector-selective insecticide in the control of mosquitoes. Pest Manag Sci 78(2):692&#x2013;702. 10.1101/669747</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/669747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34647418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verza AE, Miggiano R, Lombardo F, Fiorillo C, Arc&#xe0; B, Purgh&#xe9; B et al (2022) Biochemical and structural analysis of a cytosolic sulfotransferase of the malaria vector <i>Anopheles gambiae</i> overexpressed in the reproductive tissues. Curr Res Struct Biol 4:246&#x2013;255. 10.1016/j.crstbi.2022.07.001
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.crstbi.2022.07.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9356239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35941867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walters WP (2012) Going further than Lipinski&#x2019;s rule in drug design. Expert Opin Drug Discov 7(2):99&#x2013;107. 10.1517/17460441.2012.648612</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1517/17460441.2012.648612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22468912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Greene D, Xiao L, Qi R, Luo R (2017) Recent developments and applications of the MMPBSA method. Front Mol Biosci 4:87. 10.3389/fmolb.2017.00087</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmolb.2017.00087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5768160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29367919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng M, Pan M, Zhang W, Lin H, Wu S, Lu C et al (2021) Poly (&#x3b1;-l-lysine)-based nanomaterials for versatile biomedical applications: current advances and perspectives. Bioact Mater 6(7):1878&#x2013;1909. 10.1016/j.bioactmat.2020.12.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bioactmat.2020.12.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7744653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33364529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>