<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38808237</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2046-2069</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>24</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>RSC advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>RSC Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Novel carbazolyl-thiazolyl-chromone and carbazolyl-thiazolyl-pyrazole hybrids: synthesis, cytotoxicity evaluation and molecular docking studies.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>17245</StartPage><EndPage>17260</EndPage><MedlinePgn>17245-17260</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1039/d4ra03188a</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>A simple synthetic method was performed to design a novel series of polycyclic systems consisting of carbazole-thiazolidinone-chromone hybrids 4a-e and carbazole-thiazolidinone-pyrazole hybrids 5a-e in excellent yields. The methodology depended on the one-pot four-component reaction of 3-amino-9-ethylcarbazole, substituted isothiocyanates, ethyl bromoacetate and 6-methyl-3-formylchromone in ethanol under ultrasound waves at 50 &#xb0;C to give the carbazole-thiazolidinone-chromone hybrids 4a-e. The latter isolated products were treated with hydrazine hydrate in ethanol under ultrasound waves at 50 &#xb0;C affording the corresponding carbazole-thiazolidinone-pyrazole hybrids 5a-e. Spectral and analytical data confirmed the structures of all the synthesized compounds. The target compounds were screened for their <i>in vitro</i> anticancer activities against HCT116, PC3 and HepG2 cancer cell lines using the standard SRB method. Fortunately, both compounds 5dand5e were the most active against all cancer cell lines compared with doxorubicin and can be promising anticancer agents. Both bioactive products 5band5e were studied by the molecular docking to see how they bind with VEGFR-2 receptor. The results indicated that those compounds exhibited high affinities towards VEGFR-2 and established remarkably similar interactions to those of the powerful VEGFR-2-KDR.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>This journal is &#xa9; The Royal Society of Chemistry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hassanin</LastName><ForeName>Noha M</ForeName><Initials>NM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4310-0477</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Faculty of Education, Ain Shams University Cairo Egypt noha-mohamed@edu.asu.edu.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ali</LastName><ForeName>Tarik E</ForeName><Initials>TE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7992-3478</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Central Labs, King Khalid University, AlQuraa Abha Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Faculty of Science, King Khalid University, AlQuraa Abha Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Assiri</LastName><ForeName>Mohammed A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Faculty of Science, King Khalid University, AlQuraa Abha Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdel-Kariem</LastName><ForeName>Somaia M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Faculty of Education, Ain Shams University Cairo Egypt noha-mohamed@edu.asu.edu.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>RSC Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101581657</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2046-2069</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>Authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38808237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11132180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d4ra03188a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">d4ra03188a</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>McGuire S. World Cancer Report 2014, World Health Organization, International Agency for Research on Cancer, WHO Press, Geneva, Switzerland, 2015. Adv. Nutr. 2016;7:418&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4785485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26980827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu K. Jiang Z. Lalancette R. A. Tang X. J&#xe4;kle F. Near-Infrared-Absorbing B&#x2013;N Lewis Pair-Functionalized Anthracenes: Electronic Structure Tuning, Conformational Isomerism, and Applications in Photothermal Cancer Therapy. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2022;144:18908&#x2013;18917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36194812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moinul M. Khatun S. Amin S. A. Jha T. Gayen S. Recent trends in fragment-based anticancer drug design strategies against different targets: A mini-review. Biochem. Pharmacol. 2022;206:115301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36265594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assiri M. A. Ali A. Ibrahim M. Khan M. U. Ahmed K. Akash M. S. H. Abbas M. A. Javed A. Suleman M. hi M. K. Hussain I. Potential anticancer and antioxidant lauric acid based hydrazone synthesis and computational study toward the electronic properties. RSC Adv. 2023;13:21793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10354594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37476049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abulkhair H. S. Turky A. Ghiaty A. Ahmed H. E. Bayoumi A. H. Novel triazolophthalazine-hydrazone hybrids as potential PCAF inhibitors: Design, synthesis, in vitro anticancer evaluation, apoptosis, and molecular docking studies. Bioorg. Chem. 2020;100:103899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32454390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elkaeed E. B. Yousef R. G. Elkady H. Gobaara I. M. Alsfouk A. A. Husein D. Z. Ibrahim I. M. Metwaly A. M. Eissa I. H. The assessment of anticancer and VEGFR-2 inhibitory activities of a new 1H-&#x131;ndole derivative: In silico and in vitro approaches. Processes. 2022;10:1391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taghour M. S. Elkady H. Eldehna W. M. El-Deeb N. M. Kenawy A. M. Elkaeed E. B. Alsfouk A. A. Alesawy M. S. Metwaly A. M. Eissa I. H. Design and synthesis of thiazolidine-2,4-diones hybrids with 1,2-dihydroquinolones and 2-oxindoles as potential VEGFR-2 inhibitors: In vitro anticancer evaluation and in-silico studies. J. Enzyme Inhib. Med. Chem. 2022;37:1903&#x2013;1917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9272924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35801403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajeshwari R. Chand K. Candeias E. Cardoso S. M. Chaves S. Santos M. A. New Multitarget Hybrids Bearing Tacrine and Phenyl benzothiazole Motifs as Potential Drug Candidates for Alzheimer's Disease. Molecules. 2019;24:587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6385087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30736397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Sena Murteira Pinheiro P. Franco L. S. Montagnoli T. L. Fraga C. A. M. Molecular hybridization: a powerful tool for multitarget drug discovery. Expet Opin. Drug Discov. 2024;19:451&#x2013;470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38456452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira Pedrosa M. Duarte da Cruz R. M. de Oliveira Viana J. de Moura R. O. Ishiki H. M. Barbosa Filho J. M. Diniz M. F. Scotti M. T. Scotti L. Bezerra Mendonca F. J. Hybrid Compounds as Direct Multitarget Ligands: A Review. Curr. Top. Med. Chem. 2017;17:1044&#x2013;1079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27697048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y. P. Hu S. Liu Y. Y. Zhang M. M. Zhang W. H. Qiang L. Fu Y. H. Anti-inflammatory and antiproliferative prenylated carbazole alkaloids from Clausena vestita. Bioorg. Chem. 2019;91:103107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31344516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y. Y. Zhou H. Deng P. Zhang B. Q. Zhang Z. J. Wang G. H. Zhang S. Y. Wu Z. R. Wang Y. R. Liu Y. Q. Antimicrobial activity of natural and semi-synthetic carbazole alkaloids. Eur. J. Med. Chem. 2023;259:115627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37467619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bashir M. Bano A. Ijaz A. S. Chaudhary B. A. Recent Developments and Biological Activities of N-Substituted Carbazole Derivatives: A Review. Molecules. 2015;20:13496&#x2013;13517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6332089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26213906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caruso A. Chimento A. El-Kashef H. Lancelot J. C. Panno A. Pezzi V. Saturnino C. Sinicropi M. S. Sirianni R. Rault S. Antiproliferative Activity of Some 1,4-Dimethylcarbazoles on Cells That Express Estrogen Receptors: Part I. J. Enzyme Inhib. Med. Chem. 2012;27:609&#x2013;613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21883039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caruso A. Sinicropi M. S. Lancelot J. C. El-Kashef H. Saturnino C. Aubert G. Ballandonne C. Lesnard A. Cresteil T. Dallemagne P. Synthesis and Evaluation of Cytotoxic Activities of New Guanidines Derived from Carbazoles. Bioorg. Med. Chem. Lett. 2014;24:467&#x2013;472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24374274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panno A. Sinicropi M. S. Caruso A. El-Kashef H. Lancelot J. C. Aubert G. Lesnard A. Cresteil T. Rault S. New Trimethoxybenzamides and Trimethoxyphenylureas Derived from Dimethylcarbazole as Cytotoxic Agents. Part I. J. Heterocycl. Chem. 2014;51:E294&#x2013;E302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang G. Sun S. Guo H. Current status of carbazole hybrids as anticancer agents. Eur. J. Med. Chem. 2022;229:113999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34838335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#x142;uszy&#x144;ska A. Biological potential of carbazole derivatives. Eur. J. Med. Chem. 2015;94:405&#x2013;426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25794500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;&#xe7;&#xfc;kg&#xfc;zel G. Kocatepe A. Clercq E. D. &#x15e;ahin F. G&#xfc;ll&#xfc;ce M. Synthesis and biological activity of 4-thiazolidinones, thiosemicarbazides derived from diflunisal hydrazide. Eur. J. Med. Chem. 2006;41:353&#x2013;359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16414150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma A. Saraf S. K. 4-Thiazolidinone&#x2013;A biologically active scaffold. Eur. J. Med. Chem. 2008;43:897&#x2013;905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17870209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akerblom E. B. Synthesis and structure-activity relations of a series of antibacterially active 5-(5-nitro-2-furfurylidene)thiazolones, 5-(5-nitro-2-furylpropenylidene)thiazolones, and 6-(5-nitro-2-furyl)-4H-1,3-thiazinones. J. Med. Chem. 1974;17:609&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4598022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdel-Wahab F. Mohamed S. F. Amr A. E.-G. E. Abdalla M. M. Synthesis and reactions of thiosemicarbazides, Triazoles, and Schiff bases as antihypertensive &#x3b1;-blocking agents. Monatsh. Chem. 2008;139:1083&#x2013;1090.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amir M. Agarwal R. Synthesis and antibacterial activity of 1-thiocarbamoyl-3-methyl-4-arylhydrazono-2-pyrazolin-5-one. J. Indian Chem. Soc. 1997;74:154&#x2013;155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assiri M. A. Ali T. E. Alqahtani M. N. Shati A. A. Alfaifi M. Y. Elbehairi S. E. I. Synthesis, Cytotoxic Evaluation, Apoptosis, Cell cycle and Molecular docking Studies of Some New 5-(Arylidene/heteroarylidene)-2-(Morpholinoimino)-3-Phenylthiazolidin-4-ones. Synth. Commun. 2023;23:1240&#x2013;1261.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assiri M. A. Ali T. E. Alqahtani M. N. Shati A. A. Alfaifi M. Y. Elbehairi S. E. I. Recyclization of Morpholinochromonylidene-Thiazolidinone Using Nucleophiles: Facile Synthesis, Cytotoxic Evaluation, Apoptosis, Cell cycle and Molecular docking Studies of a Novel Series of Azole, Azine, Azepine and Pyran Derivatives. RSC Adv. 2023;13:18658&#x2013;18675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10281007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37346943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali T. E. Hussien M. El Sayed I. E. Abdelaleem A. H. Torkey H. M. Ultrasound-promoted Kabachnik&#x2013;Fields synthesis of novel chromonyl &#x3b1;-aminophosphonate derivatives incorporating nitrogen heterocycles using CdI2 nanoparticles as an efficient catalyst: evaluation of their antifungal properties. Heterocycles. 2022;104:2132&#x2013;2152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali T. E. Assiri M. A. Shati A. A. Alfaifi M. Y. Elbehairi S. E. I. One-pot three-component synthesis of a series of 2-amino-4-(4-oxo-4H-chromen-3-yl)-5-(2,2,2- trifluoroacetyl)-6-(trifluoromethyl)-4H-pyrans and 2-amino-4-(4-oxo-4H-chromen-3-yl)-5-(thiophene-2-carbonyl)-6-(trifluoromethyl)-4H-pyrans as promising anticancer agents. Russ. J. Org. Chem. 2022;58:584&#x2013;591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo W. Zuo L. Geng X. Li Z. Wang L. Radical-Polar Crossover Enabled Triple Cleavage of CF2Br2: A Multicomponent Tandem Cyclization to 3-Fluoropyrazoles. Org. Lett. 2023;25:6062&#x2013;6066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37552672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghi S. H. Moradi L. Solvent free synthesis of amidoalkyl derivatives under green and convenient conditions. J. Heterocycl. Chem. 2022;59:695&#x2013;703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeghi S. H. Yaghoobi M. Ghasemzadeh M. A. Synthesis of pyrido[2,3-d:5,6-d&#x2032;] dipyrimidines using CuFe2O4/KCC-1/PMA as a novel and efficient nanocatalyst under solvent-free conditions. Appl. Organomet. Chem. 2022;36:e6771.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rostamnia S. Lamei K. A Rapid, Catalyst-Free, Three-Component Synthesis of Rhodanines in Water Using Ultrasound. Synthesis. 2011:3080&#x2013;3082.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gholap A. R. Venkatesan K. Daniel T. R. Lahoti J. Srinivasan K. V. Ionic liquid promoted novel and efficient one pot synthesis of 3,4-dihydropyrimidin-2-(1H)-ones at ambient temperature under ultrasound irradiation. Green Chem. 2004;6:147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazgir A. Ahadi S. Ghahremanzadeh R. Khavasi H. R. Mirzaei P. Ultrasound-assisted one-pot, three-component synthesis of spiro[indoline-3,4&#x2032;-pyrazolo[3,4-b]pyridine]-2,6&#x2032;(1&#x2032;H)-diones in water. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2010;17:447&#x2013;452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19836289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z. H. Li J. J. Li T. S. Ultrasound-assisted synthesis of pyrroles catalyzed by zirconium chloride under solvent-free conditions. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2008;15:673&#x2013;676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18387331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdel-Rahman N. M. Saleh T. S. Mady M. F. Ultrasound assisted synthesis of some new 1,3,4-thiadiazole and bi(1,3,4-thiadiazole)derivatives incorporating pyrazolone moiety. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2009;16:70&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18567527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Y. Chen X. Qu L. Wang J. Yuan J. Chen S. Li X. Qu C. Ultrasonic-assisted synthesis of chrysin derivatives linked with 1,2,3-triazoles by 1,3-dipolar cycloaddition reaction. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2011;18:527&#x2013;533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20971028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahdavinia G. H. Rostamizadeh S. Amani A. M. Emdadi Z. Ultrasound-promoted greener synthesis of aryl-14-H-dibenzo[a,j]xanthenes catalyzed by NH4H2PO4/SiO2 in water. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2009;16:7&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18585075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee B. Recent developments on ultrasound-assisted one-pot multicomponent synthesis of biologically relevant heterocycles. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2017;35:15&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27771265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefani H. A. Cella R. D&#xf6;rr F. A. de Pereira C. M. Gomes F. P. Zeni G. Ultrasound-assisted synthesis of functionalized arylacetylenes. Tetrahedron Lett. 2005;46:2001&#x2013;2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bejan V. Moldoveanu C. Mangalagiu I. I. Ultrasounds assisted reactions of steroid analogous of anticipated biological activities. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2009;16:312&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19081283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zbancioc G. Zbancioc A. M. Mangalagiu I. I. Ultrasound and microwave assisted synthesis of dihydroxyacetophenone derivatives with or without 1,2-diazine skeleton. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2014;21:802&#x2013;811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24139876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zbancioc G. Moldoveanu C. Mangalagiu I. I. Ultrasound assisted synthesis of imidazolium salts: An efficient way to ionic liquids. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2015;23:376&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25465880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bejan V. Mantu D. Mangalagiu I. I. Ultrasound and microwave assisted synthesis of isoindolo-1,2-diazine: A comparative study. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2012;19:999&#x2013;1002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22464108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanzouai Y. Chalkha M. Hadni H. Laghmari M. Bouzammit R. Nakkabi A. Benali T. T&#xfc;z&#xfc;n B. Akhazzane M. El Yazidi M. Al Houari G. Design, synthesis, in-vitro and in-silico studies of chromone-isoxazoline conjugates as anti-bacterial agents. J. Mol. Struct. 2023;1293:136205&#x2013;136217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebenezer O. Shapi M. Tuszynski J. A. A Review of the Recent Development in the Synthesis and Biological Evaluations of Pyrazole Derivatives. Biomedicines. 2022;10:1124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9139179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35625859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galarraga E. Santorelli A. E. Urdaneta N. Rey-Cibati A. Valladares-Delgado M. D&#xed;az-P&#xe9;rez L. J. Milano-Franco L. Benaim G. Synthesis of novel 6-substituted-3-formyl chromone derivatives as anti-leishmanial agents and their possible mechanism of action in Leishmania donovani. J. Mol. Struct. 2023;1280:135081&#x2013;135088.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan J. Zhou W. Shen X. Wang P. C. Synthesis of Chromeno[2,3-b]quinoline Derivatives via ZnCl2-Mediated Three-component Reaction of 2-Aminochromenones, Benzaldehydes and Cyclohexane-1,3-dione. J. Heterocycl. Chem. 2023;60:1230&#x2013;1238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eslaminejad T. Mirzaei E. F. Abaszadeh M. Synthesis, Antioxidant, Cytotoxicity, Induce Apoptosis Investigation and Docking Study of New Halogenated Dihydropyrano [3,2-b]Chromene-3-Carbonitrile Derivatives on MCF-7 Breast Cancer Cell Line. Iran. J. Pharm. Res. (IJPR) 2023;22:132932&#x2013;132945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10728837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38116542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mushtaque M. Rizvi M. M. A. Molecular hybrids based on Pyrazole and 4-Thiazolidinone cores: Synthesis, characterization, and anticancer studies. J. Mol. Struct. 2023;1294:136470&#x2013;136482.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai N. C. Jadeja K. A. Jadeja D. J. Khedkar V. M. Jha P. C. Design, synthesis, antimicrobial evaluation, and molecular docking study of some 4-thiazolidinone derivatives containing pyridine and quinazoline moiety. Synth. Commun. 2021;51:952&#x2013;963.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud A. M. Al-Abd A. M. Lightfoot D. A. El-Shemy H. A. Anticancer characteristics of mevinolin against three different solid tumor cell lines was not solely p53-dependent. J. Enzyme Inhib. Med. Chem. 2012;27:673&#x2013;679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21883038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X. Liao Y. Long D. Yu T. Shen F. Lin X. The Cdc2/Cdk1 inhibitor, purvalanol A, enhances the cytotoxic effects of taxol through Op18/stathmin in non-small cell lung cancer cells in vitro. Int. J. Mol. Med. 2017;40:235&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28534969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan Y. Xu Y. Zhang X. Hu H. Xia W. Yu Z. Sun T. Zhang J. Wen C. Zheng S. Revisiting Supersaturation of a Biopharmaceutical Classification System IIB Drug: Evaluation via a Multi-Cup Dissolution Approach and Molecular Dynamic Simulation. Molecules. 2023;28:6962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10574532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37836805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris G. M. Goodsell D. S. Halliday R. S. Huey R. Hart W. E. Belew R. K. Olson A. J. Automated docking using a Lamarckian genetic algorithm and an empirical binding free energy function. J. Comput. Chem. 1998;19:1639&#x2013;1662.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huey R. Morris G. M. Olson A. J. Goodsell D. S. A semiempirical free energy force field with charge-based desolvation. J. Comput. Chem. 2007;28:1145&#x2013;1152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17274016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris G. M. Huey R. Lindstrom W. Sanner M. F. Belew R. K. Goodsell D. S. Olson A. J. AutoDock4 and AutoDockTools4: Automated docking with selective receptor flexibility. J. Comput. Chem. 2009;30:2785&#x2013;2791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2760638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19399780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trott O. Olson A. J. AutoDock Vina: improving the speed and accuracy of docking with a new scoring function, efficient optimization, and multithreading. J. Comput. Chem. 2010;31:455&#x2013;461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3041641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19499576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eberhardt J. Santos-Martins D. Tillack A. F. Forli S. AutoDock Vina 1.2.0: New Docking Methods, Expanded Force Field, and Python Bindings. J. Chem. Inf. Model. 2021;61:3891&#x2013;3898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10683950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34278794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pettersen E. F. Goddard T. D. Huang C. C. Couch G. S. Greenblatt D. M. Meng E. C. Ferrin T. E. UCSF Chimera-A visualization system for exploratory research and analysis. J. Comput. Chem. 2004;25:1605&#x2013;1612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15264254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>