<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37841189</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-1343</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>40</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS omega</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Omega</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Parabolic Viscosity Behavior of NaCl-Thickened Surfactant Systems upon Temperature Change.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>37511</StartPage><EndPage>37520</EndPage><MedlinePgn>37511-37520</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsomega.3c05855</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The viscosity of household care products plays an important role in pleasant delivery using consumer experience at home. A novel solution to mitigate the sharp rising of viscosities at low temperatures of detergents was proposed. By designing the formulation of the surfactant blend, formulators can achieve acceptable viscosity profiles in the temperature range encountered in daily life. The verification and modulation of formulas bearing parabolic viscosity-temperature behavior were systematically studied, including in single, binary, and ternary systems, based on the modulation of sodium ethoxylated alkyl sulfate (AES) by other anions, zwitterions, and nonions. The <i>R</i> ratio theory was used to have a better understanding of the molecular assembly of surfactants behind the parabolic behavior exhibited in rheology analyses. One of the key findings is that the parabolic viscosity-temperature phenomenon could be easily observed in the highly hydrated ethoxylated anionic systems like AES-based systems. For those anions lacking ethoxylation, especially sodium linear alkylbenzene sulfonate (LAS), the monotonic variation of hydration affinity with temperature led to the disappearance of parabola in the observed temperature window (&gt;0 &#xb0;C). Moreover, salinity played an important role in the hydration affinity of the polar group and the interaction between the hydrophilic headgroups. A balanced salinity should be optimized to modulate the hydration affinity in a desired range so that the parabola could be easily tuned within the target temperature region. These findings provide opportunities for the formulators in the household care industry to design products with better pourability through carefully selecting a combination of surfactants and fine-tuning their ratios to improve consumer use experience, especially in winter.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jin</LastName><ForeName>Pengwei</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7090-680X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Hutchison WhiteCat Co., Ltd., Shanghai 200231, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zhejiang Wansheng Co., Ltd., Zhejiang 317000, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Rongying</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Hutchison WhiteCat Co., Ltd., Shanghai 200231, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dai</LastName><ForeName>Li</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nanjing Huashi New Material Co., Ltd., Nanjing 210009, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2862-083X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Colloid and Interface Chemistry of State Education Ministry, Shandong University, Jinan, Shandong 250100, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Omega</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101691658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-1343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing financial interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37841189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10568579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.3c05855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Huancao W.; Shichao T.; Huadai L. YES thickening agent used in liquid washing products. Deterg. Cosmet. 2009, 32, 27&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji X.; Tian M.; Wang Y. Temperature-Induced Aggregate Transitions in Mixtures of Cationic Ammonium Gemini Surfactant with Anionic Glutamic Acid Surfactant in Aqueous Solution. Langmuir 2016, 32, 972&#x2013;981. 10.1021/acs.langmuir.5b04211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.5b04211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26750978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A.; Chaturvedi K. R.; Sharma T. Natural surfactant for sustainable carbon utilization in cleaner production of fossil fuels: Extraction, characterization and application studies. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2021, 9, 106231. 10.1016/j.jece.2021.106231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2021.106231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A.; Sharma T.; Kumar R. S.; Arif M. Biosurfactant Derived from Fenugreek Seeds and Its Impact on Wettability Alteration, Oil Recovery, and Effluent Treatment of a Rock System of Mixed Composition. Energy Fuels 2023, 37, 6683&#x2013;6696. 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c00105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c00105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y.; Chu Z.; Dreiss C. A.; Thermo-responsive Wormlike Micelles. Smart Wormlike Micelles; SpringerBriefs in Molecular Science: Springer, Berlin, Heidelberg, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulman J. H.; Stoeckenius W.; Prince L. M. Mechanism of Formation and Structure of Micro Emulsions by Electron Microscopy. J. Phys. Chem. A 1959, 63, 1677&#x2013;1680. 10.1021/j150580a027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/j150580a027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowcott J. E.; Schulman J. H. Emulsions Control of droplet size and phase continuity in transparent oil-water dispersions stabilized with soap and alcohol. Z. Elektrochem. 1955, 59, 238&#x2013;290. 10.1002/bbpc.19550590409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bbpc.19550590409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Israelachvili J. N.; Mitchell D. J.; Ninham B. W. Theory of self-assembly of hydrocarbon amphiphiles into micelles and bilayers. J. Chem. Soc., Faraday Trans. 2 1976, 72, 1525&#x2013;1568. 10.1039/f29767201525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/f29767201525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winsor P. A. Hydrotropy, solubilisation and related emulsification processes. Trans. Faraday Soc. 1948, 44, 376&#x2013;398. 10.1039/tf9484400376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/tf9484400376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchiyama H.; Acosta E.; Tran S.; Sabatini D. A.; Harwell J. H. Supersolubilization in Chlorinated Hydrocarbon Microemulsions: Solubilization Enhancement by Lipophilic and Hydrophilic Linkers. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2000, 39, 2704&#x2013;2708. 10.1021/ie990819p.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ie990819p</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourrel M.; Chambu C. The Rules for Achieving High Solubilization of Brine and Oil by Amphiphilic Molecules. Soc. Pet. Eng. J. 1983, 23, 327&#x2013;338. 10.2118/10676-PA.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2118/10676-PA</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du X.; Li L.; Lu Y.; Yang Z. Unusual viscosity behavior of a kind of anionic gemini surfactant. Colloids Surf., A 2007, 308, 147&#x2013;149. 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2007.05.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2007.05.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalur G. C.; Frounfelker B. D.; Cipriano B. H.; Norman A. I.; Raghavan S. R. Viscosity Increase with Temperature in Cationic Surfactant Solutions Due to the Growth of Wormlike Micelles. Langmuir 2005, 21, 10998&#x2013;11004. 10.1021/la052069w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la052069w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16285764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobita K.; Sakai H.; Kondo Y.; Yoshino N.; Kamogawa K.; Momozawa N.; Abe M. Temperature-Induced Critical Phenomenon of Hybrid Surfactant As Revealed by Viscosity Measurements. Langmuir 1998, 14, 4753&#x2013;4757. 10.1021/la9801007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la9801007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B.; Liu L.; Zheng C.; Lu H. pH and temperature-responsive wormlike micelles formed by single amine oxide surfactant. J. Dispersion Sci. Technol. 2018, 39, 539&#x2013;547. 10.1080/01932691.2017.1334212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01932691.2017.1334212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu N.; Wei J.; Kawaguchi Y. Rheology Test on Shear Viscosity of Surfactant Solution: Characteristic Time, Hysteresis Phenomenon, and Fitting Equation. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2016, 55, 5817&#x2013;5824. 10.1021/acs.iecr.6b00703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.iecr.6b00703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tam K. C.; Wu X. Y.; Pelton R. H. Poly(N-isopropylacrylamide). II. Effect of polymer concentration, temperature, and surfactant on the viscosity of aqueous solutions. J. Polym. Sci., Part A: Polym. Chem. 1993, 31, 963&#x2013;969. 10.1002/pola.1993.080310415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pola.1993.080310415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Y.; Heil C.; Nagy G.; Heller W. T.; An Y.; Jayaraman A.; Bharti B. Synergistic Role of Temperature and Salinity in Aggregation of Nonionic Surfactant-Coated Silica Nanoparticles. Langmuir 2023, 39, 5917&#x2013;5928. 10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c00432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c00432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10134496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37053432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acharya D. P.; Varade D.; Aramaki K. Effect of temperature on the rheology of wormlike micelles in a mixed surfactant system. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2007, 315, 330&#x2013;336. 10.1016/j.jcis.2007.06.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2007.06.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17673245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker A.; Fieber W. Viscoelasticity of anionic wormlike micelles: effects of ionic strength and small hydrophobic molecules. Soft Matter 2013, 9, 1203&#x2013;1213. 10.1039/C2SM27078A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C2SM27078A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vu T.; Koenig P.; Cochran B. M.; Ananthapadmanabhan K. P.; Weaver M.; Reeder B.; Hutton H. D.; Kasting G. B. Thickening mechanisms for an amino acid-derived surfactant composition. Colloids Surf., A 2020, 589, 124424. 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2020.124424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2020.124424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vu T.; Weaver M. R.; Kasting G. B.; Koenig P. Effect of pH on the Structure and Dynamics of Wormlike Micelles in an Amino Acid-Derived Surfactant Composition. Langmuir 2021, 37, 4112&#x2013;4120. 10.1021/acs.langmuir.0c03582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.0c03582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33789047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei X.; Geng P.; Han C.; Guo Y.; Chen X.; Zhang J.; Zhang Y.; Sun D.; Zhou S. Rheological Properties of Viscoelastic Solutions in a Cationic Surfactant-Organic Salts-Water System. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2016, 55, 5556&#x2013;5564. 10.1021/acs.iecr.6b00238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.iecr.6b00238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaler E. W.; Zana R.. Giant Micelles: Properties and Applications; CRC Press: Boca Raton, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cates M. E.; Candau S. J. Statics and dynamics of worm-like surfactant micelles. J. Phys. Condens. Matter 1990, 2, 6869&#x2013;6892. 10.1088/0953-8984/2/33/001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/0953-8984/2/33/001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmberg K.; J&#xf6;nsson B.; Kronberg B.; Lindman B.. Surfactants and Polymers in Aqueous Solution; 2 nd Ed.; John Wiley &amp; Sons: New York, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrestha R. G.; Shrestha L. K.; Aramaki K. Formation of wormlike micelle in a mixed amino-acid based anionic surfactant and cationic surfactant systems. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2007, 311, 276&#x2013;284. 10.1016/j.jcis.2007.02.050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2007.02.050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17368470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y.; Han Y.; Chu Z.; He S.; Zhang J.; Feng Y. Thermally induced structural transitions from fluids to hydrogels with pH-switchable anionic wormlike micelles. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2013, 394, 319&#x2013;328. 10.1016/j.jcis.2012.11.032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2012.11.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23266035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morita C.; Imura Y.; Ogawa T.; Kurata H.; Kawai T. Thermal-Sensitive Viscosity Transition of Elongated Micelles Induced by Breaking Intermolecular Hydrogen Bonding of Amide Groups. Langmuir 2013, 29, 5450&#x2013;5456. 10.1021/la400604m.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la400604m</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23570339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou W.; Larson R. G. A mesoscopic simulation method for predicting the rheology of semi-dilute wormlike micellar solutions. J. Rheol. 2014, 58, 681&#x2013;721. 10.1122/1.4868875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1122/1.4868875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginzburg V. V. Mesoscale Modeling of Micellization and Adsorption of Surfactants and Surfactant-Like Polymers in Solution: Challenges and Opportunities. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2022, 61, 15473&#x2013;15487. 10.1021/acs.iecr.2c01512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.iecr.2c01512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christov N. C.; Denkov N. D.; Kralchevsky P. A.; Ananthapadmanabhan K. P.; Lips A. Synergistic Sphere-to-Rod Micelle Transition in Mixed Solutions of Sodium Dodecyl Sulfate and Cocoamidopropyl Betaine. Langmuir 2004, 20, 565&#x2013;571. 10.1021/la035717p.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la035717p</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15773076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu S.; Wu J.; Somasundaran P. Micellar evolution in mixed nonionic/anionic surfactant systems. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2012, 367, 272&#x2013;279. 10.1016/j.jcis.2011.08.050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2011.08.050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22115159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu S.; Somasundaran P. Coexistence and Growth of Micellar Species in a Sugar-Based Surfactant/Phenol Mixture Studied by Analytical Ultracentrifugation. Langmuir 2007, 23, 9188&#x2013;9194. 10.1021/la7016616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la7016616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17676780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCoy T. M.; Valiakhmetova A.; Pottage M. J.; Garvey C. J.; Campo L. D.; Rehm C.; Kuryashov D. A.; Tabor R. F. Structural Evolution of Wormlike Micellar Fluids Formed by Erucyl Amidopropyl Betaine with Oil, Salts, and Surfactants. Langmuir 2016, 32, 12423&#x2013;12433. 10.1021/acs.langmuir.6b01735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.6b01735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27592638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly T.; Mohamed M. I. H.; Lehmann T. E.; Alvarado V. Amphiphilic second-order phase transitions determined through NMR. J. Mol. Liq. 2018, 268, 647&#x2013;657. 10.1016/j.molliq.2018.07.066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2018.07.066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou W.; Tan G.; Jiang H.; Vogtt K.; Weaver M.; Koenig P.; Beaucage G.; Larson R. G. From well-entangled to partially-entangled wormlike micelles. Soft Matter 2019, 15, 642&#x2013;655. 10.1039/C8SM02223B.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C8SM02223B</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30608505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu J.; Li G.; Jia X.; Wang H.; Zhang G. Rheological Properties and Microstructures of Anionic Micellar Solutions in the Presence of Different Inorganic Salts. J. Phys. Chem. B 2002, 106, 11685&#x2013;11693. 10.1021/jp014096a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp014096a</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H.; Dang L.; Yang S.; Li J.; Wei H. The study of phase behavior and rheological properties of lyotropic liquid crystals in the LAS/AES/H2O system. Colloids Surf., A 2016, 495, 221&#x2013;228. 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2016.01.055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2016.01.055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu H.; Yuan M.; Fang B.; Wang J.; Guo Y. Wormlike Micelles in Mixed Amino Acid-Based Anionic Surfactant and Zwitterionic Surfactant Systems. J. Surfactants Deterg. 2015, 18, 589&#x2013;596. 10.1007/s11743-015-1683-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11743-015-1683-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>F&#xf6;rster S.; Konrad M.; Lindner P. Shear Thinning and Orientational Ordering of Wormlike Micelles. Phys. Rev. Lett. 2005, 94, 017803. 10.1103/PhysRevLett.94.017803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevLett.94.017803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15698134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan H.; Yan Y.; Li Z.; Xu Y.; Jiang L.; Xu L.; Zhang B.; Huang J. General rules for the scaling behavior of linear wormlike micelles formed in catanionic surfactant systems. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2010, 348, 491&#x2013;497. 10.1016/j.jcis.2010.04.065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2010.04.065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20621820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vu T.; Koenig P.; Weaver M.; Hutton H. D.; Kasting G. B. Effects of cationic counterions and surfactant on viscosity of an amino acid-based surfactant system. Colloids Surf., A 2021, 626, 127040. 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2021.127040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2021.127040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varade D.; Rodr&#xed;guez-Abreu C.; Shrestha L. K.; Aramaki K. Wormlike Micelles in Mixed Surfactant Systems: Effect of Cosolvents. J. Phys. Chem. B 2007, 111, 10438&#x2013;10447. 10.1021/jp0740999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp0740999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17696527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers S. A.; Calabrese M. A.; Wagner N. J. Rheology of branched wormlike micelles. Curr. Opin. Colloid Interface Sci. 2014, 19, 530&#x2013;535. 10.1016/j.cocis.2014.10.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cocis.2014.10.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakai K.; Nomura K.; Shrestha R. G.; Endo T.; Sakamoto K.; Sakai H.; Abe M. Wormlike Micelle Formation by Acylglutamic Acid with Alkylamines. Langmuir 2012, 28, 17617&#x2013;17622. 10.1021/la303745p.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la303745p</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23157727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D.; Sun Y.; Deng Q.; Qi X.; Sun H.; Li Y. Study of the environmental responsiveness of amino acid-based surfactant sodium lauroylglutamate and its foam characteristics. Colloids Surf., A 2016, 504, 384&#x2013;392. 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2016.05.097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2016.05.097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrestha R. G.; Shrestha L. K.; Aramaki K. Wormlike micelles in mixed amino acid-based anionic/nonionic surfactant systems. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2008, 322, 596&#x2013;604. 10.1016/j.jcis.2008.03.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2008.03.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18395738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X.; Wu K.; Song W.; Lei Q.; Zhang H.; Pan J.; Ge X. Aqueous solution thickening of amino acid based surfactant by alkylpyrrolidone. J. Surfactants Deterg. 2022, 25, 7&#x2013;15. 10.1002/jsde.12544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jsde.12544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>