<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41681329</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Application of Graphite Tailings in Concrete Manufacturing: A Review.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">641</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma19030641</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Large-scale mining of graphite, a crucial strategic mineral, generates substantial amounts of graphite tailings (GT). The stockpiling of this solid waste occupies vast land resources and poses persistent environmental risks due to potential heavy metal leaching. Repurposing GT into construction materials presents a promising solution, with its use as a partial replacement for fine aggregates in cementitious composites being one of the most effective methods. This review systematically consolidates current research on graphite tailings cement mortar (GTCM) and graphite tailings concrete (GTC). Due to its physicochemical properties comparable to natural sand, GT is suitable for producing building materials. Studies consistently demonstrate that a substitution level of 10% to 20% optimizes overall performance. This optimal range enhances particle packing, promotes cement hydration via pozzolanic activity, and refines the microstructure, leading to improved workability, superior mechanical strength, and enhanced durability, including resistance to permeability, freeze-thaw cycles, and chemical attacks. Moreover, the inherent carbon content imparts electrical conductivity to GTC, enabling functional applications like de-icing and structural health monitoring. The successful utilization of GT also extends to lightweight foamed and autoclaved aerated concrete. However, research on the structural behavior of GTC components remains limited. Preliminary findings on beams and columns are encouraging, but comprehensive studies on their seismic performance and design methodologies are urgently needed to facilitate the widespread engineering application of this sustainable material and mitigate the environmental impact of tailings accumulation.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Shan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9590-9158</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shaanxi Key Laboratory of Safety and Durability of Concrete Structures, Xijing University, Xi'an 710123, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Structures Dynamic Behavior and Control of the Ministry of Education, Harbin Institute of Technology, Harbin 150090, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Jicheng</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-6282-6777</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shaanxi Key Laboratory of Safety and Durability of Concrete Structures, Xijing University, Xi'an 710123, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Sijia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Transportation, Northeast Forestry University, Harbin 150090, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Man</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7149-4528</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Transportation, Northeast Forestry University, Harbin 150090, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Honghao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Architecture and Urban Planning, Guangzhou University, 230 Wai Huan Xi Road, Guangzhou Higher Education Mega Center, Guangzhou 510006, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>52411540027</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>24JP201</GrantID><Agency>Scientific Research Program for Youth Innovation Team of Shaanxi Provincial Department of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cement mortar</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">concrete</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">concrete components</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">graphite tailings</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mechanical property</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41681329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12899960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma19030641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma19030641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gao Z., Liu H., Yang H. Overview of the distribution of graphite resources in the world and trends of supply and demand. Compr. Util. Miner. 2018;3:26&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Geological Survey (USGS)  Graphite Statistics and Information.  [(accessed on 28 October 2025)]; Available online:  https://www.usgs.gov/centers/national-minerals-information-center/graphite-statistics-and-information.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao L., Gao S., Guo J., Chen Z., Yan L., Chen J., Ou Y., Yu H., Liu Y., Zhou W. Analysis of the current situation of graphite resources development and utilization in China. China Nonmet. Miner. Ind. Guide. 2019:1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juxing Tansu  Graphite Resource Overview.  [(accessed on 28 October 2025)].  Available online:  https://juxingtansu.cn/q_126.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao D., Zhao H., Zhong W. Research on green foam concrete with large dosage of graphite tailings. Bulk Cem. 2022;3:181&#x2013;184. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1007-3922.2022.03.061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1007-3922.2022.03.061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao H., Yao Z., Liu S., Liu W. Application of graphite slag on highway subgrade. Chin. Foreign Highw. 2004;2:64&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shengo M.L. Review of practices in the managements of mineral wastes: The case of waste rocks and mine tailings. Water Air Soil Pollut. 2021;232:273. doi: 10.1007/s11270-021-05198-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11270-021-05198-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang J., Yao Z., Su G., Mao H., Liu Z. Use of graphite tailings as subgrade for highway. J. Shandong Univ. (Eng.) 2003;5:562&#x2013;567.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Che Z., Zhang C., An Q., Yan J. Current status and prospect of graphene development in China. China Basic Sci. 2020;22:56&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Wei Q., Zhang N., Zhang S., Zhang Y. Comparative study of iron-tailings-based cementitious mortars with incorporated graphite ore and graphite tailings: Strength properties and microstructure. Materials. 2023;16:3743. doi: 10.3390/ma16103743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16103743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10221033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37241372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Heilongjiang University; Harbin, China: 2020. Analysis of Electrical Conductivity of Graphite Tailings Cement Mortar.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouyang Z. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Wuhan University of Technology; Wuhan, China: 2016. Experimental Study on Comprehensive Recovery of Graphite and Vanadium from a Graphite ore in Jiangxi.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B., Zhang Y., Liu W., Gu X., Wang Q., Zhang S., Gao J. Effect of iron tailing powder-based ternary admixture on acid corrosion resistance of concrete. Materials. 2023;16:3688. doi: 10.3390/ma16103688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16103688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10223624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37241315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie Y., Liu S., Niu F., Wei S. Physical phase analysis and beneficiation test study of sericite in a graphite tailing. Nonmet. Min. 2014;37:45&#x2013;46, 62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Beijing General Research Institute of Nonferrous Metals; Beijing, China: 2014. Research on Beneficiation Process for Recovering Graphite and Sericite from Graphite Tailings.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng F., Yu Y., Zhang T. Experimental study on the preparation of ceramic bricks using graphite tailings. Nonmet. Min. 2020;43:62&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang M., Chen B., Liao L., Du G. Effect of sintering temperature on the properties of graphite tailings sintered bricks. Mineral. J. 2012;32:191&#x2013;193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu S., Li D., Li Y., Guo Q., Tian D., Zhang L., Li H. Preparation of foamed ceramics from graphite tailings using a self-foaming method. Minerals. 2023;13:521. doi: 10.3390/min13040521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min13040521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen H., Chen X., Jiao H. Research on the process and performance of preparing no-fire imitation stone bricks from graphite tailings. Nonferrous Met. (Min. Sect.) 2024;76:111&#x2013;117, 134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang R., Wang Z. Performance and Heavy Metal Analysis of Graphite Tailings Cured Using Cementitious Materials. Buildings. 2024;14:537. doi: 10.3390/buildings14020537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings14020537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moshi P., DeVries J., Hogg C., Lane C. Dry stacking of high-grade flake graphite tailings: Tanzania; Proceedings of the Mine Waste and Tailings Conference; Perth, Australia. 17&#x2013;20 November 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kathirvel P., Kwon S.J., Lee H.S., Karthick S., Saraswathy V. Graphite ore tailings as partial replacement of sand in concrete. ACI Mater. J. 2018;115:481&#x2013;492. doi: 10.14359/51702191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14359/51702191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W.-W., Zuo R.-F., Guo W.-J., Du G.-X., Liao L.-B. Research on the regulation technology of flooding frost performance in the preparation of sintered bricks using graphite tailings. Nonmet. Min. 2013;36:28&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B., Du G., Liao L., Yang M. Preparation of building ceramics using graphite tailings. Nonmet. Min. 2011;34:45&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du C., Xu Z., Yi F., Gao J., Shi K. Bearing capacity mechanism of soilbagged graphite tailings. Bull. Eng. Geol. Environ. 2024;83:24. doi: 10.1007/s10064-023-03531-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10064-023-03531-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao J., Du C., Xu Z., Yi F. Analysis of compression damage pattern and strength influencing factors in graphite-tailing-filled soilbags. Sci. Rep. 2024;14:802. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-50349-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-50349-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10774416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38191499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Z. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Liaoning University of Engineering and Technology; Fuxin, China: 2024. Study on the Bearing Performance of Bagged Graphite Tailings and Its Application Along the Hollow Stay.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hai Y., Liao L., Lv G., Qin F., Mei L., Wei Y. Application of composite powders recycled from graphite tailings in styrene-butadiene rubber. JOM. 2015;67:2733&#x2013;2738. doi: 10.1007/s11837-015-1492-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11837-015-1492-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xuan Y., Fan Z., Xu J., Ling J., He Y., Wang D., Liu P. Investigation of graphite tailings as a substitute for filler in asphalt mastics. Int. J. Pavement Eng. 2023;24:2172578. doi: 10.1080/10298436.2023.2172578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10298436.2023.2172578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y., Zhang W., Xu Y., Xing C., Liang Z., Zhang J. Investigation on preparation and properties of carbon fiber graphite tailings conductive asphalt mixture: A new approach of graphite tailings application. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;402:133057. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Xu Q., Wang Z., Li S., Wang F. Experimental study on road performance of cement stabilized graphite tailing sand. Found. Treat. 2024;6:1&#x2013;6, 14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li E., Ran X., Wang G., Li S., Wang F. Study on the strength of cement-stabilized graphite tailings under freeze-thaw cycle. Water Resour. Plan. Des. 2024;7:75&#x2013;78, 101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Shen B. Experimental study on the preparation of pavement brick layer by graphite mine tailings. China Nonmet. Min. Ind. Guide. 2012;5:24&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Liaoning University of Engineering and Technology; Fuxin, China: 2024. Improvement of Graphite Tailings and Stability of Slope Surface with Guest Soil.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Z., Feng Y., Zhang B. Experimental study on the preparation of blasting sealing materials from graphite tailings. Mod. Min. Ind. 2023;39:200&#x2013;204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao N., Zhong J., Zhang Y., Wei H., Lv S. Current status of research on the preparation of wall materials using graphite tailings in China. Sichuan Build. Mater. 2020;46:25, 28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang S., Ding H., Zhang Y., Wang Z. Research progress on the application of graphite tailings in building materials. Heilongjiang Sci. 2022;13:37&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang S., Zhang Y., Yang G., Chen Y., Ding H. Thermal activation and activity analysis of graphite tailings. Chem. Bond. 2024;46:584&#x2013;588.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Zhang Y., Li B., Wang Z. Combined effects of graphite tailings and curing conditions on the early-age performances of cement mortar. Adv. Civ. Eng. 2020;2020:5965328. doi: 10.1155/2020/5965328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/5965328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Li B., Liu H., Zhang Y., Qin X. Degradation characteristics of graphite tailings cement mortar subjected to freeze-thaw cycles. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;234:117422. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Heilongjiang University; Harbin, China: 2015. Research on Force and Conductivity of Graphite Tailings Concrete.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Jiang Q., Xue H. Mechanical and shrinkage properties of alkali-activated mortars with graphite tailings. J. Build. Eng. 2024;97:110809. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.110809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.110809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H.-N., Sun J., Zhou T., Chen H. Experimental study on static properties of graphite tailings in Jixi and Luobei. J. Eng. Heilongjiang Univ. 2022;13:13&#x2013;17, 24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Zhang C., Duan H., Shi L., Gao H. Experimental study on preparation technology and mechanical properties of graphite tailing mortar. J. Eng. Heilongjiang Univ. 2022;13:11&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sand for Construction. Standardization Administration of China; Beijing, China: 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Xue J., Li B., Wang J., Lv X. Effect of graphite tailings as substitute sand on mechanical properties of concrete. Eur. J. Environ. Civ. Eng. 2020;26:2635&#x2013;2653. doi: 10.1080/19648189.2020.1763476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19648189.2020.1763476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou T. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Heilongjiang University; Harbin, China: 2024. Experimental Study on Static-Dynamic Characteristics of Graphite Tailings in Luobei.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B., Zhang Y., Xu H., Li K., Zhao C. Microstructure evolution process and multi-scale deterioration mechanism model of graphite tailings cement-based materials subjected to high temperature. J. Clean. Prod. 2024;481:144153. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.144153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.144153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang K., Li Q., Zhao X. Study on the water stability performance of graphite tailing sand asphalt mixtures. For. Eng. 2023;39:196&#x2013;207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moshi P., DeVries J., Hogg C., Lane C. Dry Stacking of High-Grade Flake Graphite Tailings: Tanzania. Australian Centre for Geomechanics; Crawley, Australia: 2019. pp. 139&#x2013;152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hai Y. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. China University of Geosciences (Beijing); Beijing, China: 2015. Process Mineralogical Study of Graphite Tailings from Luobei, Heilongjiang and Its Application in Conductive Rubber.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv G., Chen B., Hai H., Liao L. Proceedings of the Fifth Symposium on Comprehensive Utilization of Tailings and Metallurgical Slag. School of Materials Science and Engineering, China University of Geosciences (Beijing); Beijing, China: 2014. Research on comprehensive utilization of graphite tailings in Laobei Yunshan; p. 8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han X., Wang X., Cai T. Characterization and evaluation of heavy metal pollution in graphite tailing pond and surrounding soil. J. Eng. Heilongjiang Univ. 2011;2:58&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W., Man X. Evaluation of heavy metal content and its pollution in abandoned land of Jixi mining area. J. Soil Water Conserv. 2007;6:70&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Wang X., Yang Z., Deng S., Yin W., Gou X., Zhang Y. Evaluation of potential ecological hazards of heavy metals in abandoned land of mining area in eastern Heilongjiang Province. J. Eng. Heilongjiang Univ. 2018;9:40&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Cai T., Zhang S., Liu C., Ren X., Liu W. Characteristics of matrix fertility and heavy metal pollution in different types of industrial and mining waste land and their evaluation. J. Soil Water Conserv. 2009;23:157&#x2013;161, 218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Foshan Institute of Science and Technology; Foshan, China: 2024. Study on the Deterioration Mechanism of Graphite Tailing Cement Mortar Under High Temperature.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang G., Li T. Firing of silicate cement clinker with graphite tailings batching. Cement. 2015;10:13&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Zhang Y., Wang Z., Wang L., Xing L., Yao C. Research on compressive strength and seepage resistance of graphite tailings cement mortar. J. Eng. Heilongjiang Univ. 2019;10:16&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z., Li B., Ying Y., Zhang Y., Xu H., Wang W. An investigation of the mechanical properties of basalt fibre-reinforced graphite tailings cement mortar. Buildings. 2022;12:2106. doi: 10.3390/buildings12122106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings12122106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Duan H., Jiao Y., Wang Z. Optimization analysis of graphite tailings cement mortar ratio. J. Nat. Sci. Heilongjiang Univ. 2022;39:712&#x2013;717, 767.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z., Li B., Ying Y., Zhang C., Xu H., Li K., Zhao C., Mao J., Liu Y. Sulfate resistance and degradation mechanism of basalt fiber modified graphite tailings cement-based materials. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2023;26:8757&#x2013;8775. doi: 10.1016/j.jmrt.2023.09.196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2023.09.196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scrivener K., Ouzia A., Juilland P., Mohamed P. Advances in understanding cement hydration mechanisms. Cem. Concr. Res. 2019;124:105823. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He X., Wang J., Jiang Q. Mechanical properties and drying shrinkage of graphite tailing-basalt fiber cement mortar. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;409:133898. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan X., Jiang X., Sun S., Gao Q. Study on the effect of large dosage of graphite tailings on concrete properties. Highway. 2024;69:327&#x2013;331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang B., Zhang Y., Zhao M., Zhou G., Zhou Y. Effect of graphite tailings on concrete properties. Heilongjiang Sci. 2025;16:18&#x2013;21, 26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue J. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Heilongjiang University; Harbin, China: 2019. Research on Mechanical Properties and Electrical Conductivity of Graphite Tailings Concrete.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C., Shu Y., Dai W., Zhang L., Chen C. Uniaxial compression and acoustic emission test of graphite tailing sand modified concrete. Nonmet. Min. 2022;45:94&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z., Li B., Wu F., Yu Y., Zhang Y., Xu H. Research on modification of mechanical properties of recycled aggregate concrete by replacing sand with graphite tailings. Rev. Adv. Mater. Sci. 2022;61:493&#x2013;512. doi: 10.1515/rams-2022-0046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/rams-2022-0046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Li B., Xue J., Hu J., Zhang J. Mechanical and electroconductivity properties of graphite tailings concrete. Adv. Mater. Sci. Eng. 2020;2020:9385097. doi: 10.1155/2020/9385097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/9385097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao D. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Heilongjiang University; Harbin, China: 2019. Research on Mechanical and Frost Resistance Properties of Graphite Tailings Steel Fiber Concrete.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan H., Liu H., Li B., Wang Z., Gao H. Mechanical properties and mechanism analysis of graphite tailings environment-friendly concrete. Materials. 2022;15:8870. doi: 10.3390/ma15248870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15248870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9783204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36556672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Duan H., Gao H., Wang Z., Zhang J. Graphite tailings&#x2019; effects on mechanical and physical properties of eco-efficient steel fiber-reinforced concrete. Buildings. 2022;12:509. doi: 10.3390/buildings12050509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings12050509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao G., Liu Y. Research and application of conductive concrete. Sci. Technol. Inf. 2011;15:89&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing X., Wang X., Wang Z., Xu S., Liu H. Investigations on influencing factors of resistivity measurement for graphite tailings concrete. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2021;123:104206. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2021.104206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2021.104206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang D., Song H., Chen Z. Fracture test of graphite tailing sand partially replacing traditional fine aggregate concrete. Sichuan Cem. 2024;5:1&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H. Formulation and mechanical and conductive properties of conductive concrete. Prot. Eng. 2020;42:26&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Liu K., Zhu L., Zhang D. Mechanical and electrical characteristics of graphite tailing concrete. Adv. Mater. Sci. Eng. 2018;2018:9297628. doi: 10.1155/2018/9297628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/9297628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Li X., Tong Y., Ding J., Jiang G. Correlation study of electrical resistivity and mechanical parameters of graphite tailings carbon fiber concrete. J. Eng. Heilongjiang Univ. 2020;11:11&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y., Yao B., Wei D., Jiang T., Hou M. Analysis of resistivity and conductivity mechanism of graphite-based conductive concrete. Funct. Mater. 2024;55:3150&#x2013;3158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun W. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Heilongjiang University; Harbin, China: 2019. Research on Durability Performance of Graphite Tailing Concrete.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L., Du X., Zou T. Preparation and properties of foam concrete with iron tail sand. J. Anhui Univ. Technol. (Nat. Sci. Ed.) 2024;41:81&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He S., Qin Y. Research on durability and resistance to chloride ion erosion of graphite tailings concrete. Met. Mine. 2022;6:225&#x2013;229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X., Zhang W., Wang Q., Hu Y. Research on the performance of graphite tailings foam concrete. Nonmet. Min. 2020;43:9&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X., Gao M., Zhou H., Lv J., Ding Z. Proceedings of the 8th International Conference on Civil Engineering (ICCE 2021) Springer; Singapore: 2021. Influence of fiber on properties of graphite tailings foam concrete; p. 8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hai S.-W. Preparation of foam concrete from graphite tailing. Adv. Mater. Res. 2011;356&#x2013;360:1994&#x2013;1997. doi: 10.4028/www.scientific.net/amr.356-360.1994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4028/www.scientific.net/amr.356-360.1994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S. Experimental study on the preparation of foam concrete from graphite tailings. China Nonmet. Min. Ind. Guide. 2011;4:35&#x2013;37, 51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M., He X., Wang C. Orthogonal experimental study on graphite tailing foam concrete for blocking system in cold area. J. Heilongjiang Inst. Technol. (Gen. Ed.) 2024;24:128&#x2013;132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Yuan X., Hu S., Xu H., Zhang D. Research on application technology of graphite tailing foam concrete. Highway. 2024;69:307&#x2013;311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Inner Mongolia University of Technology; Hohhot, China: 2024. Research on Impact and Frost Resistance of Graphite Tailing Foam Concrete for Barrier System.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q., Xu K., Peng Y., Zhan B., Ke S. Preparation method of graphite tailings autoclaved aerated concrete and its performance analysis. Hydropower Energy Sci. 2019;37:110&#x2013;113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng Y., Liu Y., Zhan B., Xu G. Preparation of autoclaved aerated concrete by using graphite tailings as an alternative silica source. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;267:121792. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng B.-Y., Xia H.-C., Zhu X.-G., Liu X.-Z. Experimental study on flexural performance of graphite tailing sand concrete beams. J. Xi&#x2019;an Univ. Technol. 2022;38:279&#x2013;286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng B.-F., Guo X.-Z., Xia H.-C., Yang L., Xie T. Flexural behavior of graphite tailings RC beams in chloride environment. Adv. Civ. Eng. 2023;2023:1427007. doi: 10.1155/2023/1427007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2023/1427007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang F. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Shenyang University of Architecture; Shenyang, China: 2021. Experimental Study on Seismic Performance of Regenerated Concrete Columns with Graphene Oxide.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Institute of Engineering Mechanics, China Earthquake Administration; Harbin, China: 2023. Proposed Static Test Study on Hysteresis Performance of Graphite Tailing Concrete Columns.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>