<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39432412</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2046-4924</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>68</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Health technology assessment (Winchester, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Health Technol Assess</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Strategies for older people living in care homes to prevent urinary tract infection: the StOP UTI realist synthesis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>139</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-139</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3310/DADT3410</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Urinary tract infection is the most diagnosed infection in older people. It accounts for more than 50% of antibiotic prescriptions in care homes and is a frequent reason for care home residents being hospitalised.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This realist review developed and refined programme theories for preventing and recognising urinary tract infection, exploring what works, for whom and in what circumstances.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The review used realist synthesis to explore existing literature on the detection and prevention of urinary tract infection, complemented by stakeholder consultation. It applies to the UK context, although other healthcare systems may identify synergies in our findings.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA SOURCES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Bibliographic databases searched included MEDLINE, CINAHL, EMBASE, Cochrane Library, Web of Science Core Collection (including the Social Sciences Citation Index), Sociological Abstracts, Bibliomap and National Institute for Health and Care Research Journals Library.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA SELECTION AND EXTRACTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Title and abstract screening were undertaken by two researchers independently of each other. Selection and assessment were based on relevance and rigour and cross-checked by a second researcher. Data extracted from the included studies were explored for explanations about how the interventions were considered to work (or not). Evidence tables were constructed to enable identification of patterns across studies that offered insight about the features of successful interventions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA ANALYSIS AND SYNTHESIS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Programme theories were constructed through a four-stage process involving scoping workshops, examination of relevant extant theory, analysis and synthesis of primary research, teacher-learner interviews and a cross-system stakeholder event. A process of abductive and retroductive reasoning was used to construct context-mechanism-outcome configurations to inform programme theory.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The scoping review and stakeholder engagement identified three theory areas that address the prevention and recognition of urinary tract infection and show what is needed to implement best practice. Nine context-mechanism-outcome configurations provided an explanation of how interventions to prevent and recognise urinary tract infection might work in care homes. These were (1) recognition of urinary tract infection is informed by skills in clinical reasoning, (2) decision-support tools enable a whole care team approach to communication, (3) active monitoring is recognised as a legitimate care routine, (4) hydration is recognised as a care priority for all residents, (5) systems are in place to drive action that helps residents to drink more, (6) good infection prevention practice is applied to indwelling urinary catheters, (7) proactive strategies are in place to prevent recurrent urinary tract infection, (8) care home leadership and culture fosters safe fundamental care and (9) developing knowledgeable care teams.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LIMITATIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We adapted our approach and work to online interactions with stakeholders and as a research team because of COVID-19. This also had an impact on bringing stakeholders together at a face-to-face event at the end of the project. Studies focusing on the prevention of urinary tract infection in care home settings were predominantly from the USA and Europe where the regulatory and funding systems for the long-term care of the elderly have some differences, particularly in the USA where national reporting plays a significant role in driving improvements in care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Care home staff have a vital role in the prevention and recognition of urinary tract infection, which can be enabled through integration and prioritisation within the systems and routines of care homes and delivery of person-centred care. Promoting fundamental care as a means of facilitating a holistic approach to prevention and recognition of urinary tract infection helps staff to recognise how they can contribute to antimicrobial stewardship and recognition of sepsis. Challenging assumptions made by staff about the presentation of urinary tract infection is complex and requires education that facilitates 'unlearning' and questioning of low-value practices. Programmes to prevent urinary tract infection need to be co-designed and supported through active and visible leadership by care home managers with support from specialist practitioners.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUTURE WORK" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We will focus on co-designing tools that facilitate implementation of our findings to ensure they fit with the care home context and address some of the challenges faced by care home leaders. This will underpin action at care home and system levels. Further research is needed to better understand the perspectives of residents and family carers, the effectiveness of non-pharmacological, pharmacological and specialist practitioner interventions and non-traditional approaches to training and educating the workforce in care home settings.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study is registered as PROSPERO CRD42020201782.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUNDING" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This award was funded by the National Institute for Health and Care Research (NIHR) Health Technology Assessment programme (NIHR award ref: NIHR130396) and is published in full in <i>Health Technology Assessment</i>; Vol. 28, No. 68. See the NIHR Funding and Awards website for further award information.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prieto</LastName><ForeName>Jacqui</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5524-6775</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, University of Southampton, Southampton, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilson</LastName><ForeName>Jennie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4713-9662</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Richard Wells Research Centre, University of West London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tingle</LastName><ForeName>Alison</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5557-8120</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Richard Wells Research Centre, University of West London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cooper</LastName><ForeName>Emily</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5043-4187</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Primary Care and Interventions Unit, HCAI, Fungal, AMR, AMU and Sepsis Division, UK Health Security Agency, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Handley</LastName><ForeName>Melanie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8037-5042</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Public Health and Community Care, University of Hertfordshire, De Havilland Campus, Hatfield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rycroft-Malone</LastName><ForeName>Jo</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3858-5625</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health and Medicine, Lancaster University, Lancaster, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bostock</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9261-9350</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Patient and Public Involvement, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Williams</LastName><ForeName>Lynne</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medical and Health Sciences, Bangor University, Wales, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Loveday</LastName><ForeName>Heather</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2259-8149</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Richard Wells Research Centre, University of West London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Health Technol Assess</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9706284</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1366-5278</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000900">Anti-Bacterial Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014552" MajorTopicYN="Y">Urinary Tract Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009735" MajorTopicYN="N">Nursing Homes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006707" MajorTopicYN="N">Homes for the Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006113" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United Kingdom</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000900" MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-Bacterial Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>This study was about how interventions to prevent and recognise urinary tract infections might work in care homes to reduce urinary tract infection in older people. We used an approach called realist synthesis. This aims to understand everything that influences how care is delivered to find out what works in particular situations and settings. We did this by talking to care home staff, residents, family carers and other experts about how to reduce urinary tract infection in older people living in care homes. We combined their experiences and ideas with the evidence from the research literature. From this, we developed three areas of focus: care approaches to support accurate recognition of urinary tract infection care approaches to prevent urinary tract infection/catheter-associated urinary tract infection making best practice happen. Our research shows that care staff are best placed to recognise subtle changes in a resident&#x2019;s behaviour or well-being which might indicate an infection. There are several things care staff can do to proactively help residents from developing a urinary tract infection such as prioritising residents&#x2019; hydration needs and addressing poor fluid intake. Putting in place infection prevention measures such as caring for, or where possible, removing a urinary catheter can also help. Actively monitoring residents to determine reasons for changes in behaviour can increase the focus on preventative activities and help avoid inappropriate treatment. The detection and prevention of urinary tract infection in older people could be improved in several ways, including: education tailored to the roles and work of care home staff leaders of care homes providing a culture of safety and improvement where urinary tract infection is recognised as something preventable rather than unavoidable having a safe and supportive environment where staff are confident to communicate their concerns all care team members, residents and their families and other professionals linked with the home having a common language and shared goals in the recognition, prevention and diagnosis of urinary tract infection. The COVID-19 pandemic required us to adapt our approach and work mainly online both in our interactions with stakeholders and as a research team. While this provided opportunities to extend our reach to a wider group of stakeholders, it also limited some of our engagement work.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ANTIMICROBIAL STEWARDSHIP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CATHETERS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FUNDAMENTAL CARE</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HYDRATION</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">INDWELLING</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LEADERSHIP</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LONG-TERM CARE</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">REALIST SYNTHESIS</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">URINARY TRACT INFECTIONS</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39432412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11513742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3310/DADT3410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Munson S. Care Home Stats: Number of Settings, Population &amp; Workforce. 2022. URL: %www.carehome.co.uk/advice/care-home-stats-number-of-settings-population-workforce (accessed 29 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Office for National Statistics. Care Homes and Estimating the Self-funding Population, England: 2021 to 2022. URL: %www.ons.gov.uk/peoplepopulationandcommunity/healthandsocialcare/socialcare/articles/carehomesandestimatingtheselffundingpopulationengland/2021to2022 (accessed 29 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skills for Care. The State of the Adult Social Care Sector and Workforce in England. 2022. URL: %www.skillsforcare.org.uk/Adult-Social-Care-Workforce-Data/Workforce-intelligence/documents/State-of-the-adult-social-care-sector/The-state-of-the-adult-social-care-sector-and-workforce-2022.pdf (accessed 29 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kojima G. Prevalence of frailty in nursing homes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Med Dir Assoc 2015;16:940&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26255709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greene C, Canning D, Wilson J, Bak A, Tingle A, Tsiami A, Loveday H. I-Hydrate training intervention for staff working in a care home setting: an observational study. Nurse Educ Today 2018;68:61&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29886286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson J, Bak A, Tingle T, Greene C, Tsiami A, Canning D, et al. Improving hydration of care home residents by increasing choice and opportunity to drink: a quality improvement study. Clin Nutr 2019;38:1820&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30150005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gharbi M, Drysdale JH, Lishman H, Goudie R, Molokhia M, Johnson AP, et al. Antibiotic management of urinary tract infection in elderly patients in primary care and its association with bloodstream infections and all-cause mortality: population-based cohort study. BMJ 2019;364:l525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6391656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30814048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caljouw MAA, den Elzen WPJ, Cools HJM, Gussekloo J. Predictive factors of urinary tract infections among the oldest old in the general population. A population-based prospective follow-up study. BMC Med 2011;9:57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3117726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21575195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Public Health England. English Surveillance Programme for Antimicrobial Utilisation and Resistance (ESPAUR). Annual Report 2017. PHE; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vihta KD, Stoesser N, Llewelyn MJ, Quan TP, Davies T, Fawcett NJ, et al. Trends over time in Escherichia coli bloodstream infections, urinary tract infections, and antibiotic susceptibilities in Oxfordshire, UK, 1998&#x2013;2016: a study of electronic health records. Lancet Infect Dis 2018;18:1138&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7612540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30126643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abernethy J, Guy R, Sheridan EA, Hopkins S, Kiernan M, Wilcox MH, et al.; E. coli Bacteraemia Sentinel Surveillance Group. Epidemiology of Escherichia coli bacteraemia in England: results of an enhanced sentinel surveillance programme. J Hosp Infect 2017;95:365&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28190700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biggel M, Heytens S, Latour K, Bruyndonckx R, Goossens H, Moons P. Asymptomatic bacteriuria in older adults: the most fragile women are prone to long-term colonization. BMC Geriatr 2019;19:170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6588879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31226945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowe TA, Juthani-Mehta M. Diagnosis and management of urinary tract infection in older adults. Infect Clin North Am 2014;28:75&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4079031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24484576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksen HM, Koch AM, Elstr&#xf8;m P, Nilsen RM, Harthug S, Aavitsland P. Healthcare-associated infection among residents of long-term care facilities: a cohort and nested case-control study. J Hosp Infect 2007;65:334&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17275954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genao L, Buhr GT. Urinary tract infections in older adults residing in long-term care facilities. Ann Long-Term Care 2012;20:33&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3573848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23418402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loveday HP, Wilson JA, Pratt RJ, Golsorkhi M, Tingle A, Bak A, et al. epic3: national evidence-based guidelines for preventing healthcare-associated infections in NHS hospitals in England. J Hosp Infect 2014;86:S1&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7114876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24330862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNulty C, Verlander NQ, Turner K, Fry C. Point prevalence survey of urinary catheterisation in care homes and where they were inserted, 2012. J Infect Prev 2014;15:122&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5074144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28989371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marwick C, Santiago VH, McCowan C, Broomhall J, Davey P, et al. Community acquired infections in older patients admitted to hospital from care homes versus the community: cohort study of microbiology and outcomes. BMC Geriatr 2013;13:12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3574846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23388032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE Clinical Guideline 139. Healthcare-associated Infections: Prevention and Control in Primary and Community Care. London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE); 2012. Last updated February 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32186833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE Guideline 109. Urinary Tract Infection (Lower): Antimicrobial Prescribing. London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE); 2019. Last updated July 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gould D, Gaze S, Drey N, Cooper T. Implementing clinical guidelines to prevent catheter-associated urinary tract infections and improve catheter care in nursing homes: systematic review. Am J Infect Control 2017;45:471&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28456320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spilsbury K, Hanratty B, McCaughan D. Supporting Nurses in Care Homes. York: University of York Project Report; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudman J, Meyer J, Holman C, Moyle W. Recognition of the complexity facing residential care homes: a practitioner inquiry. Prim Health Care Res Dev 2018;19:584&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6692831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29444736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee MH, Lee GA, Lee SH, Park YH. Effectiveness and core components of infection prevention and control programmes in long-term care facilities: a systematic review. J Hosp Infect 2019;102:377&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30794854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meddings J, Saint SL, Krein S, Gaies E, Reichert H, Hickner A, et al. Systematic review of interventions to reduce urinary tract infection in nursing home residents. J Hosp Med 2017;12:365&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5557395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28459908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prieto J, Wilson J, Bak A, Denton A, Flores A, Lusardi G, et al. A prevalence survey of patients with indwelling urinary catheters on district nursing caseloads in the United Kingdom: the Community Urinary Catheter Management (CCaMa) Study. J Infect Prev. 2020;21:129&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7328505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32655693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sihra N, Goodman A, Zakri R, Sahai A, Malde S. Nonantibiotic prevention and management of recurrent urinary tract infection. Nat Rev Urol 2018;15:750&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30361493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Kelly K, Phelps K, Regen EL, Carvalho F, Kondova D, Mitchell V, et al. Why are we misdiagnosing urinary tract infection in older patients? A qualitative inquiry and roadmap for staff behaviour change in the emergency department. Eur Geriatr Med 2019;10:585&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34652731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips CD, Adepoju O, Stone N, Moudouni DKM, Nwaiwu O, Zhao H, et al. Asymptomatic bacteriuria, antibiotic use, and suspected urinary tract infections in four nursing homes. BMC Geriatr 2012;12:73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3534219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23176555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beech E. To Dip or Not To Dip &#x2013; A Patient Centred Approach to Improve the Management of UTI in the Care Home Environment. Federation of Infection Societies Conference, Birmingham, 2017, abstract. URL: %https://federationinfectionsocieties.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/FISDay01-H10-1315-ElizabethBeech.pdf (accessed 29 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolle LE, Gupta K, Bradley SF, Colgan R, DeMuri GP, Drekonja D, et al. Clinical practice guideline for the management of asymptomatic bacteriuria: 2019 update by the Infectious Diseases Society of America. Clin Infect Dis 2019;68:e83&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30895288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Public Health England. Diagnosis of Urinary Tract Infections Quick Reference Tool for Primary Care for Consultation and Local Adaption. 2019. URL: %www.gov.uk/government/publications/urinary-tract-infection-diagnosis (accessed 29 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Public Health England. English Surveillance Programme for Antimicrobial Utilisation and Resistance (ESPAUR). Annual Report 2018. PHE; 2018. URL: %www.gov.uk/government/publications/english-surveillance-programme-antimicrobial-utilisation-and-resistance-espaur-report (accessed 29 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bardsley M, Blunt I, Davies S, Dixon J. Is secondary preventive care improving? Observational study of 10-year trends in emergency admissions for conditions amenable to ambulatory care. BMJ Open 2013;3:e002007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3549201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23288268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornley T, Ashiru-Oredope D, Beech E, Howard P, Kirkdale CL, Elliott H, et al. Antimicrobial use in UK long-term care facilities: results of a point prevalence survey. J Antimicrob Chemother 2019;74:2083&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6587415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30993326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nace DA, Drinka PJ, Crnich CJ. Clinical uncertainties in the approach to long term care residents with possible urinary tract infection. J Am Med Dir Assoc 2014;15:133&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24461240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Public Health England. Annual Epidemiological Commentary: Gram-negative Bacteraemia, MRSA Bacteraemia, MSSA Bacteraemia and C. difficile Infections, up to and Including Financial Year April 2018 to March 2019. 11 July 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NHS Improvement/Public Health England. Preventing Healthcare Associated Gram-negative Bloodstream Infections: An Improvement Resource. May 2017. URL: %www.england.nhs.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Gram-negative_IPCresource_pack.pdf (accessed 29 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasugba O, Mitchell BG, McInnes E, Koerner J, Cheng AC, Cheng H, Middleton S. Increased fluid intake for the prevention of urinary tract infection in adults and children in all settings: a systematic review. J Hosp Infect 2020;104:68&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31449918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawson R, Greenhalgh T, Harvey G, Walshe K. Realist review &#x2013; a new method of systematic review designed for complex policy interventions. J Health Serv Res Policy 2005;10:21&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16053581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rycroft-Malone J, McCormack B, Hutchinson AM, DeCorby K, Bucknall TK, Kent B, et al. Realist synthesis: illustrating the method for implementation research. Implement Sci 2012;7:33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3514310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22515663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rycroft-Malone J, Burton C, Hall B, McCormack B, Nutley S, Seddon D, Williams L. Improving skills and care standards in the support workforce for older people: a realist review. BMJ Open 2014;4:e005356. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2014-005356</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4039845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24879830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth A. EVIDENT Guidance for Reviewing the Evidence: A Compendium of Methodological Literature and Websites. Working Paper. January 2015. https://doi.org/10.13140/RG.2.1.1562.9842</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong G, Greenhalgh T, Westhorp G, Buckingham J, Pawson R. RAMESES publication standards: realist syntheses. BMC Med 2013;11:21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3558331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23360677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prieto J, Wilson J, Tingle A, Cooper E, Handley M, Rycroft Malone J, et al. Preventing urinary tract infection in older people living in care homes: the &#x2018;StOP UTI&#x2019; realist synthesis [published online ahead of print August 8 2024]. BMJ Qual Saf 2024. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjqs-2023-016967</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11874410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39122359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth A, Briscoe S, Wright JM. The &#x2018;realist search&#x2019;: a systematic scoping review of current practice and reporting. Res Syn Meth 2020;11:14&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31714016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harzing AW. Publish or Perish. 2007. URL: %https://harzing.com/resources/publish-or-perish (accessed 29 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalkin SM, Greenhalgh J, Jones D, Cunningham B, Lhussier M. What&#x2019;s in a mechanism? Development of a key concept in realist evaluation. Implement Sci 2015;10:49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4408605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25885787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feo R, Rasmussen P, Wiechula R, Conroy T, Kitson A. Developing effective and caring nurse-patient relationships. Nurs Stand 2017;31:54&#x2013;63. https://doi.org/10.7748/ns.2017.e10735</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28271761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawson R. Digging for nuggets: how &#x2018;bad&#x2019; research can yield &#x2018;good&#x2019; evidence. Int J Soc Res Methodol 2006;9:127&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams L, Rycroft-Malone J, Burton CR, Edwards S, Fisher D, Hall B, et al. Improving skills and care standards in the support workforce for older people: a realist synthesis of workforce development interventions. BMJ Open 2016;6:e011964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5013423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27566640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer SB, Lunnay B. The application of abductive and retroductive inference for the design and analysis of theory-driven sociological research. Sociol Res Online 2013;18:86&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gollwitzer PM. Implementation intentions: strong effects of simple plans. Am Psychol 1999;54:493&#x2013;503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE Guideline 112. Urinary Tract Infection (Recurrent): Antimicrobial Prescribing. London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE); 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrotta C, Aznar M, Mejia R, Albert X, Ng CW. Oestrogens for preventing recurrent urinary tract infection in postmenopausal women. Cochrane Database of Syst Rev 2008;2:CD005131. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD005131.pub2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18425910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonkat G, Bartoletti R, Bruy&#xe8;reet F, Cai T, Geerlings SE, K&#xf6;ves B, et al. EAU Guidelines. Edn. Presented at the EAU Annual Congress Amsterdam, the Netherlands 2022. ISBN 978-94-92671-16-5. URL: %https://uroweb.org/guidelines/urological-infections (accessed 29 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tingstrom P, Milberg A, Sund-Levander M. Early nonspecific signs and symptoms of infection in institutionalized elderly persons: perceptions of nursing assistants. Scand J Caring Sci 2010;24:24&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19954493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones LF, Cooper E, Joseph A, Allison R, Gold N, Donald I, McNulty C. Development of an information leaflet and diagnostic flow chart to improve the management of urinary tract infections in older adults: a qualitative study using the Theoretical Domains Framework. BJGP Open 2020;4:bjgpopen20X101044. https://doi.org/10.3399/bjgpopen20X101044</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7465577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32576575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beeber AS, Kistler CE, Zimmerman S, Dictus C, Ward K, Farel C, et al. Nurse decision-making for suspected UTI infections in nursing homes: potential targets to reduce antibiotic overuse. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2021;22:156&#x2013;63. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jamda.2020.06.053</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7944392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32839125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes C, Ellard D, Campbell A, Potter R, Shaw C, Gardner E, et al. A multifaceted intervention to reduce antimicrobial prescribing in care homes: a non-randomised feasibility study and process evaluation. Health Serv Deliv Res 2020;8:1&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32101392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold SH, Olesen JA, Jensen JN, Bjerrum L, Holm A, Kousgaard MB. Development of a tailored, complex intervention for clinical reflection and communication about suspected urinary tract infections in nursing home residents. Antibiotics 2020;9:360. https://doi.org/10.3390/antibiotics9060360</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7345997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32630549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones LF, Williamson H, Downing P, Lecky DM, Harcourt D, McNulty C. A qualitative investigation of the acceptability and feasibility of a urinary tract infection patient information leaflet for older adults and their carers. Antibiotics 2021;10:83. https://doi.org/10.3390/antibiotics10010083</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7830400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33467185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sund-Levander M, Tingstr&#xf6;m P. Clinical decision-making process for early nonspecific signs of infection in institutionalised elderly persons: experience of nursing assistants. Scand J Caring Sci 2013;27:27&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22536887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chambers A, MacFarlane S, Zvonar R, Evans G, Moore JE, Langford BJ, et al. A recipe for antimicrobial stewardship success: using intervention mapping to develop a program to reduce antibiotic overuse in long-term care. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol 2019;40:24&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30394258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnold SH, Jensen JN, Bjerrum L, Siersma V, Bang CW, Kousgaard MB, Holm A. Effectiveness of a tailored intervention to reduce antibiotics for urinary tract infections in nursing home residents: a cluster, randomised controlled trial. Lancet Infect Dis 2021;21:1549&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34303417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasay DK, Guirguis MS, Shkrobot RC, Slobodan JP, Wagg AS, Sadowski CA, et al. Antimicrobial stewardship in rural nursing homes: impact of interprofessional education and clinical decision tool implementation on urinary tract infection treatment in a cluster randomized trial. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol 2019;40:432&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30782227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loeb M, Brazil K, Lohfeld L, McGeer A, Simor A, Stevenson K, et al. Effect of a multifaceted intervention on number of antimicrobial prescriptions for suspected urinary tract infections in residents of nursing homes: cluster randomised controlled trial. BMJ 2005;331:669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1226247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16150741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMaughan DK, Nwaiwu O, Zhao H, Frentzel E, Mehr D, Imanpour S, et al. Impact of a decision-making aid for suspected urinary tract infection on antibiotic overuse in nursing homes. BMC Geriatr 2016;16:81. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12877-016-0255-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4833907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27084340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ydemann M. Communication in a hospital by means of a standardised method. Ugeskr Laeger 2012;174:1798&#x2013;801(in Danish).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22735111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kousgaard MB, Olesen JA, Arnold SH. Implementing an intervention to reduce use of antibiotics for suspected urinary tract infection in nursing homes: a qualitative study of barriers and enablers based on Normalization Process Theory. BMC Geriatr 2022;22:265. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12877-022-02977-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8969390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35361162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allemann H, Sund-Levander M. Nurses&#x2019; actions in response to nursing assistants&#x2019; observations of signs and symptoms of infections among nursing home residents. Nurs Open 2015;2:97&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5006863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27642516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Buul LW, van der Steen JT, Doncker SM, Achterberg WP, Schellevis FG, Veenhuizen RB, Hertogh CM. Factors influencing antibiotic prescribing in long-term care facilities: a qualitative in-depth study. BMC Geriatr 2014;14:136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4289541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25514874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaaban T, Alouah M, Lombrail P, Febvre HL, Mourad A, Morvillers JM, Rothan-Tondeur M. Decisional issues in antibiotic prescribing in French nursing homes: an ethnographic study. J Public Health Res 2019;8:1533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6886007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31819866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downs M, Blighe A, Carpenter R, Feast A, Froggatt K, Gordon S, et al. A complex intervention to reduce avoidable hospital admissions in nursing homes: a research programme including the BHiRCH-NH pilot cluster RCT. Programme Grants Appl Res 2021;9. https://doi.org/10.3310/pgfar09020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33651525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouslander JG, Lamb G, Tappen R, Herndon L, Diaz S, Roos BA, et al. Interventions to reduce hospitalisations from nursing homes: evaluation of the INTERACT II collaborative quality improvement project. J Am Geriatr Soc 2011;59:745&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21410447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitson A, Harvey G, McCormack B. Enabling the implementation of evidence based practice: a conceptual framework. Qual Health Care 1998;7:149&#x2013;58. https://doi.org/10.1136/qshc.7.3.149</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2483604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10185141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Currie G, White L. Inter-professional barriers and knowledge brokering in an organizational context: the case of healthcare. Organ Stud 2012;33:1333&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gbinigie OA, Ordonez-Mena JM, Fanshawe TR, Pl&#xfc;ddemann A, Heneghan C. Diagnostic value of symptoms and signs for identifying urinary tract infection in older adult outpatients: systematic review and meta-analysis. J Infect 2018;77:379&#x2013;90. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jinf.2018.06.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6203890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29964141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu CM, Lowder JL. Diagnosis and treatment of urinary tract infections across age groups. Am J Obstet Gynecol 2018;219:40&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29305250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berman P, Hogan DB, Fox RA. The atypical presentation of infection in old age. Age Ageing 1987;16:201&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.1093/ageing/16.4.201</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3630842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayne S, Bowden A, Sundvall PD, Gunnarsson R. The scientific evidence for a potential link between confusion and urinary tract infection in the elderly is still confusing-a systematic literature review. BMC Geriatr 2019;19:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6360770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30717706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper L, Abdelhamid A, Attreed NJ, Campbell WW, Channell AM, Chassagne P, et al. Clinical symptoms, signs and tests for identification of impending and current water-loss dehydration in older people. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2015;4:CD009647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7097739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25924806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benton D. Dehydration influences mood and cognition: a plausible hypothesis? Nutrients 2011;3:555&#x2013;73. https://doi.org/10.3390/nu3050555</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3257694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22254111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balogun SA, Philbrick JT. Delirium, a symptom of UTI in the elderly: fact or fable? A systematic review. Can Geriatr J 2014;17:22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3940475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24596591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pryor C, Clarke A. Nursing care for people with delirium superimposed on dementia. Nurs Older People 2017;29:18&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28361642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scottish Intercollegiate Guidelines Network (SIGN). Management of Suspected Bacterial Lower Urinary Tract Infection in Adult Women. Edinburgh: SIGN; 2020. (SIGN publication no. 160). URL: %www.sign.ac.uk (accessed 29 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE Quality Standards (SQ90). Urinary Tract Infections in Adults. London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE); 2015. URL: %www.nice.org.uk/guidance/qs90 (accessed 5 December 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleming A, Bradley C, Cullinan S, Byrne S. Antibiotic prescribing in long-term care facilities: a meta-synthesis of qualitative research. Drugs Aging 2015;32:295&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4412731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25832969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potter R, Campbell A, Ellard DR, Shaw C, Gardner E, Agus A, et al. Multifaceted intervention to reduce antimicrobial prescribing in care homes: a process evaluation of a UK-based non-randomised feasibility study. BMJ Open 2019;9:e032185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6887004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31753887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell C, Blighe A, Froggatt K, McCormack B, Woodward-Carlton B, Young J, et al. Family involvement in timely detection of changes in health of nursing homes residents: a qualitative exploratory study. J Clin Nurs 2018;27:317&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5767757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28557103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burton CR, Williams L, Bucknall T, Fisher D, Hall B, Harris G, et al. Theory and practical guidance for effective de-implementation of practices across health and care services: a realist synthesis. Health Serv Deliv Res 2021;9:1&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fenton JJ, Kravitz RL, Jerant A, Paterniti DA, Bang H, Williams D, et al. Promoting patient centered counseling to reduce use of low-value diagnostic tests: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Intern Med 2016;176:191&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26640973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>May L, Franks P, Jerant A, Fenton J. Watchful waiting strategy may reduce low-value diagnostic testing. J Am Board Fam Med 2016;29:710&#x2013;7. https://doi.org/10.3122/jabfm.2016.06.160056</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28076254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Little P, Gould C, Williamson I, Moore M, Warner G, Dunleavey J. Pragmatic randomised controlled trial of two prescribing strategies for childhood acute otitis media. BMJ 2001;322:336&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.322.7282.336</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC26576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11159657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacGeorge EL, Caldes EP, Smith RA, Hackman NM, San Jose A. Reducing unwarranted antibiotic use for pediatric acute otitis media: the influence of physicians&#x2019; explanation and instruction on parent compliance with &#x2018;watchful waiting&#x2019;. J Appl Commun Res 2017;45:333&#x2013;45. https://doi.org/10.1080/00909882.2017.1320575</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunn F, Lynch J, Goodman C, Sharpe R, Walshe C, Preston N, Froggatt K. Improving living and dying for people with advanced dementia living in care homes: a realist review of Namaste Care and other multisensory interventions. BMC Geriatr 2018;18:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6282262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30522450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashraf MS, Gaur S, Bushen OY, Chopra T, Chung P, Clifford K, et al.; Infection Advisory SubCommittee for AMDA&#x2014;The Society of Post-Acute and Long-Term Care Medicine. Diagnosis, treatment, and prevention of urinary tract infections in post-acute and long-term care settings: a consensus statement from AMDA&#x2019;s Infection Advisory Subcommittee. J Am Med Dir Assoc 2020;21:12&#x2013;24.e2. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jamda.2019.11.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31888862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scottish Antimicrobial Prescribing Group (SAPG), Health Improvement Scotland, NHS Scotland. Decision Aid for Diagnosis and Management of Suspected Urinary Tract Infection (UTI) in People Aged 65 Years and Over. 2021. URL: %www.sapg.scot/media/5844/decision-aid-for-diagnosis-and-management-of-suspected-uti-in-people-over-65-years.pdf (accessed 29 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Royal College of Physicians (RCP). National Early Warning Score (NEWS) 2: Standardising the Assessment of Acute-Illness Severity in the NHS Updated report of a working party. London: RCP; 2017 URL: %www.rcplondon.ac.uk/projects/outputs/national-early-warning-score-news-2 (accessed 29 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shallcross L, Rockenschaub P, Blackburn R, Nazareth I, Freemantle N, Hayward A. Antibiotic prescribing for lower UTI in elderly patients in primary care and risk of bloodstream infection: a cohort study using electronic health records in England. PLOS Med 2020;17:e1003336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7505443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32956399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>TARGET. Treating Your Infection UTI Leaflet, for Older Adults and Those Who Care for Them. Version 2.4. October 2018. https://elearning.rcgp.org.uk/mod/book/view.php?id=12647&amp;chapterid=442 (accessed 29 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AMDA &#x2013; The Society for Post-Acute and Long-Term Care Medicine. The IOU Study: Improving Outcomes of UTI Toolkit. URL: %https://paltc.org/content/iou-toolkit (accessed 29 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pettersson E, Vernby A, M&#xf6;lstad S, Lundborg CS. Can a multifaceted educational intervention targeting both nurses and physicians change the prescribing of antibiotics to nursing home residents? A cluster randomized controlled trial. J Antimicrob Chemother 2011;66:2659&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21893568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nace DA, Hanlon JT, Crnich CJ, Drinka PJ, Schweon SJ, Anderson G, Perera S. A multifaceted antimicrobial stewardship program for the treatment of uncomplicated cystitis in nursing home residents. JAMA Intern Med 2020;180:944&#x2013;51. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamainternmed.2020.1256</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7215632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32391862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Little P, Moore MV, Turner S, Rumsby K, Warner G, Lowes JA, et al. Effectiveness of five different approaches in management of urinary tract infection: randomised controlled trial. BMJ 2010;340:c199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2817051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20139214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toward Optimized Practice (TOP) Working Group for Urinary Tract Infections in Long Term Care Facilities. Diagnosis and Management of Urinary Tract Infections in Long Term Care Facilities: Clinical Practice Guideline. January 2015. URL: %www.albertahealthservices.ca/assets/info/asm/if-asm-cpg-diagnosis-management-urinary-tract-infection-ltcf.pdf (accessed 29 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Care Quality Commission (CQC). Dignity and Nutrition for Older People: Review of Compliance. 2011. Updated 29 May 2017. URL: %www.cqc.org.uk/sites/default/files/documents/20111007_dignity_and_nutrition_inspection_report_final_update.pdf (accessed 29 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Sharkawy AM, Sahota O, Maughan RJ, Lobo DN. The pathophysiology of fluid and electrolyte balance in the older adult surgical patient. Clin Nutr 2014;33:6&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clnu.2013.11.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24308897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper L, Bunn D, Jimoh FO, Fairweather-Tait SJ. Water-loss dehydration and aging. Mech Ageing Dev 2014;136&#x2013;137:50&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mad.2013.11.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24333321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Food Safety Authority (EFSA) Panel on Dietetic Products. Scientific opinion on dietary reference values for water. EFSA J 2010;8:1459. https://doi.org/10.2903/j.efsa.2010.1459</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferry M. Strategies for ensuring good hydration in the elderly. Nutr Rev 2005;63:S22&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1753-4887.2005.tb00151.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16028569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson J, Elgohari S, Livermore DM, Cookson B, Johnson A, Lamagni T, et al. Trends among pathogens reported as causing bacteraemia in England, 2004&#x2013;2008. Clin Microbiol Infect 2011;17:451&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20491834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooton TM, Vecchio M, Iroz A, Tack I, Dornic Q, Seksek I, Lotan Y. Effect of increased daily water intake in premenopausal women with recurrent urinary tract infections: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Intern Med 2018;178:1509&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamainternmed.2018.4204</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6584323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30285042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson J, Tingle A, Bak A, Greene C, Tsiami A, Loveday H. Improving fluid consumption in older people in care homes: an exploration of the factors contributing to under-hydration. Nurs Resid Care 2020;22:139&#x2013;46. https://doi.org/10.12968/nrec.2020.22.3.139</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bak A, Wilson J, Tsiami A, Loveday H. Drinking vessel preferences in older nursing home residents: optimal design and potential for increasing fluid intake. Br J Nurs 2018;27:1298&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30525974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth J, Agnew R. Evaluating a hydration intervention (DRInK Up) to prevent urinary tract infection in care home residents: a mixed methods exploratory study. J Frailty Sarcopenia Falls 2019;4:36&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7155301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32300716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lean K, Nawaz RF, Jawad S, Vincent C. Reducing urinary tract infections in care homes by improving hydration. BMJ Open Qual 2019;8:e000563. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjoq-2018-000563</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6629391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31363503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long EM, Rickenbrode A, Thibodeaux T. Practice brief: a hydration initiative in a long-term care facility. Geriatr Nurs 2013;34:340&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24073421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meddings J, Rogers MAM, Krein SL, Fakih MG, Olmsted RN, Saint S. Reducing unnecessary urinary catheter use and other strategies to prevent catheter-associated urinary tract infection: an integrative review. BMJ Qual Saf 2014;23:277&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3960353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24077850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNulty CA, Bowen J, Foy C, Gunn K, Freeman E, Tompkins D, et al. Is there an opportunity to reduce urinary catheter-related infections? Exploring variation in catheterisation rates in care homes. Br J Infect Control 2006;7:22&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meddings J, Rogers MAM, Macy M, Saint S. Systematic review and meta-analysis: reminder systems to reduce catheter-associated urinary tract infections and urinary catheter use in hospitalized patients. Clin Infect Dis 2010;51:550&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20673003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkins L, Sallis A, Chadborn T, Shaw K, Schneider A, Hopkins S, et al. Reducing catheter-associated urinary tract infections: a systematic review of barriers and facilitators and strategic behavioural analysis of interventions. Implement Sci 2020;15:44. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13012-020-01001-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7336619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32624002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanat M, Borek AJ, Atkins L, Sallis A, Ashiru-Oredope D, Beech E, et al. Optimising interventions for catheter-associated urinary tract infections (CAUTI) in primary, secondary and care home settings. Antibiotics 2020;9:1&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.3390/antibiotics9070419</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7399982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32709080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mody L, Greene TM, Meddings J, Krein SL, McNamara SE, Trautner BW, et al. A national implementation project to prevent catheter-associated urinary tract infection in nursing home residents. JAMA Intern Med 2017;177:1154&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5710434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28525923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krein SL, Harrod M, Collier S, Davis KK, Rolle AJ, Fowler KE, Mody L. A national collaborative approach to reduce catheter-associated urinary tract infections in nursing homes: a qualitative assessment. Am J Infect Control 2017;45:1342&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajic.2017.07.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5828510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28807424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sreedhara M, Mazor KM, DuBeau C, Field TS, Ela JM, Gurwitz JH. Nursing home leaders&#x2019; views on catheter use and CAUTI as a quality and safety concern. J Am Geriatr Soc 2015;63:S213&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell BG, Schellevis F, Stobberingh E, Goossens H, Pringle M. A systematic review and meta-analysis of the effects of antibiotic consumption on antibiotic resistance. BMC Infect Dis 2014;14:13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3897982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24405683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klay M, Marfyak K. Use of a continence nurse specialist in an extended care facility. Urol Nurs 2005;25:2. ProQuest One Academic. pg. 101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15900978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Northouse PG. Leadership: Theory &amp; Practice. New York: Sage Publications; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andr&#xe9; B, Sj&#xf8;vold E, Rannestad T, Ringdal GI. The impact of work culture on quality of care in nursing homes: a review study. Scand J Caring Sci 2014;28:449&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24117657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rycroft-Malone J, Seers K, Eldh AC, Cox K, Crichton N, Harvey G, et al. A realist process evaluation within the Facilitating Implementation of Research Evidence (FIRE) cluster randomised controlled international trial: an exemplar. Implement Sci 2018;13:138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6238283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30442165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley R, Griffiths AW, Shoesmith E, McDermid J, Couch E, Robinson O, et al. The influence of care home managers on the implementation of a complex intervention: findings from the process evaluation of a randomised controlled trial of dementia care mapping. BMC Geriatr 2020;20:303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7446218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32842965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall M, Pfeifer N, de Silva D, Wei L, Anderson J, Cruickshank L, et al. An evaluation of a safety improvement intervention in care homes in England: a participatory qualitative study. J R Soc Med 2018;111:414&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.1177/0141076818803457</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6243438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30235053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surr CA, Shoesmith E, Griffiths AW, Kelley R, McDermid J, Fossey J. Exploring the role of external experts in supporting staff to implement psychosocial interventions in care home settings: results from the process evaluation of a randomized controlled trial. BMC Health Serv Res 2019;19:790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6829988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31684943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buswell M, Goodman C, Roe B, Russell B, Norton C, Harwood R, et al. What works to improve and manage fecal incontinence in care home residents living with dementia? A realist synthesis of the evidence. J Am Med Dir Assoc 2017;18:752&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28859818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Low LF, Fletcher J, Goodenough B, Jeon YH, Etherton-Beer C, MacAndrew M, Beattie E. A systematic review of interventions to change staff care practices in order to improve resident outcomes in nursing homes. PLOS One 2015;10:e0140711. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0140711</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4641718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26559675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thacker SB, Berkelman RL. Public Health Surveillance in the United States. Epidemiol Rev 1988;10:164&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3066626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scanlon KA, Wells CM, Woolforde L, Khameraj A, Baumgarten J, et al. Saving lives and reducing harm. A CAUTI reduction program. Nurs Econ 2017;35:134&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu D, Kane R, Arling G. Relationship between nursing home quality indicators and potentially preventable hospitalisation. BMJ Qual Saf 2019;28:524&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30867234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haunch K, Thompson C, Arthur A, Edwards P, Goodman C, Hanratty B, et al. Understanding the staff behaviours that promote quality for older people living in long term care facilities: a realist review. Int J Nurs Stud 2021;117:103905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33714766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNulty C, Bowen J, Howell-Jones R, Walker M, Freeman E. Exploring reasons for variation in urinary catheterisation prevalence in care homes: a qualitative study. Age Ageing 2008;37:706&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18703520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith SN, Greene MT, Mody L, Banaszak-Holl J, Petersen LD, Meddings J. Evaluation of the association between Nursing Home Survey on Patient Safety culture (NHSOPS) measures and catheter-associated urinary tract infections: results of a national collaborative. BMJ Qual Saf 2018;27:464&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5869141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28951531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abusalem S, Polivka B, Coty MB, Crawford TN, Furman CD, Alaradi M. The relationship between culture of safety and rate of adverse events in long-term care facilities. J Patient Saf 2019;17:299&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30889049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins I, Gordon A, Dyas J, Logan P, Gladman J. Explaining the barriers to and tensions in delivering effective healthcare in UK care homes: a qualitative study. BMJ Open 2013;3:e003178. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2013-003178</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3717448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23872297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skills for Care. Care Certificate Workbook. 2022. URL: %www.skillsforcare.org.uk/Developing-your-workforce/Care-Certificate/Care-Certificate-workbook.aspx (accessed 29 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spilsbury K, Meyer J. Making claims on nursing work: exploring the work of healthcare assistants and the implications for registered nurses' roles. J Res Nurs 2005;10:65-83. https://doi.org/10.1177/136140960501000104</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mody L, Meddings J, Edson BS, McNamara SE, Trautner BW, Stone ND, et al. Enhancing resident safety by preventing healthcare-associated infection: a national initiative to reduce catheter-associated urinary tract infections in nursing homes. Clin Infect Dis 2015;61:86&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4481599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25814630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindeman MA, Black K, Smith R, Gough J, Bryce A, Gilsenan B, et al. Changing practice in residential aged care using participatory methods. Educ Health (Abingdon) 2003;16:22&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14741920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez SH. Emotional labor and organized emotional care: conceptualizing nursing home care work. Work Occup 2006;33:133&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicol JS, Dosser I. Understanding reflective practice. Nurs Stand 2016;30:34&#x2013;42. https://doi.org/10.7748/ns.30.36.34.s44</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27154119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nursing &amp; Midwifery Council. The Code Professional Standards of Practice and Behaviour for Nurses, Midwives and Nursing Associates. 2015. URL: %www.nmc.org.uk/globalassets/sitedocuments/nmc-publications/nmc-code.pdf (accessed 29 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page S, Meerabeau L. Achieving change through reflective practice: closing the loop. Nurse Educ Today 2000;20:365&#x2013;72. https://doi.org/10.1054/nedt.2000.0430</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10895118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeatts DE, Shen Y, Yeatts PE, Solakoglu O, Seckin G. Shared decision-making in nursing homes: factors associated with the empowerment of direct care workers. J Aging Health 2016;28:621&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26282483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE Guideline. Urinary Tract Infection (Recurrent): Antimicrobial Prescribing. NG112 (31 October 2018). URL: %www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng112 (accessed 29 October 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed H, Farewell D, Jones HM, Francis NA, Paranjothy S, Butler CC. Antibiotic prophylaxis and clinical outcomes among older adults with recurrent urinary tract infection: cohort study. Age Ageing 2019;48:228&#x2013;34. https://doi.org/10.1093/ageing/afy146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6424374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30165433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albert X, Huertas I, Pereiro II, Sanfelix J, Gosalbes V, Perrota C. Antibiotics for preventing recurrent urinary tract infection in non-pregnant women. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2004:CD001209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7032641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15266443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price JR, Guran LA, Gregory WT, McDonagh MS. Nitrofurantoin vs other prophylactic agents in reducing recurrent urinary tract infections in adult women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Obstet Gynecol 2016;215:548&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27457111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwenger EM, Tejani AM, Loewen PS. Probiotics for preventing urinary tract infections in adults and children. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2015:CD008772. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD008772.pub2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8720415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26695595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hidalgo G, Chan M, Tufenkji N. Inhibition of Escherichia coli CFT073 fliC expression and motility by cranberry materials. Appl Environ Microbiol 2011;77:6852&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3187111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21821749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juthani-Mehta M, Perley L, Chen S, Dziura J, Gupta K. Feasibility of cranberry capsule administration and clean-catch urine collection in long-term care residents. J Am Geriatr Soc 2010;58:2028&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1532-5415.2010.03080.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2953731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20929476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jepson RG, Williams G, Craig JC. Cranberries for preventing urinary tract infections. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2012;:CD001321. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD001321.pub5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7027998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23076891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kranj&#x10d;ec B, Pape&#x161; D, Altarac S. D-mannose powder for prophylaxis of recurrent urinary tract infections in women: a randomized clinical trial. World J Urol 2014;32:79&#x2013;84. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00345-013-1091-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23633128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenger SM, Bradley MS, Thomas DA, Bertolet MH, Lowder JL, Sutcliffe S. D-mannose vs other agents for recurrent urinary tract infection prevention in adult women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Obstet Gynecol 2020;223:265.e1&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajog.2020.05.048</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7395894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32497610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nalliah S, Fong JSH, Thor AYY, Lim OH. The use of chemotherapeutic agents as prophylaxis for recurrent urinary tract infection in healthy nonpregnant women: a network meta-analysis. Indian J Urol 2019;35:147&#x2013;55. https://doi.org/10.4103/iju.IJU_378_18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6458811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31000921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakhit M, Krzyzaniak N, Hilder J, Clark J, Scott AM, Mar CD. Use of methenamine hippurate to prevent urinary tract infections in community adult women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Gen Pract 2021;71:e528&#x2013;37. https://doi.org/10.3399/BJGP.2020.0833</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8136580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34001538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding C, Mossop H, Homer T, Chadwick T, King W, Carnell S, et al. Alternative to prophylactic antibiotics for the treatment of recurrent urinary tract infections in women. BMJ 2022;376:e068229. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj-2021-0068229</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8905684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35264408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksen B. A randomized, open, parallel-group study on the preventive effect of an estradiol-releasing vaginal ring (Estring) on recurrent urinary tract infections in postmenopausal women. Am J Obstet Gynecol 1999;180:1072&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0002-9378(99)70597-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10329858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrante KL, Wasenda EJ, Jung CE, Adams-Piper ER, Lukacz ES. Vaginal estrogen for the prevention of recurrent urinary tract infection in postmenopausal women: a randomized clinical trial. Female Pelvic Med Reconstr Surg 2021;27:112&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31232721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raz R, Stamm WE. A controlled trial of intravaginal estriol in postmenopausal women with recurrent urinary tract infections. N Engl J Med 1993;329:753&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJM199309093291102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8350884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raz R, Colodner R, Rohana Y, Battino S, Rottensterich E, Wasser I, Stamm W. Effectiveness of estriol-containing vaginal pessaries and nitrofurantoin macrocrystal therapy in the prevention of recurrent urinary tract infection in postmenopausal women. Clin Infect Dis 2003;36:1362&#x2013;8. https://doi.org/10.1086/374341</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12766829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>