<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39301835</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-3773</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>64</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Angewandte Chemie (International ed. in English)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Angew Chem Int Ed Engl</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Ternary Eutectic Electrolyte for Flexible Wide-Temperature Zinc-Ion Batteries from -20&#x2009;&#xb0;C to 70&#x2009;&#xb0;C.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e202414728</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e202414728</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/anie.202414728</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Aqueous Zn-ion batteries (ZIBs) have attracted attention for grid applications due to their cost-effectiveness and high security. However, their lifespan decreases at high temperatures due to declining interfacial stability and increased side reactions. To address these challenges, a ternary deep eutectic solvent-based flexible electrolyte, comprised of Zn(ClO<sub>4</sub>)<sub>2</sub>&#x2009;&#x22c5;&#x2009;6H<sub>2</sub>O, butanedinitrile (BD), and LiCl in an amphoteric polymer matrix, was developed to enable wide-temperature ZIBs working from -20&#x2009;&#xb0;C to 70&#x2009;&#xb0;C. The interactions among BD, Li<sup>+</sup>, and zinc hydrate alongside the amphoteric groups on the polyelectrolyte matrix could effectively suppress the interfacial side reactions and Zn dendrites formation. Consequently, the symmetric Zn cell demonstrates exceptional stability across a wide-temperature range, with the ability to survive up to 2780&#x2005;hours (1&#x2005;mA&#x2009;cm<sup>-2</sup>) at 50&#x2009;&#xb0;C. Furthermore, the flexible Zn||PANI battery can operate stably over 1000 cycles at 50&#x2009;&#xb0;C, boasting an initial specific capacity of 124.8&#x2005;mAh&#x2009;g<sup>-1</sup> and capacity retention rate of 87.9&#x2009;% (3&#x2005;A&#x2009;g<sup>-1</sup>). This work presents an effective strategy for designing high-stability energy storage devices with excellent security features that can function reliably across diverse temperature conditions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Wiley-VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Qinbo</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory for Modification of Chemical Fibers and Polymer Materials, College of Materials Science and Engineering, Donghua University, Shanghai, 201620, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Junfu</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory for Modification of Chemical Fibers and Polymer Materials, College of Materials Science and Engineering, Donghua University, Shanghai, 201620, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xing</LastName><ForeName>Doudou</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory for Modification of Chemical Fibers and Polymer Materials, College of Materials Science and Engineering, Donghua University, Shanghai, 201620, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Yingjie</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9332-325X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory for Modification of Chemical Fibers and Polymer Materials, College of Materials Science and Engineering, Donghua University, Shanghai, 201620, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Feng</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9269-7025</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory for Modification of Chemical Fibers and Polymer Materials, College of Materials Science and Engineering, Donghua University, Shanghai, 201620, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangsu Engineering Laboratory of Novel Functional Polymeric Materials, College of Chemistry, Chemical Engineering and Materials Science, Soochow University, Suzhou, 215123, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>52333002</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52473003</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>BK20220007</GrantID><Agency>Jiangsu Province Science Foundation for Carbon Emissions Peak and Carbon Neutrality Science and Technology Innovation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Collaborative Innovation Center of Suzhou Nano Science and Technology</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Priority Academic Program Development of Jiangsu Higher Education Institutions</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Initial Research Funds for Young Teachers of Donghua University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Angew Chem Int Ed Engl</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0370543</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1433-7851</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Eutectic electrolyte</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Zn-ion battery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electrostatic shielding</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wide temperature range</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39301835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202414728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Y. Dai, R. Lu, C. Zhang, J. Li, Y. Yuan, Y. Mao, C. Ye, Z. Cai, J. Zhu, J. Li, R. Yu, L. Cui, S. Zhao, Q. An, G. He, G. I. N. Waterhouse, P. R. Shearing, Y. Ren, J. Lu, K. Amine, Z. Wang, L. Mai, Nat. Catal. 2024, 1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Li, X. Xie, H. Liu, P. Wang, C. Deng, B. Lu, J. Zhou, S. Liang, Natl. Sci. Rev. 2022, 9, nwab177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Wang, C. Li, S. Liu, J. Zhang, D. Zhang, J. Du, Q. Zhang, Y. Yao, Adv. Energy Mater. 2023, 13, 2300250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. W. D. Gourley, R. Brown, B. D. Adams, D. Higgins, Joule 2023, 7, 1415&#x2013;1436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Zhang, Y. Tang, S. Guo, X. Cao, A. Pan, G. Fang, J. Zhou, S. Liang, Energy Environ. Sci. 2020, 13, 4625&#x2013;4665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Liu, X. Ou, Y. Niu, L. Li, D. Xing, Y. Zhou, F. Yan, Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 2024, 63, e202317944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Wang, W. Huang, A. Pei, Y. Li, F. Shi, X. Yu, Y. Cui, Nat. Energy 2019, 4, 664&#x2013;670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Fan, X. Ji, L. Chen, J. Chen, T. Deng, F. Han, J. Yue, N. Piao, R. Wang, X. Zhou, X. Xiao, L. Chen, C. Wang, Nat. Energy 2019, 4, 882&#x2013;890.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Wang, M. Sun, X. Ren, L. Hu, Z. Li, X. Yao, C. Jia, Energy Storage Mater. 2024, 68, 103333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Chen, W. Zhao, J. Jiang, X. Zhao, S. Zheng, Z. Pan, X. Yang, Energy Storage Mater. 2023, 59, 102767.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Wan, R. Wang, Z. Liu, S. Zhang, J. Hao, J. Mao, H. Li, D. Chao, L. Zhang, C. Zhang, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2310623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Zhao, L. Yu, J. Liu, J. Wang, N. Yao, X. Li, X. Chen, B. Li, Q. Zhang, Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 2022, 61, e202208042.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhang, J. Huang, H. Liu, W. Kou, Y. Dai, W. Dang, W. Wu, J. Wang, Y. Fu, Z. Jiang, Adv. Energy Mater. 2023, 13, 2300156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Yuan, J. Hao, C. Kao, C. Wu, H. Liu, S. Dou, S. Qiao, Energy Environ. Sci. 2021, 14, 5669&#x2013;5689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Du, E. H. Ang, Y. Yang, Y. Zhang, M. Ye, C. C. Li, Energy Environ. Sci. 2020, 13, 3330&#x2013;3360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Innocenti, D. Bresser, J. Garche, S. Passerini, Nat. Commun. 2024, 15, 4068.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Chen, S. Xie, X. Zhao, W. Zhou, Y. Li, J. Zhang, Z. Chen, D. Chao, Energy Storage Mater. 2022, 51, 683&#x2013;718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Wang, Y. Yang, Y. Wang, S. Dong, L. Cheng, Y. Li, Z. Wang, L. Trabzon, H. Wang, ACS Nano 2022, 16, 15770&#x2013;15778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Wang, Q. Ma, L. Zhang, Z. Liu, J. Wan, J. Mao, H. Li, S. Zhang, J. Hao, L. Zhang, C. Zhang, Adv. Energy Mater. 2023, 13, 2302543.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Wang, S. Chen, X. Liao, R. Huang, F. Wang, J. Chen, Y. Wang, F. Wang, H. Wang, Nat. Commun. 2023, 14, 5443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhu, W. Li, L. Zhang, W. Fang, Q. Ruan, J. Li, F. Zhang, H. Zhang, T. Quan, S. Zhang, Energy Environ. Sci. 2023, 16, 2825&#x2013;2855.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Wen, C. Yang, Q. Liu, J. Qiu, L. Zang, Small 2023, 19, 2303348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Quan, W. Zhou, T. Wu, M. Chen, X. Han, Q. Tian, J. Xu, J. Chen, Chem. Eng. J. 2022, 446, 137056.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Wang, J. Diao, J. N. Burrow, Z. W. Brotherton, N. A. Lynd, G. Henkelman, C. B. Mullins, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 34, 2311271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Qiu, X. Zheng, R. Zhang, Q. Lin, M. Li, J. Luo, S. Yang, Z. Liu, Q. Wang, Y. Yu, C. Yang, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 34, 2310825.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Lu, J. Hu, L. Wang, J. Li, X. Ma, Z. Zhu, H. Li, Y. Zhao, Y. Li, J. Zhao, B. Xu, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2022, 32, 2112540.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Lv, Y. Xiao, L. Ma, C. Zhi, S. Chen, Adv. Mater. 2022, 34, 2106409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Meng, L. Zhang, M. Peng, D. Shen, C. Zhu, S. Qian, J. Liu, Y. Cao, C. Yan, J. Zhou, T. Qian, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2022, 32, 2206653.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Yang, X. Du, J. Zhao, Z. Chen, J. Li, J. Xie, Y. Zhang, Z. Cui, Q. Kong, Z. Zhao, C. Wang, Q. Zhang, G. Cui, Joule 2020, 4, 1557&#x2013;1574.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Chen, X. Sun, T. Pietsch, B. Plietker, E. Brunner, M. Ruck, Adv. Mater. 2023, 35, 2207131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Chen, T. Chen, J. Fu, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 34, 2308015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Shang, D. Kundu, Joule 2023, 7, 244&#x2013;250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Zhu, Z. Tie, S. Bi, Z. Niu, Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 2024, 63, e202403712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Liu, R. Zhang, J. Mao, Y. Zhao, Q. Cai, Z. Guo, Sci. Adv. 2022, 8, eabn5097.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Liu, X. Ou, L. Li, X. Wang, J. Wen, Y. Zhou, F. Yan, J. Mater. Chem. A 2022, 10, 12235&#x2013;12246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. B. Hansen, S. Spittle, B. Chen, D. Poe, Y. Zhang, J. M. Klein, A. Horton, L. Adhikari, T. Zelovich, B. W. Doherty, B. Gurkan, E. J. Maginn, A. Ragauskas, M. Dadmun, T. A. Zawodzinski, G. A. Baker, M. E. Tuckerman, R. F. Savinell, J. R. Sangoro, Chem. Rev. 2021, 121, 1232&#x2013;1285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Hou, P. Li, Y. Qi, Y. Wang, M. Huang, C. Shen, H. Xiang, N. Li, K. Xie, ACS Energy Lett. 2023, 8, 3649&#x2013;3657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Wang, G. Liu, W. Wan, X. Li, J. Li, C. Wang, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2306546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Chen, C. Zhang, J. Li, Z. Du, F. Guo, W. Zhang, Y. Dai, W. Zong, X. Gao, J. Zhu, Y. Zhao, X. Wang, G. He, Energy Environ. Sci. 2023, 16, 2540&#x2013;2549.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Lin, G. Zhou, M. J. Robson, J. Yu, S. C. T. Kwok, F. Ciucci, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2022, 32, 2109322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Zhang, H. Zheng, L. Lin, J. Wen, S. Zhang, X. Hu, D. Zhou, B. Sa, L. Wang, J. Lin, Q. Xie, D. L. Peng, J. Lu, Adv. Energy Mater. n.d., n/a, 2401324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Deng, Z. Deng, Y. Chen, R. Feng, X. Wang, Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 2024, 63, e202316499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Hu, F. Xian, Z. Guo, C. Lu, X. Du, X. Cheng, S. Zhang, S. Dong, G. Cui, L. Chen, Chem. Mater. 2020, 32, 3405&#x2013;3413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Chen, Z. Yang, X. Xu, Y. Qiao, Z. Zhou, Z. Hao, X. Chen, Y. Liu, X. Wu, X. Zhou, L. Li, S. Chou, Adv. Mater. n.d., n/a, 2400169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Wang, X. Chen, H. Wan, B. Zhang, K. Guan, J. Yao, J. Ji, J. Li, Y. Gan, L. Lv, L. Tao, G. Ma, H. Wang, J. Zhang, H. Wang, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2023, 33, 2300795.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Li, R. Kingsbury, A. S. Thind, A. Shyamsunder, T. T. Fister, R. F. Klie, K. A. Persson, L. F. Nazar, Nat. Commun. 2023, 14, 3067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Reber, O. Borodin, M. Becker, D. Rentsch, J. H. Thienenkamp, R. Grissa, W. Zhao, A. Aribia, G. Brunklaus, C. Battaglia, R. K&#xfc;hnel, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2022, 32, 2112138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Xu, H. Li, Y. Jin, D. Zhou, B. Sun, M. Armand, G. Wang, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2309726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Li, R. Zhao, W. Zhou, L. Wang, W. Li, D. Zhao, D. Chao, JACS Au 2023, 3, 2107&#x2013;2116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Tian, J. Wang, R. Sun, T. Ali, H. Wang, B. Xie, Y. Zhong, Y. Hu, Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 2023, 62, e202310970.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Zhang, Y. Zhang, M. Ye, Z. Wen, Y. Tang, X. Liu, C. C. Li, Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 2023, 62, e202311032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Wang, Q. Li, H. Hong, S. Yang, R. Zhang, X. Wang, X. Jin, B. Xiong, S. Bai, C. Zhi, Nat. Commun. 2023, 14, 3890.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Mo, Z. Chen, G. Liang, D. Wang, Y. Zhao, H. Li, B. Dong, C. Zhi, Adv. Energy Mater. 2020, 10, 2000035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. A. Giffin, Nat. Commun. 2022, 13, 5250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Zhu, Z. Zhang, S. Zhao, A. S. Westover, I. Belharouak, P. Cao, Adv. Energy Mater. 2021, 11, 2003836.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Dong, L. Miao, G. Ma, S. Di, Y. Wang, L. Wang, J. Xu, N. Zhang, Chem. Sci. 2021, 12, 5843&#x2013;5852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Qiu, X. Du, J. Zhao, Y. Wang, J. Ju, Z. Chen, Z. Hu, D. Yan, X. Zhou, G. Cui, Nat. Commun. 2019, 10, 5374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Li, Z. Zhao, S. Zhang, L. Sun, M. Li, J. A. Yuwono, J. Mao, J. Hao, J. (Pimm) Vongsvivut, L. Xing, C. Zhao, Z. Guo, Nat. Commun. 2023, 14, 6526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Yuan, S. D. Pu, M. A. P&#xe9;rez Osorio, Z. Li, S. Zhang, S. Yang, B. Liu, C. Gong, A. S. Menon, L. F. J. Piper, X. Gao, P. G. Bruce, A. W. Robertson, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2307708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Delley, J. Chem. Phys. 1990, 92, 508&#x2013;517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Delley, J. Chem. Phys. 2000, 113, 7756&#x2013;7764.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>