<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40367910</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-0070</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>113</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Diagnostic microbiology and infectious disease</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Diagn Microbiol Infect Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Epidemiology, transmission dynamics, treatment strategies, and future perspectives on Oropouche virus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>116882</StartPage><MedlinePgn>116882</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2025.116882</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0732-8893(25)00205-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Oropouche virus (OROV), a mosquito-borne pathogen primarily found in the Amazon basin, has attracted increasing attention due to its expanding geographical spread and recurrent outbreaks. First identified in 1955, OROV causes Oropouche fever, a febrile illness with clinical features that often overlap with those of other arboviral infections, posing significant diagnostic challenges. Arboviruses such as dengue, chikungunya, zika, and yellow fever also circulate in the same regions of South and Central America, further complicating the clinical differentiation of OROV from these infections. The primary vector for OROV in urban areas is Culicoides paraensis midges, but the virus also maintains a sylvatic transmission cycle involving Aedes serratus and Coquillettidia venezuelensis mosquitoes, along with wild vertebrate reservoirs such as sloths, non-human primates, and birds. Moreover, in 2024, over 10,000 OROV cases were reported including in previously unaffected regions with Brazil recording 5,407 cases since 2015, while recent fatalities linked to severe coagulopathy, liver failure, and adverse pregnancy outcomes remain under investigation. Currently, no specific antiviral treatments are available for OROV, and the diagnostic tools are limited, highlighting the urgent need for improved management strategies. Given the increasing number of OROV cases, there is a clear need to strengthen surveillance efforts and accelerate the development of vaccines and therapeutic interventions. This review delves into the multi-faceted approach to control OROV, incorporating surveillance, antiviral therapy, and vaccine development to mitigate the impact of this emerging pathogen. Furthermore, it provides a comprehensive overview of the epidemiology and future potential antiviral candidates and challenges in current therapeutic approaches.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoosuf</LastName><ForeName>Beema T</ForeName><Initials>BT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Global Health Research, Saveetha Medical College and Hospital, Saveetha Institute of Medical and Technical Sciences, Saveetha University, Chennai, India; Faculty of Data Science and Information Technology, INTI International University, Nilai, Malaysia. Electronic address: beematy96@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gaidhane</LastName><ForeName>Abhay M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jawaharlal Nehru Medical College, and Global Health Academy, School of Epidemiology and Public Health. Datta Meghe Institute of Higher Education, Wardha, India. Electronic address: abhay.psm@dmiher.edu.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vadia</LastName><ForeName>Nasir</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Marwadi University Research Center, Department of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Faculty of Health Sciences, Marwadi University, Rajkot, 360003, Gujarat, India. Electronic address: nasirbhai.vadia@marwadieducation.edu.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Menon</LastName><ForeName>Soumya V</ForeName><Initials>SV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry and Biochemistry, School of Sciences, JAIN (Deemed to be University), Bangalore, Karnataka, India. Electronic address: v.soumya@jainuniversity.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chennakesavulu</LastName><ForeName>Kattela</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Sathyabama Institute of Science and Technology, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India. Electronic address: chennakesavulureddy.chemistry@sathyabama.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Panigrahi</LastName><ForeName>Rajashree</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, IMS and SUM Hospital, Siksha 'O' Anusandhan (Deemed to be University), Bhubaneswar, Odisha, 751003, India. Electronic address: rajashreepanigrahy@soa.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bushi</LastName><ForeName>Ganesh</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chitkara Centre for Research and Development, Chitkara University, Himachal Pradesh, 174103, India; School of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Lovely Professional University, Phagwara, India. Electronic address: ganeshbushi313@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rani</LastName><ForeName>Anju</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Graphic Era (Deemed to be University), Clement Town, Dehradun, 248002, India; Graphic Era Hill University, Clement Town, Dehradun, India. Electronic address: anjurani@geu.ac.in.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sah</LastName><ForeName>Sanjit</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Dr. D. Y. Patil Medical College Hospital and Research Centre, Dr. D. Y. Patil Vidyapeeth (Deemed-to-be-University), Pimpri, Pune, 411018, Maharashtra, India; Department of Public Health Dentistry, Dr. D. Y. Patil Medical College Hospital and Research Centre, Dr. D. Y. Patil Vidyapeeth (Deemed-to-be-University), Pimpri, Pune, 411018, Maharashtra, India; Department of Medicine, Korea Universtiy, Seoul, South Korea. Electronic address: sanjitsahnepal561@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shabil</LastName><ForeName>Muhammed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Center for Research and Development, Chandigarh University, Mohali, Punjab, India; Medical Laboratories Techniques Department, AL-Mustaqbal University, 51001, Hillah, Babil, Iraq. Electronic address: mohdshabil99@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goh</LastName><ForeName>Khang Wen</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Data Science and Information Technology, INTI International University, Nilai, Malaysia; Faculty of Mathematics and Natural Sciences, Universitas Negeri Padang, Padang, Indonesia. Electronic address: khangwen.goh@newinti.edu.my.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jena</LastName><ForeName>Diptismita</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Research Impact and Outcome, Chitkara University, Rajpura, 140417, Punjab, India; Division of Research and Innovation, Uttaranchal University, Dehradun, India. Electronic address: diptismita.jena@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Diagn Microbiol Infect Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8305899</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0732-8893</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000998">Antiviral Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Organism" UI="C000628144">Oropouche orthobunyavirus</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002044" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bunyaviridae Infections</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000635" MajorTopicYN="N">transmission</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016851" MajorTopicYN="Y">Orthobunyavirus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000998" MajorTopicYN="N">Antiviral Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072138" MajorTopicYN="N">Mosquito Vectors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002519" MajorTopicYN="N">Ceratopogonidae</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000821" MajorTopicYN="N">virology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001938" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Brazil</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acridones</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hops compounds</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oropouche virus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quercetin hydrate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transmission</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40367910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2025.116882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0732-8893(25)00205-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>