<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40219298</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2073-4360</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Polymers</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Polymers (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cellulose/Sodium Polyacrylate Interpenetrating Network Hydrogel with Intrinsic Anti-Freezing Property.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">908</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/polym17070908</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Generally, small molecule alcohols and concentrated electrolyte ions can be introduced into the medium of hydrogels as anti-freezing agents to achieve significant anti-freezing properties. However, due to the exchange effect with the external environment, the anti-freezing agents may leak or change in composition causing contamination and unstable material performance during use. Here, cellulose and sodium polyacrylate (PAAS) were used to construct interpenetrating network hydrogels, with cellulose comprising up to 63% of the system. Sodium ions and carboxylic acid groups ionized from the polyacrylate network restricting the formation of water clusters through strong hydration and significantly reduced the ice crystal formation temperature. The rigid cellulose networks provided mechanical strength for the hydrogels. The new interpenetrating network hydrogels exhibited a low anti-freezing temperature (lowest at -56.12 &#xb0;C), a high water content (over 82.5 wt%), and considerable toughness (up to 2.53 MJ m<sup>-3</sup>). The intrinsic anti-freezing hydrogel constructed in this work provides a new reference strategy for expanding the practicability of anti-freezing hydrogels.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deng</LastName><ForeName>Qianyun</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-4232-728X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Biobased Materials and Energy of Ministry of Education, College of Materials and Energy, South China Agricultural University, 483 Wushan Road, Guangzhou 510642, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guangdong Provincial Key Laboratory of Plant Resources Biorefinery, School of Chemical Engineering and Light Industry, Guangdong University of Technology, Guangzhou 510006, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4239-8566</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Biobased Materials and Energy of Ministry of Education, College of Materials and Energy, South China Agricultural University, 483 Wushan Road, Guangzhou 510642, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Maoming Branch, Guangdong Laboratory for Lingnan Modern Agriculture, Maoming 525000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Polymers (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101545357</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2073-4360</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cellulose</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydrogel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intrinsic anti-freezing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sodium polyacrylate</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest to report regarding the present study.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40219298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11991314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym17070908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">polym17070908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hu L., Chee P.L., Sugiarto S., Yu Y., Shi C., Yan R., Yao Z., Shi X., Zhi J., Kai D., et al. Hydrogel-Based Flexible Electronics. Adv. Mater. 2023;35:2205326. doi: 10.1002/adma.202205326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202205326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36037508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan H., Tong M., Wang X., Huang B., Yu X., Zhang C., Wang Y. Fully Biobased High-Strength and High-Toughness Double Cross-Linked Cellulose Hydrogel for Flexible Electrolytes. ACS Sustain. Chem. Eng. 2024;12:18231&#x2013;18244. doi: 10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c07758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c07758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ru Y., Liu M. Superwetting Gels: Wetting Principles, Applications, and Challenges. ACS Nano. 2025;19:7583&#x2013;7600. doi: 10.1021/acsnano.4c17507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsnano.4c17507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39970347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Q., Tao S., Bovone G., Han G., Deshmukh D., Tibbitt M.W., Ren Q., Bertsch P., Siqueira G., Fischer P. Versatile Mechanically Tunable Hydrogels for Therapeutic Delivery Applications. Adv. Healthc. Mater. 2024;13:2304287. doi: 10.1002/adhm.202304287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adhm.202304287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38488218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Liu Y., Xie X.-M. One-Step in Situ Synthesis of Tough and Highly Conductive Ionohydrogels with Water-Retentive and Antifreezing Properties. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2023;15:30859&#x2013;30869. doi: 10.1021/acsami.3c06028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.3c06028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37307072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z.-J., Shen T.-Y., Zhang M.-H., Xiao X., Wang H.-Q., Lu Q.-R., Luo Y.-L., Jin Z., Li C.-H. Tough, Anti-Fatigue, Self-Adhesive, and Anti-Freezing Hydrogel Electrolytes for Dendrite-Free Flexible Zinc Ion Batteries and Strain Sensors. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024;34:2314864. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202314864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202314864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Zhang X., Cui Y., Liu Y., Wang W., Guo Y., Wang Q., Dong X. Ionic Liquid/Water Binary Solvent Anti-Freezing Hydrogel for Strain and Temperature Sensors. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2024;16:5208&#x2013;5216. doi: 10.1021/acsami.3c19136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.3c19136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38236660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C., Yang K., Zhu G., Ou C., Jiang J., Zhuravlev E., Zhang Y. Anti-freezing multifunctional conductive hydrogels: From structure design to flexible electronic devices. Mater. Chem. Front. 2024;8:381&#x2013;403. doi: 10.1039/D3QM00902E.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D3QM00902E</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Huang Y., Liu B., Li Z., Zhang J., Yang G., Hiralal P., Jin S., Zhou H. Flexible and anti-freezing zinc-ion batteries using a guar-gum/sodium-alginate/ethylene-glycol hydrogel electrolyte. Energy Storage Mater. 2021;41:599&#x2013;605. doi: 10.1016/j.ensm.2021.06.034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ensm.2021.06.034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu G., Guo M., Xue S., Yang X., Wang L., Zhao C., Xiang D., Li H., Lai J., Li Z., et al. Stretchable, conductive poly(acrylamide-co-maleic acid)/triethylene glycol/NaCl double-crosslinked organohydrogel with excellent antifreezing and sensing properties. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 2022;139:e52797. doi: 10.1002/app.52797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/app.52797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X.-y., Kim H.-J. Ultra-stretchable dual-network ionic hydrogel strain sensor with moistening and anti-freezing ability. Prog. Org. Coat. 2022;166:106784. doi: 10.1016/j.porgcoat.2022.106784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.porgcoat.2022.106784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong X., Zhao C., Wang Y., Luo Y., Zhang C. Antifreezing, Ionically Conductive, Transparent, and Antidrying Carboxymethyl Chitosan Self-Healing Hydrogels as Multifunctional Sensors. ACS Biomater. Sci. Eng. 2022;8:3633&#x2013;3643. doi: 10.1021/acsbiomaterials.2c00496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsbiomaterials.2c00496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35876253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao C., Gong X., Shen L., Wang Y., Zhang C. Transparent, Antifreezing, Ionic Conductive Carboxymethyl Chitosan Hydrogels as Multifunctional Sensors. ACS Appl. Polym. Mater. 2022;4:4025&#x2013;4034. doi: 10.1021/acsapm.2c00487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsapm.2c00487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chao Y., Li Y., Wang H., Wang N., Wang T., Chu Z., Yang Z., Hu Y. Facile and fast preparation of stretchable, self-adhesive, moisturizing, antifreezing and conductive tough hydrogel for wearable strain sensors. J. Mater. Chem. C. 2024;12:446&#x2013;4416. doi: 10.1039/D3TC04113A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D3TC04113A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu L., Wang Z., Zhang X.F., Yao J. Highly conductive and anti-freezing cellulose hydrogel for flexible sensors. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2023;230:123425. doi: 10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2023.123425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2023.123425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36706872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Y., Zhang L., Li X., Yan M., Wang Y., Ma J., Wang Z. Compressible, anti-freezing, and ionic conductive cellulose/polyacrylic acid composite hydrogel prepared via AlCl3/ZnCl2 aqueous system as solvent and catalyst. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2023;253:126550. doi: 10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2023.126550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2023.126550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37657569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvam S., Yim J.-H. Leakage free electrolyte engraved flexible supercapacitors from Chitosan/GO@MnCO3 polymer hydrogel chelate film under BMIMBF4 ionic liquid assistance. J. Energy Storage. 2021;43:103300. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2021.103300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2021.103300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Q., Xu P., Xu J., Hou M., Liu Q., Dai B. Preparation and Evaluation of Composite Hydrogel for Reducing the Leakage Rate of Lost Circulation. Polymers. 2023;15:4218. doi: 10.3390/polym15214218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym15214218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10647633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37959898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Z., Jing Q., Qiao S., You W. Encapsulation/capture of S-nZVI particles by PANa-PAM hydrogel limits their leakage and improves Cr(VI) removal. Process Saf. Environ. Prot. 2023;172:124&#x2013;135. doi: 10.1016/j.psep.2023.01.068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2023.01.068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y., Yang N., Chu X., Sun F., Ali M.U., Zhang Y., Yang B., Cai Y., Liu M., Gasparini N., et al. Wide-Humidity Range Applicable, Anti-Freezing, and Healable Zwitterionic Hydrogels for Ion-Leakage-Free Iontronic Sensors. Adv. Mater. 2023;35:2211617. doi: 10.1002/adma.202211617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202211617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36921620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>You C., Fan W., Xiong X., Yang H., Fu L., Wang T., Wang F., Zhu Z., He J., Wu Y. Design Strategies for Anti-Freeze Electrolytes in Aqueous Energy Storage Devices at Low Temperatures. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024;34:2403616. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202403616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202403616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D., Liu Y., Liu Y., Peng Y., Tang Y., Xiong L., Gong X., Zheng J. A General Crosslinker Strategy to Realize Intrinsic Frozen Resistance of Hydrogels. Adv. Mater. 2021;33:2104006. doi: 10.1002/adma.202104006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202104006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34476856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou L.X., Ju H., Hao X.P., Zhang H., Zhang L., He Z., Wang J., Zheng Q., Wu Z.L. Intrinsic Anti-Freezing and Unique Phosphorescence of Glassy Hydrogels with Ultrahigh Stiffness and Toughness at Low Temperatures. Adv. Mater. 2023;35:2300244. doi: 10.1002/adma.202300244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202300244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36821869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y.Z., Nakajima T., Mredha M.T.I., Guo H.L., Cui K., Zheng Y., Cui W., Kurokawa T., Gong J.P. Facile preparation of cellulose hydrogel with Achilles tendon-like super strength through aligning hierarchical fibrous structure. Chem. Eng. J. 2022;428:132040. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2021.132040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2021.132040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhand A.P., Galarraga J.H., Burdick J.A. Enhancing Biopolymer Hydrogel Functionality through Interpenetrating Networks. Trends Biotechnol. 2021;39:519&#x2013;538. doi: 10.1016/j.tibtech.2020.08.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tibtech.2020.08.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7960570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32950262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadian M., Jaymand M. Interpenetrating polymer network hydrogels for removal of synthetic dyes: A comprehensive review. Coord. Chem. Rev. 2023;486:215152. doi: 10.1016/j.ccr.2023.215152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccr.2023.215152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Li L., Zhang Z., Cheng J., Fei Y., Lu L. An all-natural strategy for versatile interpenetrating network hydrogels with self-healing, super-adhesion and high sensitivity. Chem. Eng. J. 2021;420:129736. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2021.129736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2021.129736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du M., Lu W., Zhang Y., Mata A., Fang Y. Natural polymer-sourced interpenetrating network hydrogels: Fabrication, properties, mechanism and food applications. Trends Food Sci. Technol. 2021;116:342&#x2013;356. doi: 10.1016/j.tifs.2021.07.031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tifs.2021.07.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma H., Zou Y., Zhang S., Liu L., Yu J., Fan Y. Nanochitin and poly(N-isopropylacrylamide) interpenetrating network hydrogels for temperature sensor applications. Carbohydr. Polym. 2022;291:119544. doi: 10.1016/j.carbpol.2022.119544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbpol.2022.119544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35698374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawut A., Simayi R., Zhang X., Jiang M., Zhu Z., Wu T. Preparation, properties, self crosslinking mechanism, and characterization of UV initiated polyacrylic acid superabsorbent resins. Polym. Adv. Technol. 2022;10:3666&#x2013;3680. doi: 10.1002/pat.5819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pat.5819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma X., Wen G. Development history and synthesis of super-absorbent polymers: A review. J. Polym. Res. 2020;27:136. doi: 10.1007/s10965-020-02097-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10965-020-02097-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu T., Zhu W., Sun J. Structural Modifications of Sodium Polyacrylate-Polyacrylamide to Enhance Its Water Absorption Rate. Coatings. 2022;9:1234. doi: 10.3390/coatings12091234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/coatings12091234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., Wang P., Liu S., Chen J., Chen R., He X., Ma G., Lei Z. Factors affecting the properties of superabsorbent polymer hydrogels and methods to improve their performance: A review. J. Mater. Sci. 2021;56:16223&#x2013;16242. doi: 10.1007/s10853-021-06306-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10853-021-06306-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>