<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39109129</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>CrossFit-Induced Rhabdomyolysis in a Brazilian Coach: A Case Report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e64015</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e64015</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e64015</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.64015</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>CrossFit is a high-intensity physical activity modality that, despite its numerous health benefits, poses a risk of exercise-related injuries. The rare but serious complication of exertional rhabdomyolysis is a good example. There are few case reports describing this condition, and to the best of the author's knowledge, this is the first published case of CrossFit-induced rhabdomyolysis reported in Brazil - one of the most influential countries in the world of CrossFit. Our case report describes a 45-year-old male, an experienced Level 2 CrossFit Coach, who presented with progressive upper limb pain and dark urine two days after a routine CrossFit workout. Physical examination revealed muscle stiffening and pain upon palpation. Laboratory tests showed significantly elevated creatine phosphokinase (CPK) levels (126.891 U/L) and abnormal values of lactate dehydrogenase, alanine aminotransferase, and aspartate aminotransferase. The patient was diagnosed with exercise-induced rhabdomyolysis and treated with aggressive intravenous and oral hydration, with complete clinical improvement by the fifth day of hospitalization. The patient was dismissed without any complications and with progressively decreasing levels of CPK, with ambulatorial follow-up arranged. CrossFit-induced rhabdomyolysis, although rare, represents an important health concern due to the possibility of severe systemic consequences. The present case highlights the importance of early detection and treatment of exertional rhabdomyolysis, even in well-conditioned athletes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024, Busanello Mata Alves et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Busanello Mata Alves</LastName><ForeName>Leonardo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Surgery, Federal University of Santa Catarina, Florian&#xf3;polis, BRA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campos Martins</LastName><ForeName>Eduardo</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hip Surgery, Fractures Institute, Ba&#xed;a Sul Medical Center, Florian&#xf3;polis, BRA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sartori Centenaro</LastName><ForeName>Luiz Fernando</ForeName><Initials>LF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shoulder Surgery, Fractures Institute, Ba&#xed;a Sul Medical Center, Florian&#xf3;polis, BRA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">emergency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">injuries</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rhabdomyolysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sports</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Consent was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39109129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11302391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.64015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>CrossFit(&#xae;): &#x2018;unknowable&#x2019; or predictable? - a systematic review on predictors of CrossFit(&#xae;) performance. Meier N, Schlie J, Schmidt A. Sports (Basel) 2023;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10304543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37368562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The benefits and risks of CrossFit: a systematic review. Meyer J, Morrison J, Zuniga J. Workplace Health Saf. 2017;65:612&#x2013;618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28363035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Injury rate and patterns among CrossFit athletes. Weisenthal BM, Beck CA, Maloney MD, DeHaven KE, Giordano BD. Orthop J Sports Med. 2014;2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4555591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26535325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exertional rhabdomyolysis in the athlete: a clinical review. Tietze DC, Borchers J. Sports Health. 2014;6:336&#x2013;339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4065559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24982707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exertional rhabdomyolysis after CrossFit exercise. Adhikari P, Hari A, Morel L, Bueno Y. Cureus. 2021;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7872485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33585118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CrossFit-induced rhabdomyolysis in a young healthy Indonesian male. Lawrensia S, Henrina J, Cahyadi A. Cureus. 2021;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8169014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34094722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exertional and CrossFit-induced rhabdomyolysis. Meyer M, Sundaram S, Schafhalter-Zoppoth I. Clin J Sport Med. 2018;28:92&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28727638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CrossFit-induced rhabdomyolysis: case report. Nadaf M, Lee JK, Yang JH. Arthroscopy Orthop Sports Med. 2018;5:29&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CrossFit and rhabdomyolysis: a case series of 11 patients presenting at a single academic institution. Hopkins BS, Li D, Svet M, Kesavabhotla K, Dahdaleh NS. J Sci Med Sport. 2019;22:758&#x2013;762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30846355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyond muscle destruction: a systematic review of rhabdomyolysis for clinical practice. Chavez LO, Leon M, Einav S, Varon J. Crit Care. 2016;20:135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4908773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27301374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhabdomyolysis: historical background, clinical, diagnostic and therapeutic features. Cervellin G, Comelli I, Lippi G. Clin Chem Lab Med. 2010;48:749&#x2013;756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20298139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CrossFit(&#xae;) instructor demographics and practice trends. Waryasz GR, Suric V, Daniels AH, Gil JA, Eberson CP. Orthop Rev (Pavia) 2016;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5136753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27994826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exercise-induced rhabdomyolysis mechanisms and prevention: a literature review. Kim J, Lee J, Kim S, Ryu HY, Cha KS, Sung DJ. J Sport Health Sci. 2016;5:324&#x2013;333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6188610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30356493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exertional (exercise-induced) rhabdomyolysis. Rider BC, Coughlin AM, Carlson C, Hew-Butler T. ACSMs Health Fit J. 2019;23:16&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Approach to asymptomatic creatine kinase elevation. Moghadam-Kia S, Oddis CV, Aggarwal R. Cleve Clin J Med. 2016;83:37&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4871266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26760521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The association between rhabdomyolysis, acute kidney injury, renal replacement therapy, and mortality. Nielsen FE, Cordtz JJ, Rasmussen TB, Christiansen CF. Clin Epidemiol. 2020;12:989&#x2013;995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7522418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33061646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>