<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39597417</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>22</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Role and Mechanism of Rice Husk Ash Particle Characteristics in Cement Hydration Process.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5594</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma17225594</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Reactive rice husk ash (RHA) is used as a supplementary cementitious material (SCM) to prepare cement composite pastes. The impact of RHA content and the internal curing effect on the hydration process of the cementitious system was studied. The hydration heat, degree, and product content of the cement-RHA composite system at 3, 7, and 28 d were analyzed using hydration microcalorimetry, thermogravimetry, and XRD (Rietveld) analysis. The results show that with the increase in RHA, the main exothermic peaks move forward, and the values increase. The induction period is prolonged, and the acceleration period is shortened. The induction period of 15% RHA is extended to 3 h. The hydration heat of cement composite pastes is mainly divided into three stages. Namely, the first stage (0-18 h) is the superposition of the RHA nucleation effect and chemical effect, the second stage (18-51 h) is the superposition of the dilution effect and internal curing effect, and the third stage (51-72 h) is the internal curing effect with the water-release. The internal curing effect of RHA has a certain periodicity, which is related to its content. The water-release age in the early stage (24 h) advances with the increase of content, and the water-release effect in the later stage (7-28 d) is also significant with the increase of content. The higher the content, the more significant the promotion of the internal curing effect on cement hydration and the pozzolanic reaction of RHA.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jialei</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Architecture, NingboTech University, Ningbo 315100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Mechanics &amp; Civil Engineering, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou 221116, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoqing</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Chongqing Institute of Engineering, Chongqing 400056, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Feifei</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6492-952X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Nantong Institute of Technology, Nantong 226000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Haoyu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Architecture, NingboTech University, Ningbo 315100, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>KJQN202301910</GrantID><Agency>Chongqing Municipal Education Commission Science and Technology Research Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>SNG2022015</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Plan Project of Suzhou</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydration heat</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">internal curing effect</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rice husk ash</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">water-release</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of any commercial or associative interest in connection with the work submitted.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39597417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11595526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17225594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma17225594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Li B. Research Progress on Application of Rice Husk Ash in Cement and Concrete. Mater. Rep. 2020;34:9003&#x2013;9011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes I.J., Moraes C.A., Egea J.R., Sousa V.C. Production and characterization of silica materials from rice husk ash by different combustion processes. Powder Technol. 2024;436:119743. doi: 10.1016/j.powtec.2024.119473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.powtec.2024.119473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen P. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Harbin Institute of Technology; Harbin, China: 2014. Effect of Pretreatment on Properties of Rice Husk Ash.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu L., Wu K., Wang P., Ludwig H.M. Influence of rice husk ash on early hydration of calcium aluminate cement. J. Chin. Ceram. Soc. 2016;44:1098&#x2013;1103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pu B.-C., Liu B., Li L., Jiang L., Zhou J., Ding P. Using rice husk ash in alkali-activated ultra-high-performance concrete: Flowability, early age strength and elasticity modulus. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;443:137771. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zareei S.A., Ameri F., Dorostkar F., Ahmadi M. Rice husk ash as a partial replacement of cement in high strength concrete containing micro silica: Evaluating durability and mechanical properties. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2017;7:73&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2017.05.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2017.05.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su Q., Xu J.M. Mechanical properties of rice husk ash and glass powder concrete: Experimental and mesoscopic studies. J. Build. Eng. 2024;95:110278. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.110278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.110278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin M.N., Khan K., Arab A.M.A., Farooq F., Eldin S.M., Javed M.F. Prediction of sustainable concrete utilizing rice husk ash (RHA) as supplementary cementitious material (SCM): Optimization and hyper-tuning. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2023;25:1495&#x2013;1536. doi: 10.1016/j.jmrt.2023.06.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2023.06.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo F.C., Lee M.G., Lo S.L. Effect of coal ash and rice husk ash partial replacement in ordinary Portland cement on pervious concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;286:122947. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasara-A J., Gheewala S.H. Sustainable utilization of rice husk ash from power plants: A review. J. Clean. Prod. 2017;167:1020&#x2013;1028. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2016.11.042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2016.11.042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas B.S. Green concrete partially comprised of rice husk ash as a supplementary cementitious material&#x2013;A comprehensive review. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2018;82:3913&#x2013;3923. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2017.10.081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2017.10.081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christopher F., Bolatito A., Ahmed S. Structure and properties of mortar and concrete with rice husk ash as partial replacement of ordinary Portland cement&#x2014;A review. Int. J. Sustain. Built Environ. 2017;6:675&#x2013;692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bui D.D. Ph.D. Thesis. Delft University of Technology; Delft, The Netherlands: 2001. Rice Husk Ash as a Mineral Admixture for High Performance Concrete.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park K.B., Kwon S.J., Wang X.Y. Analysis of the effects of rice husk ash on the hydration of cementitious materials. Constr. Build. Mater. 2016;105:196&#x2013;205. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.12.086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.12.086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazari A., Toufigh V. Effects of elevated temperatures and re-curing on concrete containing rice husk ash. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;439:137277. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xea;go J.H.S., Nepomuceno A.A., Figueiredo E.P., Hasparyk N.P., Borges L.D. Effect of particle size of residual rice-husk ash in consumption of Ca(OH)2. J. Mater. Civ. Eng. 2015;27:04014178. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0001136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0001136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang S.H., Hong S.G., Moon J. The use of rice husk ash as reactive filler in ultra-high performance concrete. Cem. Concr. Res. 2019;115:389&#x2013;400. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2018.09.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2018.09.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Q., Yamamichi H., Shoya M., Sugita S. Study on the pozzolanic properties of rice husk ash by hydrochloric acid pretreatment. Cem. Concr. Res. 2004;34:521&#x2013;526. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2003.09.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2003.09.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen V.T. Ph.D. Thesis. Delft University of Technology; Delft, The Netherlands: 2011. Rice Husk Ash as a Mineral Admixture for Ultra-High Performance Concrete.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuan N.V., Ye G., Breugel K.V. Hydration and microstructure of ultra high performance concrete incorporating rice husk ash. Cem. Concr. Res. 2011;41:1104&#x2013;1111. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2011.06.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2011.06.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu S. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Shenyang University of Chemical Technology; Shenyang, China: 2019. Effects of Pretreatment and Calcination Conditions of Rice Husk on the Activity of Rice Husk Ash.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Breugel K., Van Tuan N. Ultra high performance concrete made with rice husk ash for reduced autogenous Shrinkage; Proceedings of the 4th International FIB Congress: Improving Performance of Concrete Structures; Mumbai, India. 10&#x2013;14 February 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scrivener K., Snellings R., Lothenbach B. A Practical Guide to Microstructureal Analysis of Cementitious Materials. CRC Press; Boca Raton, FL, USA: 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;&#xdf;ler C., Bui D.D., Ludwig H.M. Rice husk ash as both pozzolanic admixture and internal curing agent in ultra-high performance concrete. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2014;53:270&#x2013;278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lux&#xe1;n M.P., Madruga F., Saavedra J. Rapid evaluation of pozzolanic activity of natural products by conductivity measurement. Cem. Concr. Res. 1989;19:63&#x2013;68. doi: 10.1016/0008-8846(89)90066-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0008-8846(89)90066-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Xiao J., Zhang Z., Han K., Hu X., Jiang F. Action mechanism of rice husk ash and the effect on main performances of cement-based materials: A review. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;288:123068. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frugier P., Gin S., Minet Y. SON68 nuclear glass dissolution kinetics: Current state of knowledge and basis of the new GRAAL model. J. Nucl. Mater. 2008;380:8&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1016/j.jnucmat.2008.06.044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnucmat.2008.06.044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sj&#xf6;berg S. Silica in aqueous environments. J. Non-Cryst. Solids. 1996;196:51&#x2013;57. doi: 10.1016/0022-3093(95)00562-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0022-3093(95)00562-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maraghechi H., Rajabipour F., Pantano C.G., Burgos W.D. Effect of calciumon dissolution and precipitation reactions of amorphous silica at high alkalinity. Cem. Concr. Res. 2016;87:1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2016.05.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2016.05.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fertani-Gmati M., Jemal M. Thermochemistry and kinetics of silica dissolution in NaOH aqueous solution. Thermochim. Acta. 2011;513:43&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1016/j.tca.2010.11.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tca.2010.11.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;&#xdf;ler C., Bui D.D., Ludwig H.M. Mesoporous structure and pozzolanic reactivity of rice husk ash in cementitious system. Constr. Build. Mater. 2013;43:208&#x2013;216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habeeb G.A., Mahmud H.B. Study on properties of rice husk ash and its use as cement replacement material. Mater. Res. 2010;13:185&#x2013;190. doi: 10.1590/S1516-14392010000200011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1516-14392010000200011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchon D., Juilland P., Gallucci E., Frunz L., Flatt R.J. Molecular and submolecular scale effects of comb-copolymers on tri-calcium silicate reactivity: Toward molecular design. J. Am. Ceram. Soc. 2017;100:817&#x2013;841. doi: 10.1111/jace.14695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jace.14695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zunino F., Scrivener K.L. The influence of the filler effect on the sulfate requirement of blended cements. Cem. Concr. Res. 2019;126:105918. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105918.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazzoni A. Study of Early Hydration Mechanisms of Cement by Means of Electron Microscopy. ACM; New York, NY, USA: 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juilland P., Nicoleau L., Arvidson R.S., Gallucci E. Advances in dissolution understanding and their implications for cement hydration. RILEM Tech. Lett. 2017;2:90. doi: 10.21809/rilemtechlett.2017.47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21809/rilemtechlett.2017.47</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sensale G.R., Ribeiro A.B., Goncalves A. Effects of RHA on autogenous shrinkage of Portland cement pastes. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2008;30:892&#x2013;897. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2008.06.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2008.06.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deschner F., Lothenbach B., Winnefeld F., Neubauer J. Effect of temperature on the hydration of Portland cement blended with siliceous fly ash. Cem. Concr. Res. 2013;52:169&#x2013;181. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2013.07.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2013.07.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durdzinski P.T. Hydration of multi-component cements containing cement clinker, slag, calcareous fly ash and limestone. Water Resour. Res. 2016;29:3867&#x2013;3878.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scrivener K.L., Juilland P., Monteiro P.J. Advances in understanding hydration of Portland cement. Cem. Concr. Res. 2015;78:38&#x2013;56. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2015.05.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2015.05.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lura P., Jensen O.M., Breugel K.V. Autogenous shrinkage in high-performance cement paste: An evaluation of basic mechanisms. Cem. Concr. Res. 2003;33:223&#x2013;232. doi: 10.1016/S0008-8846(02)00890-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0008-8846(02)00890-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>