<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37880684</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2661-801X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC chemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Chem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>[1, 8]-Naphthyridine derivatives as dual inhibitor of alkaline phosphatase and carbonic anhydrase.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>142</StartPage><MedlinePgn>142</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">142</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13065-023-01052-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>[1,8]-Naphthyridine derivatives have been reported to possess important biological activities and may serve as attractive pharmacophores in the drug discovery process. [1,8]-Naphthyridine derivatives (1a-1l) were evaluated for inhibitory potential for isozymes of carbonic anhydrase (CA) and alkaline phosphatase (ALP). CAs have been reported to carry out reversible hydration of CO<sub>2</sub> into HCO<sub>3</sub><sup>-</sup>, secretion of electrolytes, acid-base regulation, bone resorption, calcification, and biosynthetic reactions. Whereas ALPs hydrolyze monophosphate esters with the release of inorganic phosphate and play an important role in bone mineralization. Both enzymes have been found to be over-expressed and raised functional activities in patients suffering from rheumatoid arthritis. The discovery of dual inhibitors of these enzymes may provide a synergistic effect to cure bone disorders such as rheumatoid arthritis and ankylosing spondylitis. Among the test compounds, the most potent inhibitors for CA-II, CA-IX, and CA-XII were 1e, 1g, and 1a with IC<sub>50</sub> values of 0.44&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.19, 0.11&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.03 and 0.32&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.07&#xa0;&#xb5;M, respectively. [1,8]-Naphthyridine derivatives (1a-1l) were approximately 4 folds more potent than standard CA inhibitor acetazolamide. While in the case of ALPs, the most potent compounds for b-TNAP and c-IAP were 1b and 1e with IC<sub>50</sub> values of 0.122&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.06 and 0.107&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.02&#xa0;&#xb5;M, respectively. Thus, synthesized derivatives proved to be 100 to 800 times more potent as compared to standard inhibitors of b-TNAP and c-IAP (Levamisole and L-phenyl alanine, respectively). In addition, selectivity and dual inhibition of [1,8]-Naphthyridine derivatives confer precedence over known inhibitors. Molecular docking and molecular simulation studies were also conducted in the present studies to define the type of interactions between potential inhibitors and enzyme active sites.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alrokayan</LastName><ForeName>Salman</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Chair for Biomedical Application of Nanomaterials, Biochemistry Department, College of Science, King Saud University, 11451, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biochemistry Department, College of Science, King Saud University, 11451, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hussain</LastName><ForeName>Tajamul</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Chair for Biomedical Application of Nanomaterials, Biochemistry Department, College of Science, King Saud University, 11451, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre of Excellence in Biotechnology Research, King Saud University, 11451, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alamery</LastName><ForeName>Salman</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biochemistry Department, College of Science, King Saud University, 11451, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohammed</LastName><ForeName>Arif Ahmed</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biochemistry Department, College of Science, King Saud University, 11451, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahmood</LastName><ForeName>Abid</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Advanced Drug Research, COMSATS University Islamabad, Abbottabad Campus, Abbottabad, 22060, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ejaz</LastName><ForeName>Syeda Abida</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Chemistry, Faculty of Pharmacv, The Islamia University of Bahawalpur, Bahawalpur, 63100, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Langer</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut F&#xfc;r Chemie, Universit&#xe4;t Rostock, A.-Einstein-Str. 3a, 18059, Rostock, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iqbal</LastName><ForeName>Jamshed</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Advanced Drug Research, COMSATS University Islamabad, Abbottabad Campus, Abbottabad, 22060, Pakistan. drjamshed@cuiatd.edu.pk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>IFKSURC-1-3703</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Education - Kingdom of Saudi Arabi</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Chem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101741142</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2661-801X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alkaline phosphatase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Carbonic anhydrase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DFT studies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Simulation studies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">[1, 8]-Naphthyridine derivatives</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There is not any financial or personal competing interest among authors.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37880684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10599030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13065-023-01052-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13065-023-01052-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Supuran CT. Carbonic anhydrases: novel therapeutic applications for inhibitors and activators. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2008;7(2):168&#x2013;181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18167490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pastorek J, Pastorekov&#xe1; S, Callebaut I, Mornon JP, Zeln&#xed;k V, Opavsk&#xfd; R, Zat'ovicov&#xe1; M, Liao S, Portetelle D, Stanbridge EJ. Cloning and characterization of MN, a human tumor-associated protein with a domain homologous to carbonic anhydrase and a putative helix-loop-helix DNA binding segment. Oncogene. 1994;9(10):2877&#x2013;2888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8084592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wykoff CC, Beasley NJ, Watson PH, Turner KJ, Pastorek J, Sibtain A, Wilson GD, Turley H, Talks KL, Maxwell PH, Pugh CW. Hypoxia-inducible expression of tumor-associated carbonic anhydrases. Cancer Res. 2000;60(24):7075&#x2013;7083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11156414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yegutkin GG. Nucleotide-and nucleoside-converting ectoenzymes important modulators of purinergic signalling cascade. Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Cell Res. 2008;1783(5):673&#x2013;694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18302942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahl R, Sergienko EA, Su Y, Mostofi YS, Yang L, Simao AM, Narisawa S, Brown B, Mangravita-Novo A, Vicchiarelli M. Discovery and validation of a series of aryl sulfonamides as selective inhibitors of tissue-nonspecific alkaline phosphatase (TNAP) J Med Chem. 2009;52(21):6919&#x2013;6925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2783186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19821572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mill&#xe1;n JL. Alkaline phosphatases: structure, substrate specificity and functional relatedness to other members of a large superfamily of enzymes. Purinergic Signal. 2006;2:335&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2254479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18404473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lansley SM, Searles RG, Hoi A, Thomas C, Moneta H, Herrick SE, Thompson PJ, Mark N, Sterrett GF, Pr&#xea;le CM. Mesothelial cell differentiation into osteoblast-and adipocyte-like cells. J Cell Mol Med. 2011;15(10):2095&#x2013;2105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4394220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21070599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henthorn PS, Whyte MP. Missense mutations of the tissue-nonspecific alkaline phosphatase gene in hypophosphatasia. Clin Chem. 1992;38(12):2501&#x2013;2505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1360878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vimalraj S. Alkaline phosphatase: structure, expression and its function in bone mineralization. Gene. 2020;754:144855.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32522695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Rashida M, Ejaz SA, Ali S, Shaukat A, Hamayoun M, Ahmed M, Iqbal J. Diarylsulfonamides and their bioisosteres as dual inhibitors of alkaline phosphatase and carbonic anhydrase: structure activity relationship and molecular modelling studies. Bioorg Med Chem. 2015;23(10):2435&#x2013;2444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25865133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes CW, Conway WF. Calcium hydroxyapatite deposition disease. Radiographics. 1990;10(6):1031&#x2013;1048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2175444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali AT, Penny CB, Paiker JE, van Niekerk C, Smit A, Ferris WF, Crowther NJ. Alkaline phosphatase is involved in the control of adipogenesis in the murine preadipocyte cell line, 3T3-L1. Clin Chim Acta. 2005;354(1&#x2013;2):101&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15748605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lall&#xe8;s J-P. Intestinal alkaline phosphatase: novel functions and protective effects. Nutr Rev. 2014;72(2):82&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24506153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizumori M, Ham M, Guth PH, Engel E, Kaunitz JD, Akiba Y. Intestinal alkaline phosphatase regulates protective surface microclimate pH in rat duodenum. J Physiol. 2009;587(14):3651&#x2013;3663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2742288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19451200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller WE, Schr&#xf6;der HC, Wang X. The understanding of the metazoan skeletal system, based on the initial discoveries with siliceous and calcareous sponges. Mar Drugs. 2017;15(6):172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5484122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28604622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bua S, Di Cesare Mannelli L, Vullo D, Ghelardini C, Bartolucci G, Scozzafava A, Supuran CT, Carta F. Design and synthesis of novel nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs and carbonic anhydrase inhibitors hybrids (NSAIDs&#x2013;CAIs) for the treatment of rheumatoid arthritis. J Med Chem. 2017;60(3):1159&#x2013;1170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28075587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demir Y, Demir N, Yildirim S, Nadaro&#x11f;lu H, Karaosmano&#x11f;lu M, Bakan E. The activities of carbonic anhydrase and alkaline phosphatase in ancient human bones. Purification and characterization of outer peripheral, cytosolic, inner peripheral, and integral CA. Prep Biochem Biotechnol. 2001;31(3):291&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11513093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanke Y, Kotake S, Akama H, Kamatani N. Alkaline phosphatase in rheumatoid arthritis patients: possible contribution of bone-type ALP to the raised activities of ALP in rheumatoid arthritis patients. Clin Rheumatol. 2002;21:198&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12111623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akgul O, Di Cesare Mannelli L, Vullo D, Angeli A, Ghelardini C, Bartolucci G, Alfawaz Altamimi AS, Scozzafava A, Supuran CT, Carta F. Discovery of novel nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs and carbonic anhydrase inhibitors hybrids (NSAIDs&#x2013;CAIs) for the management of rheumatoid arthritis. J Med Chem. 2018;61(11):4961&#x2013;4977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29746127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rindfleisch AJ, Muller D. Diagnosis and management of rheumatoid arthritis. Am Fam Phys. 2005;72(6):1037&#x2013;1047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16190501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller WE, Tolba E, Schr&#xf6;der HC, Neufurth M, Wang S, Link T, Al-Nawas B, Wang X. A new printable and durable N, O-carboxymethyl chitosan&#x2013;Ca 2+&#x2013;polyphosphate complex with morphogenetic activity. J Mater Chem B. 2015;3(8):1722&#x2013;1730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32262445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price GH. Inhibition of alkaline phosphatase by several diuretics. Clin Chim Acta. 1980;101(2&#x2013;3):313&#x2013;319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7357751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madaan A, Verma R, Kumar V, Singh AT, Jain SK, Jaggi M. 1, 8-naphthyridine derivatives: a review of multiple biological activities. Arch Pharm. 2015;348(12):837&#x2013;860.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26548568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Madaan A, Sanna VK, Vishnoi M, Joshi N, Singh AT, Jaggi M, Sharma PK, Irchhaiya R, Burman AC. Anticancer and immunomodulatory activities of novel 1, 8-naphthyridine derivatives. J Enzyme Inhib Med Chem. 2009;24(5):1169&#x2013;1178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19555167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava SK, Jha A, Agarwal SK, Mukherjee R, Burman AC. Synthesis and structure-activity relationships of potent antitumor active quinoline and naphthyridine derivatives. Anticancer Agents Med Chem. 2007;7(6):685&#x2013;709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18045063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesher GY, Froelich EJ, Gruett MD, Bailey JH, Brundage RP. 1, 8-Naphthyridine derivatives. A new class of chemotherapeutic agents. J Med Chem. 1962;5(5):1063&#x2013;1065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14056431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Yan J, Yan J, Xu H, Zhang D, Wang X, Sheng J. Expression and purification of the human epidermal growth factor receptor extracellular domain. Protein Expr Purif. 2018;144:33&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29217201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flader A, Parpart S, Ehlers P, Langer P. Synthesis of pyrrolo [1, 2-a] naphthyridines by Lewis acid mediated cycloisomerization. Org Biomol Chem. 2017;15(15):3216&#x2013;3231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28322406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaraei S-O, El-Gamal MI, Shafique Z, Amjad ST, Afridi S, Zaib S, Anbar HS, El-Gamal R, Iqbal J. Sulfonate and sulfamate derivatives possessing benzofuran or benzothiophene nucleus as potent carbonic anhydrase II/IX/XII inhibitors. Bioorg Med Chem. 2019;27(17):3889&#x2013;3901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31345748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaib S, Saeed A, Stolte K, Fl&#xf6;rke U, Shahid M, Iqbal J. New aminobenzenesulfonamide&#x2013;thiourea conjugates: synthesis and carbonic anhydrase inhibition and docking studies. Eur J Med Chem. 2014;78:140&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24681391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal J. An enzyme immobilized microassay in capillary electrophoresis for characterization and inhibition studies of alkaline phosphatases. Anal Biochem. 2011;414(2):226&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21439261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frisch ME, Trucks G, Schlegel H, Scuseria G, Robb M, Cheeseman J, Scalmani G, Barone V, Mennucci B. Petersson G. Gaussian, Inc., Wallingford CT. Gaussian 09 (Revision A. 02). 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goerigk L, Reimers JR. Efficient methods for the quantum chemical treatment of protein structures: the effects of London-dispersion and basis-set incompleteness on peptide and water-cluster geometries. J Chem Theory Comput. 2013;9(7):3240&#x2013;3251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26583999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennington R, Keith TA, Millam JM. GaussView 6.0. 16. Shawnee Mission: Semichem Inc.; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ChemicalComputingGroup . Molecular operating environment. Quebec: Chemical Computing Group Montreal; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeadIT, B. http://www.biosolveit.de/LeadIT. Accessed 12 Mar 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biovia, D. S. Discovery studio modeling environment. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowers KJ, Chow E, Xu H, Dror RO, Eastwood MP, Gregersen BA, Klepeis JL, Kolossvary I, Moraes MA, Sacerdoti FD, Salmon JK. Scalable algorithms for molecular dynamics simulations on commodity clusters. In: Proceedings of the 2006 ACM/IEEE conference on supercomputing. 2006. pp. 84-es.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira LG, Dos Santos RN, Oliva G, Andricopulo AD. Molecular docking and structure-based drug design strategies. Molecules. 2015;20(7):13384&#x2013;13421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6332083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26205061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hildebrand PW, Rose AS, Tiemann JK. Bringing molecular dynamics simulation data into view. Trends Biochem Sci. 2019;44(11):902&#x2013;913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31301982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rassolov VA, Pople JA, Ratner MA, Windus TL. 6&#x2013;31G* basis set for atoms K through Zn. J Chem Phys. 1998;109(4):1223&#x2013;1229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camiletti G, Machado S, Jorge F. Gaussian basis set of double zeta quality for atoms K through Kr: application in DFT calculations of molecular properties. J Comput Chem. 2008;29(14):2434&#x2013;2444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18612996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhuo LG, Liao W, Yu ZX. A frontier molecular orbital theory approach to understanding the Mayr equation and to quantifying nucleophilicity and electrophilicity by using HOMO and LUMO energies. Asian J Org Chem. 2012;1(4):336&#x2013;345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukui K. Role of frontier orbitals in chemical reactions. Science. 1982;218(4574):747&#x2013;754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17771019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demircio&#x11f;lu Z, Ka&#x15f;ta&#x15f; &#xc7;A, B&#xfc;y&#xfc;kg&#xfc;ng&#xf6;r O. Theoretical analysis (NBO, NPA, Mulliken Population Method) and molecular orbital studies (hardness, chemical potential, electrophilicity and Fukui function analysis) of (E)-2-((4-hydroxy-2-methylphenylimino) methyl)-3-methoxyphenol. J Mol Struct. 2015;1091:183&#x2013;195.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>