<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39873125</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1941-2452</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nutrition in clinical practice : official publication of the American Society for Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nutr Clin Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>How to educate patients and caregivers on end-of-life nutrition care and support.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>288</StartPage><EndPage>306</EndPage><MedlinePgn>288-306</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ncp.11272</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">There are numerous articles, book chapters, and published guidelines on the topic of clinical ethics in the use of artificially administered nutrition and hydration, which often incorporates end-of-life (EOL) nutrition care and support. Components of clinical ethics involve the importance of ethical principles, patient-centered care, and shared decision-making. However, there is sparse information on how to educate patients and caregivers on this subject.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Initially, PubMed and the Cochrane Library were used to find articles on the subject. Articles were reviewed and new concepts were identified to include.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">There is a practice gap with not applying clinical ethics in practice. The application of clinical ethics, which includes the teach-back method of education, soft skills and behavioral skills training, and potential sacred moments, is not well addressed in the literature. Demonstration of the process of incorporating clinical ethics into practice is beneficial in helping educate clinicians so they can then effectively educate the patient and caregiver on EOL nutrition care and support. Reasons for not applying clinical ethics in actual clinical practice may be because of clinicians not receiving training, the lack of opportunity to observe the technique applied in actual clinical practice, or possibly concern for the presumed additional time required in clinical practice to apply clinical ethics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Educating patients and caregivers on EOL nutrition care and support presupposes engaging, educating, and empowering clinicians about clinical ethics by demonstrating the process and encouraging educators to incorporate the information in an interdisciplinary/interprofessional curriculum.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 American Society for Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schwartz</LastName><ForeName>Denise Baird</ForeName><Initials>DB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9895-9073</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Providence Saint Joseph Medical Center, Burbank, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wolfe Citty</LastName><ForeName>Sandra</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4769-7760</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barrocas</LastName><ForeName>Albert</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8506-7244</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tulane University School of Medicine, New Orleans, Louisiana, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Sullivan-Maillet</LastName><ForeName>Julie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Professions, Rutgers University, Newark, New Jersey, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Nutr Clin Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8606733</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0884-5336</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013727" MajorTopicYN="Y">Terminal Care</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000941" MajorTopicYN="N">ethics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017028" MajorTopicYN="Y">Caregivers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000193" MajorTopicYN="N">education</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010353" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patient Education as Topic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018529" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nutritional Support</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000941" MajorTopicYN="N">ethics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D026690" MajorTopicYN="N">Ethics, Clinical</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000193" MajorTopicYN="N">education</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D044623" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nutrition Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical ethics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">communication skills</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">end&#x2010;of&#x2010;life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutrition support</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient&#x2010;centered care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">shared decision making</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39873125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ncp.11272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Shen MJ, Manna R, Banerjee SC, et al. Incorporating shared decision making into communication with older adults with cancer and their caregivers: development and evaluation of a geriatric shared decision&#x2010;making communication skills training module. Patient Educ Couns. 2020;103(11):2328&#x2010;2334. doi:10.1016/j.pec.2020.04.032</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Druml C, Ballmer PE, Druml W, et al. ESPEN guideline on ethical aspects of artificial nutrition and hydration. Clin Nutr. 2016;35(3):545&#x2010;556. doi:10.1016/j.clnu.2016.02.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz DB, Armanios N, Monturo C, et al. Clinical ethics and nutrition support practice: implications for practice change and curriculum development. J Acad Nutr Diet. 2016;116(11):1738&#x2010;1746. doi:10.1016/j.jand.2016.01.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cotogni P, Stragliotto S, Ossola M, Collo A, Riso S. The role of nutritional support for cancer patients in palliative care. Nutrients. 2021;13(2):306. doi:10.3390/nu13020306</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz DB, Barrocas A, Annetta MG, et al. Ethical aspects of artificially administered nutrition and hydration: an ASPEN position paper. Nutr Clin Pract. 2021;36(2):254&#x2010;267. doi:10.1002/ncp.10633</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#xe1;rdenas D, Toulson Davisson Correia MI, Hardy G, et al. Nutritional care is a human right: translating principles to clinical practice. Clin Nutr. 2022;41(7):1613&#x2010;1618. doi:10.1016/j.clnu.2022.03.021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cogle SV, Hallum M, Mulherin DW. Applying the 2022 ASPEN adult nutrition support guidelines in a 2024 ICU. Nutr Clin Pract. 2024;39(5):1055&#x2010;1068. doi:10.1002/ncp.11188</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz DB, Barrocas A. Chapter 22. Ethical and legal foundations in nutrition practice application. In: Chan LN, ed. The ASPEN Adult Nutrition Support Core Curriculum. 4th ed. ASPEN; 2025, in press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podgorica N, Flatscher&#x2010;Th&#xf6;ni M, Deufert D, Siebert U, Ganner M. A systematic review of ethical and legal issues in elder care. Nurs Ethics. 2021;28(6):895&#x2010;910. doi:10.1177/0969733020921488</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavalley SA. Caregiver informational support in different patient care settings at end of life. Home Health Care Serv Q. 2018;37(2):97&#x2010;112. doi:10.1080/01621424.2018.1438951</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Principlism. ScienceDirect. Accessed August 2, 2024. https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/psychology/principlism</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>POLST Form. National POLST. Accessed October 28, 2024. https://polst.org/form-patients/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz DB, Sumner S, Cardenas D, et al. ASPEN international survey on ethical competencies dealing with decision making in the use of artificially administered nutrition and hydration and competency application in clinical practice. Nutr Clin Pract. 2024;39(6):1475&#x2010;1482. doi:10.1002/ncp.11213</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ethical dilemmas in communications across the age spectrum: a theatrical presentation (2/15/15). ASPEN. April 5, 2021. Accessed December 16, 2024. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dtlZ-mG0Asg</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sancho&#x2010;Cantus D, Cubero&#x2010;Plazas L, Botella Navas M, Castellano&#x2010;Rioja E, Ca&#xf1;abate Ros M. Importance of soft skills in health sciences students and their repercussion after the COVID&#x2010;19 epidemic: scoping review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20(6):4901. doi:10.3390/ijerph20064901</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen W. Medical ethics issues in dementia and end of life. Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2020;22(6):31. doi:10.1007/s11920-020-01150-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malone AM, Seres AD, Lord LM. Chapter 13. Complications of enteral nutrition. In: Mueller CM, ed. The ASPEN Adult Nutrition Support Core Curriculum. 3rd ed. ASPEN; 2017:265&#x2010;296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumpf VJ, Gervasio J. Chapter 17. Complications of parenteral nutrition. In: Mueller CM, ed. The ASPEN Adult Nutrition Support Core Curriculum. 3rd ed. ASPEN; 2017:345&#x2010;360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe4;ngle S, Schnepp W, Fringer A. The need to distinguish between different forms of oral nutrition refusal and different forms of voluntary stopping of eating and drinking. Palliat Care Soc Pract. 2019;13:1178224219875738. doi:10.1177/1178224219875738</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Looper DL. End&#x2010;of&#x2010;life eating habits: why it's OK for your loved one to stop eating and drinking on hospice. Crossroads Hospice &amp; Palliative Care. May 8, 2024. Accessed October 21, 2024. https://www.crossroadshospice.com/hospice-palliative-care-blog/2014/july/20/why-it-s-ok-for-your-loved-one-to-have-no-food-or-water-on-hospice/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>What to do when a hospice patient stops eating or drinking. VITAS Healthcare. Accessed October 19, 2024. https://www.vitas.com/family-and-caregiver-support/what-to-expect-from-hospice/when-a-hospice-patient-stops-eating-or-drinking#:~:text=Near%20the%20end%20of%20life,in%20ways%20other%20than%20meals</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark J, Raijmakers NJH, Allan S, van Zuylen L, van der Heide A. Declining oral intake towards the end of life: how to talk about it? A qualitative study. Int J Palliat Nurs. 2017;23(2):74&#x2010;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritter S, Stirnemann J, Breckwoldt J, et al. Shared decision&#x2010;making training in internal medicine: a multisite intervention study. J Grad Med Educ. 2019;11(4 suppl):146&#x2010;151. doi:10.4300/JGME-D-18-00849</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samerski S. Health literacy as a social practice: social and empirical dimensions of knowledge on health and healthcare. Soc Sci Med. 2019;226:1&#x2010;8. doi:10.1016/j.socscimed.2019.02.024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeffrey D. Empathy, sympathy and compassion in healthcare: is there a problem? Is there a difference? Does it matter? J R Soc Med. 2016;109(12):446&#x2010;452. doi:10.1177/0141076816680120</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Graaff E, Bennett C, Dart J. Empathy in nutrition and dietetics: a scoping review. J Acad Nutr Diet. 2024;124(9):1181&#x2010;1205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight A, Palermo C, Reedy G, Whelan K. Communication skills: a scoping review of experiences, perceptions, and use in dietetics practice. J Acad Nutr Diet. 2024;124(9):1162&#x2010;1180.e1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arman M. Empathy, sympathy, and altruism&#x2014;an evident triad based on compassion. A theoretical model for caring. Scand J Caring Sci. 2023;37(3):862&#x2010;871. doi:10.1111/scs.13163</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firn J, Rui C, Vercler C, DeVries R, Shuman A. Identification of core ethical topics for interprofessional education in the intensive care unit: a thematic analysis. J Interprof Care. 2020;34(4):453&#x2010;460. doi:10.1080/13561820.2019.1632814</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shersher V, Haines TP, Sturgiss L, Weller C, Williams C. Definitions and use of the teach&#x2010;back method in healthcare consultations with patients: a systematic review and thematic synthesis. Patient Educ Couns. 2021;104(1):118&#x2010;129. doi:10.1016/j.pec.2020.07.026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noordman J, van Vliet L, Kaunang M, van den Muijsenbergh M, Boland G, van Dulmen S. Towards appropriate information provision for and decision&#x2010;making with patients with limited health literacy in hospital&#x2010;based palliative care in Western countries: a scoping review into available communication strategies and tools for healthcare providers. BMC Palliat Care. 2019;18(1):37. doi:10.1186/s12904-019-0421-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn M, Fowler KE, Harrod M, et al. Exploring sacred moments in hospitalized patients: an exploratory qualitative study. J Gen Intern Med. 2023;38(9):2038&#x2010;2044. doi:10.1007/s11606-022-07999-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz DB. Integrating patient&#x2010;centered care and clinical ethics into nutrition practice. Nutr Clin Pract. 2013;28(5):543&#x2010;555. doi:10.1177/0884533613500507</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Childers JW, Bulls H, Arnold R. Beyond the NURSE acronym: the functions of empathy in serious illness conversations. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2023;65(4):e375&#x2010;e379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dudrick SJ, Wilmore DW, Vars HM, Rhoads JE. Long&#x2010;term total parenteral nutrition with growth, development, and positive nitrogen balance. Surgery. 1968;64(1):134&#x2010;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;bler&#x2010;Ross E. On Death and Dying. Routledge; 1969.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beauchamp TL, Childress JF. Principles of Biomedical Ethics. Oxford University Press; 1979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagai H, Nakazawa E, Akabayashi A. The creation of the Belmont Report and its effect on ethical principles: a historical study. Monash Bioeth Rev. 2022;40(2):157&#x2010;170. doi:10.1007/s40592-022-00165-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghooi R. The Nuremberg Code&#x2014;a critique. Perspect Clin Res. 2011;2(2):72&#x2010;76. doi:10.4103/2229-3485.80371</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute of Justice. The &#x201c;Common Rule.&#x201d; Published November 19, 2007. Accessed August 24, 2024. https://nij.ojp.gov/funding/common-rule</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FranklinCovey. The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People&#xae; Habit 5: seek first to understand, then to be understood. Accessed August 1, 2024. https://www.franklincovey.com/the-7-habits/habit-5/</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>