<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41490446</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A comprehensive risk assessment method for Christmas tree combined with a multi source information fusion algorithm and an improved HAZOP method.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0339897</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0339897</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0339897</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0339897</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The Christmas tree faces significant safety risks during installation and requires extremely high reliability during operation. In this study, a comprehensive risk assessment method combined GA-BP neural network and improved HAZOP method is established, which is the first application used in the field of risk analysis for offshore oil equipment. The sample risk data during the installation and operation of the China's first domestically produced Christmas tree is extracted through multi-source fusion, and the possibility and severity levels of risk occurrence are classified and judged. By training and testing the model it shows that the average error rate of the proposed GA-BP multi-source information fusion method is only 5.10%. Through risk data extraction and evaluation, the failure probability when the Christmas tree lowering into water is found to be the highest, with a critical importance coefficient of 0.24. No high-risk failure modes are found during the production process, but there are 36 moderate risk points. Deep water gas well field testing shows the theoretical judgment is consistent with the actual discovery, and with using of hydrate inhibitor injection the blockage risk at the nozzle of the Christmas tree is alleviated, which verifying the accuracy of the method. The method has improved the risk warning system for the safe operation of the Christmas tree, and can provide technical support for similar subsea oil and gas production equipment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2026 Wang et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Qiong</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0866-5950</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Architecture and Engineering, Zhanjiang University of Science and Technology, Zhanjiang, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Education Management, Assumption University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Huimin</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Management, Xi'an University of Architecture and Technology, Xi'an, Shaanxi, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Guanlong</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CNOOC Zhanjiang Branch Company, Zhanjiang, Guandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018570" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Assessment</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="Y">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016571" MajorTopicYN="N">Neural Networks, Computer</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41490446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12768369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0339897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-25-15983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Li L, Song Y. Current status and prospects of offshore oil and gas drilling technology development in China. Acta Petrolei Sinica. 2023;44(12):2308&#x2013;18. doi: 10.7623/syxb202312019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7623/syxb202312019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qingping L, Haishan Z, Xinzhong L. The current state and future of deep water subsea production technology. Chin J Eng Sci. 2016;18(2):76. doi: 10.15302/j-sscae-2016.02.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15302/j-sscae-2016.02.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menglan D, Laibin Z, Jingjing Y. Reliability assessment of flue gas turbines based on fuzzy fault tree analysis. 2013 International Conference on Quality, Reliability, Risk, Maintenance, and Safety Engineering. Chengdu: IEEE; 2013. pp. 13828725. doi: 10.1109/QR2MSE.2013.6625557</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/QR2MSE.2013.6625557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan L, Luo J, Duan M. Quantitative risk assessment of installation process of underwater horizontal Christmas tree. J Safety Environ. 2017;17(06):2099&#x2013;103. doi: 10.13637/j.issn.1009-6094.2017.06.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13637/j.issn.1009-6094.2017.06.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheliyan AS, Bhattacharyya SK. Fuzzy fault tree analysis of oil and gas leakage in subsea production systems. J Ocean Eng Sci. 2018;3(1):38&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1016/j.joes.2017.11.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joes.2017.11.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massignan JAD, London JBA, Bessani M, Maciel CD, Fannucchi RZ, Miranda V. Bayesian inference approach for information fusion in distribution system state estimation. IEEE Trans Smart Grid. 2022;13(1):526&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1109/tsg.2021.3128053</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/tsg.2021.3128053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su H, Ren J, Wen Z. An approach using Dempster&#x2013;Shafer evidence theory to fuse multi-source observations for dam safety estimation. Soft Comput. 2018;23(14):5633&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1007/s00500-018-3220-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00500-018-3220-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia L, Geng J, Xiao J. Ellipsoid fitting based two-step optimized correction for orthogonal tri-axis magnetic compass measurements. J Chin Inertial Technol. 2018;26(4):478&#x2013;83. doi: 10.13695/j.cnki.12-1222/o3.2018.04.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13695/j.cnki.12-1222/o3.2018.04.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakkar A, Chaudhari K. Information fusion-based genetic algorithm with long short-term memory for stock price and trend prediction. Appl Soft Comput. 2022;128:109428. doi: 10.1016/j.asoc.2022.109428</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asoc.2022.109428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kande JM, Abielmona R, Harb M, Berger J, Falcon R, Petriu E. Multi-Objective Heterogeneous Multi-Asset Collection Scheduling Optimization with High-Level Information Fusion. In: Proceedings of the 2021 IEEE International Systems Conference (SysCon). 2021. pp. 1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1109/syscon48628.2021.9447098</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/syscon48628.2021.9447098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang S, Deng X, Jiang W. Optimal data fusion based on information quality function. Appl Intell. 2019;49(11):3938&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1007/s10489-019-01494-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10489-019-01494-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo J, Lv Y. Research on optimization model of multisource traffic information collection combination based on genetic algorithm. Comput Intell Neurosci. 2022;2022:3793996. doi: 10.1155/2022/3793996</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/3793996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8813245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35126490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun G, Zhang Z, Zheng B, Li Y. Multi-sensor data fusion algorithm based on trust degree and improved genetics. Sensors (Basel). 2019;19(9):2139. doi: 10.3390/s19092139</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s19092139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6539828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31072068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruan B. Prediction of stock market by BP neural network model. J Phys: Conf Ser. 2021;1744(4):042232. doi: 10.1088/1742-6596/1744/4/042232</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1742-6596/1744/4/042232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoseinian FS, Abdollahzadeh A, Rezai B. Semi-autogenous mill power prediction by a hybrid neural genetic algorithm. J Cent South Univ. 2018;25(1):151&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1007/s11771-018-3725-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11771-018-3725-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo W, Du H, Guo C, Southwell BJ, Cheong JW, Dempster AG. Information fusion for GNSS-R wind speed retrieval using statistically modified convolutional neural network. Remote Sens Environ. 2022;272:112934. doi: 10.1016/j.rse.2022.112934</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rse.2022.112934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passos LA, Papa JP, Del Ser J, Hussain A, Adeel A. Multimodal audio-visual information fusion using canonical-correlated Graph Neural Network for energy-efficient speech enhancement. Inf Fus. 2023;90:1&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1016/j.inffus.2022.09.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.inffus.2022.09.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li P, Zhang Y, Zhang Y. Face image super-resolution reconstruction based on adaptive convolution and joint loss function. Sci Technol Eng. 2025;25(06):2442&#x2013;52. doi: 10.12404/j.issn.1671-1815.2403052</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12404/j.issn.1671-1815.2403052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi X, Liu D, Sun Y. Research on the construction method of multi source information fusion model for oil monitoring. J Wuhan Univ Technol (Transp Sci Eng). 2018;42(02):253&#x2013;6. doi: 10.3963/j.issn.2095-3844.2018.02.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3963/j.issn.2095-3844.2018.02.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong F, Cui J. Multi source information fusion framework based on ontology in the petroleum field. Comput Syst Appl. 2018;27(07):272&#x2013;7. doi: 10.15888/j.cnki.csa.006439</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15888/j.cnki.csa.006439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Q. Research on multi source digital oilfield data and oilfield data fusion and methods. Chang&#x2019;an University; 2015. doi: 10.7666/d.D747583</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7666/d.D747583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hai MA. Research on estimation and prediction method of drilling geological characteristic parameters based on multi source information fusion. China University of Petroleum; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin B, Zhang X, Sun B. et al. Experimental Device Design for Gas Kick Early Detection during Deepwater Hydrate Reservoirs Drilling. Res ExpLaborat. 2019,38(04):33&#x2013;7. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1006-7167.2019.04.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1006-7167.2019.04.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiang L, Ren Y, Ma H. Prediction of horizontal well productivity in ultra-low permeability sandstone reservoirs based on GA-BP neural network. Pet Geol Eng. 2024;38(6):63&#x2013;7. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1673-8217.2024.06.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1673-8217.2024.06.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo B, Dai Y, Gao S. The pressure prediction of oil-field water flooding pipeline network based on adaptive GA-BP. Control Instruments Chem Ind. 2025;52(4):603&#x2013;9. doi: 10.20030/j.cnki.1000-3932.202504016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20030/j.cnki.1000-3932.202504016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li SH. Research on the prediction of drilling efficiency of rock crushing by rotary drilling rig based on GA-BP neural network. Yanshan University; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao S, Tang P, Sun C. Fuzzy comprehensive evaluation of underwater oil tree sea trial based on AHP. Oil Drilling Prod Technol. 2019;41(03):335&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang P, Chen X, Ju P. Application of LOPA method in SIL analysis of deepwater underwater production system. Instrumentation Users. 2022;29(01):44&#x2013;8. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1671-1041.2022.01.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1671-1041.2022.01.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y. Reliability analysis of underwater vertical Christmas tree system. China University of Petroleum (East China); 2018. https://link.cnki.net/doi/10.27644/d.cnki.gsydu.2018.001482</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.27644/d.cnki.gsydu.2018.001482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen G, Cheng B. Simulation and quantitative risk assessment of consequences of LNG leakage accidents. Nat Gas Ind. 2007;(06):133&#x2013;5, 162&#x2013;3. doi: 10.3321/j.issn:1000-0976.2007.06.041</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3321/j.issn:1000-0976.2007.06.041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu X, Liu H, Zhao Z. Analysis of wellhead stability and influence factors in deepwater drilling stage. Pet Eng Construc. 2020;47(S1):202&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y, Hui H, Lu Y. Multi-source information fusion indoor positioning method based on genetic algorithm to optimize neural network. J Chin Inertial Technol. 2020;28(1):67&#x2013;73. doi: 10.13695/j.cnki.12-1222/o3.2020.01.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13695/j.cnki.12-1222/o3.2020.01.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Z, Zhang T, Yang X. Research on equipment fault diagnosis and health management model based on BP neural network and genetic algorithm. Fault Diagnosis. 2024;11:9&#x2013;15. doi: 10.19287/j.mtmt.1005-2402.2024.11.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19287/j.mtmt.1005-2402.2024.11.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du H, Zhang T, Chen Y. Prediction of oil single well production using BP neural network based on genetic algorithm. J Chengdu Univ (Nat Sci Ed). 2021;40(01):57&#x2013;61. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1004-5422.2021.01.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1004-5422.2021.01.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Xing X, Yan Q. Adaptability analysis of risk assessment method of shallow water subsea tree. China Offshore Platform. 2022;37(06):42&#x2013;9. doi: 10.12226/j.issn.1001-4500.2022.06.20220607</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12226/j.issn.1001-4500.2022.06.20220607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren G, Wang Y, Meng W. et al. Risk analysis of deepwater horizontal christmas tree in operating mode. China Pet Mach. 2024;52(5):63&#x2013;70. doi: 10.16082/j.cnki.issn.1001-4578.2024.05.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16082/j.cnki.issn.1001-4578.2024.05.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdi M, Kabir S, Walker M. Uncertainty handling in fault tree based risk assessment: State of the art and future perspectives. Process Saf Environ Protec. 2019;131:89&#x2013;104. doi: 10.1016/j.psep.2019.09.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2019.09.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdi M, Kabir S. A fuzzy Bayesian network approach for risk analysis in process industries. Process Saf Environ Protec. 2017;111:507&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1016/j.psep.2017.08.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psep.2017.08.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>