<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40746810</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Comparative Analysis of Hydration Status Among Urban and Rural Adults in Selangor, Malaysia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e87064</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e87064</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e87064</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.87064</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Adequate hydration is essential for overall health; however, data on hydration status among Malaysian adults are limited. This study aimed to compare the hydration status of urban and rural adults in Selangor, Malaysia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A cross-sectional study was conducted involving participants from urban (n=189) and rural (n=188) areas near Universiti Putra Malaysia (UPM), selected through purposive sampling. The study included 377 healthy adults aged 18-59 years (mean {SD}: 31.34 {11.64} years). Participants with health conditions, such as diabetes, hypertension, gastrointestinal diseases, kidney disorders, and cardiovascular issues, were excluded. Additionally, individuals taking prescription medications, food supplements, consuming high levels of caffeine or alcohol, smoking heavily, or engaging in intense aerobic training were also excluded. Sociodemographic data were collected, and hydration status was assessed using urine samples (first-morning and 24-hour) and blood tests (plasma osmolality, blood count, and renal function). Urine measurements included specific gravity (USG), osmolality (UOSM), volume (UVOL), and colour (UCOL), which were compared against hydration biomarkers. Chi-square tests and independent t-tests (p&lt;0.05) were employed to compare sociodemographic characteristics and hydration status between urban and rural adults. Factor analysis was used to assess the reliability of hydration measurements.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Significant differences were observed in USG, UOSM, and UVOL of first-morning urine samples (&#x3c7;&#xb2;{2}=6.537, p=0.038; &#x3c7;&#xb2;{1}=6.465, p=0.011; t{375}=-2.10, p=0.036). Additionally, significant differences in USG and UOSM of 24-hour urine samples were noted between urban and rural adults (&#x3c7;&#xb2;{2}=27.686, p=0.000; &#x3c7;&#xb2;{2}=11.030, p=0.000). Blood tests revealed significant differences in hematocrit (HCT) (t{375}=-1.987, p=0.048), sodium concentration (Na) (t{375}=-4.468, p=0.000), potassium concentration (K) (t{375}=3.563, p=0.000), and estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) (t{371.96}=-4.247, p=0.000) between urban and rural adults. The results indicated that rural adults are less hydrated than their urban counterparts. Factor analysis confirmed that urine measurements are strong indicators of hydration status (quality scores &gt;1), with USG and UOSM in first-morning urine (FMU) showing a strong positive correlation with 24-hour urine samples (0.999), indicating that urine tests are more reliable than blood tests for assessing hydration status.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study found significant differences in hydration status between urban and rural adults in Selangor, Malaysia, based on both urine and blood measurements; however, urine tests proved to be more reliable for assessing hydration levels. These findings may inform strategies to improve hydration among Malaysian adults. Further research is warranted to investigate factors influencing hydration status.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Samah et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Samah</LastName><ForeName>Fazirah</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, Universiti Putra Malaysia, Serdang, MYS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Loh</LastName><ForeName>Su Peng</ForeName><Initials>SP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, Universiti Putra Malaysia, Serdang, MYS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sulaiman</LastName><ForeName>Norhasmah</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, Universiti Putra Malaysia, Serdang, MYS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gan</LastName><ForeName>Wan Ying</ForeName><Initials>WY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, Universiti Putra Malaysia, Serdang, MYS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmad Fuzi</LastName><ForeName>Salma Faeza</ForeName><Initials>SF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, Universiti Putra Malaysia, Serdang, MYS.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood measurements</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydration status</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">malaysia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urban and rural adults</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urine tests</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Ethics Committee for Research Involving Human Subjects at Universiti Putra Malaysia issued approval #UPM/TNCPI/RMC/JKEUPM/1.4.18.2 (JKEUPM). Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: The author would like to acknowledge the Ministry of Higher Education for the financial support through the Fundamental Research Grant Scheme (FRGS): #FRGS/1/2021/SKK06/ UPM/02/3. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40746810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12310409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.87064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shifting focus: from hydration for performance to hydration for health. Perrier ET. Ann Nutr Metab. 2017;70:4&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28614817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hydration, dehydration, underhydration, optimal hydration: are we barking up the wrong tree? Kavouras SA. Eur J Nutr. 2019;58:471&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30607564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Methods of assessment of hydration status and their usefulness in detecting dehydration in the elderly. Bak A, Tsiami A, Greene C. Curr Res Nutr Food Sci. 2017;5:43&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessment of water demand from urban and rural area in Kota Bharu, Kelantan. Fauzi SN, Musa SB. https://publisher.uthm.edu.my/periodicals/index.php/rtcebe/article/view/3165 RTCEBE. 2022;3:891&#x2013;898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malaysia voluntary national review (VNR)  [
Jul;
2024 
]. 2021. https://ekonomi.gov.my/sites/default/files/2021-07/Malaysia_Voluntary_National_Review_%28VNR%29_2021.pdf https://ekonomi.gov.my/sites/default/files/2021-07/Malaysia_Voluntary_National_Review_%28VNR%29_2021.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fluid intake, hydration status and its association with cognitive function among adolescents in Petaling Perdana, Selangor, Malaysia. Tung SE, Ch'ng YZ, Karnan TV, Chong PN, Zubaidah JO, Chin YS. Nutr Res Pract. 2020;14:490&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7520560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33029289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Factors associated with poor socioeconomic status among Malaysian older adults: an analysis according to urban and rural settings. Shahar S, Vanoh D, Mat Ludin AF, Singh DK, Hamid TA. BMC Public Health. 2019;19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6565532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31196023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plain water and beverage consumption patterns among university students in Puncak Alam, Malaysia. Teng NI, Nordin NJ, Shah AS. Malays J Nutr. 2019;25:227&#x2013;236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of Director General of Lands and Mines.  [
May;
2020 
]. 2020. https://www.jkptg.gov.my/en/ https://www.jkptg.gov.my/en/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anova, kruskal-wallis, normal scores and unequal variance. Lachenbruch PA, Clements PJ. Commun Stat - Theory Methods. 1991;20:107&#x2013;126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Is specific gravity a good estimate of urine osmolality? Imran S, Eva G, Christopher S, Flynn E, Henner D. J Clin Lab Anal. 2010;24:426&#x2013;430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6647580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21089176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urinary indices of hydration status. Armstrong LE, Maresh CM, Castellani JW, Bergeron MF, Kenefick RW, LaGasse KE, Riebe D. Int J Sport Nutr. 1994;4:265&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7987361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Human hydration indices: acute and longitudinal reference values. Armstrong LE, Pumerantz AC, Fiala KA, Roti MW, Kavouras SA, Casa DJ, Maresh CM. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2010;20:145&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20479488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engineering approaches to assessing hydration status. Garrett DC, Rae N, Fletcher JR, Zarnke S, Thorson S, Hogan DB, Fear EC. IEEE Rev Biomed Eng. 2018;11:233&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29990109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AHS Laboratory Services: Venipuncture - Central Zone.  [
Jul;
2024 
]. 2016. https://www.albertahealthservices.ca/webapps/labservices/indexAPL.asp?id=8625&amp;tests=&amp;zoneid=1&amp;details=true https://www.albertahealthservices.ca/webapps/labservices/indexAPL.asp?id=8625&amp;tests=&amp;zoneid=1&amp;details=true</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Current Population Estimates, Malaysia, 2014-2016.  [
Jul;
2024 
];https://www.dosm.gov.my/portal-main/release-content/current-population-estimates-malaysia-2014---2016 2017 2024:2014&#x2013;2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asia&#x2019;s rural-urban disparity in the context of growing inequality. Imai KS, Malaeb B. : IFAD. https://www.ifad.org/documents/d/new-ifad.org/27_research-pdf Rome, Italy. 2018;27:20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Income inequality in quality of life among rural communities in malaysia: a case for immediate policy consideration. Thangiah G, Said MA, Majid HA, Reidpath D, Su TT. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7727827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33255397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Water intake, water balance, and the elusive daily water requirement. Armstrong LE, Johnson EC. Nutrients. 2018;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6315424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30563134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racial/ethnic and socioeconomic disparities in hydration status among US adults and the role of tap water and other beverage intake. Brooks CJ, Gortmaker SL, Long MW, Cradock AL, Kenney EL. Am J Public Health. 2017;107:1387&#x2013;1394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5551608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28727528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urinalysis screening for rural communities. Bren-Cardali D, Dao L, Destruel J, Fernandez R, Figueira S, Kim U. IEEE Glob Humanit Technol Conf GHTC. 2018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diagnostic performance of afternoon urine osmolality to assess optimal hydration status in an adult healthy population. Hustrini NM, Siregar P, Nainggolan G, Harimurti K. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/28790225/ Acta Med Indones. 2017;49:112&#x2013;117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28790225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessment of hydration status in a large population. Baron S, Courbebaisse M, Lepicard EM, Friedlander G. Br J Nutr. 2015;113:147&#x2013;158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25418739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Criterion values for urine-specific gravity and urine color representing adequate water intake in healthy adults. Perrier ET, Bottin JH, Vecchio M, Lemetais G. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2017;71:561&#x2013;563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5383926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28145416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Validity of urine specific gravity when compared with plasma osmolality as a measure of hydration status in male and female NCAA collegiate athletes. Sommerfield LM, McAnulty SR, McBride JM, et al. J Strength Cond Res. 2016;30:2219&#x2013;2225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4912946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26694503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehydration is how you define it: comparison of 318 blood and urine athlete spot checks. Hew-Butler TD, Eskin C, Bickham J, Rusnak M, VanderMeulen M. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2018;4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5812394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29464103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Water intake and urinary hydration biomarkers in children. Kavouras SA, Bougatsas D, Johnson EC, Arnaoutis G, Tsipouridi S, Panagiotakos DB. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2017;71:530&#x2013;535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27876808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blood Gases and Critical Care Testing. Third Edition. Vol. 2022 Cambridge, MA: Academic Press; Osmolality, sodium, potassium, chloride, and bicarbonate; pp. 159&#x2013;192.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>