<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39296160</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2405-8440</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>17</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Heliyon</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Heliyon</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A central composite design-based targeted quercetin nanoliposomal formulation: Optimization and cytotoxic studies on MCF-7 breast cancer cell lines.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e37430</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e37430</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e37430</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e37430</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study aimed to enhance the efficacy of quercetin (QT) by formulating it into a liposomal drug delivery system utilizing the concept of central composite design. The drug:lipid ratio, cholesterol concentration, and sonication time were selected as independent variables in the study. The vesicle and percentage entrapment efficiency were selected as the dependent variables. Quercetin nanoliposomes (QT-NLs) were prepared via a combination of ethanol injection and thin film hydration. The vesicle size and entrapment efficiency of all formulations were within the ranges of 100&#xa0;nm and &gt;80&#xa0;%, respectively. The zeta potential value indicated the stability of the optimized formulation. The contour plots were used to select the desired batch range. SEM studies revealed an imperfect crystalline morphology without any unwanted agglomeration. MTT assays on VERO cell lines indicated the safety of the developed formulation. MTT assays of MCF-7&#xa0;cells revealed IC<sub>50</sub> values of 5.8&#xa0;&#x3bc;M and 7.9&#xa0;&#x3bc;M for QT-NLs and QT, respectively. In our study, the optimized formulation exhibited late and early apoptosis and necrosis when used to treat MCF-7&#xa0;cells. S and G2/M cell cycle phases of MCF-7&#xa0;cell arrest were confirmed by the cell cycle report. At sub-G0/G1 phase, 2.10&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;1.1&#xa0;%; G0/G1 phase, 34.13&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;1.9&#xa0;%; S phase, 34.55&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;0.98&#xa0;%; and G2/M phase, 26.24&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;1.7&#xa0;% of cell arrest were observed. The results demonstrated the effectiveness of the proposed design for the development of corn starch-coated QT-NLs and their activity in breast cancer cell lines.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhargav</LastName><ForeName>E</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Raghavendra Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research, Anantapur, Andhra Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohammed</LastName><ForeName>Nawaz</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Raghavendra Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research, Anantapur, Andhra Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Udit Narayan</ForeName><Initials>UN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Raghavendra Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research, Anantapur, Andhra Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ramalingam</LastName><ForeName>P</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Analysis, National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research (NIPER), Hajipur, Bihar, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Challa</LastName><ForeName>Ranadheer Reddy</ForeName><Initials>RR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Formulation and Development, Quotient Sciences, 3080 McCann Farm Dr, Garnet Valley, PA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vallamkonda</LastName><ForeName>Bhaskar</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Somerset Therapeutics Limited, New Jersey, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmad</LastName><ForeName>Sheikh F</ForeName><Initials>SF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Toxicology, College of Pharmacy, King Saud University, Riyadh-11451, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dsnbk</LastName><ForeName>Prasanth</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Pharmacy &amp; Technology Management, SVKM's Narsee Monjee Institute of Management Studies (NMIMS), Jadcherla, Hyderabad, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pasala</LastName><ForeName>Praveen Kumar</ForeName><Initials>PK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Raghavendra Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research, Anantapur, Andhra Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rudrapal</LastName><ForeName>Mithun</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Sciences, School of Biotechnology and Pharmaceutical Sciences, Vignan's Foundation for Science, Technology &amp; Research, Guntur, Andhra Pradesh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Heliyon</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101672560</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2405-8440</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Breast cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Central composite design</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cytotoxic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nanoliposomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quercetin</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39296160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11409131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e37430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2405-8440(24)13461-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Das D. Breast cancer: risk factors and prevention strategies. World J Biol Pharm Health Sci. 2022;12(3):265&#x2013;280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudrapal M., Khairnar S.J., Khan J., et al. Dietary polyphenols and their role in oxidative stress-induced human diseases: insights into protective effects, antioxidant potentials and mechanism (s) of action. Front. Pharmacol. 2022;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8882865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35237163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudrapal M., Maji S., Prajapati S.K., et al. Protective effects of diets rich in polyphenols in cigarette smoke (CS)-induced oxidative damages and associated health implications. Antioxidants. 2022;11(7):1217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9311530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35883708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudrapal M., Chetia D. Plant flavonoids as potential source of future antimalarial leads. Sys. Rev. Pharm. 2017;8(1):13&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia L., Huang S., Yin X., et al. Quercetin suppresses the mobility of breast cancer by suppressing glycolysis through Akt-mTOR pathway mediated autophagy induction. Life Sci. 2018;208:123&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30025823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudrapal M., Mishra A.K., Rani L., et al. Nanodelivery of dietary polyphenols for therapeutic applications. Molecules. 2022;27(24):8706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9784807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36557841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudrapal M., Vallinayagam S., Zothantluanga J.H., et al. Applications of Nanotechnology in Drug Discovery and Delivery. Elsevier; 2022. Nanophytomedicines: nature to medicines; pp. 71&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel G., Thakur N.S., Kushwah V., et al. Liposomal delivery of mycophenolic acid with quercetin for improved breast cancer therapy in SD rats. Front. Bioeng. Biotechnol. 2020;8:631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7308462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32612988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravichandiran V., Masilamani K., Senthilnathan B., et al. Quercetin-decorated curcumin liposome design for cancer therapy: in-vitro and in-vivo studies. Curr. Drug Deliv. 2017;14:1053&#x2013;1059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27572089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gadhwal M., Patil S., D'Mello P., et al. Synthesis, characterization and antitumour activity of some Quercetin analogs. Indian J Pharm Sci. 2013;75:233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3757866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24019576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong M.Y., Chiu G.N. Simultaneous liposomal delivery of quercetin and vincristine for enhanced estrogen-receptor-negative breast cancer treatment. Anti Cancer Drugs. 2010;21:401&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20110806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scioli Montoto S., Muraca G., Ruiz M.E. Solid lipid nanoparticles for drug delivery: pharmacological and biopharmaceutical aspects. Front. Mol. Biosci. 2020;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7662460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33195435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiwada H., Matsuo H., Harashima H. Identification of proteins mediating clearance of liposomes using a liver perfusion system. Adv. Drug Deliv. Rev. 1998;32:61&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10837636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozzuto G., Molinari A. Liposomes as nanomedical devices. Int. J. Nanomed. 2015;10:975&#x2013;999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4324542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25678787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Li X., Huang L. Non-viral nanocarriers for siRNA delivery in breast cancer. J. Contr. Release. 2014;190:440&#x2013;450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4142098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24874288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadine V., Petra H., Sarah K., et al. Toxicity of polymeric nanoparticles in vivo and in vitro. J. Nano Res. 2014;16:2379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4584143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26420981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ananda Babu S., Sanmugam A., Ashwini P., et al. Toxicity of polymeric nanodrugs as drug carriers. ACS Chem Health Saf. 2013;30:236&#x2013;250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudrapal M., Rakshit G., Singh R.P., et al. Dietary polyphenols: review on chemistry/sources, bioavailability/metabolism, antioxidant effects, and their role in disease management. Antioxidants. 2024;13(4):429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11047380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38671877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asfaram A., Ghaedi M., Javadian H., et al. Cu-and S-@ SnO2 nanoparticles loaded on activated carbon for efficient ultrasound assisted dispersive &#x3bc;SPE-spectrophotometric detection of Quercetin in Nasturtium officinale extract and fruit juice samples: CCD-RSM design. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2018;47:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29908597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhargav E., Chaithanya Barghav G., Padmanabha Reddy Y., et al. A Design of Experiment (DoE) based approach for development and optimization of nanosuspensions of telmisartan, a BCS class II antihypertensive drug. Future J Pharm Sci. 2020;6:1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhargav E., Reddy Y.P., Koteshwara K.B. Development and optimization of luliconazole nanostructured lipid carriers based gel by quality by design its skin distribution studies, dermatokinetic modeling &amp; in-vitro and ex-vivo correlation. Curr. Drug Deliv. 2021;18:1041&#x2013;1053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33319682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cristiano Ceron J., Rezende N., Daniela Fernandes S., et al. Target selectivity of cholesterol-phosphatidylcholineliposome loaded with phthalocyanine for breastcancer diagnosis and treatment by photodynamictherapy. Photodiagnosis Photodyn. Ther. 2022;39</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35803557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farzaneh H., Ebrahimi Nik M., Mashreghi M., et al. A study on the role of cholesterol and phosphatidylcholine in various features of liposomal doxorubicin: from liposomal preparation to therapy. Int. J. Pharm. 2018;551(1&#x2013;2):300&#x2013;308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30243944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toniazzo T., Peres M.S., Ramos A.P., et al. Encapsulation of Quercetin in liposomes by ethanol injection and physicochemical characterization of dispersions and lyophilized vesicles. Food Biosci. 2017;19:17&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najjari N., Sari S., Saffari M., et al. Formulation optimization and characterization of Pistacia atlantica Desf. essential oil-loaded nanostructured lipid carriers on the proliferation of human breast cancer cell line SKBR3 (in vitro studies) J. Herb. Med. 2022;36</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khorsandi L., Orazizadeh M., Niazvand F., et al. Quercetin induces apoptosis and necroptosis in MCF-7 breast cancer cells. Bratisl. Lek. Listy. 2017;118:123&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28814095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezaie F., Mokhtari M.J., Kalani M. Quercetin arrests in G2 phase, upregulates INXS LncRNA and downregulates UCA1 LncRNA in MCF-7 cells. Int J Mol Cell Med. 2021;10:208&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8800456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35178359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathyamoorthy N., Magharla D., Chintamaneni P., et al. Optimization of paclitaxel loaded poly (&#x3b5;-caprolactone) nanoparticles using Box Behnken design. Beni-Suef Univ J Basic Appl Sci. 2017;6:362&#x2013;373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khorsandi L., Orazizadeh M., Niazvand F., et al. Quercetin induces apoptosis and necroptosis in MCF-7 breast cancer cells. Bratisl. Lek. Listy. 2017;118:123&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28814095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asli D., Asli S., Feride S., et al. Celecoxib-loaded liposomes: effect of cholesterol on encapsulation and in vitro release characteristics. Biosci. Rep. 2010;30:365&#x2013;373. 2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19900165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves A.C., Magarkar A., Horta M., et al. Influence of doxorubicin on model cell membrane properties: insights from in vitro and in silico studies. Sci. Rep. 2017;7:6343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5524714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28740256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatia A., Kumar R., Katare O.P. Tamoxifen in topical liposomes: development, characterization and in vitro evaluation. J Pharm Pharm Sci. 2004;7:252&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15367383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed A.R., Weston N., Coombes A.G., et al. Liposome formulation of poorly water soluble drugs: optimization of drug loading and ESEM analysis of stability. Int. J. Pharm. 2004;285:23&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15488676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J.A., Anyarambhatla G., Ma L., et al. Development and characterization of a novel Cremophor&#xae; EL free liposome-based paclitaxel (LEP-ETU) formulation. Eur. J. Pharm. Biopharm. 2005;59:177&#x2013;187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15567316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subczynski W.K., Wisniewska A., Yin J.J., et al. Hydrophobic barriers of lipid bilayer-membranes formed by reduction of water penetration by alkyl chain unsaturation and cholesterol. Biochemistry. 1994;33:7670&#x2013;7681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8011634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jangde R., Singh D. Preparation and optimization of Quercetin-loaded liposomes for wound healing, using response surface methodology. Artif. Cells, Nanomed. Biotechnol. 2016;44:635&#x2013;641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25375215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan Z.P., Chen L.J., Fan L.Y., et al. Liposomal Quercetin efficiently suppresses growth of solid tumors in murine models. Clin. Cancer Res. 2006;12:3193&#x2013;3199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16707620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arsov Z., Quaroni L. Direct interaction between cholesterol and phosphatidylcholines in hydrated membranes revealed by ATR-FTIR spectroscopy. Chem. Phys. Lipids. 2007;150:35&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17662974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maeda H. The enhanced permeability and retention (EPR) effect in tumor vasculature: the key role of tumor-selective macromolecular drug targeting. Adv Enzyme Regul. 2001;41:189&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11384745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbasalipourkabir R., Salehzadeh A., Abdullah R. Tamoxifen-loaded solid lipid nanoparticles-induced apoptosis in breast cancer cell lines. J. Exp. Nanosci. 2016;11:161&#x2013;174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalyane D., Raval N., Maheshwari R., et al. Employment of enhanced permeability and retention effect (EPR): nanoparticle-based precision tools for targeting of therapeutic and diagnostic agent in cancer. Mater Sci Eng C Mater Biol Appl. 2019;98:1252&#x2013;1276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30813007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z.P., Schell J.B., Ho C.-T., et al. Green tea epigallocatechin gallate shows a pronounced growth inhibitory effect on cancerous cells but not on their normal counterparts. Cancer Lett. 1998;129:173&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9719459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brusselmans K., De Schrijver E., Heyns W., et al. Epigallocatechin&#x2010;3&#x2010;gallate is a potent natural inhibitor of fatty acid synthase in intact cells and selectively induces apoptosis in prostate cancer cells. Int. J. Cancer. 2023;106:856&#x2013;862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12918062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cristiano Ceron J., Rezende N., Daniela Fernandes S., et al. Target selectivity of cholesterol-phosphatidylcholineliposome loaded with phthalocyanine for breastcancer diagnosis and treatment by photodynamictherapy. Photodiagnosis Photodyn. Ther. 2022;39</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35803557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celine Stoica A., Ferreira Kleber, Hannan K., et al. Bilayer forming phospholipids as targets for cancer therapy. Int J Mol Biosci. 2022;23:5266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9100777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35563655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C., Zhang Y., Wan Y., et al. STING-activating drug delivery systems: design strategies and biomedical applications. Chinese Chem Lett. 2021;32:1615&#x2013;1625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng H., Qi Y., Zhang Z., et al. Nanomaterials toward the treatment of Alzheimer's disease: recent advances and future trends. Chinese Chem Lett. 2021;32:1857&#x2013;1868.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun M., Nie S., Pan X., et al. Quercetin-nanostructured lipid carriers: characteristics and anti-breast cancer activities in vitro. Colloids Surf. B Biointerfaces. 2014;113:15&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24060926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain A., Garg N.K., Jain A., et al. A synergistic approach of adapalene-loaded nanostructured lipid carriers, and vitamin C coadministration for treating acne. Drug Dev. Ind. Pharm. 2016;42:897&#x2013;905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26577703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>