<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37623068</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2310-2861</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Gels (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Gels</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An Elucidative Review of the Nanomaterial Effect on the Durability and Calcium-Silicate-Hydrate (C-S-H) Gel Development of Concrete.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">613</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/gels9080613</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Concrete as a building material is susceptible to degradation by environmental threats such as thermal diffusion, acid and sulphate infiltration, and chloride penetration. Hence, the inclusion of nanomaterials in concrete has a positive effect in terms of promoting its mechanical strength and durability performance, as well as resulting in energy savings due to reduced cement consumption in concrete production. This review article discussed the novel advances in research regarding C-S-H gel promotion and concrete durability improvement using nanomaterials. Basically, this review deals with topics relevant to the influence of nanomaterials on concrete's resistance to heat, acid, sulphate, chlorides, and wear deterioration, as well as the impact on concrete microstructure and chemical bonding. The significance of this review is a critical discussion on the cementation mechanism of nanoparticles in enhancing durability properties owing to their nanofiller effect, pozzolanic reactivity, and nucleation effect. The utilization of nanoparticles enhanced the hydrolysis of cement, leading to a rise in the production of C-S-H gel. Consequently, this improvement in concrete microstructure led to a reduction in the number of capillary pores and pore connectivity, thereby improving the concrete's water resistance. Microstructural and chemical evidence obtained using SEM and XRD indicated that nanomaterials facilitated the formation of cement gel either by reacting pozzolanically with portlandite to generate more C-S-H gel or by functioning as nucleation sites. Due to an increased rate of C-S-H gel formation, concrete enhanced with nanoparticles exhibited greater durability against heat damage, external attack by acids and sulphates, chloride diffusion, and surface abrasion. The durability improvement following nanomaterial incorporation into concrete can be summarised as enhanced residual mechanical strength, reduced concrete mass loss, reduced diffusion coefficients for thermal and chloride, improved performance against sulphates and acid attack, and increased surface resistance to abrasion.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Saffar</LastName><ForeName>Farqad Yousuf</ForeName><Initials>FY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, College of Engineering, Universiti Tenaga Nasional, Jalan IKRAM-UNITEN, Kajang 43000, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Energy Infrastructure, Universiti Tenaga Nasional, Jalan IKRAM-UNITEN, Kajang 43000, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wong</LastName><ForeName>Leong Sing</ForeName><Initials>LS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1271-2112</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, College of Engineering, Universiti Tenaga Nasional, Jalan IKRAM-UNITEN, Kajang 43000, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Energy Infrastructure, Universiti Tenaga Nasional, Jalan IKRAM-UNITEN, Kajang 43000, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paul</LastName><ForeName>Suvash Chandra</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9997-2077</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, International University of Business Agriculture and Technology, 4 Embankment Drive Road, Sector 10, Dhaka 1230, Bangladesh.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>FRGS/1/2022/TK01/UNITEN/02/1</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Higher Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>J510050002 - IC-6 BOLDREFRESH2025 - CENTRE OF EXCELLENCE</GrantID><Agency>Universiti Tenaga Nasional</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Gels</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101696925</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2310-2861</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">C-S-H gel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">concrete</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">durability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">energy savings</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nanomaterial</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37623068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10453857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/gels9080613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">gels9080613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nazeer M., Kapoor K., Singh S.P. Strength, durability and microstructural investigations on pervious concrete made with fly ash and silica fume as supplementary cementitious materials. J. Build. Eng. 2023;69:106275. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P.K., Monteiro P.J.M. Durability in Concrete: Microstructure, Properties, and Materials. McGraw-Hill Companies, Inc.; New York, NY, USA: 2005. pp. 121&#x2013;199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Jabari M. Integral Waterproofing of Concrete Structures. Woodhead Publishing; Cambridge, UK: 2022. Concrete durability problems: Physicochemical and transport mechanisms; pp. 69&#x2013;107. Woodhead Publishing Series in Civil and Structural Engineering.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-12-824354-1.00003-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Xu Q., Chen S. An experimental and numerical study on water permeability of concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2016;105:503&#x2013;510. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.12.184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.12.184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cyr M. Eco-Efficient Concrete. Woodhead Publishing; Cambridge, UK: 2016. Influence of supplementary cementitious materials (SCMs) on concrete durability; pp. 153&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1533/9780857098993.2.153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan X., Shi Z., Shi C., Ling T.C., Li N. A review on concrete surface treatment Part I: Types and mechanisms. Constr. Build. Mater. 2017;132:578&#x2013;590. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.12.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.12.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isayed S.H., Amjad M.A. Strength, water absorption and porosity of concrete incorporating natural and crushed aggregate. J. King Saud Univ. Eng. Sci. 1996;8:109&#x2013;119. doi: 10.1016/s1018-3639(18)30642-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1018-3639(18)30642-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claisse P. Measurement of Porosity as a Predictor of the Transport Properties of Concrete in Transport Properties of Concrete: Modelling the Durability of Structures. Woodhead Publishing; Cambridge, UK: 2021. pp. 115&#x2013;147. Transport Properties of Concrete.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-12-820249-4.00008-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baghabra Al-Amoudi O.S., Al-Kutti W.A., Ahmad S., Maslehuddin M. Correlation between compressive strength and certain durability indices of plain and blended cement concretes. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2014;31:672&#x2013;676. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2009.05.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2009.05.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peter C. Hewlett and Martin Liska. Lea&#x2019;s Chemistry of Cement and Concrete. 5th ed. Elsevier Ltd.; Amsterdam, The Netherlands: 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/C2013-0-19325-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel G., Sachdeva P., Chaudhary A.K., Singh Y. The use of nanomaterials in concrete: A review. Mater. Today Proc. 2022;69:365&#x2013;371. doi: 10.1016/j.matpr.2022.09.051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2022.09.051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reches Y. Nanoparticles as concrete additives: Review and perspectives. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;175:483&#x2013;495. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.04.214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.04.214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo D.Y., Oh T., Banthia N. Nanomaterials in ultra-high-performance concrete (UHPC)&#x2014;A review. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2022;134:104730. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silvestre J., Silvestre N., de Brito J. Review on concrete nanotechnology. Eur. J. Environ. Civ. Eng. 2015;20:455&#x2013;485. doi: 10.1080/19648189.2015.1042070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19648189.2015.1042070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L., Wang B., Hubler M.H. Carbon nanofibers (CNFs) dispersed in ultra-high performance concrete (UHPC): Mechanical property, workability and permeability investigation. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2022;131:104592. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104592.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piro N.S., Salih A., Hamad S.M., Kurda R. Comprehensive multiscale techniques to estimate the compressive strength of concrete incorporated with carbon nanotubes at various curing times and mix proportions. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2021;15:6506&#x2013;6527. doi: 10.1016/j.jmrt.2021.11.028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2021.11.028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abhilash P.P., Nayak D.K., Sangoju B., Kumar R., Kumar V. Effect of nano-silica in concrete; a review. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;278:122347. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu R., Xiao H., Geng J., Du J., Liu M. Effect of nano-CaCO3 and nano-SiO2 on improving the properties of carbon fibre-reinforced concrete and their pore-structure models. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;244:118297. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansari rad T., Tanzadeh J., Pourdada A. Laboratory evaluation of self-compacting fiber-reinforced concrete modified with hybrid of nanomaterials. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;232:117211. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruan Y., Han B., Yu X., Zhang W., Wang D. Carbon nanotubes reinforced reactive powder concrete. Compos. Part A Appl. Sci. Manuf. 2018;112:371&#x2013;382. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesa.2018.06.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesa.2018.06.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalaf M.A., Cheah C.B., Ramli M., Ahmed N.M., Al-Shwaiter A. Effect of nano zinc oxide and silica on mechanical, fluid transport and radiation attenuation properties of steel furnace slag heavyweight concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;274:121785. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maohua Z., Zhengyi L., Jiyin C., Zenong T., Zhiyi L. Durability of marine concretes with nanoparticles under combined action of bending load and salt spray erosion. Adv. Mater. Sci. Eng. 2022;2022:1968770. doi: 10.1155/2022/1968770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/1968770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khooshechin M., Tanzadeh J. Experimental and mechanical performance of shotcrete made with nanomaterials and fiber reinforcement. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;165:199&#x2013;205. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.12.199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.12.199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed T.I., El-Shafai N.M., El-Mehasseb I.M., Sharshir S.W., Tobbala D.E. Recent advances in the heating resistance, thermal gravimetric analysis, and microstructure of green concrete incorporating palm-leaf and cotton-stalk nanoparticles. J. Build. Eng. 2022;61:105252. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2022.105252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.105252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan J., Liu X., Wang X., Wang L., Weng W., Yu X., Xing G., Xie J., Lu C., Luo Y., et al. Influence of nano-attapulgite on compressive strength and microstructure of recycled aggregate concrete. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2022;134:104788. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narasimman K., Jassam T.M., Velayutham T., Yaseer M., Ruzaimah R. The synergic influence of carbon nanotube and nanosilica on the compressive strength of lightweight concrete. J. Build. Eng. 2020;32:101719. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du S., Ge Y., Shi X. A targeted approach of employing nano-materials in high-volume fly ash concrete. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2019;104:103390. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2019.103390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2019.103390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Ding S., Qiu L., Ashour A., Wang Y., Han B., Ou J. Improving bond of fiber-reinforced polymer bars with concrete through incorporating nanomaterials. Compos. B Eng. 2022;239:109960. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2022.109960.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2022.109960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia H., Cui B., Niu G., Chen J., Yang Y., Wang Q., Tang C. Experimental and mechanism study on the impermeability and thermal insulation of foam concrete regulated by nano-silica and fluorine-free foam. J. Build. Eng. 2023;64:105675. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2022.105675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.105675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahpari M., Khaloo A., Rashidi A., Saberian M., Li J. Synergetic effects of hybrid nano-blended cement on mechanical properties of conventional concrete: Experimental and analytical evaluation. Structures. 2023;48:1519&#x2013;1536. doi: 10.1016/j.istruc.2023.01.066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2023.01.066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng T., Ying K., Yang X., Hong Y. Comparative study on mechanisms for improving mechanical properties and microstructure of cement paste modified by different types of nanomaterials. Nanotechnol. Rev. 2021;10:370&#x2013;384. doi: 10.1515/ntrev-2021-0027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/ntrev-2021-0027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Lu H., Wang J., He H. Effects of Highly Crystalized Nano C-S-H Particles on Performances of Portland Cement Paste and Its Mechanism. Crystals. 2020;10:816. doi: 10.3390/cryst10090816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cryst10090816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., He X., Deng X., Wu Y., Zheng Z., Liu J., Hui D. Application of nanomaterials in ultra-high performance concrete: A review. Nanotechnol. Rev. 2020;9:1427&#x2013;1444. doi: 10.1515/ntrev-2020-0107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/ntrev-2020-0107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B., Yao W., Stephan D. Preparation of calcium silicate hydrate seeds by means of mechanochemical method and its effect on the early hydration of cement. Adv. Mech. Eng. 2019;11:168781401984058. doi: 10.1177/1687814019840586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1687814019840586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Land G., Stephan D. Controlling cement hydration with nanoparticles. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2015;57:64&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2014.12.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2014.12.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue Q., Ni C., Wu Q., Yu Z., Shen X. Effects of Nano-CSH on the hydration process and mechanical property of cementitious materials. J. Sustain. Cem.-Based Mater. 2021;11:378&#x2013;388. doi: 10.1080/21650373.2021.1972487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21650373.2021.1972487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakamy A., Shaikh F., Low I. Characteristics of nanoclay and calcined nanoclay-cement nanocomposites. Compos. Part B Eng. 2015;78:174&#x2013;184. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2015.03.074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2015.03.074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuenyongsuwan J., Sinthupinyo S., O&#x2019;Rear E.A., Pongprayoon T. Hydration accelerator and photocatalyst of nanotitanium dioxide synthesized via surfactant-assisted method in cement mortar. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2019;96:182&#x2013;193. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2018.11.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2018.11.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khamchin F., Rasiah S., Sirivivatnanon V. Properties of Metakaolin Concrete&#x2014;A Review; Proceedings of the International Conference on Sustainable Structural Concrete; La Plata, Argentina. 15&#x2013;18 September 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazari A., Riahi S. The effects of ZrO2 nanoparticles on physical and mechanical properties of high strength self-compacting concrete. Mater. Res. 2010;13:551&#x2013;556. doi: 10.1590/S1516-14392010000400019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1516-14392010000400019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devi S.C., Khan R.A. Compressive strength and durability behavior of graphene oxide reinforced concrete composites containing recycled concrete aggregate. J. Build. Eng. 2020;32:101800. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang P., Su J., Guo J., Hu S. Influence of carbon nanotube on properties of concrete: A review. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;369:130388. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.130388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.130388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Han B., Li Z., Yu X., Dong X. Effect Investigation of Nanofillers on C-S-H Gel Structure with Si NMR. J. Mater. Civ. Eng. 2019;31:04018352. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0002559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0002559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long G., Li Y., Ma C., Xie Y., Shi Y. Hydration kinetics of cement incorporating different nanoparticles at elevated temperatures. Thermochim. Acta. 2018;664:108&#x2013;117. doi: 10.1016/j.tca.2018.04.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tca.2018.04.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y., Zhang P., Guo W., Bao J., Qu C. Effect of Nano-CaCO3 on the mechanical properties and durability of concrete incorporating Fly Ash. Adv. Mater. Sci. Eng. 2020;2020:7365862. doi: 10.1155/2020/7365862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/7365862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussien R.M., Abd el-Hafez L., Mohamed R., Faried A.S., Fahmy N.G. Influence of nano waste materials on the mechanical properties, microstructure, and corrosion resistance of self-compacted concrete. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2022;16:e00859. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G., Chen X., Zhang Y., Zhuang Z., Lv Y. Studies of nano-SiO2 and subsequent water curing on enhancing the frost resistance of autoclaved PHC pipe pile concrete. J. Build. Eng. 2023;69:106209. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren J., Lai Y., Gao J. Exploring the influence of SiO2 and TiO2 nanoparticles on the mechanical properties of concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;175:277&#x2013;285. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.04.181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.04.181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu D., Wang D., Wang Y., Zhong J. Nano-engineering the interfacial transition zone between recycled concrete aggregates and fresh paste with graphene oxide. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;384:131244. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.131244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.131244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Xie X., Liu R., Lyu K., Zuo J., Li S., Liu L., Shah S.P. Research on the durability of nano-SiO2 and sodium silicate co-modified recycled coarse aggregate (RCA) concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;378:131185. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.131185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.131185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faried A.S., Mostafa S.A., Tayeh B.A., Tawfik T.A. Mechanical and durability properties of ultra-high performance concrete incorporated with various nano waste materials under different curing conditions. J. Build. Eng. 2021;43:102569. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2021.102569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2021.102569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y., He B., Li Y., Tang J., Qu L. Effects of nano-particles on improvement in wear resistance and drying shrinkage of road fly ash concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2017;151:228&#x2013;235. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.06.080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.06.080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fahmy N.G., Hussien R.M., el-Hafez L.A., Mohamed R., Faried A.S. Comparative study on fresh, mechanical, microstructures properties and corrosion resistance of self compacted concrete incorporating nanoparticles extracted from industrial wastes under various curing conditions. J. Build. Eng. 2022;57:104874. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asadi I., Shafigh P., Hassan Z.F.B.A., Mahyuddin N.B. Thermal conductivity of concrete&#x2014;A review. J. Build. Eng. 2018;20:81&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2018.07.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2018.07.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saif M.S., Shanour A.S., Abdelaziz G.E., Elsayad H.I., Shaaban I.G., Tayeh B.A., Hammad M.S. Influence of blended powders on properties of ultra-high strength fibre reinforced self compacting concrete subjected to elevated temperatures. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2023;18:e01793. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Q., Guo R., Zhao Z., Lin Z., He K. Mechanical properties of concrete at high temperature&#x2014;A review. Constr. Build. Mater. 2015;93:371&#x2013;383. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.05.131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.05.131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almasaeid H.H., Suleiman A., Alawneh R. Assessment of high-temperature damaged concrete using non-destructive tests and artificial neural network modelling. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2022;16:e01080. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao Y., Liu H., Wang X., Zhang Y., Luo G., Gong Y. Temperature effect on mechanical properties and damage identification of concrete structure. Adv. Mater. Sci. Eng. 2014;2014:191360. doi: 10.1155/2014/191360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2014/191360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin S., Wang Y., Suzuki Y. High-temperature CaO hydration/Ca(OH)2 decomposition over a multitude of cycles. Energy Fuels. 2009;23:2855&#x2013;2861. doi: 10.1021/ef801088x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ef801088x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janotka I., N&#xfc;rnbergerov&#xe1; T. Effect of temperature on structural quality of the cement paste and high-strength concrete with silica fume. Nucl. Eng. Des. 2005;235:2019&#x2013;2032. doi: 10.1016/j.nucengdes.2005.05.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nucengdes.2005.05.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali M.H., Dinkha Y.Z., Haido J.H. Mechanical properties and spalling at elevated temperature of high performance concrete made with reactive and waste inert powders. Eng. Sci. Technol. 2017;20:536&#x2013;541. doi: 10.1016/j.jestch.2016.12.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jestch.2016.12.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed H., Ahmed H., Kurda R., Alyousef R., Deifalla A.F. Heat-induced spalling of concrete: A review of the influencing factors and their importance to the phenomenon. Materials. 2022;15:1693. doi: 10.3390/ma15051693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15051693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8910905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35268924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kannangara T., Joseph P., Fragomeni S., Guerrieri M. Existing theories of concrete spalling and test methods relating to moisture migration patterns upon exposure to elevated temperatures&#x2014;A review. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2022;16:e01111. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeiml M., Leithner D., Lackner R., Mang H.A. How do polypropylene fibers improve the spalling behavior of in-situ concrete? Cem. Concr. Res. 2006;36:929&#x2013;942. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2005.12.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2005.12.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao J., Zheng R., Sun Y., Zhang P., Cui Y., Xue S., Song Q.A. state-of-the-art review on high temperature resistance of lightweight aggregate high-strength concrete. J. Build. Eng. 2023;69:106267. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu D., Tang Z., Zhang L., Zhou J., Gong Y., Tian Y., Zhong J. Effects of combined usage of supplementary cementitious materials on the thermal properties and microstructure of high-performance concrete at high temperatures. Materials. 2020;13:1833. doi: 10.3390/ma13081833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma13081833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7215796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32295001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sikora P., Abd Elrahman M., Stephan D. The influence of nanomaterials on the thermal resistance of cement-based composites&#x2014;A review. Nanomaterials. 2018;8:465. doi: 10.3390/nano8070465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nano8070465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6070830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29949903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brzozowski P., Strza&#x142;kowski J., Rychtowski P., Wr&#xf3;bel R., Tryba B., Horszczaruk E. Effect of nano-SiO2 on the microstructure and mechanical properties of concrete under high temperature conditions. Materials. 2022;15:166. doi: 10.3390/ma15010166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15010166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8745793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35009312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar R., Singh S., Singh L.P. Studies on enhanced thermally stable high strength concrete incorporating silica nanoparticles. Constr. Build. Mater. 2017;153:506&#x2013;513. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.07.057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.07.057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastami M., Baghbadrani M., Aslani F. Performance of nano-silica modified high strength concrete at elevated temperatures. Constr. Build. Mater. 2014;68:402&#x2013;408. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.06.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.06.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah A.H., Sharma U.K., Roy D.A.B., Bhargava P. MATEC Web of Conferences. EDP Sciences; Les Ulis, France: 2013. Spalling behaviour of nano SiO2 high strength concrete at elevated temperatures; p. 01009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W.-C. Compressive strength and thermal conductivity of concrete with nanoclay under various high-temperatures. Constr. Build. Mater. 2017;147:305&#x2013;311. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.04.141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.04.141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu H., Jiang J., Sun W., Zhang M. Effects of graphene sulfonate nanosheets on mechanical and thermal properties of sacrificial concrete during high temperature exposure. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2017;82:252&#x2013;264. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2017.06.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2017.06.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikbin I.M., Rafiee A., Dezhampanah S., Mehdipour S.S., Mohebbi R., Moghadam H.H., Sadrmomtazi A. Effect of high temperature on the radiation shielding properties of cementitious composites containing nano-Bi2O3. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2020;9:11135&#x2013;11153. doi: 10.1016/j.jmrt.2020.08.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2020.08.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikbin I.M., Mehdipour S., Dezhampanah S., Mohammadi R., Mohebbi R., Moghadam H.H., Sadrmomtazi A. Effect of high temperature on mechanical and gamma ray shielding properties of concrete containing nano-TiO2. Radiat. Phys. Chem. 2020;174:108967. doi: 10.1016/j.radphyschem.2020.108967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.radphyschem.2020.108967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pachideh G., Gholhaki M., Moshtagh A., Felaverjani M.K. An Investigation on the effect of high temperatures on the mechanical properties and microstructure of concrete containing multiwalled carbon nanotubes. Mater. Perform. Charact. 2018;8:503&#x2013;517. doi: 10.1520/MPC20180061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1520/MPC20180061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakthirswaran N., Jeyamurugan A., Sophia M., Suresh P. Effect of elevated temperatures on the properties of nano alumina modified concrete containing zircon sand as fine aggregate. Rom. J. Mater. 2020;50:175&#x2013;182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed A., Sanjayan J.G., Nazari A., Al-Saadi N.T.K. Effects of graphene oxide in enhancing the performance of concrete exposed to high-temperature. Aust. J. Civ. Eng. 2017;15:61&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1080/14488353.2017.1372849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14488353.2017.1372849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy L.S.I., Vijayalakshmi M.M., Praveenkumar T.R. Thermal conductivity and strength properties of nanosilica and GGBS incorporated concrete specimens. Silicon. 2022;14:145&#x2013;151. doi: 10.1007/s12633-020-00813-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12633-020-00813-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherif M.A. Effect of elevated temperature on mechanical properties of nano materials concrete. Int. J. Innov. Res. Sci. Eng. Technol. 2017;7:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shalby O.B., Elkady H.M., Nasr E.A.R., Kohail M. Assessment of mechanical and fire resistance for hybrid nano-clay and steel fibres concrete at different curing ages. J. Struct. Fire Eng. 2019;11:189&#x2013;203. doi: 10.1108/JSFE-06-2019-0024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/JSFE-06-2019-0024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahish H.A., Almutairi A.D. Effect of elevated temperatures on the compressive strength of nano-silica and nano-clay modified concretes using response surface methodology. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2023;18:e02032. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nijland T., Larbi J. Microscopic Examination of Deteriorated Concrete in Non-Destructive Evaluation of Reinforced Concrete Structures: Deterioration Processes and Standard Test Methods. Volume 1. Woodhead Publishing; Cambridge, UK: 2010. pp. 137&#x2013;179. Woodhead Publishing Series in Civil and Structural Engineering.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1533/9781845699536.2.137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensted J., Rbrough A., Page M. Chemical Degradation of Concrete in Durability of Concrete and Cement Composites. Woodhead Publishing; Cambridge, UK: 2007. pp. 86&#x2013;135. Woodhead Publishing Series in Civil and Structural Engineering.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1533/9781845693398.86</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyer T. Influence of cement type on resistance to organic acids. Mag. Concr. Res. 2017;69:175&#x2013;200. doi: 10.1680/jmacr.16.00271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1680/jmacr.16.00271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong Z., Wan Y., Wang P., Chen Z., He X., Hui X. Effect of long-term acid attack on impermeability and microstructure of compacted cement-bound soils. Environ. Technol. 2022:1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1080/09593330.2022.2093136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09593330.2022.2093136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35730580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zivica V., Bajza A. Acidic attack of cement based materials&#x2014;A review. Constr. Build. Mater. 2001;15:331&#x2013;340. doi: 10.1016/S0950-0618(01)00012-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0950-0618(01)00012-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariam Ninan C., Ajay A., Ramaswamy K.P., Thomas A.V., Bertron A. A critical review on the effect of organic acids on cement-based materials. IOP Conf. Ser. Earth Environ. Sci. 2020;491:012045. doi: 10.1088/1755-1315/491/1/012045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1755-1315/491/1/012045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diab A.M., Elyamany H.E., Abd Elmoaty A.E.M., Sreh M.M. Effect of nanomaterials additives on performance of concrete resistance against magnesium sulfate and acids. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;210:210&#x2013;231. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.03.099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.03.099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahdikhani M., Bamshad, Shirvani F. Mechanical properties and durability of concrete specimens containing nano silica in sulfuric acid rain condition. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;167:929&#x2013;935. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.01.137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.01.137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sujay H., Nair N.A., Sudarsana Rao H., Sairam V. Experimental study on durability characteristics of composite fiber reinforced high-performance concrete incorporating nanosilica and ultra fine fly ash. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;262:120738. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Praveenkumar T., Vijayalakshmi M., Meddah M. Strengths and durability performances of blended cement concrete with TiO2 nanoparticles and rice husk ash. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;217:343&#x2013;351. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.05.045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.05.045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao R., Yang J., Li G., Zhou Q., Niu M. Durability performance of multi-walled carbon nanotube reinforced ordinary Portland/calcium sulfoaluminate cement composites to sulfuric acid attack at early stage. Mater. Today Commun. 2023;35:105748. doi: 10.1016/j.mtcomm.2023.105748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtcomm.2023.105748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piasta W. Analysis of carbonate and sulphate attack on concrete structures. Eng. Fail. Anal. 2017;79:606&#x2013;614. doi: 10.1016/j.engfailanal.2017.05.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2017.05.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elahi M.M.A., Shearer C.R., Naser Rashid Reza A., Saha A.K., Khan M.N.N., Hossain M.M., Sarker P.K. Improving the sulfate attack resistance of concrete by using supplementary cementitious materials (SCMs): A review. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;281:122628. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh G., Saini B. Nanomaterial in cement industry: A brief review. Innov. Infrastruct. Solut. 2022;7:45. doi: 10.1007/s41062-021-00649-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41062-021-00649-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Zeng D., Ueda T., Fan Y., Li C., Li J. Beneficial effect of nanomaterials on the interfacial transition zone (ITZ) of non-dispersible underwater concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;293:123472. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayabhaskar A., Shanmugasundaram M. Enhancing the durability properties of concrete prepared with multiwalled carbon nanotubes. Electron. J. Struct. Eng. 2018;18:117&#x2013;127. doi: 10.56748/ejse.182712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.56748/ejse.182712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reshma T.V., Manjunatha M., Bharath A., Tangadagi R.B., Vengala J., Manjunatha L. Influence of ZnO and TiO2 on mechanical and durability properties of concrete prepared with and without polypropylene fibers. Materialia. 2021;18:101138. doi: 10.1016/j.mtla.2021.101138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtla.2021.101138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moslemi A.M., Khosravi A., Izadinia M., Heydari M. Application of nano silica in concrete for enhanced resistance against sulfate attack. Adv. Mater. Res. 2013;829:874&#x2013;878. doi: 10.4028/www.scientific.net/AMR.829.874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4028/www.scientific.net/AMR.829.874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sathe S., Zain Kangda M., Amaranatha G. Resistance against sulphate attack in concrete by addition of nano alumina. Mater. Today Proc. 2022;60:294&#x2013;298. doi: 10.1016/j.matpr.2022.01.124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2022.01.124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vishwakarma V., Uthaman S., Dasnamoorthy R., Kanagasabai V. Investigation on surface sulfate attack of nanoparticle-modified fly ash concrete. Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res. 2020;27:41372&#x2013;41380. doi: 10.1007/s11356-020-10134-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-020-10134-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32681340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T., Cao L., Zhang F., Luo J., Jiang S., Chu H., Jiang L. Reduction of SO42&#x2212; and Cl&#x2212; migration rates and degradation of silica nanoparticles incorporated cement pastes exposed to co-existence of sulfate, chloride and electric fields. Constr. Build. Mater. 2022;344:128234. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.128234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.128234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu F., Ma Z., Zhang M. Chloride penetration into concrete under the coupling effects of internal and external relative humidity. Adv. Civ. Eng. 2020;2020:1468717. doi: 10.1155/2020/1468717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/1468717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu J., Zhang S., Chen E., Li W. A review on corrosion detection and protection of existing reinforced concrete (RC) structures. Constr. Build. Mater. 2022;325:126718. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.126718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.126718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D., Li L.Y., Wang X. Chloride diffusion model for concrete in marine environment with considering binding effect. Mar. Struct. 2019;66:44&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1016/j.marstruc.2019.03.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marstruc.2019.03.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh L., Bhattacharyya S., Sharma U., Mishra G., Ahalawat S. Microstructure improvement of cementitious systems using nanomaterials: A key for enhancing the durability of concrete; Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Creep, Shrinkage, and Durability Mechanics (CONCREEP-9); Cambridge, MA, USA. 22&#x2013;25 September 2013;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/9780784413111.034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezakhani D., Jafari A., Hajabassi M. Durability, mechanical properties and rebar corrosion of slag-based cement concrete modified with graphene oxide. Structures. 2023;49:678&#x2013;697. doi: 10.1016/j.istruc.2023.01.149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2023.01.149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Hunag X., Wu Y.Y., Deng X., Zheng Z., Yang B. Studies on mechanical properties and durability of steel fiber reinforced concrete incorporating graphene oxide. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2022;130:104508. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M., Du L., Li Z., Xu R. Durability of marine concrete doped with nanoparticles under joint action of Cl- erosion and carbonation. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2023;18:e01982. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e01982.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e01982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshaghani A., Balapour M., Mashhadian M., Ozbakkaloglu T. Effects of nano-TiO2, nano-Al2O3, and nano-Fe2O3 on rheology, mechanical and durability properties of self-consolidating concrete (SCC): An experimental study. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;245:118444. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T., Xu J., Meng B., Peng G. Experimental study on the effect of carbon nanofiber content on the durability of concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;250:118891. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C. Chloride permeability and chloride binding capacity of nano-modified concrete. J. Build. Eng. 2021;41:102419. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2021.102419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2021.102419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T., Liu X., Wei Z., Zhao Y., Yan D. Study on the wear-resistant mechanism of concrete based on wear theory. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;271:121594. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaz&#x131;c&#x131;, &#x130;nan G. An investigation on the wear resistance of high strength concretes. Wear. 2006;260:615&#x2013;618. doi: 10.1016/j.wear.2005.03.028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wear.2005.03.028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adewuyi A.P., Sulaiman I.A., Akinyele J.O. Compressive strength and abrasion resistance of concretes under varying exposure conditions. Open J. Civ. Eng. 2017;07:82&#x2013;99. doi: 10.4236/ojce.2017.71005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/ojce.2017.71005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H., Zhang M.H., Ou J.P. Abrasion resistance of concrete containing nano-particles for pavement. Wear. 2006;260:1262&#x2013;1266. doi: 10.1016/j.wear.2005.08.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wear.2005.08.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D., Zhang W., Ruan Y., Yu X., Han B. Enhancements and mechanisms of nanoparticles on wear resistance and chloride penetration resistance of reactive powder concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;189:487&#x2013;497. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.09.041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.09.041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghoddousi P., Zareechian M., Shirzadi Javid A.A., Habibnejad Korayem A. Microstructural study and surface properties of concrete pavements containing nanoparticles. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;262:120103. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Jin M., Guo F., Wang Y., Tang S. Pore structural and fractal analysis of the influence of fly ash and silica fume on the mechanical property and abrasion resistance of concrete. Fractals. 2021;29:2140003. doi: 10.1142/S0218348X2140003X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1142/S0218348X2140003X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polat R., Demirbo&#x11f;a R., Karag&#xf6;l F. The effect of nano-MgO on the setting time, autogenous shrinkage, microstructure and mechanical properties of high performance cement paste and mortar. Constr. Build. Mater. 2017;156:208&#x2013;218. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.08.168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.08.168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J. Recent advance of MgO expansive agent in cement and concrete. J. Build. Eng. 2022;45:103633. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Zeng X., Li Y., Yang H., Tang S. Influences of MgO and PVA fiber on the abrasion and cracking resistance, pore structure and fractal features of hydraulic concrete. Fractal Fract. 2022;6:674. doi: 10.3390/fractalfract6110674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/fractalfract6110674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdchi M., Foroughi Asl A., Talatahari S., Gandomi A.H. Evaluation of the mechanical properties of normal concrete containing nano-MgO under freeze&#x2013;thaw conditions by evolutionary intelligence. Appl. Sci. 2021;11:2529. doi: 10.3390/app11062529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app11062529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Q., Kaikai Yu K., Zenan Zhang Z. Expansion of ordinary Portland cement paste varied with nano-MgO. Constr. Build. Mater. 2015;78:189&#x2013;193. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.12.113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.12.113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradpour R., Taheri-Nassaj E., Parhizkar T., Ghodsian M. The effects of nanoscale expansive agents on the mechanical properties of non-shrink cement-based composites: The influence of nano-MgO addition. Compos. Part B Eng. 2014;55:193&#x2013;202. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2013.06.033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2013.06.033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Y., Liu Y., Shi T., Hu Z., Zhong L., Wang H., Chen Y. Effect of nano-magnesium oxide on the expansion performance and hydration process of cement-based materials. Materials. 2021;14:3766. doi: 10.3390/ma14133766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma14133766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8269875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34279336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>