<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38680312</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-1343</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>16</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS omega</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Omega</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nanoscale Stabilization Mechanism of Sodium Sulfate Decahydrate at Polyelectrolyte Interfaces.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>18051</StartPage><EndPage>18061</EndPage><MedlinePgn>18051-18061</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsomega.3c09796</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sodium sulfate decahydrate (SSD) is a low-cost phase-change material (PCM) for thermal energy storage applications that offers substantial melting enthalpy and a suitable temperature range for near-ambient applications. However, SSD's consistent phase separation with decreased melting enthalpy over repeated thermal cycles limits its application as a PCM. Sulfonated polyelectrolytes, such as dextran sulfate sodium (DSS), have shown great effectiveness in preventing phase separation in SSD. However, there is limited understanding of the stabilization mechanism of SSD by DSS at the atomic length and time scales. In this work, we investigate SSD stabilization via DSS using neutron scattering and molecular dynamics (MD) simulations. Neutron scattering and pair distribution function analysis revealed the structural evolution of the PCM samples below and above the phase change temperatures. MD simulations revealed that water from the hydrate structure migrates from the hydrate crystal to the SSD-DSS interfacial region upon melting. The water is stabilized at this interface by aggregation around the hydrophilic sulfonic acid groups attached to the backbone of the polyelectrolyte. This architecture retains water near the dehydrated sodium sulfate, preventing phase separation and, consequently, stabilizing SSD rehydration. This work provides atomistic insight into selecting and designing stable and high-performance PCMs for heating and cooling applications in building technologies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akamo</LastName><ForeName>Damilola O</ForeName><Initials>DO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Bredesen Center for Interdisciplinary Research and Graduate Education, University of Tennessee, Knoxville, Tennessee 37996, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Buildings and Transportation Sciences Division, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Oak Ridge, Tennessee 37830, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cladek</LastName><ForeName>Bernadette</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8538-6827</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Materials Science and Engineering Department, University of Tennessee, Knoxville, Tennessee 37996, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goswami</LastName><ForeName>Monojoy</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4473-4888</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chemical Sciences Division, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Oak Ridge, Tennessee 37830, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gluesenkamp</LastName><ForeName>Kyle R</ForeName><Initials>KR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Buildings and Transportation Sciences Division, Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Oak Ridge, Tennessee 37830, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rios</LastName><ForeName>Orlando</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Materials Science and Engineering Department, University of Tennessee, Knoxville, Tennessee 37996, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keffer</LastName><ForeName>David J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6246-0286</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Materials Science and Engineering Department, University of Tennessee, Knoxville, Tennessee 37996, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Omega</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101691658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-1343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing financial interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38680312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11044206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.3c09796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fais B.; Sabio N.; Strachan N. The critical role of the industrial sector in reaching long-term emission reduction, energy efficiency and renewable targets. Appl. Energy 2016, 162, 699&#x2013;712. 10.1016/j.apenergy.2015.10.112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2015.10.112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S.; Liu P.; Li Z. Low carbon transition pathway of power sector with high penetration of renewable energy. Renewable Sustainable Energy Rev. 2020, 130, 109985. 10.1016/j.rser.2020.109985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2020.109985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira da Cunha J.; Eames P. Thermal energy storage for low and medium temperature applications using phase change materials &#x2013; A review. Appl. Energy 2016, 177, 227&#x2013;238. 10.1016/j.apenergy.2016.05.097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2016.05.097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeinelabdein R.; Omer S.; Gan G. Critical review of latent heat storage systems for free cooling in buildings. Renewable Sustainable Energy Rev. 2018, 82, 2843&#x2013;2868. 10.1016/j.rser.2017.10.046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2017.10.046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raul A.; Jain M.; Gaikwad S.; Saha S. K. Modelling and experimental study of latent heat thermal energy storage with encapsulated PCMs for solar thermal applications. Appl. Therm. Eng. 2018, 143, 415&#x2013;428. 10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2018.07.123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2018.07.123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H.; Romagnoli A.; Sze J. Y.; Py X. Application of material assessment methodology in latent heat thermal energy storage for waste heat recovery. Appl. Energy 2017, 187, 281&#x2013;290. 10.1016/j.apenergy.2016.11.070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2016.11.070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao C. Y.; Ji Y.; Xu Z.
Investigation
of the Ca(NO<sub>3</sub>)<sub>2</sub>-NaNO<sub>3</sub> mixture for
latent heat storage. Sol. Energy Mater. Sol.
Cells
2015, 140, 281&#x2013;288. 10.1016/j.solmat.2015.04.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solmat.2015.04.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan Z.; Khan Z.; Ghafoor A. A review of performance enhancement of PCM based latent heat storage system within the context of materials, thermal stability and compatibility. Energy Convers. Manage. 2016, 115, 132&#x2013;158. 10.1016/j.enconman.2016.02.045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2016.02.045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar N.; Hirschey J.; LaClair T. J.; Gluesenkamp K. R.; Graham S. Review of stability and thermal conductivity enhancements for salt hydrates. J. Energy Storage 2019, 24, 100794. 10.1016/j.est.2019.100794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2019.100794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marks S. An investigation of the thermal energy storage capacity of Glauber&#x2019;s salt with respect to thermal cycling. Sol. Energy 1980, 25 (3), 255&#x2013;258. 10.1016/0038-092X(80)90332-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0038-092X(80)90332-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marks S. B. The effect of crystal size on the thermal energy storage capacity of thickened Glauber&#x2019;s Salt. Sol. Energy 1983, 30 (1), 45&#x2013;49. 10.1016/0038-092x(83)90005-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0038-092x(83)90005-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z.; Lian Y.; Xu X.; Xu X.; Xu X.; Gu M.; Gu M. Synthesis and characterization of microencapsulated sodium sulfate decahydrate as phase change energy storage materials. Appl. Energy 2019, 255, 113830. 10.1016/j.apenergy.2019.113830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2019.113830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islam M. N.; Ahmed D. H. Delaying the temperature fluctuations through PCM integrated building walls&#x2014;Room conditions, PCM placement, and temperature of the heat sources. Energy Storage 2021, 3 (5), e245 10.1002/est2.245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/est2.245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie N.; Luo J.; Li Z.; Huang Z.; Gao X.; Fang Y.; Zhang Z. Salt hydrate/expanded vermiculite composite as a form-stable phase change material for building energy storage. Sol. Energy Mater. Sol. Cells 2019, 189, 33&#x2013;42. 10.1016/j.solmat.2018.09.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solmat.2018.09.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L.; Lu G.; Qiu G.; Yue C.; Guo M.; Ji R.; Zhang M.
Characterization of
novel shape-stabilized phase change material
mortar: Portland cement containing Na <sub>2</sub> SO <sub>4</sub> &#xb7;10H <sub>2</sub> O and fly ash for energy-efficient building. Int. J. Energy Res.
2019, 43 (11), 5812&#x2013;5823. 10.1002/er.4681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/er.4681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akamo D. O.; Kumar N.; Li Y.; Pekol C.; Li K.; Goswami M.; Hirschey J.; LaClair T. J.; Keffer D. J.; Rios O.; et al. Stabilization of low-cost phase change materials for thermal energy storage applications. iScience 2023, 26 (7), 107175. 10.1016/j.isci.2023.107175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.isci.2023.107175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10329044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37426345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong X.; Mao J.; Geng S.; Li Y.; Hou P.; Lian H. Study on performance optimization of sodium sulfate decahydrate phase change energy storage materials. J. Therm. Anal. Calorim. 2021, 143 (6), 3923&#x2013;3934. 10.1007/s10973-020-09306-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10973-020-09306-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cong L.; Zou B.; Palacios A.; Navarro M. E.; Qiao G.; Ding Y. Thickening and gelling agents for formulation of thermal energy storage materials &#x2013; A critical review. Renewable Sustainable Energy Rev. 2022, 155, 111906. 10.1016/j.rser.2021.111906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2021.111906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiemei L.; Zixuan Z.; Hu H.; Rui Y. Sodium Polyacrylate/Sodium Sulfate Decahydrate Phase Change Composites. J. Funct. Polym. 2020, 33 (2), 157&#x2013;164. 10.14133/J.CNKI.1008-9357.20190301002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14133/J.CNKI.1008-9357.20190301002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabeza L. F.; Svensson G.; Hiebler S.; Mehling H. Thermal performance of sodium acetate trihydrate thickened with different materials as phase change energy storage material. Appl. Therm. Eng. 2003, 23 (13), 1697&#x2013;1704. 10.1016/S1359-4311(03)00107-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1359-4311(03)00107-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang M.; Zhang X.; Ji J.; Hua W.; Zhao Y.; Liang J. Optimal selection of thickeners for the phase change material of Na2S2O3&#xb7;5H2O&#x2013;CH3COONa&#xb7;3H2O. J. Therm. Anal. Calorim. 2021, 147 (15), 8177&#x2013;8188. 10.1007/s10973-021-11113-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10973-021-11113-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh K.; Kwon S.; Xu W.; Wang X.; Toivakka M. Effect of micro- and nanofibrillated cellulose on the phase stability of sodium sulfate decahydrate based phase change material. Cellulose 2020, 27 (9), 5003&#x2013;5016. 10.1007/s10570-020-03121-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10570-020-03121-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y.; Yu K.; Gao X.; Ren M.; Jia M.; Yang Y. Enhanced thermal properties of hydrate salt/poly (acrylate sodium) copolymer hydrogel as form-stable phase change material via incorporation of hydroxyl carbon nanotubes. Sol. Energy Mater. Sol. Cells 2020, 208, 110387. 10.1016/j.solmat.2019.110387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solmat.2019.110387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G.; Zhang B.; Li X.; Zhou Y.; Sun Q.; Yun Q. The preparation, characterization and modification of a new phase change material: CaCl2&#xb7;6H2O&#x2013;MgCl2&#xb7;6H2O eutectic hydrate salt. Sol. Energy Mater. Sol. Cells 2014, 126, 51&#x2013;55. 10.1016/j.solmat.2014.03.031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.solmat.2014.03.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akamo D. O.; Li K.; Turnaoglu T.; Kumar N.; Li Y.; Pekol C.; Bibhanshu N.; Goswami M.; Hirschey J.; LaClair T. J.; et al. Enhanced thermal reliability and performance of calcium chloride hexahydrate phase change material using cellulose nanofibril and graphene nanoplatelet. J. Energy Storage 2024, 75, 109560. 10.1016/j.est.2023.109560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2023.109560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riahinezhad M.; Kazemi N.; McManus N.; Penlidis A. Effect of ionic strength on the reactivity ratios of acrylamide/acrylic acid (sodium acrylate) copolymerization. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 2014, 131 (20), 40949. 10.1002/app.40949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/app.40949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mili&#xe1;n Y. E.; Guti&#xe9;rrez A.; Gr&#xe1;geda M.; Ushak S. A review on encapsulation techniques for inorganic phase change materials and the influence on their thermophysical properties. Renewable Sustainable Energy Rev. 2017, 73, 983&#x2013;999. 10.1016/j.rser.2017.01.159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2017.01.159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazir H.; Batool M.; Bolivar Osorio F. J.; Isaza-Ruiz M.; Xu X.; Vignarooban K.; Phelan P.; Inamuddin; Kannan A. M. Recent developments in phase change materials for energy storage applications: A review. Int. J. Heat Mass Transfer 2019, 129, 491&#x2013;523. 10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2018.09.126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2018.09.126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y.; Kumar N.; Hirschey J.; Akamo D. O.; Li K.; Tugba T.; Goswami M.; Orlando R.; LaClair T. J.; Graham S.; et al. Stable salt hydrate-based thermal energy storage materials. Composites, Part B 2022, 233, 109621. 10.1016/j.compositesb.2022.109621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2022.109621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goswami M.; Kumar N.; Li Y.; Hirschey J.; LaClair T. J.; Akamo D. O.; Sultan S.; Rios O.; Gluesenkamp K. R.; Graham S. Understanding supercooling mechanism in sodium sulfate decahydrate phase-change material. J. Appl. Phys. 2021, 129 (24), 245109. 10.1063/5.0049512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/5.0049512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sankar Deepa A.; Tewari A. Phase transition behaviour of hydrated Glauber&#x2019;s salt based phase change materials and the effect of ionic salt additives: A molecular dynamics study. Comput. Mater. Sci. 2022, 203, 111112. 10.1016/j.commatsci.2021.111112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.commatsci.2021.111112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neuefeind J.; Feygenson M.; Carruth J.; Hoffmann R.; Chipley K. K. The Nanoscale Ordered MAterials Diffractometer NOMAD at the Spallation Neutron Source SNS. Nucl. Instrum. Methods Phys. Res., Sect. B 2012, 287, 68&#x2013;75. 10.1016/j.nimb.2012.05.037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nimb.2012.05.037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mcnutt N. W.; Rios O.; Feygenson M.; Proffen T. E.; Keffer D. J. Structural analysis of lignin-derived carbon composite anodes. J. Appl. Crystallogr. 2014, 47, 1577&#x2013;1584. 10.1107/S1600576714014666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1107/S1600576714014666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tucker M. G.; Keen D. A.; Dove M. T.; Goodwin A. L.; Hui Q. RMCProfile: Reverse Monte Carlo for polycrystalline materials. J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 2007, 19 (33), 335218. 10.1088/0953-8984/19/33/335218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/0953-8984/19/33/335218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21694141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plimpton S. Fast Parallel Algorithms for Short-Range Molecular Dynamics. J. Comput. Phys. 1995, 117, 1&#x2013;19. 10.1006/jcph.1995.1039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/jcph.1995.1039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu M.; Every H. A.; Jiskoot W.; Witkamp G. J.; Buijs W. Molecular structure of dextran sulphate sodium in aqueous environment. J. Mol. Struct. 2018, 1156, 320&#x2013;329. 10.1016/j.molstruc.2017.11.090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molstruc.2017.11.090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanwell M. D.; Curtis D. E.; Lonie D. C.; Vandermeersch T.; Zurek E.; Hutchison G. R. Avogadro: an advanced semantic chemical editor, visualization, and analysis platform. J. Cheminf. 2012, 4 (1), 17. 10.1186/1758-2946-4-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1758-2946-4-17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3542060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22889332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamburov S.; Schmidt H.; Voigt W.; Balarew C. Similarities and peculiarities between the crystal structures of the hydrates of sodium sulfate and selenate. Acta Crystallogr., Sect. B: Struct. Sci., Cryst. Eng. Mater. 2014, 70 (4), 714&#x2013;722. 10.1107/s2052520614007653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1107/s2052520614007653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25080250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayo S. L.; Olafson B. D.; Goddard W. A. G. DREIDING: A Generic Force Field for Molecular Simulations. J. Phys. Chem. 1990, 94, 8897&#x2013;8909. 10.1021/j100389a010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/j100389a010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmid N.; Eichenberger A. P.; Choutko A.; Riniker S.; Winger M.; Mark A. E.; van Gunsteren W. F. Definition and testing of the GROMOS force-field versions 54A7 and 54B7. Eur. Biophys. J. 2011, 40 (7), 843&#x2013;856. 10.1007/s00249-011-0700-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00249-011-0700-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21533652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berendsen H. J. C.; Grigera J. R.; Straatsma T. P. The missing term in effective pair potentials. J. Phys. Chem. 1987, 91, 6269&#x2013;6271. 10.1021/j100308a038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/j100308a038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoover W. G. Canonical dynamics: Equilibrium phase-space distributions. Phys. Rev. A 1985, 31, 1695&#x2013;1697. 10.1103/PhysRevA.31.1695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevA.31.1695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9895674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nos&#xe9; S. A molecular dynamics method for simulations in the canonical ensemble. Mol. Phys. 2002, 100 (1), 191&#x2013;198. 10.1080/00268970110089108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00268970110089108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akamo D. O.; Ijaola A. O.; George T. T.; Page K.; Keffer D. J.; Li Y.; Goswami M.; LaClair T. J.; Gluesenkamp K.; Rios O. Bibliometric review and recent advances in total scattering pair distribution function analysis&#x202f;: 21 years in retrospect. Eur. J. Mater. 2022, 3 (1), 2150897. 10.1080/26889277.2022.2150897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/26889277.2022.2150897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christiansen T. L.; Cooper S. R.; Jensen K. M. &#xd8;. There&#x2019;s no place like real-space: elucidating size-dependent atomic structure of nanomaterials using pair distribution function analysis. Nanoscale Adv. 2020, 2, 2234&#x2013;2254. 10.1039/d0na00120a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d0na00120a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9418950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36133369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billinge S. J. L. The rise of the X-ray atomic pair distribution function method: a series of fortunate events. Philos. Trans. R. Soc., A 2019, 377 (2147), 20180413. 10.1098/rsta.2018.0413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rsta.2018.0413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6501893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31030657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X.; Tan S.; Yang X.-Q.; Hu E. Pair distribution function analysis: Fundamentals and application to battery materials. Chin. Phys. B 2020, 29 (2), 028802. 10.1088/1674-1056/ab6656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1674-1056/ab6656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui S.; Liu J.; Selvan M. E.; Keffer D. J.; Edwards B. J.; Steele W. V. A Molecular Dynamics Study of a Nafion Polyelectrolyte Membrane and the Aqueous Phase Structure for Proton Transport. J. Phys. Chem. B 2007, 111, 2208&#x2013;2218. 10.1021/jp066388n.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp066388n</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17288476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang S. S.; Lin S. T.; Maiti P. K.; Blanco M.; Goddard W. A.; Shuler P.; Tang Y. Molecular dynamics study of a surfactant-mediated decane-water interface: Effect of molecular architecture of alkyl benzene sulfonate. J. Phys. Chem. B 2004, 108 (32), 12130&#x2013;12140. 10.1021/jp048773n.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp048773n</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao Z.; Wang S.; Peng F. Self diffusion and heat capacity of n-alkanes based phase change materials: A molecular dynamics study. Int. J. Heat Mass Transfer 2013, 64, 581&#x2013;589. 10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2013.05.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2013.05.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun M.; Liu T.; Li M.; Liu T.; Wang X.; Chen G.; Jiang D. Experimental and molecular dynamic simulation of supercooling phenomenon of sodium acetate trihydrate. J. Energy Storage 2023, 62, 106956. 10.1016/j.est.2023.106956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2023.106956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>