<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39532684</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-3773</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>64</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Angewandte Chemie (International ed. in English)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Angew Chem Int Ed Engl</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effective Proton Conduction in Quasi-Solid Zinc-Manganese Batteries via Constructing Highly Connected Transfer Pathways.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e202417049</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e202417049</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/anie.202417049</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Elusive ion behaviors in aqueous electrolyte remain a challenge to break through the practicality of aqueous zinc-manganese batteries (AZMBs), a promising candidate for safe grid-scale energy storage systems. The proposed electrolyte strategies for this issue most ignore the prominent role of proton conduction, which greatly affects the operation stability of AZMBs. Here we report a water-poor quasi-solid electrolyte with efficient proton transfer pathways based on the large-space interlayer of montmorillonite and strong-hydration Pr<sup>3+</sup> additive in AZMBs. Proton conduction is deeply understood in this quasi-solid electrolyte. Pr<sup>3+</sup> additive not only dominates the proton conduction kinetics, but also regulates the reversible manganese interfacial deposition. As a result, the Cu@Zn||&#x3b1;-MnO<sub>2</sub> cell could achieve a high specific capacity of 433&#x2005;mAh&#x2009;g<sup>-1</sup> at 0.4&#x2005;mA&#x2009;cm<sup>-2</sup> and an excellent stability up to 800 cycles with a capacity retention of 92.2&#x2009;% at 0.8&#x2005;mA&#x2009;cm<sup>-2</sup> in such water-poor quasi-solid electrolyte for the first time. Ah-scale pouch cell with mass loading of 15.19&#x2005;mg&#x2009;cm<sup>-2</sup> sustains 100 cycles after initial activation, which is much better than its counterparts. Our work provides a new path for the development of zinc metal batteries with good sustainability and practicality.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Wiley-VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Zhexuan</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Key Laboratory of Electronic Packaging and Advanced Functional Materials of Hunan Province, Central South University, Changsha, 410083, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Central South University of Forestry &amp; Technology, Changsha, 410004, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qin</LastName><ForeName>Mulan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan Provincial Key Laboratory of Environmental Catalysis &amp; Waste Recycling, College of Materials and Chemical Engineering, Hunan Institute of Engineering, Xiangtan, 411104, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fu</LastName><ForeName>Biao</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Key Laboratory of Electronic Packaging and Advanced Functional Materials of Hunan Province, Central South University, Changsha, 410083, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Mingzhu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Key Laboratory of Electronic Packaging and Advanced Functional Materials of Hunan Province, Central South University, Changsha, 410083, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Shuquan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Key Laboratory of Electronic Packaging and Advanced Functional Materials of Hunan Province, Central South University, Changsha, 410083, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Guozhao</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2140-0145</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Key Laboratory of Electronic Packaging and Advanced Functional Materials of Hunan Province, Central South University, Changsha, 410083, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Energy Metal Resources and New Materials Key Laboratory, Central South University, Changsha, 410083, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>52072411</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>51932011</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023CXQD038</GrantID><Agency>Central South University Innovation-Driven Research Program</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>22B0741</GrantID><Agency>Scientific Research Fund of Hunan Provincial Education Department</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Angew Chem Int Ed Engl</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0370543</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1433-7851</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydrogen bond network</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">manganese deposition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">proton conduction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quasi-solid electrolyte</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">zinc-manganese batteries</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39532684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202417049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Pan, Y. Shao, P. Yan, Y. Cheng, K. S. Han, Z. Nie, C. Wang, J. Yang, X. Li, P. Bhattacharya, K. T. Mueller, J. Liu, Nat. Energy 2016, 1, 16039;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Chen, X. Xie, P. Ruan, S. Liang, W.-Y. Wong, G. Fang, ACS Energy Lett. 2024, 9, 2037&#x2013;2056.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Yuan, R. Sharpe, K. He, C. Li, M. T. Saray, T. Liu, W. Yao, M. Cheng, H. Jin, S. Wang, K. Amine, R. Shahbazian-Yassar, M. S. Islam, J. Lu, Nat. Sustain. 2022, 5, 890&#x2013;898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Song, L. Wang, L. Sheng, D. Ren, H. Liang, Y. Li, A. Wang, H. Zhang, H. Xu, X. He, Energy Environ. Sci. 2023, 16, 1943&#x2013;1963;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Song, L. Wang, L. Sheng, M. Zhang, H. Liang, D. Ren, H. Cui, H. Zhang, H. Xu, X. He, Energy Storage Mater. 2023, 63, 103018;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Zhao, X. Zhao, Y. Zhou, S. Liu, G. Fang, S. Liang, Adv. Powder Mater. 2023, 2, 100139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Chao, W. Zhou, C. Ye, Q. Zhang, Y. Chen, L. Gu, K. Davey, S. Z. Qiao, Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 2019, 58, 7823&#x2013;7828;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Wu, Y. Li, A. Amardeep, Y. Shao, Y. Zhang, J. Zou, L. Wang, J. Xu, D. Kasprzak, E. J. Hansen, J. Liu, Angew. Chem. 2024, 136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Cai, J. Wang, Y. Sun, eScience 2023, 3, 100093.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. F. Bischoff, O. S. Fitz, J. Burns, M. Bauer, H. Gentischer, K. P. Birke, H. M. Henning, D. Biro, J. Electrochem. Soc. 2020, 167, 020545.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Hu, Z. Liu, L. Li, S. Guo, X. Xie, Z. Luo, G. Fang, S. Liang, Natl. Sci. Rev. 2023, 10, nwad220;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Cui, D. Zhang, G. Zhang, Y. Gan, J. Mater. Chem. A 2022, 10, 25620&#x2013;25632;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Chen, S. Cai, Y. Wu, W. Wang, M. Xu, S. J. Bao, Mater. Today Energy 2021, 20, 100646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Zhang, J. Wang, X. Liu, P.-F. Wang, Y.-G. Liu, Y. Xie, T.-F. Yi, Composites Part B 2023, 260, 110770.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Z. Liu, Z. M. Qin, X. P. Yang, X. Q. Sun, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2022, 32, 2106994;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Zhou, L. Wang, J. Liang, C. Zhang, W. Peng, Y. Li, G. Zhang, F. Zhang, X. Fan, J. Mater. Chem. C 2021, 9, 1326&#x2013;1332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Zhou, H. J. Fan, D. Zhao, D. Chao, Natl. Sci. Rev. 2023, 10, nwad265;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Chen, A. Pan, W. Zhang, X. Cao, R. Lu, S. Liang, G. Cao, Sci. China Mater. 2020, 64, 1150&#x2013;1158;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Zhao, Y. Wang, C. Huang, Y. Gao, M. Huang, Y. Ding, X. Wang, Z. Si, D. Zhou, F. Kang, Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 2023, 62, e202312193;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Huang, X. Chi, J. Wu, J. Liu, Y. Liu, Chem. Eng. J. 2021, 430, 133058.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. He, F. Zhang, Y. Xin, C. Xu, X. Hu, X. Wu, Y. Yang, H. Tian, Nat. Chem. Rev. 2023, 7, 826&#x2013;842;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Manthiram, X. Yu, S. Wang, Nat. Rev. Mater. 2017, 2, 16103;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Chang, H. Yang, X. Zhu, P. He, H. Zhou, Nat. Commun. 2022, 13, 1510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Sun, H. Ma, X. Zhang, B. Liu, L. Liu, X. Zhang, J. Feng, Q. Zhang, Y. Ding, B. Yang, L. Qu, X. Yan, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2021, 31, 2101277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Hassanali, F. Giberti, J. Cuny, T. D. Kuhne, M. Parrinello, Proc. Nat. Acad. Sci. 2013, 110, 13723&#x2013;13728;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Shi, A. Xu, D. Pan, T. Zhao, Nat. Commun. 2019, 10, 1165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Sun, Q. Nian, X. Ren, Z. Tao, Joule 2023, 7, 2700&#x2013;2731;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Li, X. Wang, J. Meng, C. Zuo, B. Wu, C. Li, W. Sun, L. Mai, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, e2308628;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Wang, J. Yan, Y. Hong, Z. Yu, J. Chen, J. Zheng, Sci. Adv. 2023, 9, eadf4589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Shi, X. Pang, S. Li, H. Wu, J. Shen, X. Wang, C. Fan, L. Cao, T. Zhu, M. Qiu, Z. Yin, Y. Kong, Y. Liu, M. Zhang, Y. Liu, F. Pan, Z. Jiang, Nat. Commun. 2022, 13, 6666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Wang, Y. Fan, D. Liao, Y. Wu, Y. Yu, C. Hu, Energy Storage Mater. 2022, 51, 212&#x2013;222;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Tian, T. Hwang, S. Malakpour Estalaki, Y. Tian, L. Zhou, T. Milazzo, S. Moon, S. Wu, R. Jian, K. Balkus, T. Luo, K. Cho, G. Xiong, Adv. Energy Mater. 2023, 13, 2300782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Wang, H. Liu, D. Lv, C. Wang, J. Yang, Y. Qian, Adv. Mater. 2023, 35, e2207908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Guo, L. Qin, J. Wu, Z. Liu, Y. Huang, Y. Xie, G. Fang, S. Liang, Natl. Sci. Rev. 2024, 11, nwae181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Feng, L. Qiao, P. Zhou, H. Bai, C. Liu, C. C. Leong, Y.-Y. Chen, W. Fai, J. Ni, H. Pan, J. Mater. Chem. A 2023, 11, 316&#x2013;329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Shao, Q. Zhu, Y. Sun, Y. Zhang, Y. Jiang, S. Deng, W. Zhang, K. Huang, S. Feng, Adv. Mater. 2022, 34, 2110172;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Zhang, X. Feng, D. Rao, X. Deng, L. Cai, B. Qiu, R. Long, Y. Xiong, Y. Lu, Y. Chai, Nat. Commun. 2020, 11, 4066.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Xue, C. Sun, X. Chen, J. Rare Earth. 2017, 35, 837&#x2013;843.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Dereka, Q. Yu, N. H. C. Lewis, W. B. Carpenter, J. M. Bowman, A. Tokmakoff, Science 2021, 371, 160&#x2013;164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. M. Kock, M. Kogler, B. Klotzer, M. F. Noisternig, S. Penner, ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2016, 8, 16428&#x2013;16443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Li, G. Li, C. Li, H. Yang, G. Qin, X. Sun, F. Li, H. M. Cheng, ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2020, 12, 13790&#x2013;13796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Lu, C.-Z. Zhao, J.-Q. Huang, Q. Zhang, Joule 2022, 6, 1172&#x2013;1198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Gonz&#xe1;lez S&#xe1;nchez, L. R. Van Loon, T. Gimmi, A. Jakob, M. A. Glaus, L. W. Diamond, Appl. Geochem. 2008, 23, 3840&#x2013;3851.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. P. Gates, L. P. Aldridge, G. G. Carnero-Guzman, R. A. Mole, D. Yu, G. N. Iles, A. Klapproth, H. N. Bordallo, Appl. Clay Sci. 2017, 147, 97&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. S. Babu, C. Lim, J. Phys. Chem. B 1999, 103, 7958&#x2013;7968.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Tyagi, C. D. Chudasama, R. V. Jasra, Spectrochim. Acta Part A 2006, 64, 273&#x2013;278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Piechocki, M. Kozanecki, J. Saramak, Polymer 2020, 210, 122974.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Gong, Y. Liu, Y. Zhao, W. Liu, G. Zeng, G. Wang, Y. Zhang, L. Gong, J. Liu, Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 2023, 62, e202308091;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Chang, G. Wang, M. Wang, Q. Wang, B. Li, H. Zhou, Y. Zhu, W. Zhang, M. Omer, N. Orlovskaya, Q. Ma, M. Gu, Z. Feng, G. Wang, Y. Yang, Nat. Energy 2021, 6, 1144&#x2013;1153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Zhang, F. Cheng, J. Liu, L. Wang, X. Long, X. Liu, F. Li, J. Chen, Nat. Commun. 2017, 8, 405;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Dai, Y. Wang, L. Sun, Y. Ding, Y. Yao, L. Yao, N. E. Drewett, W. Zhang, J. Tang, W. Zheng, Adv. Sci. 2021, 8, 2004995;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Yang, W. Zhou, D. Chen, J. Liu, Z. Yuan, M. Lu, L. Shen, V. Shulga, W. Han, D. Chao, Energy Environ. Sci. 2022, 15, 1106&#x2013;1118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Liu, L. Li, L. Qin, S. Guo, G. Fang, Z. Luo, S. Liang, Adv. Mater. 2022, 34, e2204681.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Kim, J. Lee, Y. Kim, Y. Park, H. Kim, J. W. Choi, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2023, 145, 15776&#x2013;15787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Imbrogno, K. Maruyama, F. Rivers, J. R. Baltzegar, Z. Zhang, P. W. Meyer, V. Ganesan, S. Aoshima, N. A. Lynd, ACS Macro Lett. 2021, 10, 1002&#x2013;1007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K.-J. Wu, E. C. M. Tse, C. Shang, Z. Guo, Prog. Mater. Sci. 2022, 123, 100821.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. H. Wang, S. Zheng, W. M. Yang, R. Y. Zhou, Q. F. He, P. Radjenovic, J. C. Dong, S. Li, J. Zheng, Z. L. Yang, G. Attard, F. Pan, Z. Q. Tian, J. F. Li, Nature 2021, 600, 81&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Pan, Z. Liu, S. Liu, L. Qin, Y. Yang, M. Zhou, Y. Sun, X. Cao, S. Liang, G. Fang, Adv. Energy Mater. 2023, 13, 2203766;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Guo, J. Li, B. Zhang, W. Chen, G. Fang, M. Long, S. Liang, Sci. Bull. 2022, 67, 626&#x2013;635;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Xie, H. Fu, Y. Fang, B. Lu, J. Zhou, S. Liang, Adv. Energy Mater. 2021, 12, 2102393;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Gao, X. Xie, S. Liang, B. Lu, J. Zhou, Nano-Micro Lett. 2021, 13, 69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Chen, J. Chen, W. Zhou, X. Han, Y. Yao, C. P. Wong, Adv. Mater. 2021, 33, e2007559;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Huang, J. Zhang, J. Liu, Z. Li, S. Jin, Z. Li, S. Zhang, H. Zhou, Mater. Today Energy 2019, 14, 100349;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Huang, J. Liu, J. Zhang, S. Jin, Y. Jiang, S. Zhang, Z. Li, C. Zhi, G. Du, H. Zhou, RSC Adv. 2019, 9, 16313&#x2013;16319;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Li, Y. Wang, G. Jiang, J. Li, M. Wang, Y. Niu, E. Shangguan, Mater. Chem. Front. 2022, 6, 3193&#x2013;3204;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. F. Liu, C. Y. Zhu, Y. W. Ye, Y. H. Zhang, F. Cheng, H. R. Li, ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2022, 14, 25962&#x2013;25971;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Liu, R. Chen, L. Xu, Y. Liu, Y. Dai, M. Huang, L. Mai, ACS Energy Lett. 2022, 7, 2825&#x2013;2832;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Li, A. Azizi, S. Zhou, S. Liu, C. Han, Z. Chang, A. Pan, G. Cao, eScience 2024, 100294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. W. D. Gourley, R. Brown, B. D. Adams, D. Higgins, Joule 2023, 7, 1415&#x2013;1436.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>