<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41111505</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1663-9812</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in pharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Targeted liposomal nano-therapy combining anthocyanin and cisplatin reduces Ehrlich ascites carcinoma burden.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1659575</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1659575</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1659575</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fphar.2025.1659575</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Ehrlich ascites carcinoma (EAC), a rapidly growing tumor model, poses challenges in chemotherapy due to toxicity and resistance. Liposomal drug delivery improves anticancer therapy by enhancing bioavailability, targeting, and reducing systemic toxicity. Cisplatin (Cis), although effective, induces severe hepatic and renal toxicity. Anthocyanins (Ant), natural flavonoids with antioxidant and anticancer activities, can synergize with chemotherapy and reduce toxicity. This study evaluated three nano-liposomal formulations for EAC: Ant-loaded liposomes (Ant Ls), Cis-loaded liposomes (Cis Ls), and their combination (Cis + Ant Ls).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Nano-liposomes containing Cis and/or Ant were prepared by thin-film hydration, functionalized with folic acid for targeting, and characterized by TEM for size and morphology. Encapsulation efficiency and drug release (48&#xa0;h, dialysis) were determined. Cytotoxicity was tested on HCT 116 and Vero cells (MTT assay). Serum biochemical markers (ALT, AST, urea, and creatinine) were quantified, while tumor tissues were analyzed for apoptotic (caspase-3, Bcl2), inflammatory (IL1&#x3b2;), angiogenic (VEGF), metastatic (MMP9), and antioxidant (Nrf2, HO-1) genes using qPCR.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Ant Ls demonstrated a high encapsulation efficiency of 93.06% and exhibited sustained release profiles, achieving the highest cumulative drug release of 59.11% at 48&#xa0;h. Cis Ls and/or Ant Ls demonstrated significant cytotoxic (P &lt; 0.05) effects on HCT 116 colon cancer cells while exhibiting minimal toxicity to normal Vero cells. In comparison to untreated EAC controls, mice treated with Cis Ls and/or Ant Ls exhibited significantly (P &lt; 0.05) enhanced liver and renal function and structure, as evidenced by reductions in ALT, AST, urea, and creatinine and histopathology lesions. The treatments also decreased EAC burden as noticed by a reduction in total and viable tumor cell counts, and ascitic fluid volume, along with an increase in non-viable cells. The anticancer effect of Cis Ls and/or Ant Ls was attributed to multiple mechanisms, including increased apoptosis, reduced inflammation, inhibited angiogenesis, and suppression of metastasis. The combined treatment enhanced antioxidant defenses to mitigate Cis toxicity. The combination of Cis Ls and Ant Ls markedly decreased tumor burden and demonstrated therapeutic synergy, suggesting potential for improved outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Cis Ls and Ant Ls delivery strategy mitigates liver and kidney damage while enhancing anticancer efficacy against EAC.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Awad, El-Shafiey, Ali, Abd El-Monem, Badawy, Al-Serwi, El-Magd and Hanafy.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Awad</LastName><ForeName>Mai G</ForeName><Initials>MG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zoology Department, Faculty of Women for Arts, Science and Education, Ain Shams University, Cairo, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Shafiey</LastName><ForeName>Sara H</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zoology Department, Faculty of Women for Arts, Science and Education, Ain Shams University, Cairo, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ali</LastName><ForeName>Ramadan A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zoology Department, Faculty of Women for Arts, Science and Education, Ain Shams University, Cairo, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abd El-Monem</LastName><ForeName>Dalia D</ForeName><Initials>DD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zoology Department, Faculty of Women for Arts, Science and Education, Ain Shams University, Cairo, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Badawy</LastName><ForeName>Abdelnaser A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, Faculty of Medicine, Northern Border University, Arar, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Serwi</LastName><ForeName>Rasha Hamed</ForeName><Initials>RH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Basic Dental Sciences, College of Dentistry, Princess Nourah bint Abdulrahman University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Magd</LastName><ForeName>Mohammed A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anatomy, Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, Kafrelsheikh University, Kafrelsheikh, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hanafy</LastName><ForeName>Nemany A N</ForeName><Initials>NAN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Group of Bionanotechnology and Molecular Cell Biology, Institute of Nanoscience and Nanotechnology, Kafrelsheikh University, Kafrelsheikh, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Pharmacol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101548923</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1663-9812</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ehrlich ascites carcinoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anthocyanin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cisplatin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">drug delivery systems</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">liposome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">target therapy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest. The author(s) declared that they were an editorial board member of Frontiers, at the time of submission. This had no impact on the peer review process and the final decision.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41111505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12531495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2025.1659575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1659575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>
Abass S. A., Elgazar A. A., El-kholy S. S., El-Refaiy A. I., Nawaya R. A., Bhat M. A., et al.  (2024). Unraveling the nephroprotective potential of papaverine against cisplatin toxicity through mitigating oxidative stress and inflammation: insights from <i>in silico,</i>, <i>in vitro,</i>, and <i>in vivo</i> investigations. Molecules
29, 1927. 10.3390/molecules29091927

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules29091927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11085772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38731418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Abd El- Salam A. M., Tahoun A., Hanafy N. A. N. (2023). Evaluation of liposomal hydrocolloidal NPs loaded by tea tree oil as antifungal agent <i>in vitro</i> and <i>in vivo</i> investigations: preclinical studies. Food Hydrocoll. Health
3, 100136. 10.1016/j.fhfh.2023.100136
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fhfh.2023.100136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelwahab M. A., El-Barbary A. A., El-Said K. S., Betiha M., Elkholy H. M., Chiellini E., et al. (2019). Functionalization of poly(3-hydroxybutyrate) with different thiol compounds inhibits MDM2&#x2013;p53 interactions in MCF7 cells. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 136, 46924. 10.1002/app.46924</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/app.46924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen T. M., Cullis P. R. (2013). Liposomal drug delivery systems: from concept to clinical applications. Adv. Drug Deliv. Rev. 65, 36&#x2013;48. 10.1016/j.addr.2012.09.037</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.addr.2012.09.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23036225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amararathna M., Hoskin D. W., Rupasinghe H. P. V. (2022). Anthocyanin encapsulated nanoparticles as a pulmonary delivery system. Oxidative Med. Cell. Longev. 2022, 1422929. 10.1155/2022/1422929</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/1422929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9482540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36124088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attia A. A., Salama A. F., Eldiasty J. G., Mosallam S. A. E.-R., El-Naggar S. A., El-Magd M. A., et al. (2022). Amygdalin potentiates the anti-cancer effect of sorafenib on ehrlich ascites carcinoma and ameliorates the associated liver damage. Sci. Rep. 12, 6494. 10.1038/s41598-022-10517-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-10517-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9021277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35444229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awad M. G., Ali R. A., Abd El-Monem D. D., El-Magd M. A. (2020). Graviola leaves extract enhances the anticancer effect of cisplatin on various cancer cell lines. Mol. and Cell. Toxicol. 16, 385&#x2013;399. 10.1007/s13273-020-00092-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13273-020-00092-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awad M. G., Hanafy N. A. N., Ali R. A., Abd El-Monem D. D., El-Shafiey S. H., El-Magd M. A. (2024a). Exploring the therapeutic applications of nano-therapy of encapsulated cisplatin and anthocyanin-loaded multiwalled carbon nanotubes coated with chitosan-conjugated folic acid in targeting breast and liver cancers. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 280, 135854. 10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2024.135854</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2024.135854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39307483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awad M. G., Hanafy N. A. N., Ali R. A., El-Monem D. D. A., El-Shafiey S. H., El-Magd M. A. (2024b). Unveiling the therapeutic potential of anthocyanin/cisplatin-loaded chitosan nanoparticles against breast and liver cancers. Cancer Nanotechnol. 15, 57. 10.1186/s12645-024-00297-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12645-024-00297-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azaam M. M., Kenawy E.-R., El-din A. S. B., Khamis A. A., El-Magd M. A. (2018). Antioxidant and anticancer activities of &#x3b1;-aminophosphonates containing thiadiazole moiety. J. Saudi Chem. Soc. 22, 34&#x2013;41. 10.1016/j.jscs.2017.06.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jscs.2017.06.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Babaei F., Ebrahimi Shahmabadi H., Rajabi M. R., Haddad Kashani H., Izadpanah F. (2019). Evaluation of cisplatin efficacy on HepG2 and <i>E. coli</i> cells under acidic conditions. Asian Pac. J. Cancer Prev.
20, 723&#x2013;726. 10.31557/APJCP.2019.20.3.723

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31557/APJCP.2019.20.3.723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6825765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30909670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badawy A. A., Othman R. Q. A., El-Magd M. A. (2021). Effect of combined therapy with camel milk-derived exosomes, tamoxifen, and hesperidin on breast cancer. Mol. and Cell. Toxicol. 10.1007/s13273-021-00163-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13273-021-00163-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahrami Parsa M., Tafvizi F., Chaleshi V., Ebadi M. (2023). Preparation, characterization, and Co-delivery of cisplatin and doxorubicin-loaded liposomes to enhance anticancer activities. Heliyon 9, e20657. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e20657</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e20657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10560846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37818003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho F., Gutierres J., Bueno A., Agostinho P., Zago A., Vieira J., et al. (2017). Anthocyanins control neuroinflammation and consequent memory dysfunction in mice exposed to lipopolysaccharide. Mol. Neurobiol. 54, 3350&#x2013;3367. 10.1007/s12035-016-9900-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12035-016-9900-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27167130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X.-Y., Zhou J., Luo L.-P., Han B., Li F., Chen J.-Y., et al. (2015). Black rice anthocyanins suppress metastasis of breast cancer cells by targeting RAS/RAF/MAPK pathway. BioMed Res. Int. 2015, 414250. 10.1155/2015/414250</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2015/414250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4663286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26649302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J., Hu S., Sun M., Shi J., Zhang H., Yu H., et al. (2024). Recent advances and clinical translation of liposomal delivery systems in cancer therapy. Eur. J. Pharm. Sci. 193, 106688. 10.1016/j.ejps.2023.106688</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejps.2023.106688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38171420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Y., Zhao P., Wu S., Yang T., Chen Y., Zhang X., et al. (2018). Cisplatin and curcumin co-loaded nano-liposomes for the treatment of hepatocellular carcinoma. Int. J. Pharm. 545, 261&#x2013;273. 10.1016/j.ijpharm.2018.05.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2018.05.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29730175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domingo I. K., Latif A., Bhavsar A. P. (2022). Pro-inflammatory signalling PRRopels cisplatin-induced toxicity. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 23, 7227. 10.3390/ijms23137227</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23137227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9266867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35806229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Magd M. A., Khamis A., Nasr Eldeen S. K., Ibrahim W. M., Salama A. F. (2017). Trehalose enhances the antitumor potential of methotrexate against mice bearing ehrlich ascites carcinoma. Biomed. and Pharmacother. 92, 870&#x2013;878. 10.1016/j.biopha.2017.06.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2017.06.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28599251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elbialy N. S., Mady M. M. (2015). Ehrlich tumor inhibition using doxorubicin containing liposomes. Saudi Pharm J. 23, 182&#x2013;187. 10.1016/j.jsps.2014.07.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsps.2014.07.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4420998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25972739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Fierri I., De Marchi L., Chignola R., Rossin G., Bellumori M., Perbellini A., et al.  (2023). Nanoencapsulation of anthocyanins from red cabbage (<i>Brassica oleracea</i> L. var. capitata f. rubra) through coacervation of whey protein isolate and apple high methoxyl pectin. Antioxidants
12, 1757. 10.3390/antiox12091757

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox12091757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10525587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37760059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franco M. S., Silva C. A., Leite E. A., Silveira J. N., Teixeira C. S., Cardoso V. N., et al. (2021). Investigation of the antitumor activity and toxicity of cisplatin loaded ph-sensitive-pegylated liposomes in a triple negative breast cancer animal model. J. Drug Deliv. Sci. Technol. 62, 102400. 10.1016/j.jddst.2021.102400</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jddst.2021.102400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaikwad S. S., Morade Y. Y., Kothule A. M., Kshirsagar S. J., Laddha U. D., Salunkhe K. S. (2023). Overview of phytosomes in treating cancer: advancement, challenges, and future outlook. Heliyon 9, e16561. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e16561</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2023.e16561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10227328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37260890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Gupta V., Trivedi P. (2018). Chapter 15 - <i>in vitro</i> and <i>in vivo</i> characterization of pharmaceutical topical nanocarriers containing anticancer drugs for skin cancer treatment. In Grumezescu A. M., editor. Lipid nanocarriers for drug targeting. Norwich, NY: William Andrew Publishing. p. 563&#x2013;627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamad I., Harb A. A., Bustanji Y. (2024). Liposome-based drug delivery systems in cancer research: an analysis of global landscape efforts and achievements. Pharmaceutics 16, 400. 10.3390/pharmaceutics16030400</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pharmaceutics16030400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10974372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38543294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanahan D., Weinberg R. A. (2011). Hallmarks of cancer: the next generation. Cell 144, 646&#x2013;674. 10.1016/j.cell.2011.02.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2011.02.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21376230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inkson B. J. (2016). 2 - scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and transmission electron microscopy (TEM) for materials characterization. In: H&#xfc;bschen G., Altpeter I., Tschuncky R., Herrmann H.-G., editors. Materials characterization using nondestructive evaluation (NDE) methods. Sawston, Cambridge: Woodhead Publishing. p. 17&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeyaram S., Geethakrishnan T. (2020). Vibrational spectroscopic, linear and nonlinear optical characteristics of Anthocyanin extracted from blueberry. Results Opt. 1, 100010. 10.1016/j.rio.2020.100010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rio.2020.100010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joshy K. S., Hasan A., Augustine R., Alex S., Zahid A., Dalvi Y., et al. (2022). Cisplatin encapsulated nanoparticles from polymer blends for anti-cancer drug delivery. New J. Chem. 46, 5819&#x2013;5829. 10.1039/d1nj04311k</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d1nj04311k</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jumaa Jandal M. (2025). Determination and diagnosis of anthocyanins, phenolic compounds, and antioxidant activity of black plum peel extracted using a microwave device. IOP Conf. Ser. Earth Environ. Sci. 1487, 012111. 10.1088/1755-1315/1487/1/012111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1755-1315/1487/1/012111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karthikeyan A., Senthil N., Min T. (2020). Nanocurcumin: a promising candidate for therapeutic applications. Front. Pharmacol. 11, 487. 10.3389/fphar.2020.00487</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2020.00487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7206872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32425772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Kowalczyk T., Muska&#x142;a M., Merecz-Sadowska A., Sikora J., Picot L., Sitarek P. (2024). Anti-inflammatory and anticancer effects of anthocyanins in <i>in vitro</i> and <i>in vivo</i> studies. Antioxidants
13, 1143. 10.3390/antiox13091143

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox13091143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11428540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39334802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Ledezma-Gallegos F., Jurado R., Mir R., Medina L. A., Mondragon-Fuentes L., Garcia-Lopez P. (2020). Liposomes Co-Encapsulating cisplatin/mifepristone improve the effect on cervical cancer: <i>in vitro</i> and <i>in vivo</i> assessment. Pharmaceutics
12, 897. 10.3390/pharmaceutics12090897

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pharmaceutics12090897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7558205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32971785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Yap S. Q., Yoong S. L., Nayak T. R., Chandra G. W., Ang W. H., et al. (2012). Carbon nanotube bottles for incorporation, release and enhanced cytotoxic effect of cisplatin. Carbon 50, 1625&#x2013;1634. 10.1016/j.carbon.2011.11.043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbon.2011.11.043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6522380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31105316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q., Tian Y., Li D., Sun J., Shi D., Fang L., et al. (2014). The effect of lipocisplatin on cisplatin efficacy and nephrotoxicity in malignant breast cancer treatment. Biomaterials 35, 6462&#x2013;6472. 10.1016/j.biomaterials.2014.04.023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biomaterials.2014.04.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24797881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin B. W., Gong C. C., Song H. F., Cui Y. Y. (2017). Effects of anthocyanins on the prevention and treatment of cancer. Br. J. Pharmacol. 174, 1226&#x2013;1243. 10.1111/bph.13627</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bph.13627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5429338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27646173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magdy A., Sadaka E., Hanafy N., El-Magd M. A., Allahloubi N., El Kemary M. (2020). Green tea ameliorates the side effects of the silver nanoparticles treatment of ehrlich ascites tumor in mice. Mol. and Cell. Toxicol. 16, 271&#x2013;282. 10.1007/s13273-020-00078-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13273-020-00078-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahamuni N. N., Adewuyi Y. G. (2009). Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR) method to monitor soy biodiesel and soybean oil in transesterification reactions, petrodiesel&#x2212;Biodiesel blends, and blend adulteration with soy oil. Energy and Fuels 23, 3773&#x2013;3782. 10.1021/ef900130m</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ef900130m</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Nielson L., Harley S. (2010). Chemotaxonomy: simple tests for distinguishing between anthocyanins and betacyanins. 
<i>J. Biol. Educ.</i> Summer
1996, 88&#x2013;90. 10.1080/00219266.1996.9655483
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00219266.1996.9655483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nsairat H., Khater D., Sayed U., Odeh F., Al Bawab A., Alshaer W. (2022). Liposomes: structure, composition, types, and clinical applications. Heliyon 8, e09394. 10.1016/j.heliyon.2022.e09394</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2022.e09394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9118483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35600452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Othman R., Badawy A., Alruwaili M., El-Magd M. (2021). Camel milk exosomes potentiate the anticancer effect of doxorubicin on multidrug-resistant human leukemia Hl60 cells <i>in vitro</i> and <i>in vivo</i>
. Pak. J. Med. and Health Sci.
15, 3313&#x2013;3320. 10.53350/pjmhs2115113313
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.53350/pjmhs2115113313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan M.-H., Lai C.-S., Ho C.-T. (2010). Anti-inflammatory activity of natural dietary flavonoids. Food and Funct. 1, 15&#x2013;31. 10.1039/c0fo00103a</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c0fo00103a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21776454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paramanantham A., Kim M. J., Jung E. J., Kim H. J., Chang S.-H., Jung J.-M., et al. (2020). Anthocyanins isolated from Vitis coignetiae pulliat enhances cisplatin sensitivity in MCF-7 human breast cancer cells through inhibition of akt and NF-?B activation. Molecules 25, 3623. 10.3390/molecules25163623</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules25163623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7466154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renault-Mahieux M., Vieillard V., Seguin J., Espeau P., Le D. T., Lai-Kuen R., et al. (2021). Co-Encapsulation of fisetin and cisplatin into liposomes for glioma therapy: from formulation to cell evaluation. Pharmaceutics 13, 970. 10.3390/pharmaceutics13070970</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pharmaceutics13070970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8309049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34206986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Selim N. M., Elgazar A. A., Abdel-Hamid N. M., El-Magd M. R. A., Yasri A., Hefnawy H. M. E., et al.  (2019). Chrysophanol, physcion, hesperidin and curcumin modulate the gene expression of pro-inflammatory mediators induced by LPS in HepG2: <i>in silico</i> and molecular studies. Antioxidants
8, 371. 10.3390/antiox8090371

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antiox8090371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6770650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31484451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen Y., Zhang N., Tian J., Xin G., Liu L., Sun X., et al. (2022). Advanced approaches for improving bioavailability and controlled release of anthocyanins. J. Control. release official J. Control. Release Soc. 341, 285&#x2013;299. 10.1016/j.jconrel.2021.11.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jconrel.2021.11.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34822910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin D. Y., Lu J. N., Kim G.-Y., Jung J. M., Kang H. S., Lee W. S., et al. (2011). Anti-invasive activities of anthocyanins through modulation of tight junctions and suppression of matrix metalloproteinase activities in HCT-116 human Colon carcinoma cells. Oncol. Rep. 25, 567&#x2013;572. 10.3892/or.2010.1104</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/or.2010.1104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21165577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strober W. (2015). Trypan blue exclusion test of cell viability. Curr. Protoc. Immunol. 111, A3.b.1&#x2013;a3.b.3. 10.1002/0471142735.ima03bs111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/0471142735.ima03bs111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6716531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26529666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tawfic A. A., Ibrahim H. M., Mohammed-Geba K., Abu El-Magd M. (2024a). Immunomodulatory effect of chitosan nanoparticles on ehrlich ascites carcinoma mice. Egypt. J. Veterinary Sci. 0, 1&#x2013;9. 10.21608/ejvs.2024.331998.2455</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/ejvs.2024.331998.2455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tawfic A. A., Ibrahim H. M., Mohammed-Geba K., El-Magd M. A. (2024b). Chitosan nanoparticles, camel milk exosomes And/or sorafenib induce apoptosis, inhibit tumor cells migration and angiogenesis and ameliorate the associated liver damage in ehrlich ascites carcinoma-bearing mice. Beni-Suef Univ. J. Basic Appl. Sci. 13, 74. 10.1186/s43088-024-00535-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s43088-024-00535-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venancio V. P., Cipriano P. A., Kim H., Antunes L. M., Talcott S. T., Mertens-Talcott S. U. (2017). Cocoplum (Chrysobalanus icaco L.) anthocyanins exert anti-inflammatory activity in human Colon cancer and non-malignant Colon cells. Food and Funct. 8, 307&#x2013;314. 10.1039/c6fo01498d</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c6fo01498d</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28009871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L. S., Stoner G. D. (2008). Anthocyanins and their role in cancer prevention. Cancer Lett. 269, 281&#x2013;290. 10.1016/j.canlet.2008.05.020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.canlet.2008.05.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2582525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18571839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan G.-P., Zong R.-F., Li L., Fu T., Liu F., Yu X.-H. (2010). Anticancer drug-loaded nanospheres based on biodegradable amphiphilic &#x3b5;-Caprolactone and carbonate copolymers. Pharm. Res. 27, 2743&#x2013;2752. 10.1007/s11095-010-0275-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11095-010-0275-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20859660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang T., Wu Z., Wang P., Mu T., Qin H., Zhu Z., et al. (2017). A large-inner-diameter multi-walled carbon nanotube-based dual-drug delivery system with pH-sensitive release properties. J. Mater. Sci. Mater. Med. 28, 110. 10.1007/s10856-017-5920-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10856-017-5920-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28589526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>