<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38576248</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2005-3894</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>36</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Annals of dermatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ann Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Skin Barrier Function Assessment: Electrical Impedance Spectroscopy Is Less Influenced by Daily Routine Activities Than Transepidermal Water Loss.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>99</StartPage><EndPage>111</EndPage><MedlinePgn>99-111</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5021/ad.23.052</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Skin barrier function assessment is commonly done by measuring transepidermal water loss (TEWL). An important limitation of this method is the influence of intrinsic and extrinsic factors. Electrical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) is a lesser-established method for skin barrier function assessment. Some influential factors have been described, but no guidelines exist regarding the standardization of these measurements.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the effect size of daily routine activities on TEWL and EIS, as well as their correlation with age and anatomical differences.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Healthy participants (n=31) were stratified into three age groups (18-29, 30-49, and &#x2265;50 years). In a climate-controlled room, EIS and TEWL measurements were performed on the left and right volar forearm and abdomen.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Body cream application decreased TEWL and EIS values after 15 and 90 minutes. Skin washing decreased TEWL for 15 minutes and EIS values for at least 90 minutes. TEWL was increased 5 minutes after moderate to intense exercise. Coffee intake increased TEWL on the abdomen after 60 minutes. TEWL and EIS values did not correlate with participants' age and no anatomical differences were observed. No correlation was observed between TEWL and EIS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Body cream application and skin washing should be avoided at least 90 minutes prior to measurements of TEWL and EIS. Exercise and coffee intake should also be avoided prior to TEWL measurements. EIS may be a promising tool for skin barrier function assessment as it is less affected by daily routine activities than TEWL.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Korean Dermatological Association and The Korean Society for Investigative Dermatology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huygen</LastName><ForeName>Lisa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8211-0320</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vrije Universiteit Brussel (VUB), Skin Immunology &amp; Immune Tolerance (SKIN) Research Group, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vrije Universiteit Brussel (VUB), Universitair Ziekenhuis Brussel (UZ Brussel), Department of Dermatology, Brussels, Belgium. lisa.huygen@vub.be.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thys</LastName><ForeName>Pauline Marie</ForeName><Initials>PM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-2880-2282</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vrije Universiteit Brussel (VUB), Skin Immunology &amp; Immune Tolerance (SKIN) Research Group, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wollenberg</LastName><ForeName>Andreas</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0177-8722</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vrije Universiteit Brussel (VUB), Universitair Ziekenhuis Brussel (UZ Brussel), Department of Dermatology, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology and Allergy, Ludwig-Maximilian-University, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology and Allergy, University Hospital Augsburg, Augsburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gutermuth</LastName><ForeName>Jan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9252-6004</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vrije Universiteit Brussel (VUB), Skin Immunology &amp; Immune Tolerance (SKIN) Research Group, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vrije Universiteit Brussel (VUB), Universitair Ziekenhuis Brussel (UZ Brussel), Department of Dermatology, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krohn</LastName><ForeName>Inge Kortekaas</ForeName><Initials>IK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3649-1131</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vrije Universiteit Brussel (VUB), Skin Immunology &amp; Immune Tolerance (SKIN) Research Group, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vrije Universiteit Brussel (VUB), Universitair Ziekenhuis Brussel (UZ Brussel), Department of Dermatology, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Ann Dermatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8916577</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1013-9087</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Activities of Daily Living</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electric Impedance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hydration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Skin Barrier</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transepidermal water loss</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Washing</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have nothing to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38576248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10995614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5021/ad.23.052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">36.99</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Elias PM. Skin barrier function. Curr Allergy Asthma Rep. 2008;8:299&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2843412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18606081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sano S. Psoriasis as a barrier disease. Zhonghua Pifuke Yixue Zazhi. 2015;33:64&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proksch E, Brandner JM, Jensen JM. The skin: an indispensable barrier. Exp Dermatol. 2008;17:1063&#x2013;1072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19043850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawton S. Skin 1: the structure and functions of the skin. Nurs Times. 2019;115:30&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darlenski R, Kazandjieva J, Tsankov N. Skin barrier function: morphological basis and regulatory mechanisms. J Clin Med. 2011;4:36&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elias PM, Menon GK. Structural and lipid biochemical correlates of the epidermal permeability barrier. Adv Lipid Res. 1991;24:1&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1763710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang G, Seok JK, Kang HC, Cho YY, Lee HS, Lee JY. Skin barrier abnormalities and immune dysfunction in atopic dermatitis. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:2867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7215310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32326002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen AV, Soulika AM. The dynamics of the skin&#x2019;s immune system. Int J Mol Sci. 2019;20:1811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6515324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31013709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ta&#xef;eb A. Hypothesis: from epidermal barrier dysfunction to atopic disorders. Contact Dermat. 1999;41:177&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10515093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elias PM, Wood LC, Feingold KR. Epidermal pathogenesis of inflammatory dermatoses. Am J Contact Dermat. 1999;10:119&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10444104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akiyama M. Corneocyte lipid envelope (CLE), the key structure for skin barrier function and ichthyosis pathogenesis. J Dermatol Sci. 2017;88:3&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28623042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander H, Brown S, Danby S, Flohr C. Research techniques made simple: transepidermal water loss measurement as a research tool. J Invest Dermatol. 2018;138:2295&#x2013;2300.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30348333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe4;sler K, Bergmann S, Heisig M, Naegel A, Zorn-Kruppa M, Brandner JM. The role of tight junctions in skin barrier function and dermal absorption. J Control Release. 2016;242:105&#x2013;118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27521894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fluhr JW, Feingold KR, Elias PM. Transepidermal water loss reflects permeability barrier status: validation in human and rodent in vivo and ex vivo models. Exp Dermatol. 2006;15:483&#x2013;492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16761956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berardesca E European Group for Efficacy Measurements on Cosmetics and Other Topical Products (EEMCO) EEMCO guidance for the assessment of stratum corneum hydration: electrical methods. Skin Res Technol. 1997;3:126&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27333374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinaldi AO, Korsfeldt A, Ward S, Burla D, Dreher A, Gautschi M, et al. Electrical impedance spectroscopy for the characterization of skin barrier in atopic dermatitis. Allergy. 2021;76:3066&#x2013;3079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33830511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu F, Wang C, Zhao R, Du L, Fang Z, Guo X, et al. Review of stratum corneum impedance measurement in non-invasive penetration application. Biosensors (Basel) 2018;8:31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6023082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29587456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>du Plessis J, Stefaniak A, Eloff F, John S, Agner T, Chou TC, et al. International guidelines for the in vivo assessment of skin properties in non-clinical settings: Part 2. transepidermal water loss and skin hydration. Skin Res Technol. 2013;19:265&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4522909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23331328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevisense: clinical reference Guide. Stockholm: SciBase; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicander I, Ollmar S. Clinically normal atopic skin vs. non-atopic skin as seen through electrical impedance. Skin Res Technol. 2004;10:178&#x2013;183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15225268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicander I, Ollmar S, Eek A, Lundh Rozell B, Emtestam L. Correlation of impedance response patterns to histological findings in irritant skin reactions induced by various surfactants. Br J Dermatol. 1996;134:221&#x2013;228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8746333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin M, Ruzgas T, Svedenhag P, Anderson CD, Ollmar S, Engblom J, et al. Skin hydration dynamics investigated by electrical impedance techniques in vivo and in vitro . Sci Rep. 2020;10:17218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7557913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33057021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogiers V EEMCO Group. EEMCO guidance for the assessment of transepidermal water loss in cosmetic sciences. Skin Pharmacol Appl Skin Physiol. 2001;14:117&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11316970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta HH, Nikam VV, Jaiswal CR, Mehta HB. A cross-sectional study of variations in the biophysical parameters of skin among healthy volunteers. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol. 2018;84:521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29491191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinnagoda J, Tupker RA, Agner T, Serup J. Guidelines for transepidermal water loss (TEWL) measurement. A report from the Standardization Group of the European Society of Contact Dermatitis. Contact Dermat. 1990;22:164&#x2013;178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2335090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinnagoda J, Tupker RA, Coenraads PJ, Nater JP. Transepidermal water loss with and without sweat gland inactivation. Contact Dermat. 1989;21:16&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2805656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor NA, Machado-Moreira CA. Regional variations in transepidermal water loss, eccrine sweat gland density, sweat secretion rates and electrolyte composition in resting and exercising humans. Extrem Physiol Med. 2013;2:4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3710196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23849497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darlenski R, Fluhr JW. Influence of skin type, race, sex, and anatomic location on epidermal barrier function. Clin Dermatol. 2012;30:269&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22507039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firooz A, Aghazadeh N, Rajabi Estarabadi A, Hejazi P. The effects of water exposure on biophysical properties of normal skin. Skin Res Technol. 2015;21:131&#x2013;136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25066831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fartasch M, Taeger D, Broding HC, Sch&#xf6;neweis S, Gellert B, Pohrt U, et al. Evidence of increased skin irritation after wet work: impact of water exposure and occlusion. Contact Dermat. 2012;67:217&#x2013;228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22591550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Draelos ZD. The science behind skin care: moisturizers. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2018;17:138&#x2013;144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29319217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayrovitz HN. Effects of local forearm skin heating on skin properties. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2020;40:369&#x2013;376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32628313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicander I, Nyren M, Emtestam L, Ollmar S. Baseline electrical impedance measurements at various skin sites - related to age and sex. Skin Res Technol. 1997;3:252&#x2013;258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27333585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luebberding S, Krueger N, Kerscher M. Age-related changes in skin barrier function - quantitative evaluation of 150 female subjects. Int J Cosmet Sci. 2013;35:183&#x2013;190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23113564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manuskiatti W, Schwindt DA, Maibach HI. Influence of age, anatomic site and race on skin roughness and scaliness. Dermatology. 1998;196:401&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9669115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cotterill JA, Cunliffe WJ, Williamson B, Bulusu L. Age and sex variation in skin surface lipid composition and sebum excretion rate. Br J Dermatol. 1972;87:333&#x2013;340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5077864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warner RR, Stone KJ, Boissy YL. Hydration disrupts human stratum corneum ultrastructure. J Invest Dermatol. 2003;120:275&#x2013;284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12542533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hildebrandt D, Ziegler K, Wollina U. EIectrical impedance and transepidermal water loss of healthy human skin under different conditions. Skin Res Technol. 1998;4:130&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27328906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel PN, Zwibel H. Physiology, exercise. Treasure Island: StatPearls; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danby SG, Andrew PV, Brown K, Chittock J, Kay LJ, Cork MJ. An investigation of the skin barrier restoring effects of a cream and lotion containing ceramides in a multi-vesicular emulsion in people with dry, eczema-prone, skin: the RESTORE study phase 1. Dermatol Ther (Heidelb) 2020;10:1031&#x2013;1041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7477057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32671664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Multi Skin Test Center&#xae; MC 1000 &amp; Software. Cologne: Courage+Khazaka electronic GmbH; 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berardesca E, Loden M, Serup J, Masson P, Rodrigues LM. The revised EEMCO guidance for the in vivo measurement of water in the skin. Skin Res Technol. 2018;24:351&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29923639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malvehy J, Hauschild A, Curiel-Lewandrowski C, Mohr P, Hofmann-Wellenhof R, Motley R, et al. Clinical performance of the Nevisense system in cutaneous melanoma detection: an international, multicentre, prospective and blinded clinical trial on efficacy and safety. Br J Dermatol. 2014;171:1099&#x2013;1107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4257502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24841846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicander I, Ollmar S. Electrical impedance measurements at different skin sites related to seasonal variations. Skin Res Technol. 2000;6:81&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11428947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fluhr JW, Darlenski R, Surber C. Glycerol and the skin: holistic approach to its origin and functions. Br J Dermatol. 2008;159:23&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18510666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;lenick A, Jr, O&#x2019;lenick K. Silicone polymers in skin care. MRS Bull. 2007;32:801&#x2013;806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czarnowicki T, Malajian D, Khattri S, Correa da Rosa J, Dutt R, Finney R, et al. Petrolatum: barrier repair and antimicrobial responses underlying this &#x201c;inert&#x201d; moisturizer. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2016;137:1091&#x2013;1102.e7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26431582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kov&#xe1;cs A, P&#xe9;ter-H&#xe9;deri D, Perei K, Budai-Sz&#x171;cs M, L&#xe9;ber A, G&#xe1;csi A, et al. Effects of formulation excipients on skin barrier function in creams used in pediatric care. Pharmaceutics. 2020;12:729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7465361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32759663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paci&#xea;ncia I, Rodolfo A, Le&#xe3;o L, Silva D, Cavaleiro Rufo J, Mendes F, et al. Effects of exercise on the skin epithelial barrier of young elite athletes-swimming comparatively to non-water sports training session. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7828688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33466624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Echeverri D, Montes FR, Cabrera M, Gal&#xe1;n A, Prieto A. Caffeine&#x2019;s vascular mechanisms of action. Int J Vasc Med. 2010;2010:834060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3003984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21188209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim TW, Shin YO, Lee JB, Min YK, Yang HM. Effect of caffeine on the metabolic responses of lipolysis and activated sweat gland density in human during physical activity. Food Sci Biotechnol. 2010;19:1077&#x2013;1081.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinaldi AO, Li M, Barletta E, D&#x2019;Avino P, Yazici D, Pat Y, et al. Household laundry detergents disrupt barrier integrity and induce inflammation in mouse and human skin. Allergy. 2024;79:128&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37766519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sasaki M, Sundberg M, Frei R, Ferstl R, Heye KN, Willems EP, et al. Electrical impedance spectroscopy detects skin barrier dysfunction in childhood atopic dermatitis. Allergy. 2024;79:142&#x2013;152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37753955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>