<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40899620</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-4095</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>47</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advanced materials (Deerfield Beach, Fla.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Mater</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Formation of Supramolecular Rigid Glass Based on Transparent Deep Eutectic.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e06637</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e06637</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/adma.202506637</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The development of transparent materials with mechanical rigidity and hardness via the non-covalent bonding of low-molecular-weight building blocks is a major challenge. Although various strategies have been developed to improve the mechanical performance of supramolecular materials, they are frequently accompanied by complex designs and tedious syntheses. Therefore, it is urgent to develop perspectives that are fundamentally distinguished from previous strategies. In this study, a new design solution that involves with non-covalent molecular recognition, deep eutectic solvent formation, and solvent-free photopolymerization is conceived and validated. Metal coordination and hydrogen bonding between zinc tetrafluoroborate hydrate (ZTH) and acrylamide (AM) facilitated the formation of ZTH-AM, which can be recognized as the analogue of the glass liquid in the preparation of inorganic glass. ZTH-AM significantly suppressed the nucleation and crystallization of ZTH and AM. Subsequently, it is used to fabricate transparent poly[ZTH-AM] glass in bulk using photopolymerization. The obtained supramolecular glass is rigid, exhibiting high tensile strength (93.50 MPa), Young's modulus (1.12 GPa), and hardness (92.1 HD).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Wiley&#x2010;VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hou</LastName><ForeName>Xi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Hunan University, Changsha, 410082, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meng</LastName><ForeName>Jianqiang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan Provincial Key Laboratory of Micro &amp; Nano Materials Interface Science, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Central South University, Changsha, 410083, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yin</LastName><ForeName>Tianqiang</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Mechanics and Control for Aerospace Structures, Nanjing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics, Nanjing, 210016, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Life Science and Chemistry, Hunan University of Technology, Zhuzhou, 412000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Juan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hunan Provincial Key Laboratory of Micro &amp; Nano Materials Interface Science, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Central South University, Changsha, 410083, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Gai</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Mechanics and Control for Aerospace Structures, Nanjing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics, Nanjing, 210016, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Shengyi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8640-537X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Hunan University, Changsha, 410082, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>22271087</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>22A0010</GrantID><Agency>Scientific Research Fund of Hunan Provincial Education Department</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2021JJ10010</GrantID><Agency>Outstanding Youth Scientist Foundation of Hunan Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2018RS3036</GrantID><Agency>Huxiang Young Talent Program from Hunan Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Mater</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9885358</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0935-9648</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deep eutectic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mechanical toughness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non&#x2010;covalent interaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">supramolecular glass</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transparent material</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40899620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202506637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>C. S. Henshilwood, F. d'Errico, K. L. van Niekerk, Y. Coquinot, Z. Jacobs, S.&#x2010;E. Lauritzen, M. Menu, R. Garc&#xed;a&#x2010;Moreno, Science 2011, 334, 219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. J. Wang, Z. Liu, Nat. Mater. 2023, 22, 144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Wu, C. Cai, X. Wang, Q. Zhang, Z. Tan, F. Li, S. Dong, Mater. Horiz. 2023, 10, 5152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) J. Wang, D. Zhang, F. Chu, Adv. Mater. 2020, 33, 2001135;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Z. Wang, M. S. Ganewatta, C. Tang, Prog. Polym. Sci. 2020, 101, 101197;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) M. L. Becker, J. A. Burdick, Chem. Rev. 2021, 121, 10789.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. N. Greaves, S. Sen, Adv. Phys. 2007, 56, 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) B. Yan, C. Ma, J. Gao, Y. Yuan, N. Wang, Adv. Mater. 2020, 32, 1906615;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) C. Cai, S. Wu, Y. Zhang, F. Li, Z. Tan, S. Dong, Nat. Commun. 2024, 15, 3929;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) D. J. Lundberg, C. M. Brown, E. O. Bobylev, N. J. Oldenhuis, Y. S. Alfaraj, J. Zhao, I. Kevlishvili, H. J. Kulik, J. A. Johnson, Nat. Commun. 2024, 15, 3951.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) K. Zhang, R. Li, G. Chen, X. Wang, M. He, Chem. Mater. 2022, 34, 3736;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) W. Niu, Q. Tian, Z. Liu, X. Liu, Adv. Mater. 2023, 35, 2304157;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) P. Sun, B. Qin, J.&#x2010;F. Xu, X. Zhang, Macromolecules. Chem. Phys. 2023, 224, 2200332;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>d) L. Li, X. Wang, S. Gao, S. Zheng, X. Zou, J. Xiong, W. Li, F. Yan, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2308547.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) P. Li, Z. Jin, L. Peng, F. Zhao, D. Xiao, Y. Jin, G. Yu, Adv. Mater. 2018, 30, 1800124;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) X.&#x2010;Q. Xie, Y. Zhang, Y. Liang, M. Wang, Y. Cui, J. Li, C.&#x2010;S. Liu, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2022, 134, e202114471;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) L. Xu, Y. Pan, X. Wang, Z. Xu, H. Tian, Y. Liu, X. Bu, H. Jing, T. Wang, Y. Liu, M. Liu, ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2023, 15, 4458;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>d) Z. Sun, C. Dong, B. Chen, W. Li, H. Hu, J. Zhou, C. Li, Z. Huang, Small 2023, 19, 2303612;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>e) Z. Zhang, A. Yao, P. Raffa, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 34, 2407529.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) X. Du, J. Zhou, J. Shi, B. Xu, Chem. Rev. 2015, 115, 13165;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) S. Das, P. Martin, G. Vasilyev, R. Nandi, N. Amdursky, E. Zussman, Macromolecules 2020, 53, 11130;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) A. L&#xf3;pez&#x2010;D&#xed;az, A. S. V&#xe1;zquez, E. V&#xe1;zquez, ACS Nano 2024, 18, 20817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S. Wu, C. Cai, F. Li, Z. Tan, S. Dong, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2020, 59, 11871;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) J. Zhang, L. Yao, S. Li, S. Li, Y. Wu, Z. Li, H. Qiu, Green Chem. 2023, 25, 4180;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) S. An, A. Hao, P. Xing, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2402314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) R. Xing, C. Yuan, W. Fan, X. Ren, X. Yan, Sci. Adv. 2023, 9, eadd8105;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) S. Cao, W. Fan, R. Chang, C. Yuan, X. Yan, CCS Chem. 2024, 6, 2814;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) F. Nie, D. Yan, Nat. Commun. 2024, 15, 9491;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>d) G. Yao, Y. Pan, F. Li, S. Dong, Small 2024, 20, 2405337;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>e) G. Finkelstein&#x2010;Zuta, Z. A. Arnon, T. Vijayakanth, O. Messer, O. S. Lusky, A. Wagner, G. Zilberman, R. Aizen, L. Michaeli, S. Rencus&#x2010;Lazar, S. Gilead, S. Shankar, M. J. Pavan, D. A. Goldstein, S. Kutchinsky, T. Ellenbogen, B. A. Palmer, A. Goldbourt, M. Sokol, E. Gazit, Nature 2024, 630, 368;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>f) C. Yuan, W. Fan, P. Zhou, R. Xing, S. Cao, X. Yan, Nat. Nanotechnol. 2024, 19, 1840.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Y. Zhang, C. Cai, F. Li, X. Tan, Q. Li, X. Ni, S. Dong, Mater. Horiz. 2024, 11, 5641;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) C. Cai, G. Yao, Y. Zhang, S. Zhang, F. Li, Z. Tan, S. Dong, Mater. Horiz. 2024, 11, 5732.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) L. Meazza, J. A. Foster, K. Fucke, P. Metrangolo, G. Resnati, J. W. Steed, Nat. Chem. 2013, 5, 42;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) G. Yu, X. Yan, C. Han, F. Huang, Chem. Soc. Rev. 2013, 42, 6697;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) J. Chen, Y. Ma, T. Chen, Y. Du, J. Xu, D. Wang, J. Yang, P. Hu, J. Jing, B. Yao, J. Fu, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2023, 33, 2212564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. H. Doremus, G. H. Sigel Jr., Glass Science, 2nd ed., Wiley, New York, 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Dai, B. Zhou, D. Yan, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2025, 64, e202505322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) J. Xu, J. Chen, Y. Zhang, T. Liu, J. Fu, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2021, 60, 7947;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Q. Lu, H. Li, C. Cai, Z. Tan, Chem. Eng. J. 2025, 506, 160244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) C. A. Angell, Science 1995, 267, 1924;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) P. G. Debenedetti, F. H. Stillinger, Nature 2001, 410, 259;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) Q. Zhou, Y. Shi, B. Deng, J. Neuefeind, M. Bauchy, Sci. Adv. 2021, 7, eabh1761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) H. Tong, H. Tanaka, Nat. Commun. 2019, 10, 5596;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) W.&#x2010;S. Xu, Z.&#x2010;Y. Sun, Chin. J. Polym. Sci. 2023, 41, 1329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) F. Nie, K.&#x2010;Z. Wang, D. Yan, Nat. Commun. 2023, 14, 1654;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) X. Chen, C. Hu, Y. Wang, T. Li, J. Jiang, J. Huang, S. Wang, W. Dong, J. Qiao, Adv. Sci. 2024, 11, 2304946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Qin, S. Zhang, Q. Song, Z. Huang, J.&#x2010;F. Xu, X. Zhang, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2017, 56, 7639.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) L. Yang, X. Tan, Z. Wang, X. Zhang, Chem. Rev. 2015, 115, 7196;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) B. Qin, Z. Yin, X. Tang, S. Zhang, Y. Wu, J.&#x2010;F. Xu, X. Zhang, Prog. Polym. Sci. 2020, 100, 101167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) A. J. Moul&#xe9;, K. Meerholz, Adv. Mater. 2008, 20, 240;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) R. Pokratath, L. Lermusiaux, S. Checchia, J. P. Mathew, S. R. Cooper, J. K. Mathiesen, G. Landaburu, S. Banerjee, S. Tao, N. Reichholf, S. J. L. Billinge, B. Ab&#xe9;cassis, K. M. &#xd8; Jensen, J. De. Roo, ACS Nano 2023, 17, 8796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) H. W. Sheng, W. K. Luo, F. M. Alamgir, J. M. Bai, E. Ma, Nature 2006, 439, 419;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) C. Stenz, J. Pries, T. W. Surta, M. W. Gaultois, M. Wuttig, Adv. Sci. 2023, 10, 2304323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S. Dong, J. Leng, Y. Feng, M. Liu, C. J. Stackhouse, A. Sch&#xf6;nhals, L. Chiappisi, L. Gao, W. Chen, J. Shang, L. Jin, Z. Qi, C. A. Schalley, Sci. Adv. 2017, 3, eaao0900;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Y. Liu, J. Zhang, P. Wu, CCS Chem. 2025, 7, 484.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) B. L. Dargaville, D. W. Hutmacher, Nat. Commun. 2022, 13, 4222;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) C. Espinoza, J. C. D&#xed;az, D. Kitto, H. K. Kim, J. Kamcev, ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2024, 16, 45433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) R.&#x2010;K. Huang, S.&#x2010;S. Wang, D.&#x2010;X. Liu, X. Li, J.&#x2010;M. Song, Y.&#x2010;H. Xia, D.&#x2010;D. Zhou, J. Huang, W.&#x2010;X. Zhang, X.&#x2010;M. Chen, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2019, 141, 5645;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b). L. Wang, S. Wang, G. Xu, Y. Qu, H. Zhang, W. Liu, J. Dai, T. Wang, Z. Liu, Q. Liu, K. Xiao, ACS Nano 2024, 18, 29704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) D. T. Nguyen, C. Meyers, T. D. Yee, N. A. Dudukovic, J. F. Destino, C. Zhu, E. B. Duoss, T. F. Baumann, T. Suratwala, J. E. Smay, R. Dylla&#x2010;Spears, Adv. Mater. 2017, 29, 1701181;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) H. Jia, R. Zhang, X. Niu, X. Zhang, H. Zhou, X. Liu, Z. Fang, F. Chang, B.&#x2010;O. Guan, J. Qiu, Adv. Sci. 2024, 11, 2309433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S. Liu, N. Li, L. Han, L. Li, N. Li, H. Luo, Mater. Horiz. 2018, 5, 454;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) C. Sanner, L. Sonderhouse, R. B. Hutson, L. Yan, W. R. Milner, J. Ye, Science 2021, 374, 979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) J. Li, S. Luo, F. Li, S. Dong, ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2022, 14, 27476;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) G. Yao, F. Li, S. Dong, Chem. Eng. Sci. 2023, 281, 119164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) V. H&#xe5;konsen, G. Singh, P. S. Normile, J. A. De Toro, E. Wahlstr&#xf6;m, J. He, Z. Zhang, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2019, 29, 1904825;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) C. Sheng, Y. Bu, Y. Li, L. Su, Y. Yu, D. Cao, J. Zhou, X. Chen, W. Lu, H. Shu, ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2023, 15, 14704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) J. Xu, X. Li, J. Li, X. Li, B. Li, Y. Wang, L. Wu, W. Li, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2017, 56, 8731;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) X. Li, Z. Du, Z. Song, B. Li, L. Wu, Q. Liu, H. Zhang, W. Li, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2018, 28, 1800599;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) C. Gu, Y. Peng, J. Li, H. Wang, X.&#x2010;Q. Xie, X. Cao, C.&#x2010;S. Liu, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2020, 59, 18768;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>d) Y. Zhang, M. Guo, G. Li, X. Chen, Z. Liu, J. Shao, Y. Huang, G. He, CCS Chem. 2023, 5, 1917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Li, Y. Chen, C. Guo, S. Jia, Y. Zhou, Z. Liu, E. Jiang, X. Chen, Y. Zou, P. Huo, Y. Yan, Z. Zhu, Y. H. Ng, Y. Gong, J. C. Crittenden, Y. Yan, ACS Catal. 2024, 14, 13400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) E. B. Stukalin, L.&#x2010;H. Cai, N. A. Kumar, L. Leibler, M. Rubinstein, Macromolecules 2013, 46, 7525;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) A. Faghihnejad, K. E. Feldman, J. Yu, M. V. Tirrell, J. N. Israelachvili, C. J. Hawker, E. J. Kramer, H. Zeng, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2014, 24, 2322;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) D. Jin, Q. Wang, K. F. Chan, N. Xia, H. Yang, Q. Wang, S. C. H. Yu, L. Zhang, Sci. Adv. 2023, 9, eadf9278;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>d) C. Liu, Y. Wang, S. Shi, Y. Zheng, Z. Ye, J. Liao, Q. Sun, B. Dang, X. Shen, ACS Nano 2024, 18, 27420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) X. Yang, B. Zhang, Y. Gao, C. Liu, G. Li, B. Rao, D. Chu, N. Yan, M. Zhang, G. He, Adv. Sci. 2022, 9, 2101652;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) S. Zhang, L. Ma, W. Ma, L. Chen, K. Gao, S. Yu, M. Zhang, L. Zhang, G. He, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2022, 61, e202209054.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>