<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39491990</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-3336</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>463</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of hazardous materials</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hazard Mater</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigating the role of Na-bentonite colloids in facilitating Sr transport in granite minerals through column experiments and modeling.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>132851</StartPage><MedlinePgn>132851</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2023.132851</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0304-3894(23)02135-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Colloids play a crucial role in influencing the mobility of radionuclides in high-level radioactive waste repositories. However, the co-transport behavior of radionuclides and colloids in geological media remains insufficiently understood. This study investigated the transport of Strontium (Sr) in four types of granite minerals (quartz, biotite, K-feldspar, and plagioclase) in the presence and absence of Na-bentonite colloids (Na-BC) using column experiments. Employing a stepwise modeling strategy, this study first determined the basic flow and transport parameters through breakthrough curve analysis of the conservative tracer (Br). Then, the experimental data of Sr in the colloid-free Sr transport experiments and Na-BC in the Sr-colloid co-transport experiments were quantitatively explained using a two-site sorption model and a two kinetic sites model, respectively. Finally, the co-transport behavior of Sr and Na-BC was fitted using the colloid-facilitated solute transport model. The stepwise modeling allowed quantification of the kinetics of Sr sorption onto mobile and immobile Na-BC and highlighted the role of straining in Na-BC retention. In the absence of Na-BC, Sr transport experienced the greatest retardation in biotite, followed by plagioclase, K-feldspar, and quartz, respectively, which positively correlated with the specific surface area of the minerals. Moreover, Na-BC enhanced Sr transport with the same retardation order in all tested minerals, with recovery rate increments of 68.61%, 19.21%, 6.67%, and 4.33%, respectively. The transport of Sr in K-feldspar was found to be less affected by Na-BC compared to the other tested minerals, likely due to the strong cation exchange capacity of K<sup>+</sup> among the cation components of minerals, making hydrated K<sup>+</sup> more likely to exchange with Sr<sup>2+</sup> on K-feldspar surfaces. These findings hold significant implications for assessing the risks associated with the transport of radionuclides in deep geological repositories.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoying</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Construction Engineering, Jilin University, Changchun 130026, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cai</LastName><ForeName>Fangfei</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Construction Engineering, Jilin University, Changchun 130026, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Funing</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Environmental and Municipal Engineering, Qingdao University of Technology, Qingdao 266520, China. Electronic address: mafn18@mails.jlu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reimus</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Los Alamos National Laboratory, Los Alamos, NM 87545, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qi</LastName><ForeName>Linlin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Construction Engineering, Jilin University, Changchun 130026, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Di</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Science and Technology Research Center of China Customs, Beijing, 100026, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soltanian</LastName><ForeName>Mohamad Reza</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geosciences, University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, OH, USA; Department of Environmental Engineering, University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, OH, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dai</LastName><ForeName>Zhenxue</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Construction Engineering, Jilin University, Changchun 130026, China; School of Environmental and Municipal Engineering, Qingdao University of Technology, Qingdao 266520, China; Key Laboratory of Groundwater Resources and Environment, Jilin University, Ministry of Education, Changchun 130021, China. Electronic address: dzx@jlu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>J Hazard Mater</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9422688</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0304-3894</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Co-transport</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Granite minerals</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Na-bentonite colloids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sorption</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sr(II)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>59</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39491990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2023.132851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0304-3894(23)02135-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>