<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40092050</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1773-2247</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>102</Volume><Issue>Pt A</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of drug delivery science and technology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Drug Deliv Sci Technol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of PEGylated liposomes on cytotoxicity of tamoxifen and piperine on MCF-7 human breast carcinoma cells.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">106331</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jddst.2024.106331</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Tamoxifen (TMF) is an anticancer agent used for managing estrogen receptor-positive breast cancer. It has limited therapeutic efficacy against breast cancer, which could be enhanced by the coadministration of herbal drugs like piperine (PIP). However, the hydrophobic nature of TMF and PIP restricts their therapeutic application. Therefore, the present study focuses on the impact of the anticancer activity of TMF in combination with PIP and after entrapping them into liposomes (TMF-PIP-LPs and TMF-PIP-PEG-LPs). The liposomes were prepared using the thin film hydration method. In addition, the morphology of the prepared liposomes was found spherical after SEM and TEM analyses. Further, the <i>in vitro</i> cytotoxicity (IC<sub>50</sub>) study of pure PIP and TMF was found to be 90.3 &#xb1; 10.2 &#x3bc;g/mL and 40.9 &#xb1; 5.9 &#x3bc;g/mL, respectively. Interestingly, an improved cytotoxicity (IC<sub>50</sub>) was observed when the TMF and PIP were loaded into liposomes (TMF-PIP-LPs: 21 &#xb1; 1.6 &#x3bc;g/mL and TMF-PIP-PEG-LPs: 10 &#xb1; 0.5 &#x3bc;g/mL). Also, the PEGylated liposomes showed improvement in cellular uptake as compared to liposomes without PEGylation in MCF-7 human breast carcinoma cells. Thus, the enhanced cellular uptake and improved cytotoxicity of PEGylated liposomes can be a suitable strategy for delivering TMF with PIP for breast cancer treatment.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vaiphei</LastName><ForeName>Klaudi K</ForeName><Initials>KK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics, National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research (NIPER) Guwahati, Kamrup, Assam, 781101, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prabakaran</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics, National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research (NIPER) Guwahati, Kamrup, Assam, 781101, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Snigdha</LastName><ForeName>Singh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics, National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research (NIPER) Guwahati, Kamrup, Assam, 781101, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murkute</LastName><ForeName>Satyajit Laxman</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research (NIPER) Guwahati, Kamrup, Assam, 781101, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohapatra</LastName><ForeName>Purusottam</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research (NIPER) Guwahati, Kamrup, Assam, 781101, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sahoo</LastName><ForeName>Rakesh Kumar</ForeName><Initials>RK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, School of Chemical Sciences and Pharmacy, Central University of Rajasthan, Bandar Sindri, Ajmer, Rajasthan 305817, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Batheja</LastName><ForeName>Sanya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, School of Chemical Sciences and Pharmacy, Central University of Rajasthan, Bandar Sindri, Ajmer, Rajasthan 305817, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gupta</LastName><ForeName>Umesh</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, School of Chemical Sciences and Pharmacy, Central University of Rajasthan, Bandar Sindri, Ajmer, Rajasthan 305817, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Puri</LastName><ForeName>Anu</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Cancer Research Nanobiology Program, National Cancer Institute at Frederick, National Institutes of Health, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roy</LastName><ForeName>Upal</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Biomedical Sciences, The University of Texas Rio Grande Valley (UTRGV), One West University Blvd., Brownsville, Texas 78520, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alexander</LastName><ForeName>Amit</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0391-7650</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics, National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research (NIPER) Guwahati, Kamrup, Assam, 781101, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 AI147731</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R15 NS108815</GrantID><Acronym>NS</Acronym><Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>France</Country><MedlineTA>J Drug Deliv Sci Technol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101214432</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1773-2247</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anticancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MCF-7</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">breast cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">liposomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">piperine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tamoxifen</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40092050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2034471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11905287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jddst.2024.106331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">106331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Torgovnick A, Schumacher B, DNA repair mechanisms in cancer development and therapy, Front Genet, 6 (2015) 157&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4407582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25954303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jha S, Prabakaran A, Sahoo RK, Batheja S, Gupta U, Alexander A, Antiproliferative activity of syringic acid-loaded nanostructured lipid carriers against MCF-7 human breast carcinoma cells, Journal of Drug Delivery Science and Technology, 98 (2024) 105902.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeSantis C, Ma J, Bryan L, Jemal A, Breast cancer statistics, 2013, CA: a cancer journal for clinicians, 64 (2014) 52&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24114568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariotto AB, Etzioni R, Hurlbert M, Penberthy L, Mayer M, Estimation of the number of women living with metastatic breast cancer in the United States, Cancer Epidemiology, Biomarkers &amp; Prevention, 26 (2017) 809&#x2013;815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5833304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28522448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Midlenko A, Mussina K, Zhakhina G, Sakko Y, Rashidova G, Saktashev B, Adilbay D, Shatkovskaya O, Gaipov A, Prevalence, incidence, and mortality rates of breast cancer in Kazakhstan: data from the Unified National Electronic Health System, 2014&#x2013;2019, Front Public Health, 11 (2023) 1132742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10153091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37143985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charan M, Verma AK, Hussain S, Misri S, Mishra S, Majumder S, Ramaswamy B, Ahirwar D, Ganju RK, Molecular and Cellular Factors Associated with Racial Disparity in Breast Cancer, Int J Mol Sci, 21 (2020) 5936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7460595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32824813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye F, Dewanjee S, Li Y, Jha NK, Chen Z-S, Kumar A, Vishakha T. Behl SK Jha H. Tang, Advancements in clinical aspects of targeted therapy and immunotherapy in breast cancer, Molecular cancer, 22 (2023) 105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10324146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37415164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Gong Q, Luo K, Biomarker-driven molecular imaging probes in radiotherapy, Theranostics, 14 (2024) 4127&#x2013;4146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11234278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38994026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain AS, Goel PN, Shah SM, Dhawan VV, Nikam Y, Gude RP, Nagarsenker MS, Tamoxifen guided liposomes for targeting encapsulated anticancer agent to estrogen receptor positive breast cancer cells: in vitro and in vivo evaluation, Biomed Pharmacother, 68 (2014) 429&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24721327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangla B, Neupane YR, Singh A, Kohli K, Tamoxifen and Sulphoraphane for the breast cancer management: A synergistic nanomedicine approach, Med Hypotheses, 132 (2019) 109379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31454641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangla B, Beg S, Alam O, Ahsan W, Haque A, Patel KS, Almalki WH, Alrobaian M, Kohli K, Systematic development and validation of RP-HPLC method for simultaneous estimation of tamoxifen and sulphoraphane with specific application for nanolipidic formulations, Arabian Journal of Chemistry, 13 (2020) 7909&#x2013;7920.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Zheng Q, Song M, Xiao J, Cao Y, Huang Q, Ho C-T, Lu M, A review on the bioavailability, bio-efficacies and novel delivery systems for piperine, Food &amp; Function, 12 (2021) 8867&#x2013;8881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34528635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khamis AAA, Ali EMM, El-Moneim MAA, Abd-Alhaseeb MM, El-Magd MA, Salim EI, Hesperidin, piperine and bee venom synergistically potentiate the anticancer effect of tamoxifen against breast cancer cells, Biomedicine &amp; Pharmacotherapy, 105 (2018) 1335&#x2013;1343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30021371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitra S, Anand U, Jha NK, Shekhawat MS, Saha SC, Nongdam P, Rengasamy KR, Pro&#x107;k&#xf3;w J, Dey A, Anticancer applications and pharmacological properties of piperidine and piperine: a comprehensive review on molecular mechanisms and therapeutic perspectives, Frontiers in Pharmacology, 12 (2022) 772418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8776707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35069196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quijia CR, Chorilli M, Piperine for treating breast cancer: A review of molecular mechanisms, combination with anticancer drugs, and nanosystems, Phytotherapy Research, 36 (2022) 147&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34559416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Bai J, Du W, Kong D, The mechanisms of action of mitochondrial targeting agents in cancer: inhibiting oxidative phosphorylation and inducing apoptosis, Frontiers in Pharmacology, 14 (2023) 1243613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10635426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37954849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M, Wang S, Qi Z, Meng X, Hu M, Liu X, Song Y, Deng Y, Deuterated colchicine liposomes based on oligomeric hyaluronic acid modification enhance anti-tumor effect and reduce systemic toxicity, Int J Pharm, (2022) 122578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36596316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salmaso S, Mastrotto F, Roverso M, Gandin V, De Martin S, Gabbia D, De Franco M, Vaccarin C, Verona M, Chilin A, Caliceti P, Bogialli S, Marzaro G, Tyrosine kinase inhibitor prodrug-loaded liposomes for controlled release at tumor microenvironment, J Control Release, 340 (2021) 318&#x2013;330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34748872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sebaaly C, Greige-Gerges H, Stainmesse S, Fessi H, Charcosset C, Effect of composition, hydrogenation of phospholipids and lyophilization on the characteristics of eugenol-loaded liposomes prepared by ethanol injection method, Food Bioscience, 15 (2016) 1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prathyusha E, Ahmed PA,H, Dethe MR, Agrawal M, Gangipangi V, Sudhagar S, Krishna KV, Dubey SK, Pemmaraju DB, Alexander A, Investigation of ROS generating capacity of curcumin-loaded liposomes and its in vitro cytotoxicity on MCF-7 cell lines using photodynamic therapy, Photodiagnosis and Photodynamic Therapy, 40 (2022) 103091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36031144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nisini R, Poerio N, Mariotti S, De Santis F, Fraziano M, The Multirole of Liposomes in Therapy and Prevention of Infectious Diseases, Front Immunol, 9 (2018) 155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5807682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29459867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander PA,A, Biophysical analysis on molecular interactions between chitosan-coated sinapic acid loaded liposomes and mucin, Biochimica et Biophysica Acta (BBA) - General Subjects, 1868 (2024) 130517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37935351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malviya N, Alexander PA,A, Comparative study on ethosomes and transferosomes for enhancing skin permeability of sinapic acid, Journal of Molecular Liquids, 383 (2023) 122098.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goins B, Phillips WT, Bao A, Strategies for improving the intratumoral distribution of liposomal drugs in cancer therapy, Expert Opinion on Drug Delivery, 13 (2016) 873&#x2013;889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4933501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26981891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghaferi M, Asadollahzadeh MJ, Akbarzadeh A, Ebrahimi Shahmabadi H, Alavi SE, Enhanced Efficacy of PEGylated Liposomal Cisplatin: In Vitro and In Vivo Evaluation, International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 21 (2020) 559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7013419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31952316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nosova AS, Koloskova OO, Nikonova AA, Simonova VA, Smirnov VV, Kudlay D, Khaitov MR, Diversity of PEGylation methods of liposomes and their influence on RNA delivery, Medchemcomm, 10 (2019) 369&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6457174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31015904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kar PA,S, Vignesh K, Kolhe UD, An Overview of Paclitaxel Delivery Systems, in: Saneja A, Panda AK, Lichtfouse E. (Eds.) Sustainable Agriculture Reviews 43: Pharmaceutical Technology for Natural Products Delivery Vol. 1 Fundamentals and Applications, Springer International Publishing, Cham, 2020, pp. 161&#x2013;215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhury N, Chaudhry S, Hall N, Olverson G, Zhang Q-J, Mandal T, Dash S, Kundu A, Targeted Delivery of Doxorubicin Liposomes for Her-2+ Breast Cancer Treatment, AAPS PharmSciTech, 21 (2020) 202&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7995642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32696338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Bai Y, Li Y, Li X, Luo K, Reprogramming the immunosuppressive tumor microenvironment through nanomedicine: an immunometabolism perspective, eBioMedicine, 107 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11388279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39178747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Immordino ML, Dosio F, Cattel L, Stealth liposomes: review of the basic science, rationale, and clinical applications, existing and potential, Int J Nanomedicine, 1 (2006) 297&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2426795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17717971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koudelka S, Tur&#xe1;nek J, Liposomal paclitaxel formulations J Control Release, 163 (2012) 322&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22989535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhavsar D, Gajjar J, Sawant K, Formulation and development of smart pH responsive mesoporous silica nanoparticles for breast cancer targeted delivery of anastrozole: In vitro and in vivo characterizations, Microporous and Mesoporous Materials, 279 (2019) 107&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doerflinger A, Quang NN, Gravel E, Pinna G, Vandamme M, Ducong&#xe9; F, Doris E, Biotin-functionalized targeted polydiacetylene micelles, Chemical Communications, 54 (2018) 3613&#x2013;3616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29577125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosmann T, Rapid colorimetric assay for cellular growth and survival: application to proliferation and cytotoxicity assays, J Immunol Methods, 65 (1983) 55&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6606682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Zhang L, Zhu W, Guo R, Sun H, Chen X, Deng N, Barriers and strategies of cationic liposomes for cancer gene therapy, Molecular Therapy-Methods &amp; Clinical Development, 18 (2020) 751&#x2013;764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7452052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32913882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraft JC, Freeling JP, Wang Z, Ho RJ, Emerging research and clinical development trends of liposome and lipid nanoparticle drug delivery systems, J Pharm Sci, 103 (2014) 29&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4074410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24338748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danaei M, Dehghankhold M, Ataei S, Hasanzadeh Davarani F, Javanmard R, Dokhani A, Khorasani S, Mozafari MR, Impact of Particle Size and Polydispersity Index on the Clinical Applications of Lipidic Nanocarrier Systems, Pharmaceutics, 10 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6027495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29783687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A&#x11f;ardan NBM, De&#x11f;im Z, Y&#x131;lmaz &#x15e;, Alt&#x131;nta&#x15f; L, Topal T, Tamoxifen/raloxifene loaded liposomes for oral treatment of breast cancer, Journal of Drug Delivery Science and Technology, 57 (2020) 101612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nsairat H, Khater D, Sayed U, Odeh F, Al Bawab A, Alshaer W, Liposomes: structure, composition, types, and clinical applications, Heliyon, 8 (2022) e09394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9118483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35600452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardiansyah A, Yang M-C, Liu T-Y, Kuo C-Y, Huang L-Y, Chan T-Y , Hydrophobic Drug-Loaded PEGylated Magnetic Liposomes for Drug-Controlled Release, Nanoscale Research Letters, 12 (2017) 355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5436991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28525950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Wang J, Sun M, Zhang J, Bi Y, Coating liposomes with ring-like PEG: the synthesis and stealth effect of cholesterol&#x2013;PEG&#x2013;cholesterol, Materials Advances, 3 (2022) 2417&#x2013;2424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maji R, Dey NS, Satapathy BS, Mukherjee B, Mondal S, Preparation and characterization of Tamoxifen citrate loaded nanoparticles for breast cancer therapy, Int J Nanomedicine, 9 (2014) 3107&#x2013;3118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4077606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25028549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suzery M, Ria R, Cahyono B, Alkaloids piperine in dichloromethane fraction of red galangal rizhome ( Alpinia purpurata ), IOP Conference Series: Materials Science and Engineering, 509 (2019) 012076.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta U, Singh V, Kumar V, Khajuria Y, Spectroscopic Studies of Cholesterol: Fourier Transform Infra-Red and Vibrational Frequency Analysis, Material Focus, 3 (2014) 1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie J, Li Y, Song L, Pan Z, Ye S, Hou Z, Design of a novel curcumin-soybean phosphatidylcholine complex-based targeted drug delivery systems, Drug Deliv, 24 (2017) 707&#x2013;719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8241017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28436718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee P, Geng T, Mahanty A, Li T, Zong L, Wang B, Integrating the drug, disulfiram into the vitamin E-TPGS-modified PEGylated nanostructured lipid carriers to synergize its repurposing for anticancer therapy of solid tumors, Int J Pharm, 557 (2019) 374&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30610896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Jubori AA, Sulaiman GM, Tawfeeq AT, Mohammed HA, Khan RA, Mohammed SAA, Layer-by-Layer Nanoparticles of Tamoxifen and Resveratrol for Dual Drug Delivery System and Potential Triple-Negative Breast Cancer Treatment, Pharmaceutics, 13 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8309206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34371789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Pu C, Tang W, Wang S, Sun Q, Gallic acid liposomes decorated with lactoferrin: Characterization, in vitro digestion and antibacterial activity, Food Chemistry, 293 (2019) 315&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31151617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu H, Chen P, Liu X, Lian Y, Xi J, Li J, Song J, Li X, Trimethylated chitosan-coated flexible liposomes with resveratrol for topical drug delivery to reduce blue-light-induced retinal damage, International Journal of Biological Macromolecules, (2023) 126480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37634770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamauchi M, Tsutsumi K, Abe M, Uosaki Y, Nakakura M, Aoki N, Release of drugs from liposomes varies with particle size, Biol Pharm Bull, 30 (2007) 963&#x2013;966.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17473443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raju R, Abuwatfa WH, Pitt WG, Husseini GA, Liposomes for the Treatment of Brain Cancer&#x2014;A Review, Pharmaceuticals, 16 (2023) 1056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10458450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37630971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Megahed MA, El-Sawy HS, Reda AM, Abd-Allah FI, Abu Elyazid SK, Lila AE, Ismael HR, El-Say KM, Effect of nanovesicular surface-functionalization via chitosan and/or PEGylation on cytotoxicity of tamoxifen in induced-breast cancer model, Life Sciences, 307 (2022) 120908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36028168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clemons M, Danson S, Howell A, Tamoxifen (&#x2018;Nolvadex&#x2019;): a review: Antitumour treatment, Cancer treatment reviews, 28 (2002) 165&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12363457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang J, Ji H, Ren J, Li M, Zheng N, Wu L, Solid lipid nanoparticles with TPGS and Brij 78: a co-delivery vehicle of curcumin and piperine for reversing P-glycoprotein-mediated multidrug resistance in vitro, Oncology Letters, 13 (2017) 389&#x2013;395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5245101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28123572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steffes VM, Zhang Z, MacDonald S, Crowe J, Ewert KK, Carragher B, Potter CS, Safinya CR, PEGylation of Paclitaxel-Loaded Cationic Liposomes Drives Steric Stabilization of Bicelles and Vesicles thereby Enhancing Delivery and Cytotoxicity to Human Cancer Cells, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces, 12 (2020) 151&#x2013;162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6984750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31820904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>