<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40918916</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Venous Thromboembolism Risk Assessment in Prolonged Fasting During Ramadan: The Global Ramadan Free Thrombosis Project.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e89406</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e89406</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e89406</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.89406</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Fasting during the month of Ramadan is practiced by over a billion Muslims worldwide. This religious observance, which involves complete abstention from food and fluids during daylight hours, may contribute to dehydration and increase the risk of venous thromboembolism (VTE), particularly in hot climates. Despite this theoretical concern, limited clinical evidence exists on the actual incidence and risk of VTE associated with prolonged fasting. This study aimed to assess the risk of VTE in fasting individuals during Ramadan using the Caprini risk assessment model and propose a prophylactic strategy tailored for the fasting population. Methodology A multicenter, observational study was conducted across several countries during the Ramadan period. Standard Caprini scores were calculated, and additional fasting-specific risk factors, including fasting duration, temperature exposure, physical activity, and hydration, were recorded. The presence of varicose veins and a history of thrombophilia were also evaluated. VTE events were tracked and analyzed during the fasting period. Results A proportion of participants developed VTE during the fasting period. Those who experienced thrombotic events had higher Caprini risk scores and a greater prevalence of contributing factors such as varicose veins, venous reflux, and thrombophilia. All events occurred during the fasting period and were not attributed to other medical conditions. Conclusions Ramadan fasting may unmask or exacerbate thrombotic risk, particularly in individuals with pre-existing venous disease or thrombophilia. Risk stratification using the Caprini score, supplemented with fasting-specific factors, can help identify at-risk individuals. Targeted preventive strategies, including patient education, fluid management, and medical prophylaxis for high-risk groups, should be considered to ensure safe fasting practices during Ramadan.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Caprini et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caprini</LastName><ForeName>Joseph</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vascular Surgery, Pritzker School of Medicine at the University of Chicago, Chicago, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fakhry</LastName><ForeName>Ayman</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vascular Surgery, Egyptian Military Academy, Cairo, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nagib</LastName><ForeName>Sohiel</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vascular Surgery, Royal Vascular Center, Alexandria, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Mallah</LastName><ForeName>Abdullah H</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Education, Maastricht University, Maastricht, NLD.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Education, Al-Azhar University, Cairo, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vascular Surgery, Al-Azhar University, Cairo, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barsim</LastName><ForeName>Eslam M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vascular Surgery, Faculty of Medicine, Menofia University, Menofia, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farrag</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Surgery, Alexandria Main University Hospital, Alexandria, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abouelseoud</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vascular Surgery, Alexandria Main University Hospital, Alexandria, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alnadi</LastName><ForeName>Omar</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Surgery, Abu Qir General Hospital, Alexandria, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moner</LastName><ForeName>Mahmoud</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Surgery and Medicine, Al-Ahrar Teaching Hospital, Al-Sharqia, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghazy</LastName><ForeName>Ziad M</ForeName><Initials>ZM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vascular Surgery, Abu Qir General Hospital, Alexandria, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seken</LastName><ForeName>Rahma A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Al-Azhar University, Damietta, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jabr</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine and Surgery, Abu Qir General Hospital, Alexandria, EGY.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boucelma</LastName><ForeName>Malika</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Bachir Mentouri Hospital, Kouba, DZA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zyada</LastName><ForeName>Ayman</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vascular Surgery, University Hospitals of Leicester NHS Trust, Leicester, GBR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">caprini score</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deep venous thrombosis (dvt)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fasting ramadan</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">risk assessment model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">venous thromboembolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vte prophylaxis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Egyptian Venous Forum Medical Ethics and Research Committee (EVFMERC) issued approval R125T. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40918916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12410030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.89406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ghani F. Pew Research Center. Most Muslims say they fast during Ramadan.  [
Jan;
2020 
]. 2013. https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2013/07/09/global-median-of-93-of-muslims-say-they-fast-during-ramadan/ https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2013/07/09/global-median-of-93-of-muslims-say-they-fast-during-ramadan/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Is there any effect of Ramadan fasting on acute coronary heart disease events? Temizhan A, D&#xf6;nderici O, Ouz D, Demirbas B. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0167-5273(99)00082-0. Int J Cardiol. 1999;70:149&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10454303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patient-guided modifications of oral anticoagulant drug intake during Ramadan fasting: a multicenter cross-sectional study. Batarfi A, Alenezi H, Alshehri A, et al. J Thromb Thrombolysis. 2021;51:485&#x2013;493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7886720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32666427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>BIMA BIMA. British Islamic Medical Association (BIMA): Ramadan rapid review.  [
Mar;
2025 
]. 2020. https://www.ahpcc.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Ramadan-Rapid-Review-Recommendations.pdf https://www.ahpcc.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/05/Ramadan-Rapid-Review-Recommendations.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramadan fasting: recommendations for patients with cardiovascular disease. Akhtar AM, Ghouri N, Chahal CA, et al. Heart. 2022;108:258&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8819657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33990414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Air travel and the risk of thromboembolism. Gavish I, Brenner B. Intern Emerg Med. 2011;6:113&#x2013;116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21057984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasting-induced natriuresis and SGLT: a new hypothesis for an old enigma. Heyman SN, Bursztyn M, Szalat A, Muszkat M, Abassi Z. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2020;11:217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7221140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32457696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Individual risk assessment is the best strategy for thromboembolic prophylaxis. Caprini JA. Dis Mon. 2010;56:552&#x2013;559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20971324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Water, hydration, and health. Popkin BM, D'Anci KE, Rosenberg IH. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1753-4887.2010.00304.x. Nutr Rev. 2010;68:439&#x2013;458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2908954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20646222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dehydration as a possible cause of monthly variation in the incidence of venous thromboembolism. Elias S, Hoffman R, Saharov G, Brenner B, Nadir Y. https://doi.org/10.1177/1076029616649435. Clin Appl Thromb Hemost. 2016;22:569&#x2013;574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27206642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessment of VTE risk factors during fasting hours in Ramadan in hot weather countries. Caprini J, Fakhry A, Ayman S. https://egyptianvenousforum.org/3d-flip-book/egyptian-journal-of-phlebology-lymphology/ Egyptian J Phlebol Lymphol. 2024;1:14&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varicose veins and risk of venous thromboembolic diseases: a two-sample-based Mendelian randomization study. Li R, Chen Z, Gui L, et al. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2022;9:849027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9047357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35498031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winter and venous thromboembolism: a dangerous liaison? Manfredini R, Gallerani M, Salmi R, Dentali F, Ageno W. Future Cardiol. 2011;7:717&#x2013;719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22050054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A comprehensive review of risk factors and thrombophilia evaluation in venous thromboembolism. Dicks AB, Moussallem E, Stanbro M, Walls J, Gandhi S, Gray BH. J Clin Med. 2024;13:362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10816375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38256496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>