<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39775086</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Study on the durability of solidified mud under chloride and dry-wet coupling.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1071</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1071</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1071</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-024-82856-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In order to study the durability of solidified waste mud, dry-wet cycle experiments were carried out under the erosion of sodium chloride solutions with different concentrations. The unconfined compressive strength and mass change rate of solidified mud were studied and analyzed. The results show that when the number of dry-wet cycles increases, the unconfined compressive strength and mass of the sample show a downward trend. The unconfined compressive strength of the solidified mud in 40&#xa0;g / L sodium chloride solution decreases the most, reaching 52.89%, and the mass loss reaches 8.36&#xa0;g. The microstructure analysis was carried out by scanning electron microscopy. It was found that the hydration products such as hydrated calcium silicate gel ( C-S-H ) and calcium hydroxide crystal ( C-H ) in the solidified mud samples under the coupling of chloride erosion and dry-wet cycle were reduced, and more pores and cracks appeared. Under the same number of dry-wet cycles, the higher the concentration of sodium chloride solution, the more serious the micro-damage inside the sample. The decrease of the strength of the solidified slurry is due to the hydrolysis of the hydration products in the solidified mud under the combined action of chloride salt and dry-wet cycle, and some of the materials are dissolved, resulting in more cracks.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Songtao</LastName><ForeName>Zhang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Anhui University of Science and Technology, AnHui Huainan, 232001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anhui Water Resources Development Co., Ltd, AnHui Bengbu, 233000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jianyong</LastName><ForeName>Pang</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Anhui University of Science and Technology, AnHui Huainan, 232001, China. jypang@aust.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jinsong</LastName><ForeName>Zhang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Anhui University of Science and Technology, AnHui Huainan, 232001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Changwei</LastName><ForeName>Zhou</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Anhui University of Science and Technology, AnHui Huainan, 232001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yaxing</LastName><ForeName>Wang</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering and Architecture, Anhui University of Science and Technology, AnHui Huainan, 232001, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023AH051219</GrantID><Agency>Anhui Provincial Higher Education Science Research Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chloride salt</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dry-wet cycle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Microstructure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Solidified mud</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Unconfined compressive strength</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39775086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11707068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-82856-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-024-82856-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fernando, P. T . et al. Investigations about the effect of aggregates on strength and microstructure of geopolymeric mine waste mud binders. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>37</b>(6), 933&#x2013;941 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2007.02.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, S. H. et al. Experimental and field study on treatment waste mud by in-situ solidification. Proceedings of the Institution of Civil Engineers - Municipal Engineer, 173(4), 1&#x2013;23 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rykusova, N. et al. Identification of properties of recycled highdensity polyethylene composites when filled with waste mud solids. <i>Eastern-European J. Enterp. Technol.</i><b>2</b>(10(98)), 55&#x2013;60 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15587/1729-4061.2019.163656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, D. Q. et al. Research progress of solid waste recycling for land reclamation technology in Singapore. <i>Environ. Sci. Res</i>. <b>31</b>(07), 1174&#x2013;1181 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guang, L. et al. Immobilization of heavy metal contaminated soil by different cementation materials. <i>Res. J. Environ. Sci.</i><b>23</b>(1), 106&#x2013;111 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zentar, R. et al. Utilization of siliceous-aluminous fly ash and cement for solidification of marine sediments. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>35</b>, 856&#x2013;863 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2012.04.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi, Y. et al. Test on alkali-activated ground granulated blast-furnace slag (GGBS) for Lianyungang soft soil stabilization. <i>Chin. J. Rock Mechan. Eng.</i><b>32</b>(9), 1820&#x2013;1826 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou, X. D. et al. Biological consolidation test study of hydraulic fill for land reclamation at North Bay of Guangxi Province. <i>Rock Soil Mech.</i>. <b>36</b>(1), 28&#x2013;33 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, W. et al. Soil-water transfer mechanism for solidified dredged materials. <i>J. Geotech. GeoEnviron. Eng.</i><b>133</b>(5), 588&#x2013;598 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)1090-0241(2007)133:5(588)</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, Y. et al. Change of mechanical behavior between solidified and remolded solidified dredged materials. <i>Eng. Geol.</i><b>119</b>(3), 112&#x2013;119 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enggeo.2011.03.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, T. J. et al. Change law of water content of dredged clays treated by quick lime. <i>Rock. Soil. Mech.</i><b>30</b>(9), 2775&#x2013;2779 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, C. M., et al . A fundamental parametric study on the solidification of Malaysian dredged marine soils. <i>World Appl. Sci.</i><b>24</b>(6), 784&#x2013;793 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, W. J. et al. Optimization of microstructure and mechanical performance of clay-rich sand-washing slurry-based geopolymers. <i>Appl. Clay Sci.</i><b>260</b>, 107551&#x2013;107551 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J. J. et al. Study of evolution law off issures of expansive clay under wetting and drying cycles. <i>Rock Soil Mech.</i><b>32</b>(9), 2729&#x2013;27340 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, W. et al. Experimental study on shear strength characteristics of sulfate saline soil in Ningxia region under long-term freeze-thaw cycles. <i>Cold Reg. Sci. Technol.</i><b>160</b>, 48&#x2013;57 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.coldregions.2019.01.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv, Q. et al. A study on the effect of the salt content on the solidification of sulfate saline soil solidified with an alkali-activated geopolymer. <i>Constr. Building Mater.</i><b>176</b>(10), 68&#x2013;74 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.05.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, J. et al. Mechanical properties of alkali slag-slag solidified sludge in eroded environment. <i>Hydrogeol. Eng. Geol.</i><b>46</b>(06), 83&#x2013;89 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maio, D. Exposure of bentonite to salt solution: osmotic and mechanical effects. <i>Geotechnique</i><b>46</b>(4), 695&#x2013;707 (1996).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1680/geot.1996.46.4.695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di, M. et al. Shear displacements induced by decrease in pore solution concentration on a pre-existing slip surface. <i>Eng. Geol.</i><b>200</b>, 1&#x2013;9 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enggeo.2015.11.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng, T. Study on the strength degradation law and service life of grouting materials for subsea tunnels. <i>Hydrogeological Eng. Geol.</i><b>38</b>(01), 65&#x2013;68 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bian X. et al. Effect of drying-wet cycle on physical and mechanical properties of polymer absorbent resin solidified mud soil. <i>China J. High. Transp</i>. <b>36</b>(10), 55&#x2013;63 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J. S. et al. Experimental study on the characteristics of slag-lime-water glass composite cured mud. <i>Arab. J. Geosci.</i><b>15</b>(18), 1&#x2013;9 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12517-022-10772-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou, M. X. et al. Experimental study on expansive soil preparation engineering mud. <i>J. Northwest. F Univ. (Natural Sci. Edition)</i>. <b>04</b>, 44 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cong, A. S. et al. Design, Construction and Application of deep Foundation pit anti-seepage body [M]. Beijing: Intellectual Property (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, H. R. et al. Study on the damage mechanism of microstructure of sand conglomerate in Maijishan Grottoes by freeze-thaw cycles. <i>Chin. J. Mech. Eng.</i><b>40</b>(03), 545&#x2013;555 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, Q. Y. et al. Frost resistance and damage model of BSFC under Freeze-Thaw Cycles. <i>J. Building Mater.</i><b>24</b>(06), 1169&#x2013;1178 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, X. Study on physical and mechanical properties and damage model of sandstone under acid dry wet cycle. <i>Anhui University of Science &amp; Technology</i> (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malliou, O. et al. Properties of stabilized/solidified admixtures of cement and sewage sludge[J]. <i>Cement Concr. Compos.</i><b>29</b>(1), 55&#x2013;61 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2006.08.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cha, F. S. et al. Experimental Study on Strength and Microscopic Characteristics of Cement Solidified lead Contaminated soil under NaCl erosion Environment. <i>Rock Mech. Rock Eng.</i><b>34</b>(S2), 4325&#x2013;4332 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L. J. Comparative Experimental Study on Expansibility and Shrinkage of Expansive soil.&#xa0;<i>Southwest Jiaotong University</i> (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su, X. P. et al. Experimental study on durability of concrete under single salt erosion and freeze-thaw cycles. <i>Industrial Building</i>. <b>44</b>(09), 110&#x2013;113 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, C. M. et al. Experimental study on strength deterioration model of compacted loess under wetting-drying cycles. <i>J. Rock. Mech. Eng.</i><b>37</b>(12), 2804&#x2013;2818 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu X. J.et al. Improvement of mechanical properties and condensation mechanism of calcium hydroxide on slag alkali-activated materials. <i>J. Jiangsu Vocat. Tech. Coll. Archit.</i><b>24</b>(03), 31&#x2013;38 (2024)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, M. et al. Basic mechanical properties and microscopic properties of alkali-activated slag/fly ash desert sand concrete. <i>Materials Reports</i> 1&#x2013;26(2024)</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>