<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41254461</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Use of Golf Carts as On-Course Transportation During Competitive Golf Events: A Scoping Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>117</StartPage><EndPage>136</EndPage><MedlinePgn>117-136</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-025-02354-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Golf is enjoyed by over 108 million people globally, and has established elite female, male and disability competitive schedules. The use of golf carts during elite competition is a topic of discussion regarding the principles of inclusivity and competitive fairness with important scientific, legal and ethical considerations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The primary aim was to evaluate the evidence relating to riding a golf cart in comparison to walking the golf course, pertaining specifically to: (1) inclusivity and safety, and (2) competitive fairness. The secondary aim was to identify knowledge gaps and research priorities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a scoping review and the search strategy was applied to the following databases, and articles were extracted by independent reviewers from PubMed, Web of Science, Scopus and ProQuest Central. Grey literature was examined using Google Advanced Search. A five-stage scoping review methodology followed the Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses extension for Scoping Reviews (PRISMA-ScR). Articles were collated using an online tool (Covidence) and evaluated against pre-determined criteria. Data from included studies were collated to facilitate descriptive and thematic analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of the 879 studies identified, 72 were included for analysis. Seven themes emerged: physical demands, inclusion and accessibility, cognitive demands, legal and ethical, nutrition and hydration, competitive fairness, and safety and injury risk. Golf carts promote accessibility, particularly for individuals with disabilities. Safety concerns predominantly arise in non-elite settings, with incidents linked to operator error, poor safety governance and use on public highways. There is compelling evidence demonstrating that in-round riding of golf carts reduces the physical demands of golf, with users expending less energy and covering shorter distances, although effects on performance is uncertain. Golf cart use may mitigate the environmental aspects of golf, including the effects of hot/humid weather or hilly topography.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Golf carts can increase inclusivity for golfers and enable clubs and organisations to meet their ethical and legal requirements around accessibility. However, riding golf carts may diminish some of the health benefits of golf, and present a risk of injury and practical challenges. In the competitive setting, golf cart use reduces the physical demands of the game, affecting the environmental challenges of variable weather and terrain. It is biologically plausible and likely that this would offer a performance advantage in some circumstances. More research is needed to guide the fair use of this enabling technology within clearly defined contexts by: (1) evaluating the performance deficits associated with medical issues in which the use of golf carts might be considered permissible, and (2) evaluating the magnitude and nature of competitive advantages experienced by golf cart riders.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hall</LastName><ForeName>Andrew J</ForeName><Initials>AJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4582-8368</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, University of St Andrews, North Haugh, St Andrews, Fife, KY16 9TF, UK. ajh52@st-andrews.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport and Exercise, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK. ajh52@st-andrews.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>European Tour Performance Institute, European Tour Group, Virginia Water, UK. ajh52@st-andrews.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bishop</LastName><ForeName>Chris</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1505-1287</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>European Tour Performance Institute, European Tour Group, Virginia Water, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>London Sports Institute, University of Middlesex, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Donnell</LastName><ForeName>Amy</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise Sciences, Liverpool John Moores University, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ladies European Tour Performance Institute, Ladies European Tour, Denham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bennett</LastName><ForeName>Tony</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Disability and Inclusion, International Golf Federation, Lausanne, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Presidents Office, EDGA (Formerly European Disabled Golf Association), Wassenaar, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Close</LastName><ForeName>Graeme L</ForeName><Initials>GL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>European Tour Performance Institute, European Tour Group, Virginia Water, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute for Sport and Exercise Sciences, Liverpool John Moores University, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Du Plessis</LastName><ForeName>Wimpie</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical and Scientific Department, Sunshine Tour, Johannesburg, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murray</LastName><ForeName>Andrew D</ForeName><Initials>AD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport and Exercise, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>European Tour Performance Institute, European Tour Group, Virginia Water, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical and Scientific Department, The R&amp;A, St Andrews, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000098583">Scoping Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006055" MajorTopicYN="Y">Golf</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000293" MajorTopicYN="N">injuries</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003163" MajorTopicYN="Y">Competitive Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014186" MajorTopicYN="Y">Transportation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019876" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sports Equipment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012449" MajorTopicYN="N">Safety</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Funding: Andrew J. Hall received modest funding for the preparation of this article from The R&amp;A and European Tour Group. Conflict of interest: The authors have paid and unpaid roles providing services in support of elite/professional golfers. Chris Bishop, Amy O&#x2019;Donnell, Tony Bennett, Graeme L. Close, Wimpie Du Plessis and Andrew D. Murray have paid and unpaid roles within international organisations that govern professional and amateur golf. Andrew J. Hall has no conflicts of interest that are directly relevant to the content of this article. Ethics approval: No specific research ethics committee review is applicable. Consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Availability of data and material: All data are publicly available in the published literature. Code availability: Not applicable. Author contributions: AJH: conceptualisation, data curation, formal analysis, methodology, project administration, writing (original draft), writing (review and editing). CB: writing (original draft), writing (review and editing). AOD: data curation, writing (review and editing). TB: writing (review and editing). GLC: writing (review and editing). WDP: writing (review and editing). ADM: conceptualisation, data curation, methodology, project administration, supervision, writing (original draft), writing (review and editing). All authors approve of the publication of this article and agree to be accountable for all aspects of the work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41254461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12913357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-025-02354-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-025-02354-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>The R&amp;A. Over 100 million golfers in R&amp;A markets as participation grows. 2025. https://www.randa.org/articles/over-100-million-golfers-in-randa-markets-as-global-participation-continues-to-grow. Accessed 31 Aug 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The R&amp;A. R&amp;A annual review (2021). 2021. https://assets-us-01.kc-usercontent.com/c42c7bf4-dca7-00ea-4f2e-373223f80f76/d67da449-0e4b-41eb-93ce-4229b5467ae9/AnnualReview 2021.pdf. Accessed 10 Nov 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luscombe J, Murray AD, Jenkins E, Archibald D. A rapid review to identify physical activity accrued while playing golf. BMJ Open. 2017;7:e018993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5719314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29187418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray AD, Daines L, Archibald D, Hawkes RA, Schiphorst C, Kelly P, et al. The relationships between golf and health: a scoping review. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:12&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5256129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27697939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter SE, Beaumont AJ, Sorbie GG. Physical activity accrued whilst golf caddying. Int J Golf Sci. 2023;11:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorbie G, Richardson AK, Glen J, Hardie S, Taliep S, Wade M, et al. The association of golf participation with health and wellbeing: a comparative study. Int J Golf Sci. 2020;9:1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorbie GG, Williams AK, Carter SE, Campbell AK, Glen J, Lavallee D, et al. Improved physical health in middle-older aged golf caddies following 24 weeks of high-volume physical activity. J Phys Act Health. 2023;21:134&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37939701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray AD, Hawkes RA, Kelly P, Grant L, Mutrie N. Do golf fans walk the talk? Follow-up of spectators&#x2019; beliefs and self-reported physical activity 3 months after they attended a professional golf tournament in the UK. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2019;5:e000503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6347860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30740236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>USGA. USGA competitive fairness gender policy. 2024. https://champ-admin.usga.org/player/articles/usga-competitive-fairness-gender-policy. Accessed 10 Nov 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&amp;A. The R&amp;A introduces fair competition policy. 2024. https://www.randa.org/articles/the-r-a-introduces-fair-competition-policy-for-its-professional-and-elite-amateur-championships. Accessed 10 Nov 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Congress US. Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990. S.933 USA; 1990. https://www.govinfo.gov/app/details/STATUTE-104/STATUTE-104-Pg327#:~:text=DocumentCitations&amp;text=AmericanswithDisabilitiesActof1990%2CPublicLaw336%2CU.S.,%2FSTATUTE-104-Pg327. Accessed 10 Nov 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Government U. The Equality Act (2010). 2024. https://www.legislation.gov.uk/ukpga/2010/15/contents. Accessed 19 Oct 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson BR. PGA Tour, Inc &#x3bd;. Martin: The U.S. Supreme Court misses the cut on Americans with Disabilities Act. Labor Lawyer. 2002;18:47&#x2013;78. https://www.jstor.org/stable/40862788. Accessed 10 Nov 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>States SC of the U. PGA Tour, Inc., v Casey Martin&#x2014;Opinion of the Court. 2001. p. 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sports S. The 148th Open: John Daly denied permission to use golf cart at Portrush. Golf News Sky Sports. 2019. https://www.skysports.com/golf/news/14866/11758102/the-148th-open-john-daly-denied-permission-to-use-golf-cart-at-portrush. Accessed 31 Aug 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sports S. John Daly approved to use golf cart at PGA Championship. Golf News Sky Sports. 2019. https://www.skysports.com/golf/news/12176/11714459/john-daly-approved-to-use-golf-cart-at-pga-championship. Accessed 31 Aug 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EDGA. The G4D Tour. Leaders Sport. 2024: p. 8&#x2013;15. https://leadersinsport.com/sport-business/leaders-events/leaders-sport-awards/2023-categories/purpose-shortlists/the-g4d-tour/#:~:text=TheG4DTour(Golf for,incollaborationwiththeR%26A. Accessed 19 Oct 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guillaume S, Bennett T, Allen PM, Morrison A, Hawkes R, Jayabalan P. The global state of play: a study of the demographic characteristics of disability golfers. PM&amp;R. 2023;15:1309&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12226809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36730163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>USGA. Single rider cart policy for Senior Amateur Championships. US Golf Association; https://www.usga.org/content/dam/usga/pdf/ChampionshipResources/SingleRiderCartPolicyAlt.pdf. Accessed 10 Nov 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tricco AC, Lillie E, Zarin W, O&#x2019;Brien KK, Colquhoun H, Levac D, et al. PRISMA extension for scoping reviews (PRISMA-ScR): checklist and explanation. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169:467&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters MDJ, Marnie C, Tricco AC, Pollock D, Munn Z, Alexander L, et al. Updated methodological guidance for the conduct of scoping reviews. JBI Evid Synth. 2020;18:2119&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33038124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levac D, Colquhoun H, O&#x2019;Brien KK. Scoping studies: advancing the methodology. Implement Sci. 2010;5:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2954944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20854677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arksey H, O&#x2019;Malley L. Scoping studies: towards a methodological framework. Int J Soc Res Methodol. 2005;8:19&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiger ME, Varpio L. Thematic analysis of qualitative data: AMEE guide no. 131. Med Teach. 2020;42:846&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32356468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman AL, Hadfield M, Chapman CJ. Qualitative research in healthcare: an introduction to grounded theory using thematic analysis. J R Coll Physicians Edinb. 2015;45:201&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26517098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith CJ, Callister R, Lubans DR. A systematic review of strength and conditioning programmes designed to improve fitness characteristics in golfers. J Sports Sci. 2011;29:933&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21547836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puterbaugh JS. A good walk spoiled: on the disappearance of golf as an active sport in America. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2011;10:228&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23531899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrmann SD, Willis EA, Ainsworth BE, Barreira TV, Hastert M, Kracht CL, et al. 2024 Adult compendium of physical activities: a third update of the energy costs of human activities. J Sport Health Sci. 2024;13:6&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10818145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38242596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berlin N, Cooke MB, Belski R. Nutritional considerations for elite golf: a narrative review. Nutrients. 2023;15:4116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10574085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37836399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McBride D. Provision of enabling technology in professional sports. Percept Mot Skills. 2000;90:1219&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10939073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conger SA, Herrmann SD, Willis EA, Nightingale TE, Sherman JR, Ainsworth BE. 2024 wheelchair compendium of physical activities: an update of activity codes and energy expenditure values. J Sport Health Sci. 2024;13:18&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10818147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38242594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandervoort AA, Lindsay DM, Lynn SK, Noffal GJ. Golf is a physical activity for a lifetime. Int J Golf Sci. 2012;1:54&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donnell A, Murray A, Nguyen A, Salmon T, Taylor S, Morton JP, et al. Nutrition and golf performance: a systematic scoping review. Sports Med. 2024;54:3081&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11608286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39347918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheuvront SN, Kenefick RW. Dehydration: physiology, assessment, and performance effects. Compr Physiol. 2014;4:257&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24692140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brennan A, Murray A, Mountjoy M, Hellstrom J, Coughlan D, Wells J, et al. Associations between physical characteristics and golf clubhead speed: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2024;54:1553&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11239735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38424374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zoffer M. Competitive golf: how longer courses are changing athletes and their approach to the game. Nutrients. 2022;14:1732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9104041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35565702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willis EA, Herrmann SD, Hastert M, Kracht CL, Barreira TV, Schuna JMJ, et al. Older adult compendium of physical activities: energy costs of human activities in adults aged 60 and older. J Sport Health Sci. 2024;13:13&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10818108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38242593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson M-MG, Morley JE. Impaired cognitive function and mental performance in mild dehydration. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2003;57(Suppl. 2):S24&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14681710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McHardy A, Pollard H. Muscle activity during the golf swing. Br J Sports Med. 2005;39:799&#x2013;804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1725059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16244187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellstr&#xf6;m J. Competitive elite golf. Sports Med. 2009;39:723&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19691363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith MF. The role of physiology in the development of golf performance. Sport Med. 2010;40:635&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20632736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres-Ronda L, S&#xe1;nchez-Medina L, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Badillo JJ. Muscle strength and golf performance: a critical review. J Sports Sci Med. 2011;10:9&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3737887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monforte J, Smith B, Bennett T. Benefits, barriers and facilitators to golf participation among disabled people: identifying opportunities to increase uptake and foster inclusion. Int J Golf Sci. 2021;10:1&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broman G, Johnsson L, Kaijser L. Golf: a high intensity interval activity for elderly men. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2004;16:375&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15636463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odabas HI, Gercek N. In-game physiological responses of young elite male and female golf players: a field-based study. Ann Appl Sport Sci. 2022. 10.52547/aassjournal.1048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.52547/aassjournal.1048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres-Ronda L, Delextrat A, Gonzalez-Badillo JJ. The relationship between golf performance, anthropometrics, muscular strength and power characteristics in young elite players. Int Sport J. 2014;15:156&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hierholzer KM. Energy expenditure of collegiate golfers in a competitive setting. Northern Illinois University; 2016. https://huskiecommons.lib.niu.edu/allgraduate-thesesdissertations/2873/. Accessed 10 Nov 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kettinen J, Tikkanen H, Hiltunen M, Murray A, Horn N, Taylor WR, et al. Cognitive and biomarker responses in healthy older adults to a 18-hole golf round and different walking types: a randomised cross-over study. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2023;9:e001629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10582962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37860153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolkodoff NE, Haase GM, Pennymon BN. Energy expenditure compared to mental focus &amp; score in three modes of golf transport/play. World J Adv Res Rev. 2022;16:825&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells JET, Charalambous LH, Mitchell ACS, Coughlan D, Brearley SL, Hawkes RA, et al. Relationships between Challenge Tour golfers&#x2019; clubhead velocity and force producing capabilities during a countermovement jump and isometric mid-thigh pull. J Sports Sci. 2019;37:1381&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30572804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasper AM, O&#x2019;Donnell A, Langan-Evans C, Jones A, Lindsay A, Murray A, et al. Assessment of activity energy expenditure during competitive golf: the effects of bag carrying, electric or manual trolleys. Eur J Sport Sci. 2023;23:330&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35098891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathers JF, Grealy MA. Motor control strategies and the effects of fatigue on golf putting performance. Front Psychol. 2014;4:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3888943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24454298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sell TC, Abt JP, Lephart SM. Physical activity-related benefits of walking during golf. University of Pittsburgh. 2008;1:128&#x2013;32. https://sites.pitt.edu/~neurolab/publications/2008/Articles/Sell_WSCG_2008_PhysicalActivity-RelatedBenefitsofWalkingDuring Golf.pdf. Accessed 10 Nov 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyerly GW, Ludlam DN, Henry SM, Beam SL, Martel GF. The effect of walking versus riding on energy expenditure in golf. Gazz Med Ital Arch Sci Med. 2022;181:110&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson JD, Smith J, Shah JP, Wisniewski SJ, Dahm DL. Golf after total knee arthroplasty: do patients return to walking the course? Am J Sports Med. 2009;37:2201&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19684299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higdon NR, Finch WH, Leib D, Dugan EL. Effects of fatigue on golf performance. Sports Biomech. 2012;11:190&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22900400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells GD, Elmi M, Thomas S. Physiological correlates of golf performance. J Strength Cond Res. 2009;23:741&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19387406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayabalan P, Bergman R, Jauregui E, Hanaoka C, Stoker AM. Acute physiological effects of continuous versus intermittent walking during golf in individuals with knee osteoarthritis: a pilot study. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2022;101:460&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8783928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34310345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zunzer SC, von Duvillard SP, Tschakert G, Mangus B, Hofmann P. Energy expenditure and sex differences of golf playing. J Sports Sci. 2013;31(10):1045&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23362842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>G4D. The G4D Tour: sport business. https://leadersinsport.com/sport-business/leaders-events/leaders-sport-awards/2023-categories/purpose-shortlists/the-g4d-tour/. Accessed 13 Nov 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>England Golf. Buggy policy: including disabled people. 2021. p. 3&#x2013;5. https://www.gcma.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/buggy-policy-and-use1.pdf. Accessed 10 Nov 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>England Golf. Creating an equitable buggy policy: guidance to help you review your existing policy and decision making. 2019. p. 1&#x2013;6. https://static.whsplatform.englandgolf.org/clubs/1000-1/uploads/downloads/governance/buggies_transportation/creating-an-equitable-buggy-policy-how-to-guide-for-clubs.pdf. Accessed 19 Oct 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martowicz M, Budgett R, Pape M, Mascagni K, Engebretsen L, Dienstbach-Wech L, et al. Position statement: IOC framework on fairness, inclusion and non-discrimination on the basis of gender identity and sex variations. Br J Sports Med. 2023;57:26&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36526281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golf E. Buggies and transportation. 2024. p. 2024. https://www.englandgolf.org/resource-detail/buggies-and-transportation. Accessed 19 Oct 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scottish Golf. Exploring positive action by golf clubs. 2024. p. 2024. https://www.scottishgolf.org/news-detail?newsarticleid=2238. Accessed 19 Oct 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scottish Golf. Creating an equitable buggy policy. 2023. https://static.clubhouse.scottishgolf.org/clubs/1000/uploads/files_and_docs/club_business/buggypolicy.pdf. Accessed 10 Nov 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandiera D, Racinais S, Garrandes F, Adami PE, Bermon S, Pitsiladis YP, et al. Heat-related risk at Paris 2024: a proposal for classification and review of international federations policies. Br J Sports Med. 2024;58:860&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38950917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forestier N, Nougier V. The effects of muscular fatigue on the coordination of a multijoint movement in human. Neurosci Lett. 1998;252:187&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9739992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobrosielski DA, Brubaker PH, Berry MJ, Ayabe M, Miller HS. The metabolic demand of golf in patients with heart disease and in healthy adults. J Cardiopulm Rehabil. 2002;22:96&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11984207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorist MM, Kernell D, Meijman TF, Zijdewind I. Motor fatigue and cognitive task performance in humans. J Physiol. 2002;545:313&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2290666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12433971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith MF, Newell AJ, Baker MR. Effect of acute mild dehydration on cognitive-motor performance in golf. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26:3075&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22190159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mumford PW, Tribby AC, Poole CN, Dalbo VJ, Scanlan AT, Moon JR, et al. Effect of caffeine on golf performance and fatigue during a competitive tournament. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48:132&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26285020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson EJ, Hayes PR, Allison SJ. The effect of a carbohydrate-caffeine sports drink on simulated golf performance. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2009;34:681&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19767804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welsh RS, Davis JM, Burke JR, Williams HG. Carbohydrates and physical/mental performance during intermittent exercise to fatigue. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34:723&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11932585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompsett DJ, Vento KA, Der Ananian C, Hondula D, Wardenaar FC. The effects of three different types of macronutrient feedings on golf performance and levels of fatigue and alertness. Nutr Health. 2022;28:509&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35747933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagashima Y, Ehara K, Ehara Y, Mitsume A, Kubo K, Mineo S. Effects of continuous carbohydrate intake with gummies during the golf round on interstitial glucose, golf performance, and cognitive performance of competitive golfers: a randomized repeated-measures crossover design. Nutrients. 2023;15:3245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10384188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37513663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Supreme Court. PGA Tour Inc. v Casey Martin: Syllabus. 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Supreme Court. PGA Tour, Inc., v Casey Martin: Dissenting. 2001. p. 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schauer F. The dilemma of ignorance: PGA Tour, Inc. v Casey Martin. Supreme Court Rev. 2001;2001:267&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiappa E. What is golf?: pragmatic essentializing and definitional argument in PGA Tour, Inc. V. Martin. Argum Advocacy. 2001;38:18&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piil JF, Kingma B, Morris NB, Christiansen L, Ioannou LG, Flouris AD, et al. Proposed framework for forecasting heat-effects on motor-cognitive performance in the Summer Olympics. Temperature. 2021;8:262&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8409751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34485620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanderbrook D, Anoushiravani AA, O&#x2019;Connor CM, Adams C, Whitney D, Tartaglione J, et al. The impact of total knee arthroplasty on golfing activity. Ann Jt. 2022;7:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10929374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38529158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maas KW, Hasbrook CA. Media promotion of the paradigm citizen/golfer: an analysis of golf magazines&#x2019; representations of disability, gender, and age. Sociol Sport J. 2001;18:21&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas PR, Over R. Psychological and psychomotor skills associated with performance in golf. Sport Psychol. 2016;8:73&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett H. Beyond the tee: navigating the course. The player journey for golfers with a disability, lessons learned, and changes made. Durham University; 2022. http://etheses.dur.ac.uk/14659/. Accessed 10 Nov 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson DS, Mehan TJ, Smith GA, McKenzie LB. Golf cart-related injuries in the U.s. Am J Prev Med. 2008;35:55&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18541177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGwin GJ, Zoghby JT, Griffin R, Rue LW 3rd. Incidence of golf cart-related injury in the United States. J Trauma. 2008;64:1562&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18545124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horvath KZ, McAdams RJ, Roberts KJ, Zhu M, McKenzie LB. Fun ride or risky transport: golf cart-related injuries treated in U.S. emergency departments from 2007 through 2017. J Saf Res. 2020;75:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33334466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castaldo JE, Raquet B, Roberts M, VandeWeerd C. Analysis of death and disability due to golf cart crashes in the Villages, Florida: 2011&#x2013;2019. Traffic Inj Prev. 2020;21:437&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32812819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson RK, Goran MI, Ferrara MS, Poehlman ET. Athetosis increases resting metabolic rate in adults with cerebral palsy. J Am Diet Assoc. 1996;96:145&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8557940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nardon M, Ruzzante F, O&#x2019;Donnell L, Adami A, Dayanidhi S, Bertucco M. Energetics of walking in individuals with cerebral palsy and typical development, across severity and age: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Gait Posture. 2021;90:388&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34564011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowell BG. Energy cost of participation in golf as determined by telemetry. Eugene (OR): Microform Publications, School of Health, Physical Education, and Recreation, University of Oregon; 1973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aylwin P, Havenith G, Cardinale M, Lloyd A, Ihsan M, Taylor L, et al. Thermoregulatory responses during road races in hot-humid conditions at the 2019 Athletics World Championships. J Appl Physiol. 2023;134:1300&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10190834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37022963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson KI, Hillman C, Stillman CM, Ballard RM, Bloodgood B, Conroy DE, et al. Physical activity, cognition, and brain outcomes: a review of the 2018 Physical Activity Guidelines. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51:1242&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6527141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31095081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. Physical activity. 2025. https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/physical-activity. Accessed 31 Aug 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drake JQ, Leeper B, by Jeffrey Kessler RL, Feher D, Stepek MJ, Lefranc-Barthe M. CAS 2020/A/6807 Blake Leeper v. International Association of Athletics Federations Arbitral Award delivered by the Court of Arbitration for Sport sitting in the following composition. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Court of Arbitration for Sport. CAS 2009/A/1948 Appeal by Mr Robert Berger v World Anti-Doping Authority. Proc. Court Arbitr. Sport. 2009. http://arbitrationlaw.com/files/free_pdfs/CAS2009-A-1948RBvWADAAward.pdf. Accessed 21 Dec 2024.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>