<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41224828</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Chitosan coated cotton fabric embedded with silver nanoparticles for azo dye degradation in aqueous solutions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>39644</StartPage><MedlinePgn>39644</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">39644</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-23222-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Anthropogenic activities have led to severe environmental degradation, posing a significant threat to global sustainability. Among these pollutants, synthetic dyes are of particular concern due to their contribution to water contamination and detrimental effects on ecosystems. Herein, we present an eco-friendly approach to remove toxic dyes from wastewater using silver nanoparticle-decorated chitosan-coated cotton fabric (Ag/Chi-CF) as a heterogeneous nano-catalyst. A 1 wt% Chi solution was applied to cotton fabric to enhance surface functionality and improve metal ion uptake capacity. The functionalized fabric was then treated with silver nitrate (AgNO&#x2083;) solutions at concentrations of 100, 200, and 300&#xa0;&#x3bc;g/mL. Next, the subsequent reduction with 0.1&#xa0;M NaBH<sub>4</sub> hydrate facilitates the in situ formation of silver nanoparticles, which is confirmed by a visible color change. The untreated cotton fabric (CF), chitosan-coated cotton (Chi-CF), and Ag/Chi-CF were characterized by SEM, XRD, EDX, and FTIR for their surface morphology, crystal structure, elemental analysis, and functional groups, respectively. Catalytic degradation studies were conducted with UV-Vis spectroscopy using Congo red dye as a model pollutant. The Ag3/Chi-CF nano-catalyst demonstrated excellent catalytic performance, achieving approximately 90% degradation of 50&#xa0;ppm dye within 20&#xa0;min (k_obs&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.1&#xa0;min&#x207b;<sup>1</sup>), following a second-order kinetic model, while showing a poor fit to zero-order and first-order models. The reusability of the Ag3/Chi-CF catalyst was demonstrated through three cycles, with minimal loss in performance to approximately 77%, highlighting its potential for sustainable wastewater treatment applications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bibi</LastName><ForeName>Hajra</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Chemical Sciences, University of Peshawar, Peshawar, 25120, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Abrar Ali</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Stokes Laboratories, School of Engineering, Bernal Institute, University of Limerick, Limerick, V94 T9PX, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>It Ee</ForeName><Initials>IE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Artificial Intelligence and Engineering, Multimedia University, 63100, Cyberjaya, Malaysia. ielee@mmu.edu.my.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Smart Systems and Automation, COE for Robotics and Sensing Technologies, Multimedia University, 63100, Cyberjaya, Selangor, Malaysia. ielee@mmu.edu.my.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wali</LastName><ForeName>Qamar</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Artificial Intelligence and Engineering, Multimedia University, 63100, Cyberjaya, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Smart Systems and Automation, COE for Robotics and Sensing Technologies, Multimedia University, 63100, Cyberjaya, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MMUE/240001</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Higher Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>MMUE/240001</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Higher Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>MMUE/240001</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Higher Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>MMUE/240001</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Higher Education</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dye degradation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nano-catalysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Supported nanomaterials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Water pollution</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41224828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12612183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-23222-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-23222-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zeleke, M. A., Khan, A. A., Lavren&#x10d;i&#x10d; &#x160;tangar, U., Mequanint, K. &amp; Kwapinski, W. Garlic (Allium sativum) extract mediated synthesis of self-redox SnO2 nanomaterials for reduction of Cr(VI) under dark condition. <i>Surf. Interfaces</i><b>71</b>, 106869 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.surfin.2025.106869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma, K., Rajan, S. &amp; Nayak, S. K. Water pollution: Primary sources and associated human health hazards with special emphasis on rural areas. <i>Water Resour. Manag. Rural Dev. Chall. Mitig.</i>10.1016/B978-0-443-18778-0.00014-3 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-443-18778-0.00014-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishmitha, P. S. et al. Understanding emerging contaminants in water and wastewater: A comprehensive review on detection, impacts, and solutions. <i>J. Hazard. Mater. Adv.</i><b>18</b>, 100755 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benhadria, Eh. et al. Copper oxide nanoparticles-decorated cellulose acetate: Eco-friendly catalysts for reduction of toxic organic dyes in aqueous media. <i>Int. J. Biol. Macromol.</i><b>284</b>, 137982 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2024.137982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39592044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. &amp; Azam, W. Natural resource scarcity, fossil fuel energy consumption, and total greenhouse gas emissions in top emitting countries. <i>Geosci. Front.</i><b>15</b>, 101757 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gsf.2023.101757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awais, et al. Catalytic degradation of dyes using gold nanoparticles supported over chitosan coated cotton cloth composite. <i>Mater. Res. Express.</i><b>12</b>, 015008 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2053-1591/adaac6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullah, S. et al. Enhanced photoactivity of BiVO4/Ag/Ag2O Z-scheme photocatalyst for efficient environmental remediation under natural sunlight and low-cost LED illumination. <i>Colloids Surf. Physicochem. Eng. Asp.</i><b>600</b>, 124946 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2020.124946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Tohamy, R. et al. A critical review on the treatment of dye-containing wastewater: Ecotoxicological and health concerns of textile dyes and possible remediation approaches for environmental safety. <i>Ecotoxicol. Environ. Saf.</i><b>231</b>, 113160 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoenv.2021.113160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35026583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parida, V. K. et al. Insights into the synthetic dye contamination in textile wastewater: Impacts on aquatic ecosystems and human health, and eco-friendly remediation strategies for environmental sustainability. <i>J. Ind. Eng. Chem.</i>10.1016/J.JIEC.2025.04.019 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.JIEC.2025.04.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandanshive, V. et al. In situ textile wastewater treatment in high rate transpiration system furrows planted with aquatic macrophytes and floating phytobeds. <i>Chemosphere</i><b>252</b>, 126513 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2020.126513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32203784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nahar, N., Haque, M. S. &amp; Haque, S. E. Groundwater conservation, and recycling and reuse of textile wastewater in a denim industry of Bangladesh. <i>Water Resour. Ind.</i><b>31</b>, 100249 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wri.2024.100249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutta, P., Razaya Rabbi, M., Sufian, M. A. &amp; Mahjebin, S. Effects of textile dyeing effluent on the environment and its treatment: A review. <i>Eng. Appl. Sci. Lett. (EASL)</i><b>5</b>, 1&#x2013;17 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30538/psrp-easl2022.0080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singha, K., Pandit, P., Maity, S. &amp; Sharma, S. R. <i>Harmful Environmental Effects for Textile Chemical Dyeing Practice</i> (Elsevier, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awais Ali, N., Khan, A., Asiri, A. M. &amp; Kamal, T. Potential application of in-situ synthesized cobalt nanoparticles on chitosan-coated cotton cloth substrate as catalyst for the reduction of pollutants. <i>Environ. Technol. Innov.</i><b>23</b>, 101675 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eti.2021.101675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamil, I. et al. A review of the gold nanoparticles&#x2019; synthesis and application in dye degradation. <i>Clean. Chem. Eng.</i><b>10</b>, 100126 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clce.2024.100126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naeem, H., Ajmal, M., Muntha, S., Ambreen, J. &amp; Siddiq, M. Synthesis and characterization of graphene oxide sheets integrated with gold nanoparticles and their applications to adsorptive removal and catalytic reduction of water contaminants. <i>RSC Adv.</i><b>8</b>, 3599&#x2013;3610 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C7RA12030C</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9077651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35542905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kodasi, B. et al. Novel jointured green synthesis of chitosan-silver nanocomposite: An approach towards reduction of nitroarenes, anti-proliferative, wound healing and antioxidant applications. <i>Int. J. Biol. Macromol.</i><b>246</b>, 125578 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2023.125578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37379943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soto, K. M. et al. Rapid and facile synthesis of gold nanoparticles with two Mexican medicinal plants and a comparison with traditional chemical synthesis. <i>Mater. Chem. Phys.</i><b>295</b>, 127109 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matchemphys.2022.127109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bharathi, A. et al. Microscopic characterization based synthesis of silver nanoparticles using <i>Merremia quinquefolia</i> (L.) Hallier f. leaf extract: their biological approaches and degradation of methylene blue dye. <i>Microsc. Res. Tech.</i><b>88</b>, 1664&#x2013;1680 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jemt.24789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39887535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogundare, S. A. et al. Catalytic degradation of methylene blue dye and antibacterial activity of biosynthesized silver nanoparticles using <i>Peltophorum pterocarpum</i> (DC.) leaves. <i>Environ. Sci. Adv.</i><b>2</b>, 247&#x2013;256 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D2VA00164K</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hijazi, B. U., Faraj, M., Mhanna, R. &amp; El-Dakdouki, M. H. Biosynthesis of silver nanoparticles as a reliable alternative for the catalytic degradation of organic dyes and antibacterial applications. <i>Curr. Res. Green Sustain. Chem.</i><b>8</b>, 100408 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.crgsc.2024.100408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, N. et al. Chitosan-coated cotton cloth supported copper nanoparticles for toxic dye reduction. <i>Int J Biol Macromol</i><b>111</b>, 832&#x2013;838 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2018.01.092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29355628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benhadria, Eh. et al. Eco-friendly Cu&#x2082;O/Cu nanoparticles encapsulated in cellulose acetate: A sustainable catalyst for 4-nitrophenol reduction and antibacterial applications. <i>J. Environ. Chem. Eng.</i><b>13</b>, 115077 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2024.115077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg, N., Bera, S., Rastogi, L., Ballal, A. &amp; Balaramakrishna, M. V. Synthesis and characterization of L-asparagine stabilised gold nanoparticles: Catalyst for degradation of organic dyes. <i>Spectrochim. Acta A Mol. Biomol. Spectrosc.</i><b>232</b>, 118126 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.saa.2020.118126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32062492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benhadria, Eh. et al. Cellulose acetate-stabilized Cu2O nanoparticles for enhanced catalytic reduction of organic pollutants. <i>J. Inorg Organomet Polym Mater</i><b>35</b>, 3325&#x2013;3343 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10904-024-03458-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debnath, P. &amp; Ray, S. K. Synthesis of sodium alginate grafted and silver nanoparticles filled anionic copolymer polyelectrolytes for adsorption and photocatalytic degradation of a cationic dye from water. <i>Int. J. Biol. Macromol.</i><b>285</b>, 138228 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2024.138228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39631592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, A. et al. Catalytic degradation of various dyes using silver nanoparticles fabricated within chitosan based microgels. <i>Int. J. Biol Macromol</i><b>283</b>, 137965 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2024.137965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39581408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ul-Islam, M. et al. Chitosan-based nanostructured biomaterials: Synthesis, properties, and biomedical applications. <i>Adv. Ind. Eng. search</i><b>7</b>, 79&#x2013;99 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav, H., Malviya, R. &amp; Kaushik, N. Chitosan in biomedicine: A comprehensive review of recent developments. <i>Carbohydr. Polym. Technol. and Appl.</i><b>8</b>, 100551 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez-G&#xf3;mez, C. P., Cecilia, J. A., Guidotti, M. &amp; Soengas, R. Chitosan: A natural biopolymer with a wide and varied range of applications. <i>Molecules</i><b>25</b>, 3981 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules25173981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7504732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32882899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strnad, S. &amp; Zemlji&#x10d;, L. F. Cellulose&#x2014;Chitosan functional biocomposites. <i>Polymers</i><b>15</b>, 425 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym15020425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9863338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36679314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph, B., Sagarika, V. K., Sabu, C., Kalarikkal, N. &amp; Thomas, S. Cellulose nanocomposites: Fabrication and biomedical applications. <i>J. Bioresour. Bioprod.</i><b>5</b>, 223&#x2013;237 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, F. et al. Chitosan coated cotton cloth supported zero-valent nanoparticles: Simple but economically viable, efficient and easily retrievable catalysts. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>7</b>, 1&#x2013;16 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-16815-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5717218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29209040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klemm, D., Heublein, B., Fink, H. P. &amp; Bohn, A. Cellulose: Fascinating biopolymer and sustainable raw material. <i>Angewandte Chemie&#x2014;Int. Ed.</i><b>44</b>, 3358&#x2013;3393 (2005).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.200460587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15861454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, M. S., Selvam, V. &amp; Vadivel, M. Synthesis and characterization of silane modified iron (III) oxide nanoparticles reinforced chitosan nanocomposites. <i>Eng. Sci. Adv. Tech.</i><b>2</b>, 1258&#x2013;1263 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faghihi, K. &amp; Shabanian, M. Thermal and optical properties of silver-polyimide nanocomposite based on diphenyl sulfone moieties in the main chain. <i>J. Chil. Chem. Soc.</i><b>56</b>, 665&#x2013;667 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4067/S0717-97072011000200009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abidi, N., Cabrales, L. &amp; Haigler, C. H. Changes in the cell wall and cellulose content of developing cotton fibers investigated by FTIR spectroscopy. <i>Carbohyd. Polym.</i><b>16</b>(100), 9&#x2013;16 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbpol.2013.01.074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24188832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piotrowska-Kirschling, A. &amp; Brzeska, J. Review of chitosan nanomaterials for metal cation adsorption. <i>Prog. Chem. Appl. Chitin Deriv.</i><b>25</b>, 51&#x2013;62 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15259/PCACD.25.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinayagam, R. et al. Peltophorum pterocarpum flower mediated synthesis of silver nanoparticles and its catalytic degradation of acid blue 113 dye. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 1&#x2013;11 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-11980-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12280203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40691501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali, S. et al. Photocatalytic removal of textile wastewater-originated methylene blue and malachite green dyes using spent black tea extract-coated silver nanoparticles. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b>, 1&#x2013;17 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11730607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39805978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varadavenkatesan, T., Nagendran, V., Vinayagam, R., Goveas, L. C. &amp; Selvaraj, R. Green synthesis of silver nanoparticles using Lagerstroemia speciosa fruit extract: Catalytic efficiency in dye degradation. <i>Mater. Technol.</i><b>40</b>, 2463955 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10667857.2025.2463955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narv&#xe1;ez-Mu&#xf1;oz, C. et al. Polyacrylonitrile/silver nanoparticles composite for catalytic dye reduction and real-time monitoring. <i>Polymers</i><b>17</b>, 1762 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym17131762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12252141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40647772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maity, A., Bhaumik, D. M. &amp; Brink, H. G. Effective degradation of congo red dye in aqueous solution using highly recyclable silver nanoparticles decorated polyaniline nanowires. (2025) 10.2139/SSRN.5334775</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selvaraj, R. et al. Eco-friendly synthesis of silver nanoparticles from rubber fig leaves and their application in the catalytic degradation of Congo Red dye. <i>Mater. Technol.</i><b>40</b>, 2498585 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10667857.2025.2498585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pal, T. et al. Organized media as redox catalysts. <i>Langmuir</i><b>14</b>, 4724&#x2013;4730 (1998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la980057n</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>