<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40821157</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cannabinoid Hyperemesis Syndrome Presenting as Postoperative Nausea and Vomiting in a Chronic Cannabis User: A Case Report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e87990</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e87990</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e87990</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.87990</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome (CHS) is a paradoxical condition seen in chronic cannabis users, marked by recurrent nausea, vomiting, and abdominal discomfort. Although more widely recognized in emergency medicine, CHS remains underdiagnosed in the perioperative setting, where its symptoms may be misattributed to common postoperative phenomena such as anesthetic effects, opioid-induced nausea, or surgical complications. This diagnostic gap can delay appropriate management and lead to unnecessary interventions. We report the case of a 40-year-old woman with a two-year history of daily cannabis use who underwent a laparoscopic hysterectomy, mid-urethral sling placement, and pelvic organ prolapse repair. In the immediate postoperative period, she experienced persistent nausea and vomiting despite the administration of multiple antiemetics, including ondansetron and metoclopramide, and opioids for pain control. By postoperative day 2, vomiting occurred in discrete, refractory episodes despite continued pharmacologic management, prompting concern for an atypical cause. The patient was placed on nil per os (NPO) status, but symptoms escalated on postoperative day 3, culminating in a prolonged episode of emesis accompanied by hematemesis and hallucinations. At this stage, CHS was strongly suspected given her chronic cannabis use, clinical trajectory, and lack of response to standard therapies. Supportive care was intensified with intravenous hydration and electrolyte replacement for significant hypokalemia and hypophosphatemia. The patient's condition stabilized over the next 24 hours, with gradual resolution of symptoms and resumption of oral intake by postoperative day 4. She was discharged in stable condition with a tailored regimen of antiemetics, analgesics, and counseling on cannabis cessation. She abstained from cannabis throughout hospitalization. This case highlights a critical but underrecognized cause of refractory postoperative nausea and vomiting (PONV). In patients with a history of chronic cannabis use, perioperative teams should maintain a high index of suspicion for CHS when standard antiemetic regimens fail. Early identification not only prevents unnecessary diagnostic testing and extended hospitalization but also enables more effective patient education and targeted counseling. Broader awareness of CHS among surgical and anesthesia teams can improve outcomes through timely diagnosis, supportive care, appropriate discharge planning, and public health efforts to raise awareness of cannabis-related complications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Atkins et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Atkins</LastName><ForeName>Justin B</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kirk Kerkorian School of Medicine, University of Nevada, Las Vegas (UNLV), Las Vegas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Levine</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kirk Kerkorian School of Medicine, University of Nevada, Las Vegas (UNLV), Las Vegas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaw</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, Kirk Kerkorian School of Medicine, University of Nevada, Las Vegas (UNLV), Las Vegas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">abdominal pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anesthesiology implications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antiemetic resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cannabis withdrawal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic cannabis use</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cyclic vomiting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hot water bathing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">perioperative complications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postoperative nausea</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40821157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12354985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.87990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cannabinoid hyperemesis: cyclical hyperemesis in association with chronic cannabis abuse. Allen JH, de Moore GM, Heddle R, Twartz JC. Gut. 2004;53:1566&#x2013;1570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1774264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15479672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome: pathophysiology and treatment in the emergency department. Richards JR. J Emerg Med. 2018;54:354&#x2013;363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29310960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cannabinoid hyperemesis: a case series of 98 patients. Simonetto DA, Oxentenko AS, Herman ML, Szostek JH. Mayo Clin Proc. 2012;87:114&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3538402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22305024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome: diagnosis, pathophysiology, and treatment-a systematic review. Sorensen CJ, DeSanto K, Borgelt L, Phillips KT, Monte AA. J Med Toxicol. 2017;13:71&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5330965</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28000146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastroduodenal disorders. Stanghellini V, Chan FK, Hasler WL, Malagelada JR, Suzuki H, Tack J, Talley NJ. Gastroenterology. 2016;150:1380&#x2013;1392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27147122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome: a rising complication. Peles S, Khalife R, Magliocco A. Cureus. 2025;17:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11910202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40091958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spectrum of gastric emptying patterns in adult patients with cyclic vomiting syndrome. Hejazi RA, Lavenbarg TH, McCallum RW. https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1365-2982.2010.01584.x. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2010;22:1298-302, e338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20723071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Role of chronic cannabis use: cyclic vomiting syndrome vs cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome. Venkatesan T, Levinthal DJ, Li BU, et al. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2019;31:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6788295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31241817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical, psychiatric and manometric profile of cyclic vomiting syndrome in adults and response to tricyclic therapy. Namin F, Patel J, Lin Z, Sarosiek I, Foran P, Esmaeili P, McCallum R. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2007;19:196&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17300289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Successful treatment of cannabinoid hyperemesis syndrome with topical capsaicin. Moon AM, Buckley SA, Mark NM. ACG Case Rep J. 2018;5:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5758720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29379817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>