<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39601408</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1941-2452</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nutrition in clinical practice : official publication of the American Society for Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nutr Clin Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Associations between malnutrition and dehydration among older adults: A cross-sectional observational study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>630</StartPage><EndPage>642</EndPage><MedlinePgn>630-642</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ncp.11246</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">There is debate as to the association between dehydration and malnutrition. Thus, this study aimed to investigate the correlation between dehydration and malnutrition and their impact on geriatric syndromes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This cross-sectional study included older adults (&#x2265;60 years) who attended one outpatient geriatric clinic. Malnutrition was defined according to the Mini Nutritional Assessment (MNA) score (&lt;17), and dehydration was based on a single calculation method (plasma osmolarity [Posm]&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;295&#x2009;mmol/L).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Among the 1409 patients studied, the prevalence of malnutrition and dehydration was 19% and 33%, respectively. The rate of malnutrition in the setting of dehydration was 18%, and the rate of dehydration in patients with malnutrition was 30% (P&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.05). Polypharmacy, hypertension, diabetes mellitus, and higher body mass index (BMI) were associated solely with dehydration, whereas older age, a lower level of education, depression, and lower BMI were associated solely with malnutrition. Among patients with dehydration, there was a significant negative correlation between the MNA and Posm (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001, r&#x2009;=&#x2009;-0.20). Inversely, among patients without dehydration, the correlation was positive and significant (P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001, r&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.14).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">A negative correlation was found between the MNA score and Posm in patients with dehydration, whereas the correlation is positive among patients without dehydration. This inverse relationship between the MNA score and Posm in patients with different levels of hydration is one potential reason for the lack of a significant correlation between malnutrition and dehydration in previously reported studies. Different risk factors of malnutrition may predominate in settings of dehydration vs no dehydration.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 American Society for Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heybeli</LastName><ForeName>Cihan</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Dokuz Eylul University Hospital, Izmir, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Uzun</LastName><ForeName>Ozcan</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Yalova Education and Research Hospital, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Lee</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Health Performance and Wellbeing, Anglia Ruskin University, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Veronese</LastName><ForeName>Nicola</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Geriatric Unit, Department of Medicine, University of Palermo, Palermo, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rahmati</LastName><ForeName>Masoud</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CEReSS-Health Service Research and Quality of Life Center, Aix-Marseille University, Marseille, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, Faculty of Literature and Human Sciences, Lorestan University, Khoramabad, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, Faculty of Literature and Humanities, Vali-E-Asr University of Rafsanjan, Rafsanjan, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hajek</LastName><ForeName>Andr&#xe9;</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Economics and Health Services Research, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg Center for Health Economics, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soysal</LastName><ForeName>Pinar</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6042-1718</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Geriatric Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Bezmialem Vakif University, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Nutr Clin Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8606733</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0884-5336</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003681" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dehydration</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D044342" MajorTopicYN="Y">Malnutrition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015577" MajorTopicYN="N">Geriatric Assessment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015596" MajorTopicYN="N">Nutrition Assessment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009752" MajorTopicYN="N">Nutritional Status</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019338" MajorTopicYN="N">Polypharmacy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aged</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dehydration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">elderly nutrition physiological phenomena</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">malnutrition</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39601408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ncp.11246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>F&#xe1;varo&#x2010;Moreira NC, Krausch&#x2010;Hofmann S, Matthys C, et al. Risk factors for malnutrition in older adults: a systematic review of the literature based on longitudinal data. Adv Nutr. 2016;7(3):507&#x2010;522.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norman K, Ha&#xdf; U, Pirlich M. Malnutrition in older adults&#x2010;recent advances and remaining challenges. Nutrients. 2021;13(8):2764.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saka B, Kaya O, Ozturk GB, Erten N, Karan MA. Malnutrition in the elderly and its relationship with other geriatric syndromes. Clin Nutr. 2010;29(6):745&#x2010;748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsen EL, Brovold T, Bergland A, Bye A. Prevalence of factors associated with malnutrition among acute geriatric patients in Norway: a cross&#x2010;sectional study. BMJ Open. 2016;6(9):e011512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smoliner C, Norman K, Wagner KH, Hartig W, Lochs H, Pirlich M. Malnutrition and depression in the institutionalised elderly. Br J Nutr. 2009;102(11):1663&#x2010;1667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Bokhorst&#x2010;de van der Schueren MAE, Lonterman&#x2010;Monasch S, de Vries OJ, Danner SA, Kramer MHH, Muller M. Prevalence and determinants for malnutrition in geriatric outpatients. Clin Nutr. 2013;32(6):1007&#x2010;1011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soysal P, Isik AT, Arik F, Kalan U, Eyvaz A, Veronese N. Validity of the Mini&#x2010;Nutritional Assessment scale for evaluating frailty status in older adults. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2019;20(2):183&#x2010;187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verlaan S, Ligthart&#x2010;Melis GC, Wijers SLJ, Cederholm T, Maier AB, de van der Schueren MAE. High prevalence of physical frailty among community&#x2010;dwelling malnourished older adults&#x2014;a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2017;18(5):374&#x2010;382.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei K, Nyunt MSZ, Gao Q, Wee SL, Ng TP. Frailty and malnutrition: related and distinct syndrome prevalence and association among community&#x2010;dwelling older adults: Singapore longitudinal ageing studies. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2017;18(12):1019&#x2010;1028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojzischke J, van Wijngaarden J, van den Berg C, et al. Nutritional status and functionality in geriatric rehabilitation patients: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Eur Geriatr Med. 2020;11(2):195&#x2010;207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cereda E, Pedrolli C, Klersy C, et al. Nutritional status in older persons according to healthcare setting: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of prevalence data using MNA &#xae;. Clin Nutr. 2016;35(6):1282&#x2010;1290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiesswetter E, Pohlhausen S, Uhlig K, et al. Prognostic differences of the Mini Nutritional Assessment short form and long form in relation to 1&#x2010;year functional decline and mortality in community&#x2010;dwelling older adults receiving home care. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2014;62(3):512&#x2010;517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai AC, Yang SF, Wang JY. Validation of population&#x2010;specific Mini&#x2010;Nutritional Assessment with its long&#x2010;term mortality&#x2010;predicting ability: results of a population&#x2010;based longitudinal 4&#x2010;year study in Taiwan. Br J Nutr. 2010;104(1):93&#x2010;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei K, Nyunt MSZ, Gao Q, Wee SL, Yap KB, Ng TP. Association of frailty and malnutrition with long&#x2010;term functional and mortality outcomes among community&#x2010;dwelling older adults: results from the Singapore longitudinal aging study 1. JAMA Netw Open. 2018;1(3):e180650.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei K, Nyunt MSZ, Gao Q, Wee SL, Ng TP. Long&#x2010;term changes in nutritional status are associated with functional and mortality outcomes among community&#x2010;living older adults. Nutrition. 2019;66:180&#x2010;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkinson E, Hooper L, Fynn J, et al. Low&#x2010;intake dehydration prevalence in non&#x2010;hospitalised older adults: systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Clin Nutr. 2023;42(8):1510&#x2010;1520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong LE. Assessing hydration status: the elusive gold standard. J Am Coll Nutr. 2007;26(5 suppl):575S&#x2010;584S.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper L, Bunn D, Jimoh FO, Fairweather&#x2010;Tait SJ. Water&#x2010;loss dehydration and aging. Mech Ageing Dev. 2014;136&#x2010;137:50&#x2010;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engelheart S, Forslund HB, Brummer RJ, Ljungqvist O. Dehydration and loss of appetite: key nutrition features in older people receiving home health care. Nutrition. 2021;91&#x2010;92:111385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atciyurt K, Heybeli C, Smith L, Veronese N, Soysal P. The prevalence, risk factors and clinical implications of dehydration in older patients: a cross&#x2010;sectional study. Acta Clin Belg. 2024;79(1):12&#x2010;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volkert D, Beck AM, Cederholm T, et al. ESPEN practical guideline: clinical nutrition and hydration in geriatrics. Clin Nutr. 2022;41(4):958&#x2010;989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cederholm T, Barazzoni R, Austin P, et al. ESPEN guidelines on definitions and terminology of clinical nutrition. Clin Nutr. 2017;36(1):49&#x2010;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck AM, Bech CB, Knudsen AW, Munk T. Malnutrition and dehydration in older adults&#x2014;how are the overlap between the two conditions? Clin Nutr Open Sci. 2023;51:72&#x2010;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunn DK, Hooper L. Signs and symptoms of low&#x2010;intake dehydration do not work in older care home residents&#x2014;DRIE diagnostic accuracy study. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2019;20(8):963&#x2010;970.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunn D, Hooper L, Welch A. Dehydration and malnutrition in residential care: recommendations for strategies for improving practice derived from a scoping review of existing policies and guidelines. Geriatrics (Basel). 2018;3(4):77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volkert D, Beck AM, Cederholm T, et al. Management of malnutrition in older patients&#x2014;current approaches, evidence and open questions. J Clin Med. 2019;8(7):974.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bech CB, Svendsen JA, Knudsen AW, Munk T, Beck AM. The association between malnutrition and dehydration in older adults admitted to a geriatric unit: an observational study. Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2023;57:598&#x2010;605.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jespersen JB, Beck AM, Munk T, Jensen HO, Knudsen AW. Low&#x2010;intake dehydration and nutrition impact symptoms in older medical patients&#x2014;a retrospective study. Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2023;57:190&#x2010;196.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levey AS, de Jong PE, Coresh J, et al. The definition, classification, and prognosis of chronic kidney disease: a KDIGO Controversies Conference report. Kidney Int. 2011;80(1):17&#x2010;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levey AS, Stevens LA, Schmid CH, et al. A new equation to estimate glomerular filtration rate. Ann Intern Med. 2009;150(9):604&#x2010;612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association Professional Practice C. 2. Diagnosis and classification of diabetes: standards of care in diabetes&#x2010;2024. Diabetes Care. 2024;47(suppl 1):S20&#x2010;S42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy M, Brooks C, New S, Lumbers M. The use of the Mini&#x2010;Nutritional Assessment (MNA) tool in elderly orthopaedic patients. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2000;54(7):555&#x2010;562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Munk T, Bech CB, Klausen TW, R&#xf8;nholt F, Suetta C, Knudsen AW. Accuracy of the calculated serum osmolarity to screen for hyperosmolar dehydration in older hospitalised medical patients. Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2021;43:415&#x2010;419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dokuzlar O, Koc Okudur S, Soysal P, et al. Factors that increase risk of falling in older men according to four different clinical methods. Exp Aging Res. 2020;46(1):83&#x2010;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molloy DW, Alemayehu E, Roberts R. Reliability of a Standardized Mini&#x2010;Mental State Examination compared with the traditional Mini&#x2010;Mental State Examination. Am J Psychiatry. 1991;148(1):102&#x2010;105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regier DA, Kuhl EA, Kupfer DJ. The DSM&#x2010;5: classification and criteria changes. World Psychiatry. 2013;12(2):92&#x2010;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yildiz S, Heybeli C, Soysal P, Smith L, Veronese N, Kazancioglu R. Frequency and clinical impact of anticholinergic burden in older patients: comparing older patients with and without chronic kidney disease. Arch Gerontol Geriat. 2023;112:105041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haider SI, Johnell K, Weitoft GR, Thorslund M, Fastbom J. The influence of educational level on polypharmacy and inappropriate drug use: a register&#x2010;based study of more than 600,000 older people. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2009;57(1):62&#x2010;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang P, Yuan Y, Lu D, et al. Diagnostic accuracy of the Eating Assessment Tool&#x2010;10 (EAT&#x2010;10) in screening dysphagia: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Dysphagia. 2023;38(1):145&#x2010;158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz&#x2010;Jentoft AJ, Bahat G, Bauer J, et al. Sarcopenia: revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing. 2019;48(4):601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soysal P, Heybeli C, Koc Okudur S, Caliskan Bozyel E, Smith L, Kazancioglu R. Prevalence and co&#x2010;incidence of geriatric syndromes according to glomerular filtration rate in older patients. Int Urol Nephrol. 2023;55(2):469&#x2010;476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durmaz B, Soysal P, Ellidokuz H, Isik AT. Validity and reliability of geriatric depression scale&#x2010;15 (short form) in Turkish older adults. North Clin Istanb. 2018;5(3):216&#x2010;220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalantar&#x2010;Zadeh K, Block G, Horwich T, Fonarow GC. Reverse epidemiology of conventional cardiovascular risk factors in patients with chronic heart failure. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2004;43(8):1439&#x2010;1444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kashiji A, Tajiri M, Chikugo M, et al. Hyponatremia is a prognostic factor in patients receiving nutrition support. Am J Med Sci. 2021;361(6):744&#x2010;750.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou KR, Huang MS, Chiu WC, et al. A comprehensive assessment of oral health, swallowing difficulty, and nutritional status in older nursing home residents. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):19914.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindroos EK, Saarela RKT, Suominen MH, et al. Burden of oral symptoms and its associations with nutrition, well&#x2010;being, and survival among nursing home residents. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2019;20(5):537&#x2010;543.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamura BK, Bell CL, Masaki KH, Amella EJ. Factors associated with weight loss, low BMI, and malnutrition among nursing home patients: a systematic review of the literature. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2013;14(9):649&#x2010;655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muckelbauer R, Sarganas G, Gr&#xfc;neis A, M&#xfc;ller&#x2010;Nordhorn J. Association between water consumption and body weight outcomes: a systematic review. Am J Clin Nutr. 2013;98(2):282&#x2010;299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang T, Ravi N, Plegue MA, Sonneville KR, Davis MM. Inadequate hydration, BMI, and obesity among US adults: NHANES 2009&#x2010;2012. Ann Fam Med. 2016;14(4):320&#x2010;324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soysal P, Koc Okudur S, Kilic N, Ipar O, Smith L. The prevalence of undernutrition and associated factors in older obese patients. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2022;34(9):2023&#x2010;2030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojszel ZB. Determinants of nutritional status of older people in long&#x2010;term care settings on the example of the nursing home in Bia&#x142;ystok. Adv Med Sci. 2006;51:168&#x2010;173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulnik D, Elmadfa I. Assessment of the nutritional situation of elderly nursing home residents in Vienna. Ann Nutr Metab. 2008;52(suppl 1):51&#x2010;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sella&#x2010;Weiss O. Association between swallowing function, malnutrition and frailty in community dwelling older people. Clin Nutr ESPEN. 2021;45:476&#x2010;485.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>