<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39506506</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-4184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>358</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Archiv der Pharmazie</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arch Pharm (Weinheim)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Unveiling tomorrow: Carbonic anhydrase activators and inhibitors pioneering new frontiers in Alzheimer's disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2400748</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2400748</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ardp.202400748</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Alzheimer's disease (AD) is a neurodegenerative disorder and a principal basis of dementia in the elderly population globally. Recently, human carbonic anhydrases (hCAs, EC 4.2.1.1) were demonstrated as possible new targets for treating AD. hCAs are vital for maintaining pH balance and performing other physiological processes as they catalyze the reversible hydration of carbon dioxide to bicarbonate and a proton. Current research indicates that hCA plays a role in brain functions critical for transmitting neural signals. Activation of carbonic anhydrase (CA) has emerged as a promising avenue in addressing memory loss and cognitive issues. Conversely, the exploration of CA inhibition represents a novel frontier in this field. By enhancing glial fitness and cerebrovascular health and blocking amyloid-&#x3b2; (A&#x3b2;)-induced mitochondrial dysfunction pathways, cytochrome C (CytC) release, caspase 9 activation, and H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> generation in neurons, CA inhibitors improve cognition and lessen the pathology caused by A&#x3b2;. Recent research has pushed hCAs into the spotlight as critical players in AD pathogenesis and precise therapeutic targets. The captivating dilemma of choosing between hCA inhibitors and activators looms large, as inhibitors reduce A&#x3b2; aggregation and improve cerebral blood flow, while activators enhance cerebrovascular functions and restore pH balance. The current review sheds light on the clinical evidence for hCAs and the roles of inhibitors and activators in AD. Additionally, this review offers a fascinating outlook on the data that may aid medicinal chemists in designing and developing new leads that are more effective and selective for upcoming in vitro and in vivo studies, allowing for the discovery and introduction of novel drug candidates for the treatment of AD to the market and into the clinical pipeline.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Deutsche Pharmazeutische Gesellschaft.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mishra</LastName><ForeName>Km Abha</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicinal Chemistry, National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research (NIPER) Guwahati, Guwahati, Assam, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sethi</LastName><ForeName>Kalyan K</ForeName><Initials>KK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7627-0053</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicinal Chemistry, National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research (NIPER) Guwahati, Guwahati, Assam, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>None</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Arch Pharm (Weinheim)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0330167</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0365-6233</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002257">Carbonic Anhydrase Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 4.2.1.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002256">Carbonic Anhydrases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016229">Amyloid beta-Peptides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000544" MajorTopicYN="Y">Alzheimer Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002257" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carbonic Anhydrase Inhibitors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000138" MajorTopicYN="N">chemical synthesis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002256" MajorTopicYN="N">Carbonic Anhydrases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016229" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyloid beta-Peptides</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000037" MajorTopicYN="N">antagonists &amp; inhibitors</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alzheimer's disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">carbonic anhydrase inhibitors and activators</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hippocampal hCA deficiency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mitochondrial dysfunction</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39506506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ardp.202400748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Alzheimer's Association, Alzheimer's Disease Facts and Figures Special Report More Than Normal Aging: Understanding Mild Cognitive Impairment, Alzheimer's Association, Chicago, IL 2022. https://www.alz.org &#x203a;alzheimers&#x2010;facts&#x2010;and&#x2010;figures (accessed: 2024&#x2010;01&#x2010;08).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. The Top 10 Causes of Death, World Health Organization, Geneva, Switzerland, WHO Home Page. https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/the-top-10-causes-of-death (accessed: 2024&#x2010;01&#x2010;08).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. E. Hebert, J. Weuve, P. A. Scherr, D. A. Evans, Neurology 2013, 80(19), 1778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Zhang, Y. Tian, Z. T. Wang, Y. H. Ma, L. Tan, J. T. Yu, J. Prev. Alzheimers Dis. 2021, 8, 313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. M. Boisvert, G. A. Erikson, M. N. Shokhirev, N. J. Allen, Cell. Rep. 2018, 22(1), 269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Zhao, Y. Ren, Y. Yamazaki, W. Qiao, F. Li, L. M. Felton, S. Mahmoudiandehkordi, A. Kueider&#x2010;Paisley, B. Sonoustoun, M. Arnold, F. Shue, J. Zheng, O. N. Attrebi, Y. A. Martens, Z. Li, L. Bastea, A. D. Meneses, K. Chen, J. W. Thompson, L. St John&#x2010;Williams, M. Tachibana, T. Aikawa, H. Oue, L. Job, A. Yamazaki, C. C. Liu, P. Storz, Y. W. Asmann, N. Ertekin&#x2010;Taner, T. Kanekiyo, R. Kaddurah&#x2010;Daouk, G. Bu, Neuron 2020, 106(5), 727.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Gauthier, C. Webster, S. Servaes, J. A. Morais, P. Rosa&#x2010;Neto, World Alzheimer Report 2022, Alzheimer's Disease International 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzheimer's Association, 2022 Alzheimer's Disease Facts and Figures. Alzheimer's Dementia 2022, 18 (4), 700&#x2013;789.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Citron, Nat. Rev. Drug Discovery 2010, 9(5), 387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Blennow, M. J. de Leon, H. Zetterberg, Lancet 2006, 368(9533), 387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Atri, Semin. Neurol. 2019, 39, 227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. M. Glymour, J. Weuve, C. Dufouil, E. R. Mayeda, Am. J. Epidemiol. 2022, 191(8), 1347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Vaz, V. Silva, C. Monteiro, S. Silvestre, Clin. Interventions Aging. 2022, 17, 797.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. S. Doody, R. Raman, M. Farlow, T. Iwatsubo, B. Vellas, S. Joffe, K. Kieburtz, F. He, X. Sun, R. G. Thomas, P. S. Aisen, E. Siemers, G. Sethuraman, R. Mohs, N. Engl. J. Med. 2013, 369, 341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Vandenberghe, J. O. Rinne, M. Boada, S. Katayama, P. Scheltens, B. Vellas, M. Tuchman, A. Gass, J. B. Fiebach, D. Hill, K. Lobello, D. Li, T. McRae, P. Lucas, I. Evans, K. Booth, G. Luscan, B. T. Wyman, L. Hua, L. Yang, H. R. Brashear, R. S. Black, Alzheimer's Res. Ther. 2016, 8, 18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Lancet Neurology, Lancet Neurol. 2017, 16, 97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Burki, Lancet 2018, 391, 2486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. F. Egan, J. Kost, T. Voss, Y. Mukai, P. S. Aisen, J. L. Cummings, P. N. Tariot, B. Vellas, C. H. van Dyck, M. Boada, Y. Zhang, W. Li, C. Furtek, E. Mahoney, L. Harper Mozley, Y. Mo, C. Sur, D. Michelson, N. Engl. J. Med. 2019, 380, 1408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Henley, N. Raghavan, R. Sperling, P. Aisen, R. Raman, G. Romano, N. Engl. J. Med. 2019, 380, 1483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Pardo&#x2010;Moreno, A. Gonz&#xe1;lez&#x2010;Acedo, A. Rivas&#x2010;Dom&#xed;nguez, V. Garc&#xed;a&#x2010;Morales, F. J. Garc&#xed;a&#x2010;Cozar, J. J. Ramos&#x2010;Rodr&#xed;guez, L. Melguizo&#x2010;Rodr&#xed;guez, Pharmaceutics 2022, 14, 1117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Asher, R. Priefer, Life Sci. 2022, 306, 120861.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Courbage, G. Montoliu&#x2010;Montes, J. Wagner, Eur. J. Health Econ. 2020, 21, 1131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. P. Connolly, N. Kotsopoulos, M. J. Postma, A. Bhatt, Value Health 2017, 20(2), 273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Black, Working for a Healthier Tomorrow, Govt. UK, London, UK 2008, https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/workingfor-a-healthier-tomorrow-work-and-health-in-britain/ (accessed: 2024&#x2010;01&#x2010;08).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Mare&#x161;ov&#xe1;, J. Dolejs, H. Mohelska, L. K. Bryan, Curr. Alzheimer Res. 2020, 16, 1245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Dauphinot, M. Potashman, M. Levitchi&#x2010;Benea, R. Su, I. Rubino, P. Krolak&#x2010;Salmon, Alzheimer's Res. Ther. 2022, 14, 34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO, Global Action Plan on the Public Health Response to Dementia 2017&#x2013;2025, WHO, Geneva, Switzerland.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Li, X. Feng, X. Sun, N. Hou, F. Han, Y. Liu, Front. Aging Neurosci. 2022, 14, 937486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Pedroza, M. K. Miller&#x2010;Petrie, C. Chen, S. Chakrabarti, A. Chapin, S. Hay, G. Tsakalos, A. Wimo, J. L. Dieleman, EclinicalMedicine 2022, 45, 101337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Jia, C. Wei, S. Chen, F. Li, Y. Tang, W. Qin, L. Zhao, H. Jin, H. Xu, F. Wang, A. Zhou, X. Zuo, L. Wu, Y. Han, Y. Han, L. Huang, Q. Wang, D. Li, C. Chu, L. Shi, M. Gong, Y. Du, J. Zhang, J. Zhang, C. Zhou, J. Lv, Y. Lv, H. Xie, Y. Ji, F. Li, E. Yu, B. Luo, Y. Wang, S. Yang, Q. Qu, Q. Guo, F. Liang, J. Zhang, L. Tan, L. Shen, K. Zhang, J. Zhang, D. Peng, M. Tang, P. Lv, B. Fang, L. Chu, L. Jia, S. Gauthier, Alzheimer's Dementia: J. Alzheimer's Assoc. 2018, 14(4), 483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Nandi, N. Counts, S. Chen, B. Seligman, D. Tortorice, D. Vigo, D. E. Bloom, EclinicalMedicine 2022, 51, 101580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Wong, Am. J. Manage. Care. 2020, 26(8), 177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. H. Millican, B. J. Piper, Medicare Advantage Risk Score Primer: What You Need to Know About Diagnoses Supporting Risk Scores and Revenue Payment Timing, Milliman White Paper, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Pharmacists Association, Medication Therapy Management (MTM) Services, American Pharmacists Association, Washington, DC 2008, https://www.pharmacist.com/medication-therapymanagement-services/ (accessed: 2024&#x2010;01&#x2010;08).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Sharma, P. Srivastava, A. Seth, P. N. Tripathi, A. G. Banerjee, S. K. Shrivastava, Prog. Neurobiol. 2019, 174, 53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. E. Hurtado, L. Molina&#x2010;Porcel, M. Iba, A. K. Aboagye, S. M. Paul, J. Q. Trojanowski, V. M. Y. Lee, Am. J. Pathol. 2010, 177(4), 1977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Rajmohan, P. H. Reddy, J. Alzheimer's Dis. 2017, 57(4), 975.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Q. Trojanowski, V. M. Y. Lee, Ann. N. Y. Acad. Sci. 2000, 924, 62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Serrano&#x2010;Pozo, M. P. Frosch, E. Masliah, B. T. Hyman, Cold Spring Harbor Perspect. Med. 2011, 1(1), a006189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Mandelkow, Trends Cell Biol. 1998, 8(11), 425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Iqbal, I. Grundke&#x2010;Iqbal, J. Alzheimer's Dis. 2002, 4(3), 235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Verkhratsky, V. Parpura, J. J. Rodriguez&#x2010;Arellano, R. Zorec, Adv. Exp. Med. Biol. 2019, 1175, 273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. V. Hansen, J. E. Hanson, M. Sheng, J. Cell Biol. 2018, 217(2), 459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Ghiso, Y. Tomidokoro, T. Revesz, B. Frangione, A. Rostagno, Hirosaki Igaku = Hirosaki Med. J. 2010, 61(Suppl.), 111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. A. DeTure, D. W. Dickson, Mol. Neurodegener. 2019, 14, 32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. E. Funk, R. E. Mrak, J. Kuret, Neuropathol. Appl. Neurobiol. 2011, 37(3), 295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. W. Scheff, D. A. Price, F. A. Schmitt, E. J. Mufson, Neurobiol. Aging 2006, 27(10), 1372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. T. DeKosky, S. W. Scheff, Ann. Neurol. 1990, 27(5), 457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. E. Tanzi, Cold Spring Harbor Perspect. Med. 2012, 2, a006296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. C. Lambert, P. Amouyel, Curr. Opin. Genet. Dev. 2011, 21, 295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Giri, M. Zhang, Y. Lu, Clin. Interventions Aging. 2016, 11, 665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. W. Mahley, Science 1988, 240, 622.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Jin, A. L. Peel, X. O. Mao, L. Xie, B. A. Cottrell, D. C. Henshall, D. A. Greenberg,. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 2004, 101(1), 343.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Li, H. Yamamori, Y. Tatebayashi, B. Shafit&#x2010;Zagardo, H. Tanimukai, S. Chen, K. Iqbal, I. Grundke&#x2010;Iqbal, J. Neuropathol. Exp. Neurol. 2008, 67(1), 78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Capasso, C. T. Supuran, Expert Opin. Ther. Targets 2015, 19, 1689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Patel, J. H. Miao, E. Yetiskul, A. Anokhin, S. H. Majmundar, Physiology, Carbon Dioxide Retention, StatPearls, Treasure Island, FL 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. J. Arthurs, M. Sudhakar, Contin. Educ. Anaesth. Crit. Care Pain 2005, 5(6), 207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. T. Supuran, Nat. Rev. Drug Discovery 2008, 7, 168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. T. Supuran, J. Enzyme Inhib. Med. Chem. 2012, 27, 759.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. T. Supuran, Bioorg. Med. Chem. Lett. 2010, 20, 3467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Alka, J. R. Casey, IUBMB Life 2014, 66(9), 596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. R. Chegwidden, N. D. Carter, EXS 2000, 90, 13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. E. Tashian, BioEssays 1989, 10(6), 186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. B. Mishra, M. Tiwari, C. T. Supuran, Med. Res. Rev. 2020, 40, 2485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. T. Supuran, J. Enzyme Inhib. Med. Chem. 2016, 31, 345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Nocentini, A. Angeli, F. Carta, J. Y. Winum, R. Zalubovskis, S. Carradori, C. Capasso, W. A. Donald, C. T. Supuran, J. Enzyme Inhib. Med. Chem. 2021, 36, 561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Del Prete, D. Vullo, G. M. Fisher, K. T. Andrews, S. A. Poulsen, C. Capasso, C. T. Supuran, Bioorg. Med. Chem. Lett. 2014, 24, 4389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. H. Maren, Drug Dev. Res. 1987, 10, 255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. J. Wistrand, EXS 2000, 90, 413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Y. Liao, J. Med. Genet. 2003, 40(4), 257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Weiwei, R. Hu, Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 2009, 390(3), 368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Hayes, Ann. Clin. Psychiatry 1994, 6(2), 91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. R. Song, B. Wu, Y. T. Yang, J. Chen, L. J. Zhang, Z. W. Zhang, H. Y. Shi, C. L. Huang, J. X. Pan, P. Xie, Braz. J. Med. Biol. Res. 2015, 48(11), 973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. B. Gao, A. Clermont, S. Rook, S. J. Fonda, V. J. Srinivasan, M. Wojtkowski, J. G. Fujimoto, R. L. Avery, P. G. Arrigg, S. E. Bursell, L. P. Aiello, E. P. Feener, Nat. Med. 2007, 13(2), 181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. E. Leaf, D. S. Goldfarb, J. Appl. Physiol. 2007, 102(4), 1313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. R. Swenson, SubCell. Biochem. 2014, 75, 361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. G. Jang, S. M. Yun, K. Ahn, J. H. Song, S. A. Jo, Y. Y. Kim, D. K. Kim, M. H. Park, C. Han, Y. H. Koh, J. Alzheimer's Dis. 2010, 21(3), 939.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Lemon, E. Canepa, M. A. Ilies, S. Fossati, Front. Aging Neurosci. 2021, 13, 772278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Heming, S. Urien, C. Faisy, Crit. Care 2012, 16(4), 318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Polack, E. Berco, Y. Greenwald, Encycl. Ophthalmol. 2014, 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Aggarwal, B. Kondeti, R. McKenna, Expert Opin. Ther. Pat. 2013, 23(6), 717.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Ciccone, C. Cerri, S. Nencetti, E. Orlandini, Molecules 2021, 26(21), 6380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Hudalla, Z. Michael, N. Christodoulou, G. R. Willis, A. Fernandez&#x2010;Gonzalez, E. J. Filatava, P. Dieffenbach, L. E. Fredenburgh, R. S. Stearman, M. W. Geraci, S. Kourembanas, H. Christou, Am. J. Respir. Cell Mol. Biol. 2019, 61(4), 512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Wang, D. Eskandari, D. Zou, L. Grote, J. Hedner, Sleep 2015, 38(7), 1067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Hoff, D. Zou, S. Schiza, Y. Demir, L. Grote, I. Bouloukaki, &#x15e;. Beydemir, D. Eskandari, K. Stenl&#xf6;f, J. Hedner, J. Sleep. Res. 2020, 29(2), e12956.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. L. Du, A. L. Du, H. M. Ren, A. L. Du, H. M. Ren, C. Z. Lu, J. L. Tu, C. F. Xu, Y. A. Sun, Autoimmunity 2009, 42(3), 209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Du, S. Huang, X. Zhao, K. Feng, S. Zhang, J. Huang, X. Miao, F. Baggi, R. S. Ostrom, Y. Zhang, X. Chen, C. Xu, Autophagy 2017, 13(11), 1981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. V. Alvarez, E. N. Vithana, Z. Yang, A. H. Koh, K. Yeung, V. Yong, H. J. Shandro, Y. Chen, P. Kolatkar, P. Palasingam, K. Zhang, T. Aung, J. R. Casey, Invest. Opthalmol. Visual Sci. 2007, 48, 3459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Datta, A. Waheed, G. Bonapace, G. N. Shah, W. S. Sly, Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 2009, 106(9), 3437.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. De Simone, C. Supuran, Curr. Top. Med. Chem. 2007, 7(9), 879.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Queen., P. Khan, A. Azam, M. I. Hassan, Curr. Protein Pept. Sci. 2018, 19(9), 909.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. C. R. Picco, L. Marangoni&#x2010;Lopes, T. M. Parisotto, R. Mattos&#x2010;Graner, M. Nobre&#x2010;Dos&#x2010;Santos, Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2019, 20(11), 2673.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Esberg, S. Haworth, C. Brunius, P. Lif Holgerson, I. Johansson, Sci. Rep. 2019, 9(1), 452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Pastorekova, R. J. Gillies, Cancer Metastasis Rev. 2019, 38(1&#x2013;2), 65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Thiry, J. M. Dogn&#xe9;, B. Masereel, C. T. Supuran, Trends Pharmacol. Sci. 2006, 27(11), 566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. T. Supuran, Expert Opin. Ther. Pat. 2018, 28(10), 713.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. K. Korhonen, E. Naeaetaenen, M. Hyyppae, Acta Histochem. 1964, 18, 336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Liu, D. Lu, R. Bowser, J. Liu, Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2016, 17(11), 1820.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. S. Ghandour, O. K. Langley, G. Vincendon, G. Gombos, D. Filippi, N. Limozin, C. Dalmasso, G. Laurent, Neuroscience 1980, 5, 559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Kida, S. Palminiello, A. A. Golabek, M. Walus, T. Wierzba&#x2010;Bobrowicz, A. Rabe, G. Albertini, K. E. Wisniewski, J. Neuropathol. Exp. Neurol. 2006, 65(7), 664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Kumpulainen, L. K. Korhonen, J. Histochem. Cytochem. 1982, 30, 283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Jeffrey, G. A. H. Wells, A. W. Bridges, J. Comp. Pathol. 1991, 104, 337.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. K. Kimelberg, P. E. Stieg, J. E. Mazurkiewicz, J. Neurochem. 1982, 39, 734.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Linser, J. Neurosci. 1985, 5(9), 2388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. N&#xf3;gr&#xe1;di, C. Kelly, N. D. Carter, Neurosci. Lett. 1993, 151, 162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. K. Harju, F. Bootorabi, M. Kuuslahti, C. T. Supuran, S. Parkkila, J. Enzyme Inhib. Med. Chem. 2012, 28(2), 231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. S. Ghandour, A. K. Parkkila, S. Parkkila, A. Waheed, W. S. Sly, J. Neurochem. 2000, 75(5), 2212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Svichar, A. Waheed, W. S. Sly, J. C. Hennings, C. A. H&#xfc;bner, M. Chesler, J. Neurosci. 2009, 29, 3252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. K. Tong, L. P. Brion, C. Suarez, M. Chesler, J. Neurosci. 2000, 20(22), 8247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. K. Rasmussen, E. Boedtkjer, J. Cereb. Blood Flow Metab. 2018, 38, 492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Ruusuvuori, A. K. Huebner, I. Kirilkin, A. Y. Yukin, P. Blaesse, M. Helmy, H. Jung Kang, M. El Muayed, J. Christopher Hennings, J. Voipio, N. &#x160;estan, C. A. H&#xfc;bner, K. Kaila, EMBO J. 2013, 32, 2275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. L. Karjalainen, H. K. Haapasalo, A. Aspatwar, H. Barker, S. Parkkila, J. A. Haapasalo, BMC Cancer 2018, 18, 584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Ivanov, S. Y. Liao, A. Ivanova, A. Danilkovitch&#x2010;Miagkova, N. Tarasova, G. Weirich, M. J. Merrill, M. A. Proescholdt, E. H. Oldfield, J. Lee, J. Zavada, A. Waheed, W. Sly, M. I. Lerman, E. J. Stanbridge, Am. J. Pathol. 2001, 158, 905.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Halmi, S. Parkkila, J. Honkaniemi, Neurochem. Int. 2006, 48, 24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Cetin, I. I. Gonul, O. Gumusay, I. Bilgetekin, E. Algin, A. Ozet, A. Uner, Neuropathology 2018, 38, 457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Parkkila, A.&#x2010;K. Parkkila, H. Rajaniemi, G. N. Shah, J. H. Grubb, A. Waheed, W. S. Sly, Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 2001, 98, 1918.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Lehtonen, B. Shen, M. Vihinen, A. Casini, A. Scozzafava, C. T. Supuran, A. K. Parkkila, J. Saarnio, A. J. Kivel&#xe4;, A. Waheed, W. S. Sly, S. Parkkila, J. Biol. Chem. 2004, 279(4), 2719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Borreli, O. K. Langley, M. S. Ghandour, J. P. Delaunoy, G. Gombos, Neurosci. Lett. 1982, 32, 321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. S. Ghandour, O. K. Langley, X. L. Zhu, A. Waheed, W. S. Sly, Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 1992, 89(15), 6823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. M. Lakkis, K. S. O'Shea, R. E. Tashian, J. Histochem, Cytochem. 1997, 45, 657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. M. Lakkis, Histochem. J. 1997, 29, 135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Taniuchi, I. Nishimori, T. Takeuchi, K. Fujikawa&#x2010;Adachi, Y. Ohtsuki, S. Onishi, Neuroscience 2002, 112(1), 93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Kallio, S. Pastorekova, J. Pastorek, A. Waheed, W. S. Sly, S. Mannisto, M. Heikinheimo, S. Parkkila, BMC. Dev. Biol. 2006, 6, 22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Hilvo, A. Innocenti, S. M. Monti, G. D. e Simone, C. T. Supuran, S. Parkkila, Curr. Pharm. Des. 2008, 14(7), 672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Chesler, Physiol. Rev. 2003, 83, 1183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Ruusuvuori, K. Kaila, Sub. Cell. Biochem. 2014, 75, 271.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Pasternack, J. Voipio, K. Kaila, Acta Physiol. Scand. 1993, 148, 229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. H. Stridh, M. D. Alt, S. Wittmann, H. Heidtmann, M. Aggarwal, B. Riederer, U. Seidler, G. Wennemuth, R. McKenna, J. W. Deitmer, H. M. Becker, J. Physiol. 2012, 590, 2333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Jiao, J. Yan, Y. Zhao, L. R. Donahue, W. G. Beamer, X. Li, B. A. Roe, M. S. Le Doux, W. Gu, Genetics 2005, 171, 1239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. R. Cobb, E. H. Buhl, K. Halasy, O. Paulsen, P. Somogyi, Nature 1995, 378, 75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. K. Sun, W. Q. Zhao, T. J. Nelson, D. L. Alkon, J. Neurophysiol. 2001, 85(1), 269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Poirazi, B. W. Mel, Neuron 2001, 29, 779.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. E. Vogt, W. G. Regehr, J. Neurosci. 2001, 21, 75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. P. Wiebe, U. V. St&#xe4;ubli, J. Neurosci. 2001, 21, 3955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Bhatt, U. K. Mondal, C. T. Supuran, M. A. Ilies, R. McKenna, Mol. Neurobiol. 2018, 55, 7431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Ruusuvuori, H. Li, K. Huttu, J. M. Palva, S. Smirnov, C. Rivera, K. Kaila, J. Voipio, J. Neurosci. 2004, 24(11), 2699.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. J. Staley, B. L. Soldo, W. R. Proctor, Science 1995, 269, 977.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Z. Ozsoy, Neurochem. Res. 2021, 46(11), 2783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. Ferrer, R. Blanco, M. Carmona, R. Ribera, E. Goutan, B. Puig, M. J. Rey, A. Cardozo, F. Vi&#xf1;als, T. Ribalta, Brain Pathol. 2001, 11(2), 144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Liu, Exp. Cell Res. 2003, 287(2), 387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Zhu, H. Lee, A. K. Raina, G. Perry, M. A. Smith, Neurosignals 2002, 11(5), 270.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Canto de Souza, G. Provensi, D. Vullo, F. Carta, A. Scozzafava, A. Costa, S. D. Schmidt, M. B. Passani, C. T. Supuran, P. Blandina, Neuropharmacology 2017, 118, 148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Zhu, R. J. Castellani, A. Takeda, A. Nunomura, C. S. Atwood, G. Perry, M. A. Smith, Mech. Ageing Dev. 2001, 123(1), 39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Blandina, G. Provensi, M. B. Passani, C. Capasso, C. T. Supuran, J. Enzyme Inhib. Med. Chem. 2020, 35(1), 1206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Sun, Y. Chen, C. Pang, N. Wu, J. Li, Acta Pharmacol. Sin. 2013, 35, 41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. T. Hyman, G. W. Van Hoesen, A. R. Damasio, C. L. Barnes, Science 1984, 225(4667), 1168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. G. Morris, M. D. Kopelman, Q. J. Exp. Psychol. Sect. A 1986, 38, 575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Danysz, C. G. Parsons, Br. J. Pharmacol. 2012, 167(2), 324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. T. Yang, W. L. Chien, D. H. Lu, H. C. Liou, W. M. Fu, Neuropharmacology 2013, 67, 412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. K. Sun, D. L. Alkon, J. Pharmacol. Exp. Ther. 2001, 297(3), 961.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Geers, G. Gros, Physiol. Rev. 2000, 80(2), 681.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Kaila, J. Voipio, P. Paalasmaa, M. Pasternack, R. A. Deisz, J. Physiol. 1993, 464, 273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Brini, E. Carafoli, T. Cal&#xec;, Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 2017, 483(4), 1116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. N. Bourne, K. M. Harris, Annu. Rev. Neurosci. 2008, 31, 47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Halpain, Trends Neurosci 2000, 23(4), 141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Bertling, P. Blaesse, P. Seja, E. Kremneva, G. Gateva, M. A. Virtanen, M. Summanen, I. Spoljaric, P. Uvarov, M. Blaesse, V. O. Paavilainen, L. Vutskits, K. Kaila, P. Hotulainen, E. Ruusuvuori, EMBO Rep 2021, 22(4), e50145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Goldstein, D. B. Calne, A. Lieberman, M. O. Thorner, Ergot Compounds and Brain Function: Neuroendocrine and Neuropsychiatric Aspects, Raven Press, New York 1980, pp. 323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Meier&#x2010;Ruge, P. Iwangoff, K. Reichlmeier, Arch. Gerontol. Geriatr. 1984, 3, 161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. S. Sly, P. Y. Hu, Annu. Rev. Biochem. 1995, 64, 375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Sone, H. Sei, Y. Morita, T. Ogura, S. Sone, Physiol. Behav. 1998, 63, 213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Kaila, B. R. Ransom, pH and Brain Function, John Wiley and Sons, New Jersey, US 1998, pp. 688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Singh, R. Kukreti, L. Saso, S. Kukreti, Molecules 2019, 24(8), 1583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Tannenberg, H. Scott, R. Westphalen, P. Dodd, Curr. Alzheimer Res. 2004, 1(1), 11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Sun, Y. Tu, Y. Guo, H. L. Jiang, Y.&#x2010;H. Li, Y. Wang, B. C. Zhao, X.&#x2010;Z. Gao, X. Li, S.&#x2010;X. Feng, Y. F. Li, Zhen ci yan jiu = Acupunct. Res. 2019, 44(6), 412.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Sultana, M. Perluigi, S. F. Newman, W. M. Pierce, C. Cini, R. Coccia, D. A. Butterfield, Antioxid. Redox Signaling 2010, 12, 327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. S. Sly, M. P. Whyte, V. Sundaram, R. E. Tashian, D. Hewett&#x2010;Emmett, P. Guibaud, M. Vainsel, H. J. Baluarte, A. Gruskin, M. Al&#x2010;Mosawi, N. Sakati, A. Ohlsson, N. Engl. J. Med. 1985, 313(3), 139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Y. Liao, K. M. Darcy, L. M. Randall, C. Tian, B. J. Monk, R. A. Burger, J. P. Fruehauf, W. A. Peters, R. J. Stock, E. J. Stanbridge, Gynecol. Oncol. 2010, 116(3), 452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. B. Loiselle, P. E. Morgan, B. V. Alvarez, J. R. Casey, Am. J. Physiol.&#x2013;Cell Physiol 2004, 286(6), C1423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. K. Sun, T. J. Nelson, D. L. Alkon, Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 2000, 97, 12300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. Puscas, M. Coltau, R. Pasca, J. Pharmacol. Exp. Ther. 1996, 277, 1464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. Puscas, G. B&#xfa;z&#xe1;s, L. Sturzu, S. V&#x103;lean, Arzneimittel. Forsch. 1984, 34(9), 946.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. M. Biskobing, M. S. Nanes, J. Rubin, Endocrinology 1994, 134(3), 1493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Siegmund, A. T&#xfc;llmann, M. Holke, P. Ott, L. Uher, Horm. Metab. Res. 1974, 6, 158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. K. Sun, D. L. Alkon, Trends Pharmacol. Sci. 2002, 23(2), 83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Silverberg, M. Mayo, T. Saul, J. Fellmann, D. McGuire, Cerebrospinal Fluid Res 2006, 3, 7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. D. Silverberg, G. Heit, S. Huhn, R. A. Jaffe, S. D. Chang, H. Bronte&#x2013;Stewart, E. Rubenstein, K. Possin, T. A. Saul, Neurology 2001, 57, 1763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. D. Silverberg, M. Mayo, T. Saul, E. Rubenstein, D. McGuire, Lancet Neurol 2003, 2, 506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Sakka, G. Coll, J. Chazal, Eur. Ann. Otorhinolaryngol. Head Neck Dis. 2011, 128, 309.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Kant, E. G. Stopa, C. E. Johanson, A. Baird, G. D. Silverberg, Fluids Barriers CNS 2018, 15, 34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. D. Brown, S. L. Davies, T. Speake, I. D. Millar, Neuroscience 2004, 129, 955.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. P. Vogh, D. R. Godman, T. H. Maren, J. Pharmacol. Exp. Ther. 1987, 243(1), 35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. K. Diem, R. O. Carare, R. O. Weller, N. W. Bressloff, PLoS ONE 2018, 13, e0205276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. R. Burgess, S. J. E. Lucas, K. M. E. Burgess, K. E. Sprecher, J. Donnelly, A. S. Basnet, M. M. Tymko, T. Day, K. Smith, N. Lewis, P. N. Ainslie, J. Appl. Physiol. 2018, 124, 1341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Murakami, T. Yonehara, A. Takaki, S. Fujioka, T. Hirano, Y. Ushio, J. Nucl. Med.: Off. Publ. Soci. Nucl. Med. 2002, 43(5), 577.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. M. Tarasoff&#x2010;Conway, R. O. Carare, R. S. Osorio, L. Glodzik, T. Butler, E. Fieremans, L. Axel, H. Rusinek, C. Nicholson, B. V. Zlokovic, B. Frangione, K. Blennow, J. M&#xe9;nard, H. Zetterberg, T. Wisniewski, M. J. de Leon, Nat. Rev. Neurol. 2015, 11(8), 457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Angiulli, M. E. Solesio, L. Debure, J. R. Cejudo, T. Wisniewski, S. Fossati, J. Alzheimers Assoc. 2018, 14(7), P1296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Sultana, D. Boyd&#x2010;Kimball, J. Cai, W. M. Pierce, J. B. Klein, M. Merchant, D. A. Butterfield, J. Alzheimer's Dis. 2007, 11(2), 153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. A. Butterfield, T. Reed, S. F. Newman, R. Sultana, Rad. Biol. Med. 2007, 43(5), 658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Sultana, H. F. Poon, J. Cai, W. M. Pierce, M. Merchant, J. B. Klein, W. R. Markesbery, D. A. Butterfield, Neurobiol. Dis. 2006, 22(1), 76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Sultana, D. Boyd&#x2010;Kimball, H. F. Poon, J. Cai, W. M. Pierce, J. B. Klein, M. Merchant, W. R. Markesbery, D. A. Butterfield, Neurobiol. Aging 2006, 27(11), 1564.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. J. Szabolcs, M. Kopp, G. E. Schaden, Brain Res 1989, 492(1&#x2013;2), 12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Hensley, N. Hall, R. Subramaniam, P. Cole, M. Harris, M. Aksenov, M. Aksenova, S. P. Gabbita, J. F. Wu, J. M. Carney, M. Lovell, W. R. Markesbery, D. A. Butterfield, J. Neurochem. 1995, 65(5), 2146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Fossati, M. E. Solesio, E. Pavlov, T. Wisniewski, Alzheimer's Dement 2016, 12(7), P650.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Canepa, R. Vazquez&#x2010;Torres, R. M. Parodi&#x2010;Rullan, F. Angiulli, L. Debure, S. Fossati, Alzheimer's Dement 2021, 17(S3), e054199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Sotolongo, J. Ghiso, A. Rostagno, Alzheimers Res. Ther. 2020, 12(1), 13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. T. Supuran, Future Med. Chem. 2018, 10(5), 561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Angeli, E. Berrino, S. Carradori, C. T. Supuran, M. Cirri, F. Carta, G. Costantino, Molecules 2021, 26(23), 7331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Cortes&#x2010;Canteli, C. Iadecola, J. Am. Coll. Cardiol. 2020, 75(8), 942.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Parodi&#x2010;Rull&#xe1;n, J. Ghiso, E. Cabrera, A. Rostagno, S. Fossati, Aging Cell 2020, 19, e13258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. E. Solesio, P. M. Peixoto, L. Debure, S. M. Madamba, M. J. de Leon, T. Wisniewski, E. V. Pavlov, S. Fossati, Aging Cell 2018, 17(4), e12787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Fossati, P. Giannoni, M. E. Solesio, S. L. Cocklin, E. Cabrera, J. Ghiso, A. Rostagno, Neurobiol. Dis. 2016, 86, 29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Provensi, F. Carta, A. Nocentini, C. T. Supuran, F. Casamenti, M. B. Passani, S. Fossati, Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2019, 20(19), 4724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Anzovino, E. Canepa, M. Alves, N. L. Lemon, R. O. Carare, S. Fossati, Cells 2023, 12(24), 2840.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. Elder, C. Tu, L. J. Ming, R. McKenna, D. N. Silverman, Arch. Biochem. Biophys. 2005, 437(1), 106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. M. Maupin, N. Castillo, S. Taraphder, C. Tu, R. Mckenna, D. N. Silverman, G. A. Voth, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2011, 133(16), 6223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Temperini, A. Innocenti, A. Scozzafava, C. T. Supuran, Bioorg. Med. Chem. 2008, 16(18), 8373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Briganti, S. Mangani, P. Orioli, A. Scozzafava, G. Vernaglione, C. T. Supuran, Biochemistry 1997, 36(34), 10384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Temperini, A. Scozzafava, C. T. Supuran, Bioorg. Med. Chem. Lett. 2006, 16(19), 5152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Temperini, A. Scozzafava, L. Puccetti, C. T. Supuran, Bioorg. Med. Chem. Lett. 2005, 15(23), 5136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Temperini, A. Innocenti, A. Scozzafava, A. Mastrolorenzo, C. T. Supuran, Bioorg. Med. Chem. Lett. 2007, 17(13), 628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. G. Khalifah, J. Biol. Chem. 1971, 246(8), 2561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Tanini, A. Capperucci, C. T. Supuran, A. Angeli, Bioorg. Chem. 2019, 87, 516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. T. Supuran, M. Barboiu, C. Luca, E. Pop, M. Brewster, A. Dinculescu, Eur. J. Med. Chem. 1996, 31(7&#x2013;8), 597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Scozzafava, Eur. J. Med. Chem. 2000, 35(1), 31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Briganti, A. Scozzafava, C. T. Supuran, Bioorg. Med. Chem. Lett. 1999, 9(14), 2043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. T. Supuran, A. Scozzafava, Bioorg. Med. Chem. 1999, 7(12), 2915.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. C. Saada, D. Vullo, J. L. Montero, A. Scozzafava, J. Y. Winum, C. T. Supuran, Bioorg. Med. Chem. Lett. 2011, 21(16), 4884.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. C. Saada, D. Vullo, J. L. Montero, A. Scozzafava, C. T. Supuran, J. Y. Winum, Bioorg. Med. Chem. 2014, 22(17), 4752.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Draghici, D. Vullo, S. Akocak, E. A. Walker, C. T. Supuran, M. A. Ilies, Chem. Commun. 2014, 50(45), 5980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Aggarwal, B. Kondeti, C. Tu, C. M. Maupin, D. N. Silverman, R. McKenna, IUCrJ 2014, 1(Pt 2), 129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Mollica, G. Macedonio, A. Stefanucci, S. Carradori, A. Akdemir, A. Angeli, C. T. Supuran, Molecules 2017, 22(12), 2178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Akocak, N. Lolak, S. Bua, A. Nocentini, G. Karakoc, C. T. Supuran, Bioorg. Med. Chem. 2019, 27(5), 800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Akocak, N. Lolak, S. Bua, A. Nocentini, C. T. Supuran, J. Enzyme Inhib. Med. Chem. 2019, 34(1), 1193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Scozzafava, C. T. Supuran, J. Med. Chem. 2001, 45(2), 284.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. R. Abdo, D. Vullo, M. C. Saada, J. L. Montero, A. Scozzafava, J. Y. Winum, C. T. Supuran, Bioorg. Med. Chem. Lett. 2009, 19(9), 2440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. C. Saada, J. L. Montero, D. Vullo, A. Scozzafava, J. Y. Winum, C. T. Supuran, J. Med. Chem. 2011, 54(5), 1170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Cuffaro, R. Di Leo, L. Ciccone, A. Nocentini, C. T. Supuran, E. Nuti, A. Rossello, J. Enzyme, Inhib. Med. Chem. 2023, 38(1), 2164574.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Nocentini, D. Cuffaro, L. Ciccone, E. Orlandini, S. Nencetti, E. Nuti, A. Rossello, C. T. Supuran, J. Enzyme Inhib. Med. Chem. 2021, 36(1), 48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Fiorentino, A. Nocentini, D. Rotili, C. T. Supuran, A. Mai, J. Enzyme, Inhib. Med. Chem. 2023, 38(1), 2188147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Provensi, A. Nocentini, M. B. Passani, P. Blandina, C. T. Supuran, J. Enzyme Inhib. Med. Chem. 2021, 36(1), 719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Sugimoto, H. Ikeda, H. Tsukamoto, K. Kihira, M. Ishioka, J. Hirose, T. Hata, H. Fujioka, Y. Ono, Biol. Pharm. Bull. 2010, 33(2), 301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Casini, S. Caccia, A. Scozzafava, C. T. Supuran, Bioorg. Med. Chem. Lett. 2003, 13(16), 2765.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Abd&#xfc;lkadir Coban, &#x15e;. Beydemir, I. G&#xfc;cin, D. Ekinci, A. Innocenti, D. Vullo, C. T. Supuran, Bioorg. Med. Chem. 2009, 17(16), 5791.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. M. Breinin, AMA Arch. Ophthalmol. 1954, 52(3), 333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. I. Moreira, C. Carvalho, X. Zhu, M. A. Smith, G. Perry, Biochim. Biophys. Acta (BBA)&#x2014;Mol. Basis Dis 2010, 1802(1), 2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. H. Swerdlow, J. M. Burns, S. M. Khan, J. Alzheimer's Dis. 2010, 20(Suppl. 2), S265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Marchenkov, N. Ryabova, V. Balobanov, A. Glukhov, N. Ilyina, N. Katina, Biomolecules 2021, 11(11), 1608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Canepa, R. Parodi&#x2010;Rullan, R. Vazquez&#x2010;Torres, B. Gamallo&#x2010;Lana, R. Guzman&#x2010;Hernandez, N. L. Lemon, F. Angiulli, L. Debure, M. Ilies, L. &#xd8;stergaard, T. Wisniewski, E. Guti&#xe9;rrez&#x2010;Jim&#xe9;nez, A. Mar, S. Fossati, Alzheimers Dement 2023, 20(3), 2297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Pollard, F. Shephard, J. Freed, S. Liddell, L. Chakrabarti, Aging 2016, 8(10), 2425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Drummond, S. Nayak, A. Faustin, G. Pires, R. A. Hickman, M. Askenazi, M. Cohen, T. Haldiman, C. Kim, X. Han, Y. Shao, J. G. Safar, B. Ueberheide, T. Wisniewski, Acta Neuropathol 2017, 133(6), 933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Wang, T. Ke, X. Zhang, Y. Chen, M. Liu, J. Chen, W. Luo, Neurotoxicol. Teratol. 2013, 35, 28.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>