<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41473655</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Roles of Psychiatry, Dietary, and Oncology Services in Occupational Medicine: A Comprehensive Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e98069</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e98069</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e98069</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.98069</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Occupational medicine manages the interface between health and work. Many employees live with mental illness, cancer, or diet-related diseases in safety-critical roles. These burdens change attention, stamina, risk, and retention. Psychiatry stabilizes mood, sleep, cognition, and substance use. Dietetic services improve energy balance, hydration, and micronutrients. Oncology aligns staging, treatment, and survivorship with duty risk. Services are often siloed, delaying care and widening inequity. Teams need clear roles, shared tools, and models that fit shifts, heat, chemicals, and job design. This article aims to synthesize the roles of psychiatric, dietetic, and oncology services in occupational medicine; to describe feasible models across prevention, clinical management, assessment, and return to work; and to propose simple tools and metrics for routine use. We searched peer-reviewed studies, guidelines, and consensus statements about adult workers. We included interventions usable in routine practice, such as brief screens, counseling, task modification, medication management, and coordinated care. Findings were mapped to prevention, clinical management, work capacity assessment, and sustained return to work. We extracted setting, workforce, elements, and outcomes, including incidents, sickness absence, presenteeism, claims, and retention. Strength of evidence was summarized pragmatically. In psychiatry, depression, anxiety, PTSD, insomnia, ADHD, and substance use are common. Brief case finding supports safe staffing. CBT, trauma-informed support, motivational interviewing, and monitored medication reduce incidents and days lost. Symptoms should be translated into task limits; for example, avoid lone work during acute suicidality and night duty while insomnia persists. In dietetic services, nutritional risk drives cardiometabolic disease, anemia, dehydration, heat illness, and fatigue; shift work disrupts glycemic control. Actions include brief screens, energy and hydration plans for heat, and alignment of diabetes meals and medication to prevent hypoglycemia. Healthy canteens, cool water, and breaks lower fatigue and errors. In oncology, duties should be aligned with staging, treatment intent, and expected adverse effects, including those affecting infection risk, cytopenias, neuropathy, and lymphedema. During treatment, immunosuppression, anemia, and nausea restrict tasks; measures include vaccine review, substitution away from biohazards and heavy lifting, and compression for lymphedema. Shared tools improve coordination: a joint problem list linking symptoms to tasks; a one-page plan with limits, controls, and review dates; and simple metrics such as incidents, near misses, absence, work ability, and worker-reported outcomes. Implementation improves when confidentiality is protected, stigma is reduced, supervisors are trained, and reviews are fair. Integrated psychiatric, dietetic, and oncology input can make work safer and more inclusive. Begin with a joint task-risk review, match brief evidence-based actions to the job, and set clear fitness and re-evaluation points. Employers should provide healthy food, cool water, fatigue controls, and time for care. Clinics should use validated screens, simple nutrition checks, and work ability indices and record accommodations plainly. Research should test pragmatic bundles and report outcomes that matter to workers and supervisors, including incidents, stable return to work, and equity.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Jogie et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jogie</LastName><ForeName>Joshua A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Occupational Health Unit, St. James Medical Complex, Port of Spain, TTO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohammed</LastName><ForeName>Zahir</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oncology Department, St. James Medical Complex, Port of Spain, TTO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bobb</LastName><ForeName>Tricia</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Psychiatry Department, Arima General Hospital, Arima, TTO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suite-Stewart</LastName><ForeName>Zara</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nutrition and Dietetics Department, St. James Medical Complex, Port of Spain, TTO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ali</LastName><ForeName>Shivan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Occupational Health Unit, St. James Medical Complex, Port of Spain, TTO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dietary services</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">occupational medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oncology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychiatry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">return-to-work</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41473655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12746529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.98069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mental health at work: WHO guidelines. Malik A, Ayuso-Mateos JL, Baranyi G, Barbui C, Thornicroft G, van Ommeren M, Akhtar A. World Psychiatry. 2023;22:331&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10168149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37159361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Workplace mental health screening: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Strudwick J, Gayed A, Deady M, et al. Occup Environ Med. 2023;80:469&#x2013;484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10423530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37321849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of exposure to long working hours on depression: a systematic review and meta-analysis from the WHO/ILO joint estimates of the work-related burden of disease and injury. Rugulies R, S&#xf8;rensen K, Di Tecco C, et al. Environ Int. 2021;155:106629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34144478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interventions to improve return to work in depressed people. Nieuwenhuijsen K, Verbeek JH, Neumeyer-Gromen A, Verhoeven AC, B&#xfc;ltmann U, Faber B. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2020;10:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8094165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33052607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Universal, selective and indicated interventions for supporting mental health at the workplace: an umbrella review of meta-analyses. Miguel C, Amarnath A, Akhtar A, et al. Occup Environ Med. 2023;80:225&#x2013;236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10086469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36828633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatigue and its management in the workplace. Caldwell JA, Caldwell JL, Thompson LA, Lieberman HR. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2019;96:272&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30391406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sleep and productivity benefits of digital cognitive behavioral therapy for insomnia: a randomized controlled trial conducted in the workplace environment. Bostock S, Luik AI, Espie CA. J Occup Environ Med. 2016;58:683&#x2013;689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27257747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A randomized controlled intervention of workplace-based group cognitive behavioral therapy for insomnia. Schiller H, S&#xf6;derstr&#xf6;m M, Lekander M, Rajaleid K, Kecklund G. Int Arch Occup Environ Health. 2018;91:413&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5908834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29387936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of cognitive behavioral therapy for insomnia in workers: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Takano Y, Ibata R, Machida N, Ubara A, Okajima I. Sleep Med Rev. 2023;71:101839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37657127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Occupational injuries and use of benzodiazepines: a systematic review and metanalysis. Garbarino S, Lanteri P, Bragazzi NL, Gualerzi G, Ricc&#xf2; M. Front Hum Neurosci. 2021;15:629719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8155305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34054447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Addressing attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder in the workplace. Sarkis E. Postgrad Med. 2014;126:25&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25295647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Occupational issues of adults with ADHD. Adamou M, Arif M, Asherson P, et al. BMC Psychiatry. 2013;13:59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3599848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23414364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guiding principles for determining work shift duration and addressing the effects of work shift duration on performance, safety, and health: guidance from the American Academy of Sleep Medicine and the Sleep Research Society. Gurubhagavatula I, Barger LK, Barnes CM, et al. J Clin Sleep Med. 2021;17:2283&#x2013;2306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8636361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34666885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Work-related fatigue: a hazard for workers experiencing disproportionate occupational risks. Cunningham TR, Guerin RJ, Ferguson J, Cavallari J. Am J Ind Med. 2022;65:913&#x2013;925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9325913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35088430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shift work and diabetes mellitus: a meta-analysis of observational studies. Gan Y, Yang C, Tong X, et al. Occup Environ Med. 2015;72:72&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25030030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association between night shift work and the risk of type 2 diabetes mellitus: a cohort-based meta-analysis. Xie F, Hu K, Fu R, Zhang Y, Xiao K, Tu J. BMC Endocr Disord. 2024;24:268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11653577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39696306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Night shift work, genetic risk, and type 2 diabetes in the UK Biobank. Vetter C, Dashti HS, Lane JM, et al. Diabetes Care. 2018;41:762&#x2013;769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5860836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29440150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Automated behavioral workplace intervention to prevent weight gain and improve diet: the choosewell 365 randomized clinical trial. Thorndike AN, McCurley JL, Gelsomin ED, et al. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8185595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34097048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Interventions to promote healthy meals in full-service restaurants and canteens: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Mandracchia F, Tarro L, Llaurad&#xf3; E, Valls RM, Sol&#xe0; R. Nutrients. 2021;13:1350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8073122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33919552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effectiveness of nutrition and health intervention in workplace setting: a systematic review. Rachmah Q, Martiana T, Mulyono M, et al. J Public Health Res. 2021;11:2312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8859724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34781627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of heat and a rest-shade-hydration intervention program on productivity of piece-paid industrial agricultural workers at risk of chronic kidney disease of nontraditional origin. Hansson E, Jakobsson K, Glaser J, et al. Ann Work Expo Health. 2024;68:366&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11033565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38367206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Occupational heat stress: multi-country observations and interventions. Ioannou LG, Mantzios K, Tsoutsoubi L, et al. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:6303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8296111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34200783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sustainable solutions to mitigate occupational heat strain - an umbrella review of physiological effects and global health perspectives. Morris NB, Jay O, Flouris AD, et al. Environ Health. 2020;19:95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7487490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32887627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Occupational heat exposure and the risk of chronic kidney disease of nontraditional origin in the United States. Chapman CL, Hess HW, Lucas RA, et al. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2021;321:0&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8409908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34161738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Occupational heat stress management: does one size fit all? Notley SR, Flouris AD, Kenny GP. Am J Ind Med. 2019;62:1017&#x2013;1023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30791115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Return to work after a cancer diagnosis: a meta-review of reviews and a meta-synthesis of recent qualitative studies. Butow P, Laidsaar-Powell R, Konings S, Lim CY, Koczwara B. J Cancer Surviv. 2020;14:114&#x2013;134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31858379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Return to work in cancer patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Tavan H, Azadi A, Veisani Y. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30820118/ Indian J Palliat Care. 2019;25:147&#x2013;152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6388592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30820118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chemotherapy-induced peripheral neuropathy: a current review. Staff NP, Grisold A, Grisold W, Windebank AJ. Ann Neurol. 2017;81:772&#x2013;781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5656281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28486769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neurological outcomes of chemotherapy-induced peripheral neuropathy in patients with cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Suzuki K, Morishita S, Nakano J, Okayama T, Inoue J, Tanaka T, Fukushima T. Integr Cancer Ther. 2023;22:15347354231185110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10571681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37822238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chemotherapy-induced peripheral neuropathy (CIPN): a narrative review and proposed theoretical model. Lee KT, Bulls HW, Hoogland AI, James BW, Colon-Echevarria CB, Jim HS. Cancers (Basel) 2024;16:2571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11274737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39061210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Identifying trajectories and predictors of chemotherapy-induced peripheral neuropathy symptoms, physical functioning, and falls across treatment and recovery in adults treated with neurotoxic chemotherapy: the PATTERN observational study protocol (NCT05790538) Winters-Stone KM, Krasnow SM, Horak FB, et al. BMC Cancer. 2023;23:1087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10636878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37946117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weight lifting in women with breast-cancer-related lymphedema. Schmitz KH, Ahmed RL, Troxel A, et al. N Engl J Med. 2009;361:664&#x2013;673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19675330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weight lifting for women at risk for breast cancer-related lymphedema: a randomized trial. Schmitz KH, Ahmed RL, Troxel AB, et al. JAMA. 2010;304:2699&#x2013;2705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21148134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Worse and worse off: the impact of lymphedema on work and career after breast cancer. Boyages J, Kalfa S, Xu Y, et al. Springerplus. 2016;5:657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4870504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27330922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outpatient management of fever and neutropenia in adults treated for malignancy: American Society of Clinical Oncology and Infectious Diseases Society of America clinical practice guideline update. Taplitz RA, Kennedy EB, Bow EJ, et al. J Clin Oncol. 2018;36:1443&#x2013;1453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29461916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outpatient management of fever and neutropenia in adults treated for malignancy: American Society of Clinical Oncology and Infectious Diseases Society of America clinical practice guideline update summary. Taplitz RA, Kennedy EB, Flowers CR. J Oncol Pract. 2018;14:250&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29517953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambulatory management of low-risk febrile neutropenia in adult oncological patients. Systematic review. Forcano-Queralt E, Lemes-Quintana C, Orozco-Beltr&#xe1;n D. Support Care Cancer. 2023;31:665.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10624743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37921996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The prognostic value of the work ability index for sickness absence among office workers. Reeuwijk KG, Robroek SJ, Niessen MA, Kraaijenhagen RA, Vergouwe Y, Burdorf A. PLoS One. 2015;10:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4446207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26017387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Validity of the work productivity and activity impairment questionnaire - general health version in patients with rheumatoid arthritis. Zhang W, Bansback N, Boonen A, Young A, Singh A, Anis AH. Arthritis Res Ther. 2010;12:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2991008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20860837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Work ability score and future work ability as predictors of register-based disability pension and long-term sickness absence: a three-year follow-up study. Kinnunen U, N&#xe4;tti J. Scand J Public Health. 2018;46:321&#x2013;330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29212430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Predictive validity of the work ability index and its individual items in the general population. Lundin A, Leijon O, Vaez M, Hallgren M, Torg&#xe9;n M. Scand J Public Health. 2017;45:350&#x2013;356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28385066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Telephone screening, outreach, and care management for depressed workers and impact on clinical and work productivity outcomes: a randomized controlled trial. Wang PS, Simon GE, Avorn J, et al. JAMA. 2007;298:1401&#x2013;1411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2859667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17895456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Work-focused cognitive-behavioural therapy and individual job support to increase work participation in common mental disorders: a randomised controlled multicentre trial. Reme SE, Grasdal AL, L&#xf8;vvik C, Lie SA, &#xd8;verland S. Occup Environ Med. 2015;72:745&#x2013;752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4602235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26251065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A randomized, placebo-controlled trial of online cognitive behavioral therapy for chronic insomnia disorder delivered via an automated media-rich web application. Espie CA, Kyle SD, Williams C, Ong JC, Douglas NJ, Hames P, Brown JS. Sleep. 2012;35:769&#x2013;781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3353040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22654196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Managing fatigue: it's about sleep. Dawson D, McCulloch K. Sleep Med Rev. 2005;9:365&#x2013;380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16099184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedative hypnotic medication use and the risk of motor vehicle crash. Hansen RN, Boudreau DM, Ebel BE, Grossman DC, Sullivan SD. Am J Public Health. 2015;105:0&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4504291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26066943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Who benefits from individual placement and support? A meta-analysis. de Winter L, Couwenbergh C, van Weeghel J, Sanches S, Michon H, Bond GR. Epidemiol Psychiatr Sci. 2022;31:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9281491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35815640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The work limitations questionnaire. Lerner D, Amick BC 3rd, Rogers WH, Malspeis S, Bungay K, Cynn D. Med Care. 2001;39:72&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11176545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The work role functioning questionnaire 2.0 (Dutch version): examination of its reliability, validity and responsiveness in the general working population. Abma FI, van der Klink JJ, B&#xfc;ltmann U. J Occup Rehabil. 2013;23:135&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22869455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Validation of the work role functioning questionnaire 2.0 in cancer patients. Dorland HF, Abma FI, Roelen CA, B&#xfc;ltmann U, Amick BC 3rd. Eur J Cancer Care (Engl) 2021;30:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8365733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33538368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adverse metabolic and cardiovascular consequences of circadian misalignment. Scheer FA, Hilton MF, Mantzoros CS, Shea SA. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2009;106:4453&#x2013;4458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2657421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19255424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of circadian misalignment on energy metabolism during simulated nightshift work. McHill AW, Melanson EL, Higgins J, Connick E, Moehlman TM, Stothard ER, Wright KP Jr. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2014;111:17302&#x2013;17307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4260578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25404342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calories purchased by hospital employees after implementation of a cafeteria traffic light-labeling and choice architecture program. Thorndike AN, Gelsomin ED, McCurley JL, Levy DE. JAMA Netw Open. 2019;2:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6624805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31290988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of calorie labelling in worksite cafeterias: a stepped wedge randomised controlled pilot trial. Vasiljevic M, Cartwright E, Pilling M, et al. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2018;15:41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5950179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29754587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Influence of fasting during the night shift on next day eating behavior, hunger, and glucose and insulin levels: a randomized, three-condition, crossover trial. Teixeira BS, Silva CM, Silva AT, et al. Eur J Nutr. 2023;62:1281&#x2013;1293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36526739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fasting as an intervention to alter the impact of simulated night-shift work on glucose metabolism in healthy adults: a cluster randomised controlled trial. Centofanti S, Heilbronn LK, Wittert G, et al. Diabetologia. 2025;68:203&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11663163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39422718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A rest-shade-hydration-hygiene program reduces acute kidney injury and increases production at a sugar mill in Nicaragua, an economic analysis [PREPRINT] Schlader ZJ, Boswell T, Prince H, et al. medRxiv. 2025;0:0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of heat mitigation strategies on thermoregulation and productivity during simulated occupational work in the heat in physically active young men. Morrissey-Basler MC, Brewer GJ, Anderson T, et al. Front Sports Act Living. 2024;5:1274141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10808760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38274034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Multinational Association for Supportive Care in Cancer risk index: a multinational scoring system for identifying low-risk febrile neutropenic cancer patients. Klastersky J, Paesmans M, Rubenstein EB, et al. J Clin Oncol. 2000;18:3038&#x2013;3051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10944139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Febrile neutropenia: a prospective study to validate the Multinational Association of Supportive Care of Cancer (MASCC) risk-index score. Uys A, Rapoport BL, Anderson R. Support Care Cancer. 2004;12:555&#x2013;560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15197637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Accuracy of the Multinational Association of Supportive Care in Cancer (MASCC) and clinical index of stable febrile neutropenia (CISNE) scores for predicting serious complications in adult patients with febrile neutropenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Zheng B, Toarta C, Cheng W, Taljaard M, Reaume N, Perry JJ. Crit Rev Oncol Hematol. 2020;149:102922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32244162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevention and management of chemotherapy-induced peripheral neuropathy in survivors of adult cancers: ASCO guideline update. Loprinzi CL, Lacchetti C, Bleeker J, et al. J Clin Oncol. 2020;38:3325&#x2013;3348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32663120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chemotherapy-induced peripheral neuropathy: where are we now? Colvin LA. Pain. 2019;160:0&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6499732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31008843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Return-to-work interventions integrated into cancer care: a systematic review. Tamminga SJ, de Boer AG, Verbeek JH, Frings-Dresen MH. Occup Environ Med. 2010;67:639&#x2013;648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20798030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effectiveness of a tailored work-related support intervention for patients diagnosed with gastrointestinal cancer: a multicenter randomized controlled trial. Zaman AC, Tytgat KM, Klinkenbijl JH, et al. J Occup Rehabil. 2021;31:323&#x2013;338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8172517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32880094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>