<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38967358</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Utility of Body Weight, Urine Color, and Thirst Perception (WUT) in Determining Hydration in Young Adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2404</StartPage><EndPage>2412</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2404-2412</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003514</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The primary aim of this study was to assess the efficacy of the weight, urine, and thirst (WUT) framework in predicting dehydration after a body water manipulation protocol, while concurrently determining the individual and interactive contributions of the model components.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The total study sample was 93 participants (female, n = 47), recruited from two institutions. Phase 1 involved collecting daily hydration measures from free-living participants (study 1, 58 participants for 3 d; study 2, 35 participants for 7 d). Phase 2 entailed a 2-h passive heating protocol, where participants from study 2 were randomly assigned to one of three groups that manipulated total body water over 24 h using passive heating and fluid restriction. During each phase, participants provided urine samples, underwent body mass measurements, and completed questionnaires pertaining to thirst perception. Morning and 24-h urine samples were assessed for color, osmolality, and specific gravity. Differences between intervention groups, based on the probability of hydration status, were examined (ANOVA), and ridge regression analysis assessed the relative importance of variables within the WUT model.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The study revealed significant differences among the intervention groups for predicted probability of dehydration, as determined by changes in body mass ( P = 0.001), urine color ( P = 0.044), and thirst perception ( P &lt; 0.001). Binomial ridge regression indicated that changes in body mass (58%) and thirst perception (26%) were the most influential predictors of dehydration.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These data support use of an enhanced version of the WUT model, underscoring the significance of changes in body mass and thirst perception in the assessment of hydration status.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adams</LastName><ForeName>William M</ForeName><Initials>WM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anderson</LastName><ForeName>Travis</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zaplatosch</LastName><ForeName>Mitchell E</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheuvront</LastName><ForeName>Samuel N</ForeName><Initials>SN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Science Synergy, LLC, Franklin, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kenefick</LastName><ForeName>Robert W</ForeName><Initials>RW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Entrinsic Bioscience, Norwood, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yates</LastName><ForeName>Brandon A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morrissey-Basler</LastName><ForeName>Margaret C</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Casa</LastName><ForeName>Douglas J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wideman</LastName><ForeName>Laurie</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, University of North Carolina at Greensboro, Greensboro, NC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013894" MajorTopicYN="Y">Thirst</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003681" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dehydration</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000652" MajorTopicYN="N">urine</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001835" MajorTopicYN="Y">Body Weight</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014556" MajorTopicYN="N">Urine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003116" MajorTopicYN="N">Color</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000074267" MajorTopicYN="N">Organism Hydration Status</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001834" MajorTopicYN="N">Body Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013046" MajorTopicYN="N">Specific Gravity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010465" MajorTopicYN="N">Perception</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009994" MajorTopicYN="N">Osmolar Concentration</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38967358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000003514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202412000-00016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cheuvront SN, Kenefick RW. Dehydration: physiology, assessment, and performance effects. Compr Physiol . 2011;4(1):257&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheuvront SN, Sawka MN. Hydration assessment of athletes. Sports Sci Exch . 2005;18(2):1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong LE, Maresh CM, Castellani JW, et al. Urinary indices of hydration status. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 1994;4(3):265&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes F, Mythen M, Montgomery H. The sensitivity of the human thirst response to changes in plasma osmolality: a systematic review. Perioper Med (Lond) . 2018;7:1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekiguchi Y, Benjamin CL, Butler CR, et al. Relationships between WUT (body weight, urine color, and thirst level) criteria and urine indices of hydration status. Sports Health . 2022;14(4):566&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keefe MS, Luk HY, Rolloque JS, Jiwan NC, McCollum TB, Sekiguchi Y. The weight, urine colour and thirst Venn diagram is an accurate tool compared with urinary and blood markers for hydration assessment at morning and afternoon timepoints in euhydrated and free-living individuals. Br J Nutr . 2024;131(7):1181&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wardenaar FC, Whitenack L, Vento KA, Seltzer RGN, Siegler J, Kavouras SA. Validity of combined hydration self-assessment measurements to estimate a low vs. High urine concentration in a small sample of (tactical) athletes. Eur J Nutr . 2024;63(1):185&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stachenfeld NS. Sex hormone effects on body fluid regulation. Exerc Sport Sci Rev . 2008;36(3):152&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson AS, Pollock ML. Generalized equations for predicting body density of men. Br J Nutr . 1978;40(3):497&#x2013;504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson AS, Pollock ML, Ward A. Generalized equations for predicting body density of women. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 1980;12(3):175&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siri WE. Body composition from fluid spaces and density: analysis of methods. 1961. Nutrition . 1993;9(5):480&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engell DB, Maller O, Sawka MN, Francesconi RN, Drolet L, Young AJ. Thirst and fluid intake following graded hypohydration levels in humans. Physiol Behav . 1987;40(2):229&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenzie AL, Mu&#xf1;oz CX, Armstrong LE. Accuracy of urine color to detect equal to or greater than 2% body mass loss in men. J Athl Train . 2015;50(12):1306&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panel E, Nda A. Scientific opinion on dietary reference values for water. EFSA J . 2010;8(3):1459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheuvront SN, Fraser CG, Kenefick RW, Ely BR, Sawka MN. Reference change values for monitoring dehydration. Clin Chem Lab Med . 2011;49(6):1033&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheuvront SN, Ely BR, Kenefick RW, Sawka MN. Biological variation and diagnostic accuracy of dehydration assessment markers. Am J Clin Nutr . 2010;92(3):565&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoerl AE, Kennard RW. Ridge regression: biased estimation for nonorthogonal problems. Dent Tech . 2000;42(1):80&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman J, Hastie T, Tibshirani R, et al. Package &#x201c;glmnet&#x201d;. 2021; Available from: CRAN R Repository.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shore AC, Markandu ND, Sagnella GA, et al. Endocrine and renal response to water loading and water restriction in normal man. Clin Sci (Lond) . 1988;75(2):171&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheuvront SN, Carter R, Montain SJ, Sawka MN. Daily body mass variability and stability in active men undergoing exercise-heat stress. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 2004;14(5):532&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widjaja A, Morris RJ, Levy JC, Frayn KN, Manley SE, Turner RC. Within- and between-subject variation in commonly measured anthropometric and biochemical variables. Clin Chem . 1999;45(4):561&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epstein FH, Kleeman CR, Hendrikx A. The influence of bodily hydration on the renal concentrating process. J Clin Invest . 1957;36(5):629&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamel KS, Ethier JH, Richardson RM, Bear RA, Halperin ML. Urine electrolytes and osmolality: when and how to use them. Am J Nephrol . 1990;10(2):89&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoker AS. Application of the clearance concept to hyponatremic and hypernatremic disorders: a phenomenological analysis. Clin Chem . 1994;40(7 Pt 1):1220&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirreffs SM, Merson SJ, Fraser SM, Archer DT. The effects of fluid restriction on hydration status and subjective feelings in man. Br J Nutr . 2004;91(6):951&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis LA, Yates BA, McKenzie AL, Mu&#xf1;oz CX, Casa DJ, Armstrong LE. Effects of three oral nutritional supplements on human hydration indices. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab . 2016;26(4):356&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenefick RW, Heavens KR, Dennis WE, et al. Quantification of chromatographic effects of vitamin B supplementation in urine and implications for hydration assessment. J Appl Physiol (1985) . 2015;119(2):110&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong LE, Ganio MS, Klau JF, Johnson EC, Casa DJ, Maresh CM. Novel hydration assessment techniques employing thirst and a water intake challenge in healthy men. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab . 2014;39(2):138&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams WM, Vandermark LW, Belval LN, Casa DJ. The utility of thirst as a measure of hydration status following exercise-induced dehydration. Nutrients . 2019;11(11):2689.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenleaf JE. Problem: thirst, drinking behavior, and involuntary dehydration. Med Sci Sports Exerc . 1992;24(6):645&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreoli TE, Reeves WB, Bichet DG. Endocrine control of water balance. In: Fray JCS, Goodman HM, editors. Handbook of Physiology&#x2014;Endocrine Regulation of Water and Electrolyte Balance . New York: Oxford University Press; 2000. pp. 530&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraser CG, Cummings ST, Wilkinson SP, et al. Biological variability of 26 clinical chemistry analytes in elderly people. Clin Chem . 1989;35(5):783&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ric&#xf3;s C, Iglesias N, Garc&#xed;a-Lario JV, et al. Within-subject biological variation in disease: collated data and clinical consequences. Ann Clin Biochem . 2007;44(Pt 4):343&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips PA, Rolls BJ, Ledingham JG, et al. Reduced thirst after water deprivation in healthy elderly men. N Engl J Med . 1984;311(12):753&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>