<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40141514</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Microencapsulated Temperature Rise Inhibitor on the Temperature Rise of Medium-Sized Concrete.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1230</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma18061230</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study investigates the effect of microencapsulated temperature rise inhibitors (TRIs) on the hydration temperature evolution and crack resistance of medium-sized concrete structures. Unlike mass concrete, medium-sized concrete elements such as beams, slabs, and columns pose unique challenges in temperature control due to their moderate volume, limited heat dissipation, and susceptibility to thermal stress-induced cracking. To address this issue, concrete mixtures with TRI dosages of 0%, 0.05%, 0.1%, and 0.15% were evaluated using a sealed foam box method, allowing for precise monitoring of hydration temperature development under insulated conditions. The results indicate that TRIs effectively suppress peak hydration temperature and delays its occurrence, with higher TRI dosages leading to more pronounced effects. X-ray diffraction (XRD) and scanning electron microscopy (SEM) analyses confirm that the hydration suppression is attributed to a controlled-release mechanism, where TRIs gradually dissolve, forming a hydration barrier on cement particles. This slows down calcium hydroxide (CH) crystallization, alters C-S-H gel evolution, and reduces early age heat accumulation, mitigating thermal cracking risks. Furthermore, mechanical property tests reveal that, while early age compressive and tensile strength decrease with TRI addition, long-term strength recovery is achieved at optimum TRI dosages. This study identifies 0.1% TRI as the most effective dosage, striking a balance between hydration heat reduction and long-term mechanical performance. These findings provide a scientific basis for optimizing TRI dosages in medium-sized concrete applications, offering a practical solution for thermal cracking prevention.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yingda</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6152-8349</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Transportation Tunnel Engineering, Ministry of Education, School of Civil Engineering, Southwest Jiaotong University, Chengdu 610031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Architecture and Civil Engineering, Xihua University, Chengdu 610039, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jinhua Xinsheng Zeolite Development Co., Ltd., Jinhua 321000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Junru</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Transportation Tunnel Engineering, Ministry of Education, School of Civil Engineering, Southwest Jiaotong University, Chengdu 610031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jinhua Xinsheng Zeolite Development Co., Ltd., Jinhua 321000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Zhijian</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Transportation Tunnel Engineering, Ministry of Education, School of Civil Engineering, Southwest Jiaotong University, Chengdu 610031, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Xinyue</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Architecture and Civil Engineering, Xihua University, Chengdu 610039, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Haojie</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Architecture and Civil Engineering, Xihua University, Chengdu 610039, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023-1-128</GrantID><Agency>Jinhua Key Science and Technology Plan Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>Z231001 and ZH20240062</GrantID><Agency>Xihua University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SEM</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">XRD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydration temperature</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medium-sized concrete</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microencapsulated TRI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">optimal dosage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thermal cracking</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Authors Yingda Zhang and Jun Chen were employed by Jinhua Xinsheng Zeolite Development Co., Ltd. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40141514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11943680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma18061230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma18061230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Huang M., Nini&#x107; J., Zhang Q. BIM, machine learning and computer vision techniques in underground construction: Current status and future perspectives. Tunn. Undergr. Space Technol. 2021;108:103677. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2020.103677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2020.103677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik M., Bhattacharyya S., Barai S. Thermal and mechanical properties of concrete and its constituents at elevated temperatures: A review. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;270:121398. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhamad A., Yehia S., Lubl&#xf3;y &#xc9;., Elchalakani M. Performance of different concrete types exposed to elevated temperatures: A review. Materials. 2022;15:5032. doi: 10.3390/ma15145032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15145032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9324992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35888499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu Z., Zhang Y., Liu Z., Si R., Wu J. A review on early-age cracking of concrete: Causes and control. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2024;21:e03848. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2024.e03848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2024.e03848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen L., Monte F., Di Luzio G., Cusatis G., Li W., Felicetti R., Lombardi F., Lualdi M., Cao M., Ren Q. On the moisture migration of concrete subject to high temperature with different heating rates. Cem. Concr. Res. 2021;146:106492. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2021.106492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2021.106492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C., Chen S. Study on Temperature Control and Cracking Risk of Mass Concrete Sidewalls with a Cooling-Pipe System. Buildings. 2024;14:872. doi: 10.3390/buildings14040872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings14040872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu S., Liu J., Peng C., Zhang J., Sun H. Multi-objective optimization of mix proportions for mass concrete with enhanced resistance to cracking and reduced temperature rise. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2024;20:e02810. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Kim T., Castel A., Xu T. Thermal cracking in high volume of fly ash and GGBFS concrete. Int. J. Concr. Struct. Mater. 2023;17:65. doi: 10.1186/s40069-023-00626-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40069-023-00626-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Springenschmid R. Prevention of Thermal Cracking in Concrete at Early Ages. CRC Press; London, UK: 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Maio U., Gaetano D., Greco F., Luciano R., Pranno A. Degradation analysis of dynamic properties for plain concrete structures under mixed-mode fracture conditions via an improved cohesive crack approach. Fract. Struct. Integr. 2024;18:422&#x2013;439. doi: 10.3221/IGF-ESIS.68.28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3221/IGF-ESIS.68.28</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Miao Y., Li Y., Wang F., Mu S., Wang L., Gao S., Lu Z., Liu Z., Jiang J. Investigation of the damage self-healing and chloride-water coupled transport inhibition mechanism of microencapsulated concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;435:136838. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin J., Zhang G., Liu Y., Wang Z., Yang N., Wang Y., Mou R., Qiao Y., Wang J., Wu Z. Environmental impact and thermal cracking resistance of low heat cement (LHC) and moderate heat cement (MHC) concrete at early ages. J. Build. Eng. 2020;32:101668. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Liu X., Xu Z., Yuan W., Xu Y., Yao Z., Liu Z., Si R. Early-Age Cracking of Fly Ash and GGBFS Concrete Due to Shrinkage, Creep, and Thermal Effects: A Review. Materials. 2024;17:2288. doi: 10.3390/ma17102288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17102288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11123166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38793355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tasri A., Susilawati A. Effect of cooling water temperature and space between cooling pipes of post-cooling system on temperature and thermal stress in mass concrete. J. Build. Eng. 2019;24:100731. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2019.100731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2019.100731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghav M., Park T., Yang H., Lee S., Karthick S., Lee H. Review of the effects of supplementary cementitious materials and chemical additives on the physical, mechanical and durability properties of hydraulic concrete. Materials. 2021;14:7270. doi: 10.3390/ma14237270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma14237270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8672277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34885424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Y., Scrivener K., Yu C., Ouzia A., Liu J. Effect of a novel starch-based temperature rise inhibitor on cement hydration and microstructure development: The second peak study. Cem. Concr. Res. 2021;141:106325. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2020.106325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2020.106325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Ju S., Chu H., Liu Z., Yang Z., Wang F., Jiang J. Hydration process and microstructure evolution of low exothermic concrete produced with urea. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;248:118640. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song H., Yum W., Sim S., Jeon D., Yoon S., Oh J. Proposed specific heat capacity model for a concrete wall containing phase change material (PCM) under field experiment conditions. Constr. Build. Mater. 2022;336:127381. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.127381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.127381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mello L., dos Anjos M., de S&#xe1; M., de Souza N., de Farias E. Effect of high temperatures on self-compacting concrete with high levels of sugarcane bagasse ash and metakaolin. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;248:118715. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia F., Yao Y., Wang J. Influence and mechanism research of hydration heat inhibitor on low-heat portland cement. Front. Mater. 2021;8:697380. doi: 10.3389/fmats.2021.697380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmats.2021.697380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang X., Sun L., Sun F., Zhang G., Guo S., Bu Y. Cement hydration kinetics study in the temperature range from 15 C to 95 C. Cem. Concr. Res. 2021;148:106552. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2021.106552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2021.106552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linderoth O., Wads&#xf6; L., Jansen D. Long-term cement hydration studies with isothermal calorimetry. Cem. Concr. Res. 2021;141:106344. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2020.106344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2020.106344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Matos P., Neto J., Jansen D., Angeles G., Kirchheim A., Campos C. In-situ laboratory X-ray diffraction applied to assess cement hydration. Cem. Concr. Res. 2022;162:106988. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2022.106988.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2022.106988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hydration-Inhibiting and Anti-Cracking Water-Repellent Admixtures for Concrete. China Association for Engineering Construction Standardization; Suzhou, China: 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Common Portland Cement. China Standard Press; Beijing, China: 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fly Ash Used for Cement and Concrete. China Standard Press; Beijing, China: 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sand for Construction. China Building Materials Federation; Beijing, China: 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pebble and Crushed Stone for Construction. China Building Materials Federation; Beijing, China: 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia F., Yao Y., Li C. Preparation and Mechanism Research of Hydration-heat-inhibiting Materials with Microcapsule Sustained-releasing Technology. J. Wuhan Univ. Technol.-Mater. Sci. Ed. 2021;36:697&#x2013;705. doi: 10.1007/s11595-021-2462-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11595-021-2462-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Code for Design of Concrete Structures. China Architecture &amp; Building Press; Beijing, China: 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z., Scherer G., Bauer A. Morphology of cementitious material during early hydration. Cem. Concr. Res. 2018;107:85&#x2013;100. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2018.02.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2018.02.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esteves L. On the hydration of water-entrained cement&#x2013;silica systems: Combined SEM, XRD and thermal analysis in cement pastes. Thermochim. Acta. 2011;518:27&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1016/j.tca.2011.02.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tca.2011.02.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giro-Paloma J., Mart&#xed;nez M., Cabeza L., Fern&#xe1;ndez A. Types, methods, techniques, and applications for microencapsulated phase change materials (MPCM): A review. Renew. Sustain. Energy Rev. 2016;53:1059&#x2013;1075. doi: 10.1016/j.rser.2015.09.040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rser.2015.09.040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makul N., Sua-iam G. Effect of granular urea on the properties of self-consolidating concrete incorporating untreated rice husk ash: Flowability, compressive strength and temperature rise. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;162:489&#x2013;502. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.12.023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.12.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Shen X., Yang M., Zhang Y., Liu Z., Jiang J. Design and synthesis of sustained-release microcapsules and their impact on the regulation of cement hydration. Constr. Build. Mater. 2025;459:139686. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.139686.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.139686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Y., Wang R., Liu J., Tang J., Scrivener K. Effect of a liquid-type temperature rise inhibitor on cement hydration. Cem. Concr. Res. 2021;140:106286. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2020.106286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2020.106286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safiuddin M., Kaish A., Woon C., Raman S. Early-age cracking in concrete: Causes, consequences, remedial measures, and recommendations. Appl. Sci. 2018;8:1730. doi: 10.3390/app8101730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app8101730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira A., Oliveira A., Vieira J., Junior A., Cascudo O. Study of the development of hydration of ternary cement pastes using X-ray computed microtomography, XRD-Rietveld method, TG/DTG, DSC, calorimetry and FTIR techniques. J. Build. Eng. 2023;64:105616. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2022.105616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.105616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>