<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38793244</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Design of a Novel Alkali-Activated Binder for Solidifying Silty Soft Clay and the Study of Its Solidification Mechanism.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2177</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma17102177</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In order to overcome the problems of the high economic and environmental costs of a traditional ordinary portland cement-based binder, this study used self-combusted coal gangue (SCCG), granulated blast furnace slag (GBFS) and phosphorous slag (PS) to prepare a novel SCCG-GBFS-PS (SGP) ternary alkali-activated binder for solidifying silty soft clay (SC). Firstly, the parameters of the SGP ternary binder were optimized using orthogonal experiments. Then the effects of the SGP ternary binder content (mass ratio of the SGP ternary binder and the SGP-solidified soil), initial water content of SC (mass ratio of SC' water and SC) and types of additives on the unconfined compressive strength (UCS) of the SGP-solidified soil were analyzed. Finally, the hydration products and microstructure of the SGP-solidified soil were analyzed to investigate the solidification mechanism of the SGP ternary binder. The results showed that the optimal mass ratio of GBFS and PS is 2:1, and the optimal alkali activator content (mass ratio of Na<sub>2</sub>O and the SGP ternary binder) and modulus of alkali activator (molar ratio of SiO<sub>2</sub> and Na<sub>2</sub>O of alkali activator) were 13% and 1.3, respectively. When the SGP ternary binder content was 16% and the initial water content of SC was 35%, the SGP-solidified soil met the requirement of UCS for tertiary cured soil. The incorporation of triethanolamine and polyvinyl alcohol improved the UCS, while the incorporation of Na<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub> significantly deteriorated the UCS of the SGP-solidified soil. The C-S-H gels and C(N)-A-S-H gels generated by hydration of the SGP-solidified soil were interspersed, interwoven and adhered to each other to form a network-like space structure that played the roles of skeleton, bonding soil particles and filling pores, which improved the macroscopic properties of the SGP-solidified soil. The results of this study provide a reference for the design and development of a solid waste-based binder for solidifying SC.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jing</LastName><ForeName>Yaohui</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Jilin University of Architecture and Technology, Changchun 130114, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yannian</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7772-0063</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Jilin University of Architecture and Technology, Changchun 130114, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Dalian Jiaotong University, Dalian 116028, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Dalian Jiaotong University, Dalian 116028, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Qingjie</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Shenyang Jianzhu University, Shenyang 110168, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>JJKH20241496KJ</GrantID><Agency>Scientific research project of Education Department of Jilin Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52234004</GrantID><Agency>Key Project of National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>23-407-3-02</GrantID><Agency>Shenyang Science and Technology Plan Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">additives</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">alkali-activated binder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">silty soft clay</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">solidification mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">unconfined compressive strength</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest. The funder was not involved in the study design, collection, analysis, interpretation of data, the writing of this article or the decision to submit it for publication.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38793244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11122948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17102177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma17102177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang A., Dong W., Zhan Q., Zhou J. Study on Long Term Property of Soft Soil Solidified with Industrial Waste Residue and Regenerated Fine Aggregate. Materials. 2023;16:2447. doi: 10.3390/ma16062447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16062447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10057132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36984327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shang Y., Cui Z., Zhang Y. Experimental Study on the Synergistic Solidification of Soft Soil with Ceramic Powder&#x2013;Slag&#x2013;Phosphorus Slag. Sustainability. 2023;15:15474. doi: 10.3390/su152115474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su152115474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong W., Zhan Q., Zhao X., Wang A., Zhang Y. Study on the solidification property and mechanism of soft soil based on the industrial waste residue. Rev. Adv. Mater. Sci. 2023;62:20220303. doi: 10.1515/rams-2022-0303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/rams-2022-0303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammadi E.L., Najafi E.K., Ranjbar P.Z., Payan M., Chenari R.J., Fatahi B. Recycling industrial alkaline solutions for soil stabilization by low-concentrated fly ash-based alkali cements. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;393:132083. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Chian S.C., Ma T., Ding J. Stabilization of dredged clays with ternary alkali-activated materials: Towards sustainable solid wastes recycling. J. Clean. Prod. 2023;426:139086. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.139086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2023.139086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A.K., Anand K. Performance appraisal of coal ash stabilized rammed earth. J. Build. Eng. 2018;18:51&#x2013;57. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2018.03.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2018.03.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezzat S.M. A critical review of microbially induced carbonate precipitation for soil stabilization: The global experiences and future prospective. Pedosphere. 2023;33:717&#x2013;730. doi: 10.1016/j.pedsph.2023.01.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pedsph.2023.01.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Z., Luo B., Zhao Y., Li X., Su Y., Huang H., Wang Q. Experimental Investigation of Unconfined Compression Strength and Microstructure Characteristics of Slag and Fly Ash-Based Geopolymer Stabilized Riverside Soft Soil. Polymers. 2022;14:307. doi: 10.3390/polym14020307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym14020307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8778108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35054713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah M.M., Shahzad H.M., Khalid U., Farooq K., Rehman Z.U. Experimental Study on Sustainable Utilization of CKD for Improvement of Collapsible Soil. Arab. J. Sci. Eng. 2023;48:5667&#x2013;5682. doi: 10.1007/s13369-022-07565-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13369-022-07565-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamza M., Farooq K., Rehman Z.U., Mujtaba H., Khalid U. Utilization of eggshell food waste to mitigate geotechnical vulnerabilities of fat clay: A micro&#x2013;macro-investigation. Environ. Earth Sci. 2023;82:247. doi: 10.1007/s12665-023-10921-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-023-10921-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou H., Wang X., Wu Y., Zhang X. Mechanical properties and micro-mechanisms of marine soft soil stabilized by different calcium content precursors based geopolymers. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;305:124722. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayub F., Khan S.A. An overview of geopolymer composites for stabilization of soft soils. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;404:133195. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prusty J.K., Pradhan B. Evaluation of durability and microstructure evolution of chloride added fly ash and fly ash-GGBS based geopolymer concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;401:132925. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sattar O., Khalid U., Rehman Z.U., Kayani W.I., Haider A. Impact of crushing shape and geopolymerization on reclaimed concrete aggregate for recycling in the flexible pavement: An enhanced circular economy solution. Road Mater. Pavement Des. 2023;2023:1&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1080/14680629.2023.2287711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14680629.2023.2287711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zerzouri M., Hamzaoui R., Ziyani L., Alehyen S. Influence of slag based pre-geopolymer powders obtained by mechanosynthesis on structure, microstructure and mechanical performance of geopolymer pastes. Constr. Build. Mater. 2022;361:129637. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y., Li C., Li H., Bai C., Wang Z., Yang T., Gu T. Microwave-thermal-assisted curing method on geopolymer preparation from Panzhihua high-titanium slag by alkali activation. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;400:132614. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang L., Chen B., Chen B. Strength evolutions of varying water content-dredged sludge stabilized with alkali-activated ground granulated blast-furnace slag. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;275:122111. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.122111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.122111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murmu A.L., Dhole N., Patel A. Stabilisation of black cotton soil for subgrade application using fly ash geopolymer. Road Mater. Pavement Des. 2018;21:867&#x2013;885. doi: 10.1080/14680629.2018.1530131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14680629.2018.1530131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M., Guo H., El-Korchi T., Zhang G., Tao M. Experimental feasibility study of geopolymer as the next-generation soil stabilizer. Constr. Build. Mater. 2013;47:1468&#x2013;1478. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2013.06.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2013.06.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miraki H., Shariatmadari N., Ghadir P., Jahandari S., Tao Z., Siddique R. Clayey soil stabilization using alkali-activated volcanic ash and slag. J. Rock Mech. Geotech. Eng. 2021;14:576&#x2013;591. doi: 10.1016/j.jrmge.2021.08.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jrmge.2021.08.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y., Han X., Sun Z., Jin P., Li K., Wang F., Gong J. Study on the Reactivity Activation of Coal Gangue for Efficient Utilization. Materials. 2023;16:6321. doi: 10.3390/ma16186321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16186321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10534527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37763598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han R., Guo X., Guan J., Yao X., Hao Y. Activation Mechanism of Coal Gangue and Its Impact on the Properties of Geopolymers: A Review. Polymers. 2022;14:3861. doi: 10.3390/polym14183861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym14183861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9504180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36146009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y., Zhang Z., Ji Y., Song L., Ma M. Experimental Research on Improving Activity of Calcinated Coal Gangue via Increasing Calcium Content. Materials. 2023;16:2705. doi: 10.3390/ma16072705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16072705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10095759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37049001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Qiao Y., Shao J., Bai C., Li H., Lu S., Zhang X., Yang K., Colombo P. Sodium-based alkali-activated foams from self-ignition coal gangue by facile microwave foaming route. Ceram. Int. 2022;48:33914&#x2013;33925. doi: 10.1016/j.ceramint.2022.07.340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceramint.2022.07.340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cong X., Lu S., Yao Y., Wang Z. Fabrication and characterization of self-ignition coal gangue autoclaved aerated concrete. Mater. Des. 2016;97:155&#x2013;162. doi: 10.1016/j.matdes.2016.02.068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2016.02.068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Deng X., Liu J., Hui D. Mechanical properties and microstructures of hypergolic and calcined coal gangue based geopolymer recycled concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;221:691&#x2013;708. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.06.048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.06.048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin L., Gao X. Properties of coal gangue-Portland cement mixture with carbonation. Fuel. 2019;245:67. doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2019.02.067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2019.02.067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J., Yu X., He X., Su Y., Zeng J., Dai F., Guan S. Effect of Ultrafine Fly Ash and Water Glass Content on the Performance of Phosphorus Slag-Based Geopolymer. Materials. 2022;15:5395. doi: 10.3390/ma15155395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15155395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9369517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35955329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Zhang N., Xiao H., Zhao J., Zhang Y., Liu X. Structural Characterization of Phosphorous Slag Regarding Occurrence State of Phosphorus in Dicalcium Silicate. Materials. 2022;15:7450. doi: 10.3390/ma15217450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15217450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9654798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36363043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia R., Wang Q., Luo T. Investigation of the relationship among the hydration, microstructure and compressive strength of alkali-activated phosphorus slag. J. Build. Eng. 2023;76:107293. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2023.107293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.107293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia R., Wang Q., Luo T. Understanding the workability of alkali-activated phosphorus slag pastes: Effects of alkali dose and silicate modulus on early-age hydration reactions. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2022;133:104649. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Yang D., Wang Q. Performance study of alkali-activated phosphate slag-granulated blast furnace slag composites: Effect of the granulated blast furnace slag content. Arch. Civ. Mech. Eng. 2023;23:181. doi: 10.1007/s43452-023-00724-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43452-023-00724-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song W., Zhu Z., Pu S., Wan Y., Huo W., Song S., Zhang J., Yao K., Hu L. Efficient use of steel slag in alkali-activated fly ash-steel slag-ground granulated blast furnace slag ternary blends. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;259:119814. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Lu M., Sheng K., Shao Z., Yao Y., Hong B. Development of new material for geopolymer lightweight cellular concrete and its cementing mechanism. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;367:130253. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.130253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.130253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Lu C., Hu X., Shi C. Effect of silica fume on rheology of slag-fly ash-silica fume-based geopolymer pastes with different activators. Cem. Concr. Res. 2023;174:107336. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2023.107336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2023.107336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Wang W., Zhang Y., Gu X. Research on hydration characteristics of OSR-GGBFS-FA alkali-activated materials. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;411:134321. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu K., Zeng G., Shu B., Luo D. Study on the Performance and Solidification Mechanism of Multi-Source Solid-Waste-Based Soft Soil Solidification Materials. Materials. 2023;16:4517. doi: 10.3390/ma16134517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16134517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10342454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37444830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard for Geotechnical Testing Methods. Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development; Beijing, China: 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y., Yang C., Li K., Qu F., Yan C., Wu Z. Toward understanding the activation and hydration mechanisms of composite activated coal gangue geopolymer. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;318:125999. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.125999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.125999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng H., Li Y.-F., Zhang C. Modeling of discharge voltage for lithium-ion batteries through orthogonal experiments at subzero environment. J. Energy Storage. 2022;52:105058. doi: 10.1016/j.est.2022.105058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.est.2022.105058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv W., Li A., Ma J., Cui H., Zhang X., Zhang W., Guo Y. Relative importance of certain factors affecting the thermal environment in subway stations based on field and orthogonal experiments. Sustain. Cities Soc. 2020;56:102107. doi: 10.1016/j.scs.2020.102107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scs.2020.102107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan J., Li L., He P., Chen Z., Lao C., Jia D., Zhou Y. Effects of kinds of alkali-activated ions on geopolymerization process of geopolymer cement pastes. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;293:123536. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed B.S., Haruna S., Wahab M., Liew M., Haruna A. Mechanical and microstructural properties of high calcium fly ash one-part geopolymer cement made with granular activator. Heliyon. 2019;5:e02255. doi: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2019.e02255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2019.e02255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6819772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31687531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phoo-Ngernkham T., Maegawa A., Mishima N., Hatanaka S., Chindaprasirt P. Effects of sodium hydroxide and sodium silicate solutions on compressive and shear bond strengths of FA&#x2013;GBFS geopolymer. Constr. Build. Mater. 2015;91:1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.05.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.05.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suksiripattanapong C., Horpibulsuk S., Yeanyong C., Arulrajah A. Evaluation of polyvinyl alcohol and high calcium fly ash based geopolymer for the improvement of soft Bangkok clay. Transp. Geotech. 2020;27:100476. doi: 10.1016/j.trgeo.2020.100476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trgeo.2020.100476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Technical Standard for Application of Soil Stabilizer. Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development; Beijing, China: 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suksiripattanapong C., Horpibulsuk S., Boongrasan S., Udomchai A., Chinkulkijniwat A., Arulrajah A. Unit weight, strength and microstructure of a water treatment sludge&#x2013;fly ash lightweight cellular geopolymer. Constr. Build. Mater. 2015;94:807&#x2013;816. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.07.091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.07.091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phetchuay C., Horpibulsuk S., Arulrajah A., Suksiripattanapong C., Udomchai A. Strength development in soft marine clay stabilized by fly ash and calcium carbide residue based geopolymer. Appl. Clay Sci. 2016;127&#x2013;128:134&#x2013;142. doi: 10.1016/j.clay.2016.04.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clay.2016.04.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Technical Regulations for Deep Mixing Reinforcement Method of Soft Soil Foundation. Metallurgical Industry Press; Beijing, China: 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y., Qian J., Jiang Y., Jia S., Xu X., Liu X.-Q., Cui P. Target-specific modification of diethylenetriamine with hydroxyalkyls: Efficient absorbents for CO2 capture. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2024;335:126075. doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2023.126075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2023.126075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park C.M., Wang D., Han J., Heo J., Su C. Evaluation of the colloidal stability and adsorption performance of reduced graphene oxide&#x2013;elemental silver/magnetite nanohybrids for selected toxic heavy metals in aqueous solutions. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2018;471:8&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2018.11.240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2018.11.240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7424532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32801406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Chen Y., Sun T., Saleem A., Wang C. Enhanced removal of Cr(III)-EDTA chelates from high-salinity water by ternary complex formation on DETA functionalized magnetic carbon-based adsorbents. Ecotoxicol. Environ. Saf. 2020;209:111858. doi: 10.1016/j.ecoenv.2020.111858.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoenv.2020.111858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33385680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun G., Tang Q., Zhang J., Liu Z. Early activation of high volume fly ash by ternary activator and its activation mechanism. J. Environ. Manag. 2020;267:110638. doi: 10.1016/j.jenvman.2020.110638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2020.110638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32421671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allahverdi A., Maleki A., Mahinroosta M. Chemical activation of slag-blended Portland cement. J. Build. Eng. 2018;18:76&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2018.03.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2018.03.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia D., Chen R., Cheng J., Tang Y., Xiao C., Li Z. Desert sand-high calcium fly ash-based alkali-activated mortar: Flowability, mechanical properties, and microscopic analysis. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;398:131729. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.131729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.131729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang H., Ren L., Gu X., Zheng J., Cui L. Synergistic effect of activator nature and curing temperature on time-dependent rheological behavior of cemented paste backfill containing alkali-activated slag. Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res. 2022;30:12857&#x2013;12871. doi: 10.1007/s11356-022-23053-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-022-23053-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36114965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., Hao X., Wei C., Liu X., Zhang Z. Activation of low-activity calcium silicate in converter steelmaking slag based on synergy of multiple solid wastes in cementitious material. Constr. Build. Mater. 2022;351:128925. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.128925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.128925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song W., Zhu Z., Peng Y., Wan Y., Xu X., Pu S., Song S., Wei Y. Effect of steel slag on fresh, hardened and microstructural properties of high-calcium fly ash based geopolymers at standard curing condition. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;229:116933. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.116933.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.116933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrera-Luna K., Perez-Cortes P., Garcia J.E. Influence of quicklime and Portland cement, as alkaline activators, on the reaction products of supersulfated cements based on pumice. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2024;146:105379. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2023.105379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2023.105379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu C., Zhang Z., Tang X., Gui Z., Liu F. Synthesis and characterization of one-part alkali-activated grouting materials based on granulated blast furnace slag, uncalcined coal gangue and microscopic fly ash sinking beads. Constr. Build. Mater. 2022;345:128254. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.128254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.128254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mujtaba H., Khalid U., Farooq K., Elahi M., Rehman Z., Shahzad H.M. Sustainable Utilization of Powdered Glass to Improve the Mechanical Behavior of Fat Clay. KSCE J. Civ. Eng. 2020;24:3628&#x2013;3639. doi: 10.1007/s12205-020-0159-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12205-020-0159-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalid U., Rehman Z.U., Ullah I., Khan K., Kayani W.I. Efficacy of geopolymerization for integrated bagasse ash and quarry dust in comparison to fly ash as an admixture: A comparative study. J. Eng. Res. 2023 doi: 10.1016/j.jer.2023.08.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jer.2023.08.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ullah I., Khalid U., Rehman Z.U., Shah M.M., Khan I., Ijaz N. Integrated recycling of geopolymerized quarry dust and bagasse ash with facemasks for the balanced amelioration of the fat clay: A multi-waste solution. Environ. Earth Sci. 2023;82:516. doi: 10.1007/s12665-023-11219-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-023-11219-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>