<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37641667</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2322-3219</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Season>Spring</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medical hypothesis, discovery &amp; innovation ophthalmology journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Med Hypothesis Discov Innov Ophthalmol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparing morphologic features and complications of main clear corneal incision between junior and senior residents observed using anterior segment optical coherence tomography.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>18</StartPage><EndPage>27</EndPage><MedlinePgn>18-27</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.51329/mehdiophthal1466</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Wound construction is a critical step in phacoemulsification. Using anterior segment optical coherence tomography (AS-OCT), we compared the morphological features and complications of main incisions made by junior or senior residents during phacoemulsification.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This cross-sectional comparative study included eyes with senile cataracts that underwent uneventful phacoemulsification with a clear corneal incision made by seven senior and eight junior ophthalmology residents. All eyes underwent postoperative image acquisition using AS-OCT on day one and at three months, examining for morphological features and potential complications of the main incision.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We included 50 eyes of 50 patients with a male-to-female ratio of 22 (44%) to 28 (56%); 26 (52%) were operated on by junior residents and 24 (48%) by seniors. The mean geometric features of the main incisions and the frequency of early and late wound complications were comparable between the two groups (all <i>P</i>&#x2005;&gt;&#x2005;0.05). A significant correlation was found between the incision length and angle with the superior (r&#x2005;=&#x2005;+ 0.80; <i>P</i>&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;0.001 and r&#x2005;=&#x2005;- 0.63; <i>P</i>&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;0.001, respectively) and inferior (r&#x2005;=&#x2005;+ 0.84; <i>P</i>&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;0.001 and r&#x2005;=&#x2005;- 0.68; <i>P</i>&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;0.001, respectively) areas of the incision, as well as between the length and angle of incision (r&#x2005;=&#x2005;- 0.74; <i>P</i>&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;0.001). The number of planes in the wound architecture was not significantly different according to senior or junior resident status (<i>P</i>&#x2005;&gt;&#x2005;0.05). Although the number of eyes with stromal hydration was significantly greater for junior residents than for seniors (<i>P</i>&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;0.001), the corneal thickness at the entrance to the cornea or the anterior chamber, presence of endothelial wound gaping, and Descemet's membrane detachment were comparable between eyes with and without stromal hydration (all <i>P</i>&#x2005;&gt;&#x2005;0.05). At three months, 29 (58%) patients returned for examination, in whom seven (24%) had late wound complications.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study found no significant differences in the performances of junior and senior residents in terms of wound construction or its associated complications. However, considering the overall rate of some observed wound-related complications, we recommended revision of the resident educational curriculum concerning the structure and complications of the main incision.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gharaee</LastName><ForeName>Hamid</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eye Research Center, Mashhad University of Medical Sciences, Mashhad, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sedaghat</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad-Reza</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eye Research Center, Mashhad University of Medical Sciences, Mashhad, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sadeghi</LastName><ForeName>Javad</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eye Research Center, Mashhad University of Medical Sciences, Mashhad, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tabesh</LastName><ForeName>Hamed</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Biostatistics Department of Medical Informatics, Mashhad University of Medical Sciences, Mashhad, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gharouni</LastName><ForeName>Ahmad</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eye Research Center, Mashhad University of Medical Sciences, Mashhad, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghasemi Moghadam</LastName><ForeName>Somayeh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eye Research Center, Mashhad University of Medical Sciences, Mashhad, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nozari</LastName><ForeName>Vahide</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eye Research Center, Mashhad University of Medical Sciences, Mashhad, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beigi</LastName><ForeName>Samira</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eye Research Center, Mashhad University of Medical Sciences, Mashhad, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Med Hypothesis Discov Innov Ophthalmol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101611331</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2322-3219</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">academic training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cataracts</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">corneas</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">optical coherence tomography</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">phacoemulsifications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postoperative complication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surgical incision</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37641667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10445308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.51329/mehdiophthal1466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pascolini D, Mariotti SP. Global estimates of visual impairment: 2010. Br J Ophthalmol. 2012;96(5):614&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22133988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee CM, Afshari NA. The global state of cataract blindness. Curr Opin Ophthalmol. 2017;28(1):98&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27820750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurnani B, Kaur K. StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2023. Phacoemulsification. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das S, Kummelil MK, Kharbanda V, Arora V, Nagappa S, Shetty R, et al. Microscope Integrated Intraoperative Spectral Domain Optical Coherence Tomography for Cataract Surgery: Uses and Applications. Curr Eye Res. 2016;41(5):643&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26237163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrens A, Stark WJ, Pratzer KA, McDonnell PJ. Dynamics of small-incision clear cornea wounds after phacoemulsification surgery using optical coherence tomography in the early postoperative period. J Refract Surg. 2008;24(1):46&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18269148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar DA, Agarwal A, Prakash G, Jacob S, Saravanan Y, Agarwal A. Evaluation of intraocular lens tilt with anterior segment optical coherence tomography. Am J Ophthalmol. 2011;151(3):406&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21236406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mastropasqua L, Toto L, De Nicola G, Nubile M, Carpineto P. OCT imaging of capsular block syndrome with crystalline cortical remnants in the capsular bag. Ophthalmic Surg Lasers Imaging. 2009;40(4):399&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19634745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SB, Cornish EE, Grigg JR, McCluskey PJ. Anterior segment optical coherence tomography and its clinical applications. Clin Exp Optom. 2019;102(3):195&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30635934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JS, Hou CH, Yang ML, Kuo JZ, Lin KK. A different approach to assess resident phacoemulsification learning curve: analysis of both completion and complication rates. Eye (Lond). 2009;23(3):683&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18239676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashemi H, Mohammadpour M, Jabbarvand M, Nezamdoost Z, Ghadimi H. Incidence of and risk factors for vitreous loss in resident-performed phacoemulsification surgery. J Cataract Refract Surg. 2013;39(9):1377&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23870438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsinopoulos IT, Lamprogiannis LP, Tsaousis KT, Mataftsi A, Symeonidis C, Chalvatzis NT, et al. Surgical outcomes in phacoemulsification after application of a risk stratification system. Clin Ophthalmol. 2013;7:895&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3663436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23717035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ergun &#x15e;B, Kocam&#x131;&#x15f; S&#x130;, &#xc7;akmak HB, &#xc7;a&#x11f;&#x131;l N. The evaluation of the risk factors for capsular complications in phacoemulsification. Int Ophthalmol. 2018;38(5):1851&#x2013;1861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28852905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien PD, Fitzpatrick P, Kilmartin DJ, Beatty S. Risk factors for endothelial cell loss after phacoemulsification surgery by a junior resident. J Cataract Refract Surg. 2004;30(4):839&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15093647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplowitz K, Yazdanie M, Abazari A. A review of teaching methods and outcomes of resident phacoemulsification. Surv Ophthalmol. 2018;63(2):257&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28941765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randleman JB, Wolfe JD, Woodward M, Lynn MJ, Cherwek DH, Srivastava SK. The resident surgeon phacoemulsification learning curve. Arch Ophthalmol. 2007;125(9):1215&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17846361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gharaee H, Jahani M, Banan S. A Comparative Assessment of Intraoperative Complication Rates in Resident-Performed Phacoemulsification Surgeries According to Najjar-Awwad Preoperative Risk Stratification. Clin Ophthalmol. 2020;14:1329&#x2013;1336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7244740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32546939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavallini GM, Verdina T, Forlini M, Volante V, De Maria M, Torlai G, et al. Long-term follow-up for bimanual microincision cataract surgery: comparison of results obtained by surgeons in training and experienced surgeons. Clin Ophthalmol. 2016;10:979&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4888734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27307701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira A, Salaroli C, Filho FR, Pinto FT, Souza N, Sousa BA, et al. Architectural analysis of clear corneal incision techniques in cataract surgery using Fourier-domain OCT. Ophthalmic Surg Lasers Imaging. 2012;43(6 Suppl):S103&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23357317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schallhorn JM, Tang M, Li Y, Song JC, Huang D. Optical coherence tomography of clear corneal incisions for cataract surgery. J Cataract Refract Surg. 2008;34(9):1561&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2556292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18721720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuda S, Kawana K, Yasuno Y, Oshika T. Wound architecture of clear corneal incision with or without stromal hydration observed with 3-dimensional optical coherence tomography. Am J Ophthalmol. 2011;151(3):413&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21236408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calladine D, Packard R. Clear corneal incision architecture in the immediate postoperative period evaluated using optical coherence tomography. J Cataract Refract Surg. 2007;33(8):1429&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17662437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres LF, Saez-Espinola F, Colina JM, Retchkiman M, Patel MR, Agurto R, et al. In vivo architectural analysis of 3 2 mm clear corneal incisions for phacoemulsification using optical coherence tomography. J Cataract Refract Surg. 2006;32(11):1820&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17081864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia Y, Liu X, Luo L, Zeng Y, Cai X, Zeng M, et al. Early changes in clear cornea incision after phacoemulsification: an anterior segment optical coherence tomography study. Acta Ophthalmol. 2009;87(7):764&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19548882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupont-Monod S, Labb&#xe9; A, Fayol N, Chassignol A, Bourges JL, Baudouin C. In vivo architectural analysis of clear corneal incisions using anterior segment optical coherence tomography. J Cataract Refract Surg. 2009;35(3):444&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19251136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Can I, Bayhan HA, Celik H, Bostanc&#x131; Ceran B. Anterior segment optical coherence tomography evaluation and comparison of main clear corneal incisions in microcoaxial and biaxial cataract surgery. J Cataract Refract Surg. 2011;37(3):490&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21333873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyles GW, Cohen KL, Lam D. OCT-documented incision features and natural history of clear corneal incisions used for bimanual microincision cataract surgery. Cornea. 2011;30(6):681&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3590306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21242779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Dixit L, Weikert MP, Jenkins RB, Koch DD. Healing changes in clear corneal cataract incisions evaluated using Fourier-domain optical coherence tomography. J Cataract Refract Surg. 2012;38(4):660&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22321355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavallini GM, Campi L, Torlai G, Forlini M, Fornasari E. Clear corneal incisions in bimanual microincision cataract surgery: long-term wound-healing architecture. J Cataract Refract Surg. 2012;38(10):1743&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22921232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taban M, Rao B, Reznik J, Zhang J, Chen Z, McDonnell PJ. Dynamic morphology of sutureless cataract wounds--effect of incision angle and location. Surv Ophthalmol. 2004;49 Suppl 2:S62&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15028481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calladine D, Tanner V. Optical coherence tomography of the effects of stromal hydration on clear corneal incision architecture. J Cataract Refract Surg. 2009;35(8):1367&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19631122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho FL, Salowi MA, Bastion MC. The Effect of Eye Patching on Clear Corneal Incision Architecture in Phacoemulsification: A Randomized Controlled Trial. Asia Pac J Ophthalmol (Phila). 2017;6(5):429&#x2013;434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28379650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>