<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41306181</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Case of Atrial Fibrillation and Rapid Ventricular Response in a 22-Year-Old Athlete With Sickle Cell Trait.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e95437</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e95437</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e95437</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.95437</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sickle cell trait (SCT) is generally regarded as a benign carrier state of sickle cell disease (SCD); however, emerging evidence indicates that it may be associated with adverse cardiovascular outcomes, including atrial fibrillation (AF). AF is uncommon among young, otherwise healthy athletes, and its occurrence in individuals with SCT is not extensively documented. We present a case involving a 22-year-old male collegiate football player with a history of SCT who presented with palpitations initiated during practice. Upon arrival, he was hemodynamically stable; nonetheless, his initial electrocardiogram (ECG) revealed atrial fibrillation with rapid ventricular response (AF RVR). Laboratory investigations were unremarkable, including a normal troponin level. The patient was administered intravenous (IV) diltiazem for rate control, and synchronized cardioversion was successfully performed to restore sinus rhythm. Short-term anticoagulation therapy with apixaban was prescribed, along with flecainide on an as-needed basis for rhythm management. The patient was subsequently referred for outpatient catheter ablation and placed on a three-month restriction from contact sports. This case underscores a rare presentation of AF RVR in a young athlete with SCT. Exertional stress may contribute to arrhythmogenesis through mechanisms such as vaso-occlusion, hypoxia, acidosis, and dehydration. Current guidelines recommend rate control, cardioversion when clinically indicated, and short-term anticoagulation in cases of new-onset AF. Catheter ablation presents a potential definitive therapeutic option for young, symptomatic individuals. Preventive measures for athletes with SCT should include adequate hydration, heat acclimatization, and education of players and coaching staff. This case highlights the importance of heightened awareness, adherence to guideline-based management, and the necessity for further research into the association between SCT and AF in young athletes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Moseley et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moseley</LastName><ForeName>Tristan S</ForeName><Initials>TS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Edward Via College of Osteopathic Medicine, Monroe, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sasser</LastName><ForeName>Steven M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Edward Via College of Osteopathic Medicine, Monroe, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jordan</LastName><ForeName>Ryan T</ForeName><Initials>RT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Edward Via College of Osteopathic Medicine, Monroe, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Overturf</LastName><ForeName>Matthew D</ForeName><Initials>MD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anatomical Sciences, Edward Via College of Osteopathic Medicine, Monroe, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">atrial fibrillation (af)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sickle cell disease (scd)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sickle cell trait</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">supraventricular tachycardia (svt)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">synchronized cardioversion</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41306181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12645802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.95437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ashorobi D, Ramsey A, Killeen RB, Bhatt R. StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2025. Sickle cell trait.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30725815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long-term survival with sickle cell disease: a nationwide cohort study of Medicare and Medicaid beneficiaries. Jiao B, Johnson KM, Ramsey SD, Bender MA, Devine B, Basu A. Blood Adv. 2023;7:3276&#x2013;3283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10336259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36929166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Practical guidance for management of atrial fibrillation in sports cardiology. Palermi A, Molinari LV, Ricci F, Gallina S, Renda G. Curr Probl Cardiol. 2025;50:102995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39890043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Where there is smoke, there is fire: afib in SCD. Uniat J, Wood JC. Blood Adv. 2024;8:5639&#x2013;5640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11564921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39471346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association of sickle cell trait with atrial fibrillation: the REGARDS cohort. Douce DR, Soliman EZ, Naik R, et al. J Electrocardiol. 2019;55:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6639128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31028976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sickle cell trait and sudden death. Mitchell BL. Sports Med Open. 2018;4:19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5966366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29796715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elevations of inflammatory and procoagulant biomarkers in elderly persons with renal insufficiency. Shlipak MG, Fried LF, Crump C, et al. Circulation. 2003;107:87&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12515748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Close bidirectional relationship between chronic kidney disease and atrial fibrillation: the Niigata preventive medicine study. Watanabe H, Watanabe T, Sasaki S, Nagai K, Roden DM, Aizawa Y. Am Heart J. 2009;158:629&#x2013;636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19781424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radiofrequency ablation to achieve durable pulmonary vein isolation. Mulder MJ, Kemme MJ, Allaart CP. Europace. 2022;24:874&#x2013;886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34964469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exertional sickling: questions and controversy. Blinder MA, Russel S. Hematol Rep. 2014;6:5502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4274478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25568759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyperchloremia - why and how. Nagami GT. Nefrologia. 2016;36:347&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27267918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2023 ACC/AHA/ACCP/HRS guideline for the diagnosis and management of atrial fibrillation: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Joglar JA, Chung MK, Armbruster AL, et al. Circulation. 2024;149:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11095842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38033089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diltiazem dosing strategies in the management of atrial fibrillation with rapid ventricular rate. Bishop J Jr, Akram G. Cureus. 2021;13:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8592802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34804686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2015 ACC/AHA/hrs guideline for the management of adult patients with supraventricular tachycardia: executive summary: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on clinical practice guidelines and the Heart Rhythm Society. Page RL, Joglar JA, Caldwell MA, et al. Circulation. 2016;133:0&#x2013;505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26399662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goyal A, Singh B, Chhabra L, Singhal M. StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2025. Synchronized electrical cardioversion.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29489237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The CHA2DS2-VASc score identifies those patients with atrial fibrillation and a CHADS2 score of 1 who are unlikely to benefit from oral anticoagulant therapy. Coppens M, Eikelboom JW, Hart RG, et al. Eur Heart J. 2013;34:170&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23018151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The role of echocardiography in atrial fibrillation and cardioversion. Troughton RW, Asher CR, Klein AL. Heart. 2003;89:1447&#x2013;1454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1767994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14617563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apixaban in patients with atrial fibrillation: a systematic review. Maan A, Heist EK, Shaikh AY, Ruskin JN, Mansour M. J Atr Fibrillation. 2012;5:499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5153118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28496755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arunachalam K, Alzahrani T. StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2025. Flecainide.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31194431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>What does the blanking period blank? Mariani MA, Pozzoli A, Maat G, Alfieri OR, Benussi S. J Atr Fibrillation. 2015;8:1268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5135184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27957225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Can oral anticoagulants be stopped safely after a successful atrial fibrillation ablation? Chao TF, Lin YJ, Chang SL, et al. J Thorac Dis. 2015;7:172&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4321065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25713733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>