<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38845874</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2405-8440</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Heliyon</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Heliyon</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Preparation of a novel foamed concrete modified with carbon fiber and graphite: Mechanical, electro-magnetic and microstructural characteristics based on X-CT.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e31665</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e31665</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e31665</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e31665</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In this paper, foam concrete is modified using graphite and carbon fiber as absorbents. The mechanical properties are analyzed in conjunction with hydration products, pore size distribution based on XCT test. Additionally, the resistivity, complex permittivity and complex permeability are tested. The results demonstrate that carbon fiber enhances the proportion of pores with diameters less than 200&#xa0;&#x3bc;m in foam concrete, thereby significantly enhancing its flexural strength. Furthermore, incorporating graphite helps offset the initial retardation of sulfoaluminate cement hydration induced by carbon fibers, leading to an increase in the average pore size and a reduction in compressive strength. The incorporation of carbon fibers at a concentration of 0.6&#xa0;wt% achieves the percolation threshold, akin to scenarios with singular fiber incorporation. Exceeding 2&#xa0;wt% graphite content results in negligible influence on the conductivity. The synergistic integration of graphite and carbon fibers significantly improves the electromagnetic wave absorption performance of the composite. At a thickness of 6&#xa0;mm, the material exhibits an effective bandwidth where the reflection loss is less than -10 dB, extending up to 2.5&#xa0;GHz, which constitutes 52.08&#xa0;% of the tested frequency spectrum.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tu</LastName><ForeName>Qin-Chuan</ForeName><Initials>QC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Architecture and Environment, Hubei University of Technology, Wuhan, 430068, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Intelligent Health Perception and Ecological Restoration of Rivers and Lakes, Ministry of Education, Hubei University of Technology, Wuhan, 430068, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xia</LastName><ForeName>Qing-Hui</ForeName><Initials>QH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Architecture and Environment, Hubei University of Technology, Wuhan, 430068, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Yao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Architecture and Environment, Hubei University of Technology, Wuhan, 430068, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bai</LastName><ForeName>Ying-Hua</ForeName><Initials>YH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Architecture and Environment, Hubei University of Technology, Wuhan, 430068, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Intelligent Health Perception and Ecological Restoration of Rivers and Lakes, Ministry of Education, Hubei University of Technology, Wuhan, 430068, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Heliyon</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101672560</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2405-8440</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Carbon fiber (D)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic property (C)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">X-CT (B)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38845874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11153095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e31665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2405-8440(24)07696-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Xu J., Cao J., Guo M., Yang S., Yao H., Lei M., Hao Y., Bi K. Metamaterial mechanical antenna for very low frequency wireless communication. Adv. Compos. Hybrid Mater. 2021;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baoguo Han, Liqing Zhang, Jinping Ou, Smart and Multifunctional Concrete toward Sustainable Infrastructures, Springer, Singapore..</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanasinghe D., Aslani F., Ma G., Habibi D. Review of polymer composites with diverse nanofillers for electromagnetic interference shielding. Nanomaterials. 2020;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7153630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32192158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phalguni M., Sujith R. Electromagnetic interference (EMI): measurement and reduction techniques. J. Electron. Mater. 2020;49</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haneet K., Kumar J.R. Electromagnetic radiation reduction in 5G networks and beyond using thermal radiation mode. IEEE Trans. Veh. Technol. 2020;69</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Y., Cui Y., Lu L., Wang F., Hu S. Microwave absorbing mortar using magnetic hollow fly ash microspheres/Fe3O4 composite as absorbent. J. Mater. Civ. Eng. 2018:30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A&#xef;tcin P.-C. Cements of yesterday and today. Cement Concr. Res. 2000;30</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y., Zhou Q., Deng Y. The reinforcement attributes of multi-scale hybrid fiber throughout the uniaxial compression of ultra-low-weight foamed cement-based composites. Construct. Build. Mater. 2020;242</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peitao X., Zhicheng S., Mei F., Kai S., Yao L., Kelan Y., Chunzhao L., A M.T.A., Meina H., Shuwei M., Gemeng L., Hua H., Runhua F., Zhanhu G. Recent advances in radio-frequency negative dielectric metamaterials by designing heterogeneous composites. Adv. Compos. Hybrid Mater. 2022;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiongfei L., Nan W., Zhuang W. Effects of the absorber, thickness and surface roughness on the electromagnetic wave absorption characteristics of magnesium phosphate cement. Construct. Build. Mater. 2022;344</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiongfei L., Zhuang W., Nan W., Yaoyao W. Effects of EPS, Mn&#x2013;Zn ferrite, and layers on the electromagnetic absorption performance of magnesium phosphate cement. J. Mater. Civ. Eng. 2023;35</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y.F., Hao W.J., Li B.Y., Duan Y.P., Liu S.H. Double-layered cement composites with superior electromagnetic wave absorbing properties containing carbon black and expanded polystyrene. Adv. Mater. Res. 2013;2586</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie S., Ji Z., Li B., Zhu L., Wang J. Electromagnetic wave absorption properties of helical carbon fibers and expanded glass beads filled cement-based composites. Composites Part A. 2018:114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B., Duan Y., Zhang Y., Liu S. Electromagnetic wave absorption properties of cement-based composites filled with porous materials. Mater. Des. 2010;32</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z., Yang C., Cheng H., Zhou L., Ren J., Zhu Y. vol. 39. IJHT; 2021. (The Electromagnetic Wave Absorbing Property of Dual-Layer Cement Matrix Composites Based on the Principle of Electromagnetic Energy - Thermal Energy Conversion).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie P., Liu Y., Feng M., Niu M., Liu C., Wu N., Sui K., Patil R.R., Pan D., Guo Z., Fan R. Hierarchically porous Co/C nanocomposites for ultralight high-performance microwave absorption. Adv. Compos. Hybrid Mater. 2021;4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Wang Z., Ning M. Optimization of electromagnetic wave absorption bandwidth of cement-based composites with doped expanded perlite. Construct. Build. Mater. 2020;259</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan H., Liu S., Duan Y., Cheng J. Cement based electromagnetic shielding and absorbing building materials. Cement Concr. Compos. 2005;28</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho S., Kim J., Hong I. Electromagnetic shielding characteristics of eco-friendly foamed concrete wall. Int. J. Antenn. Propag. 2017:20171&#x2013;20178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho S., Yoo J., Kim J., et al. Prediction of electromagnetic transmission properties using dielectric property modeling of foamed concrete containing BFS. Construct. Build. Mater. 2017:151650&#x2013;151660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anatol'evna E.T., Ivanovich A.S., Alekseevich G.T., et al. Electromagnetic activation of water-cement pastes and foam concretes. Vestnik MGSU. 2012;(12):149&#x2013;153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal A., Shahzad F., Hantanasirisakul K., Kim M.K., Kwon J., Hong J., Kim H., Kim D., Gogotsi Y., Koo C.M. Anomalous absorption of electromagnetic waves by 2D transition metal carbonitride Ti3CNT x (MXene) Science. 2020;369</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32703878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lingxi H., Yuping D., Xuhao D., Yuansong Z., Guojia M., Yi L., Shaohua G., Weiping Z. Bioinspired metamaterials: multibands electromagnetic wave adaptability and hydrophobic characteristics. Small. 2019:15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31402564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D., Yang P., Hou P., Zhang L., Zhang X., Zhou Z., Xie N., Huang S., Cheng X. Cement-based composites endowed with novel functions through controlling interface microstructure from Fe3O4@SiO2 nanoparticles. Cement Concr. Compos. 2017;80</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Zhang T., Zhou L. Investigation on electromagnetic and microwave absorption properties of copper slag-filled cement mortar. Cement Concr. Compos. 2016;74</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y H.N., Daeik J., L H.K., N I.W. Influence of carbon fiber additions on the electromagnetic wave shielding characteristics of CNT-cement composites. Construct. Build. Mater. 2021;269</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gijoon P., Sungwook K., Kyu P.G., Namkon L. Influence of carbon fiber on the electromagnetic shielding effectiveness of high-performance fiber-reinforced cementitious composites. J. Build. Eng. 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Xie Y., Lu W., Chou T.-W. Flexible electromagnetic wave absorbing composite based on 3D rGO-CNT-Fe 3 O 4 ternary films. Carbon. 2018;129</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yun Q., Haibo Y., Yan C., Bo W., Ying L. Structure design of Prussian blue analogue derived CoFe@C composite with tunable microwave absorption performance. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2022;571</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krzysztof M., Micha&#x142; M., Wojciech P., Adrian R., Maciej S., Tomasz T. Methods of protecting buildings against HPM radiation-A review of materials absorbing the energy of electromagnetic waves. Materials. 2020:13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7730210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33287143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xin Jia. Effect of graphite on the microwave susceptibility of cement foam concrete. J. Microw. Power Electromagn. Energy. 2015;49</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yifei S., Hongquan J., Bingbing L., Hui Q. Electromagnetic (EM) wave absorption properties of cementitious building composites containing MnZn ferrite: preferable effective bandwidth and thickness via iron and graphite addition. J. Magn. Magn Mater. 2022;560</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B., Zhang Y., Chen R. Experimental and numerical simulation of absorbing property of cement-based material blending with graphite and carbon fibers. Hong Kong,China. 2013:31&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espinoza Moreno C.A., et al. Electrical percolation and fluidity of conductive recycled mortar cement: graphite powder: recycled sand with addition of industrial waste carbon fiber. Carbon Letters. 2020;31(4):707&#x2013;720.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ying-hua B., Bo X., Huawei L., Ran T., Qi-hang Z. Mechanical properties and electromagnetic absorption characteristics of foam Cement-based absorbing materials. Construct. Build. Mater. 2022;330</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu Hongtao. Shenyang Ligong University; 2016. Study on the Properties of Foam Cement Based Absorbing Materials.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song L., Erlei B., Jinyu X., Jialin C. Research on electromagnetic properties and microwave deicing performance of carbon fiber modified concrete. Construct. Build. Mater. 2021;286</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maksymilian F., Paulina S., Waldemar P. Smart graphite&#x2013;cement composites with low percolation threshold. Materials. 2022;15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9031721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35454463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han B., Zhang L., Zhang C., Wang Y., Yu X., Ou J. Reinforcement effect and mechanism of carbon fibers to mechanical and electrically conductive properties of cement-based materials. Construct. Build. Mater. 2016;125</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nam I.W., Souri H., Lee H.K. Percolation threshold and piezoresistive response of multi-wall carbon nanotube/cement composites. Smart Struct. Syst. 2016;18</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun M., Li Z., Mao Q., Shen D. Study on the hole conduction phenomenon in carbon fiber-reinforced concrete. Cement Concr. Res. 1998;28</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei Y., Yuanyi Y., Qi Z., Yang L., Gan D., Tingting Y. Broadband electromagnetic wave absorbing performance by designing the foam structure and double-layer for cement-based composites containing MWCNTs. Cement Concr. Compos. 2022;131</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan D., Yuanyi Y., Qi Z., Yang L., Lei Y., Tingting Y. Lightweight and broadband electromagnetic wave absorbing foamed cement-based composites incorporated with hybrid dielectric fibers. Construct. Build. Mater. 2022;327</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C., Li J., Guo S. High-performance electromagnetic wave absorption by designing the multilayer graphene/thermoplastic polyurethane porous composites with gradient foam ratio structure. Composites Part A. 2019:125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiantian S., Shuai X., Zhijiang J., Chao M., Zihao W., Junyu W., Jing W. Synergistic effects of carbon black and steel fibers on electromagnetic wave shielding and mechanical properties of graphite/cement composites. J. Build. Eng. 2022;45</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>