<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41825818</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1878-7568</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Acta biomaterialia</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Acta Biomater</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biomimetic zwitterionic micelles for efficient mucus penetration and pulmonary targeting in acute lung injury.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1742-7061(26)00168-6</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.actbio.2026.03.021</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Nebulized inhalation represents an attractive approach for pulmonary drug delivery due to its non-invasiveness and direct lung targeting capability. However, the effectiveness of conventional inhaled formulations is limited by their inability to simultaneously evade mucociliary clearance and macrophage phagocytosis, leading to suboptimal lung retention and low bioavailability. To address these challenges, a series of ultra-small zwitterionic "camouflage" micelles, Distearoylphosphatidylethanolamine (DSPE)-block-poly (N-methacryloyloxyethyl-N, N-dimethylammonium-&#x3b1;-N-methylcarboxybetaine) (CB) (D-PCB<sub>n</sub>), were developed to synergize biomimetic targeting with enhanced mucosal penetration. The micelles feature a DSPE-based core structurally modeled after dipalmitoylphosphatidylcholine (DPPC), a key pulmonary surfactant lipid, enabling biomimetic alveolar targeting. Simultaneously, a carboxybetaine-derived corona facilitates robust hydration-mediated surface lubrication for efficient mucus penetration. Among the series, the optimized D-PCB<sub>30</sub> variant exhibited superior mucus-permeating capacity, enhanced pulmonary deposition, and high encapsulation efficiency for dexamethasone. In vivo evaluation in a murine model following aerosol administration demonstrated significantly improved lung accumulation, extended residence time, reduced systemic distribution, and enhanced anti-inflammatory efficacy. Transcriptomic analysis further indicated modulation of critical inflammatory pathways and reprogramming of macrophage polarization (M1 to M2 phenotype), corroborating the therapeutic benefits achieved through enhanced barrier penetration. These results demonstrate the potential of D-PCB<sub>n</sub> micelles as a promising inhalable nanoplatform for targeted treatment of lung diseases. STATEMENT OF SIGNIFICANCE: Delivering therapeutics to injured lungs is hampered by mucus barriers, rapid clearance, and immune sequestration. Here, we describe ultra-small, biomimetic zwitterionic micelles D-PCBMA<sub>n</sub> (D-PCB<sub>30</sub>) that combine a DPPC-mimetic DSPE core with a carboxybetaine corona to create a "camouflage-and-lubricate" nanoplatform. D-PCB<sub>30</sub> exhibits a low critical micelle concentration (CMC), high drug loading, and stability upon nebulization, enabling deep mucus penetration, reduced macrophage uptake, and sustained pulmonary residence. When loaded with dexamethasone (DEX) and delivered by nebulization, D-PCB<sub>30</sub> increases local drug deposition while reducing systemic exposure, resulting in potent attenuation of LPS-driven inflammation, preservation of alveolar architecture, and diminished fibrotic remodeling. Mechanistically, transcriptomic profiling reveals suppression of TLR/MyD88/NF-&#x3ba;B inflammatory circuits and induction of tissue-repair programs, alongside a shift in macrophage phenotype toward resolution. With an encouraging biosafety profile and mitigated steroid side effects, D-PCB<sub>30</sub> represents a clinically promising strategy to overcome pulmonary barriers and to deliver targeted, effective therapies for acute inflammatory lung disease.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 Acta Materialia Inc. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dai</LastName><ForeName>Xiangrong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Postgraduate Training Base Alliance of Wenzhou Medical University, Whenzhou 325000, China; Wenzhou Institute, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Wenzhou 325000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liao</LastName><ForeName>Yi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Postgraduate Training Base Alliance of Wenzhou Medical University, Whenzhou 325000, China; Wenzhou Institute, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Wenzhou 325000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Rong</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Postgraduate Training Base Alliance of Wenzhou Medical University, Whenzhou 325000, China; Wenzhou Institute, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Wenzhou 325000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jin</LastName><ForeName>Xuanxiang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, The First Affiliated Hospital of Wenzhou Medical University, Wenzhou 325000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Jiajia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, The Second Affiliated Hospital and Yuying Children's Hospital of Wenzhou Medical University, Wenzhou 325027, China. Electronic address: dongjiajia@wmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Postgraduate Training Base Alliance of Wenzhou Medical University, Whenzhou 325000, China; Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, The Quzhou Affiliated Hospital of Wenzhou Medical University, Quzhou People's Hospital, Quzhou 324000, China; Wenzhou Institute, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Wenzhou 325000, China. Electronic address: tanying@ucas.ac.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jin</LastName><ForeName>Xuru</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, The Quzhou Affiliated Hospital of Wenzhou Medical University, Quzhou People's Hospital, Quzhou 324000, China; Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, The First Affiliated Hospital of Wenzhou Medical University, Wenzhou 325000, China. Electronic address: xuru.jin@wmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Acta Biomater</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101233144</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1742-7061</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acute lung injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DSPE</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Micelles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mucus penetration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Zwitterionic polymers</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41825818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actbio.2026.03.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1742-7061(26)00168-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>