<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41583951</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0974-777X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Season>Oct-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of global infectious diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Glob Infect Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Oral Manifestations of Monkeypox: A Global Scoping Review of Evidence.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>187</StartPage><EndPage>195</EndPage><MedlinePgn>187-195</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/jgid.jgid_17_25</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Monkeypox, a zoonotic disease caused by the monkeypox virus, has emerged as a significant global public health concern, particularly due to outbreaks in non-endemic regions. While cutaneous lesions are its hallmark, oral manifestations like mucosal lesions, ulcers, and enanthema may precede other symptoms, posing unique diagnostic challenges. This review aimed to assess the prevalence, clinical features, and implications of oral manifestations of monkeypox, emphasizing their importance in medical and dental practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A scoping review following PRISMA-ScR guidelines analyzed studies on oral symptoms of monkeypox published from 2005 to 2024. Comprehensive searches of databases like PubMed, Scopus, Web of Science, and Embase were carried out and MeSH terms such as "oral lesions," "monkeypox," and "stomatitis" were used. Three independent reviewers extracted data on clinical presentations, prevalence, and implications for dental care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Oral lesions, including ulcers, vesicles, sore throats, and necrosis on the tongue, gingiva, and buccal mucosa, are key diagnostic markers of monkeypox. Prevalence rates varied widely (7-100%), with higher rates evident in immunocompromised individuals and pediatric populations, with smaller studies often reporting higher rates. Lesions typically lasted 7-14 days, extending to three weeks in severe cases and were associated with secondary infections, pain and dysphagia particularly in immunocompromised individuals. Management included hydration, analgesics, and, in some cases, antiviral therapy like tecovirimat. The findings emphasize the need for standardized reporting of oral symptoms to enhance diagnostic accuracy and clinical care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Oral manifestations of monkeypox are critical diagnostic and transmission markers. Dental practitioners should consider monkeypox in the differential diagnosis of unexplained oral ulcers, particularly in high-risk populations. Heightened awareness and standardized reporting can optimize diagnosis, care, and epidemic control efforts.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Journal of Global Infectious Diseases.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sridhar</LastName><ForeName>Chitathoor</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Meenakshi Academy of Higher Education and Research, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krithika</LastName><ForeName>Chandrasekaran</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oral Medicine and Radiology, Meenakshi Ammal Dental College, Meenakshi Academy of Higher Education and Research, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deshpande</LastName><ForeName>Ashwini</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Research, Meenakshi Academy of Higher Education and Research, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santhanakrishnan</LastName><ForeName>Srijanani</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Research, Meenakshi Academy of Higher Education and Research, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Narasingam</LastName><ForeName>Arunagirinathan</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Research, Central Research Laboratory, Meenakshi Academy of Higher Education and Research, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pachamuthu</LastName><ForeName>Balakrishnan</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Research, Central Research Laboratory, Meenakshi Academy of Higher Education and Research, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>J Glob Infect Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101521436</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0974-777X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epidemiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">monkeypox virus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mucosal lesions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oral health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oral ulcers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vesicles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">zoonoses</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41583951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12826637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jgid.jgid_17_25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JGID-17-187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Guarner J, Del Rio C, Malani PN. Monkeypox in 2022-what clinicians need to know. JAMA. 2022;328:139&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35696257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma K, Akre S, Chakole S, Wanjari MB. Monkeypox: An emerging disease. Cureus. 2022;14:e29393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9585651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36304368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds MG, Yorita KL, Kuehnert MJ, Davidson WB, Huhn GD, Holman RC, et al. Clinical manifestations of human monkeypox influenced by route of infection. J Infect Dis. 2006;194:773&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16941343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan DH, Jaeranny S, Li M, Sukhdeo SS, Monge JC, Callejas MF, et al. Atypical Clinical presentation of monkeypox complicated by myopericarditis. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2022;9:ofac394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9416060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36043183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sookaromdee P, Wiwanitkit V. Mouth sores and monkeypox: A consideration. J Stomatol Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2022;123:593&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9598802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35760308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters SM, Hill NB, Halepas S. Oral manifestations of monkeypox: A report of 2 cases. J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2022;80:1836&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9528233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36055370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Issa AW, Alkhofash NF, Gopinath D, Varma SR. Oral manifestations in monkeypox: A scoping review on implications for oral health. Dent J (Basel) 2023;11:132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10217612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37232783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandhi P A, Patro SK, Sandeep M, Satapathy P, Shamim MA, Kumar V, et al. Oral manifestation of the monkeypox virus: A systematic review and meta-analysis. EClinicalMedicine. 2023;56:101817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9815964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36628187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amato M, Di Spirito F, Boccia G, Fornino D, D&#x2019;Ambrosio F, De Caro F. Human monkeypox: Oral implications and recommendations for oral screening and infection control in dental practice. J Pers Med. 2022;12:2000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9788482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36556221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samaranayake L, Anil S. The monkeypox outbreak and implications for dental practice. Int Dent J. 2022;72:589&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9485535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35934521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur A, Goel R, Singh R, Bhardwaj A, Kumari R, Gambhir RS. Identifying monkeypox: Do dental professionals have adequate knowledge and awareness? Rocz Panstw Zakl Hig. 2022;73:365&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36169392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huhn GD, Bauer AM, Yorita K, Graham MB, Sejvar J, Likos A, et al. Clinical characteristics of human monkeypox, and risk factors for severe disease. Clin Infect Dis. 2005;41:1742&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16288398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaughan A, Aarons E, Astbury J, Balasegaram S, Beadsworth M, Beck CR, et al. Two cases of monkeypox imported to the United Kingdom, September 2018. Euro Surveill. 2018;23:1800509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6157091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30255836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng OT, Lee V, Marimuthu K, Vasoo S, Chan G, Lin RT, et al. Acase of imported monkeypox in Singapore. Lancet Infect Dis. 2019;19:1166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7129797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31657773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yinka-Ogunleye A, Aruna O, Dalhat M, Ogoina D, McCollum A, Disu Y, et al. Outbreak of human monkeypox in Nigeria in 2017-18: A clinical and epidemiological report. Lancet Infect Dis. 2019;19:872&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9628943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31285143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukhdeo SS, Aldhaheri K, Lam PW, Walmsley S. A case of human monkeypox in Canada. CMAJ. 2022;194:E1031&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9481252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35793837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang YR, Lee M, Shin H, Kim JW, Choi MM, Kim YM, et al. The first case of monkeypox in the republic of Korea. J Korean Med Sci. 2022;37:e224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9274108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35818706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matias WR, Koshy JM, Nagami EH, Kovac V, Moeng LR, Shenoy ES, et al. Tecovirimat for the treatment of human monkeypox: An initial series from Massachusetts, United States. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2022;9:ofac377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9356679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35949403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girometti N, Byrne R, Bracchi M, Heskin J, McOwan A, Tittle V, et al. Demographic and clinical characteristics of confirmed human monkeypox virus cases in individuals attending a sexual health centre in London, UK: An observational analysis. Lancet Infect Dis. 2022;22:1321&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9534773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35785793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel A, Bilinska J, Tam JC, Da Silva Fontoura D, Mason CY, Daunt A, et al. Clinical features and novel presentations of human monkeypox in a central London centre during the 2022 outbreak: Descriptive case series. BMJ. 2022;378:e072410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9331915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35902115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davido B, D&#x2019;Anglejan E, Baudoin R, Dahmane L, Chaud A, Cortier M, et al. Monkeypox outbreak 2022: An unusual case of peritonsillar abscess in a person previously vaccinated against smallpox. J Travel Med. 2022;29:taac082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35876271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima EL, Barra LA, Borges LM, Medeiros LA, Tomishige MY, Santos LS, et al. First case report of monkeypox in Brazil: Clinical manifestations and differential diagnosis with sexually transmitted infections. Rev Inst Med Trop Sao Paulo. 2022;64:e54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9448252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36074449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ambrogio F, Laface C, De Caro AP, Loconsole D, Centrone F, Lettini T, et al. Peri-oral monkeypox virus infection: A clinical report with confirmatory polymerase chain reaction findings. Vaccines (Basel) 2022;11:36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9863311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36679881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George AE, Heera AB, Harikrishnan H, Reghukumar A, Varghese SA, Chandran R, et al. The dermatological evolution of the first case of monkeypox reported in India. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol. 2023;89:578&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37067112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ardila CM, Arrubla-Escobar DE, Vivares-Builes AM. Oral lesions in patients with human monkeypox: A systematic scoping review. J Oral Pathol Med. 2023;52:459&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36263594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sah R, Siddiq A, Reda A, Abdelaal A, Padhi BK, Mohanty A, et al. Oral manifestations of mpox: A common presentation? J Am Dent Assoc. 2023;154:279&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36635205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ridho FM, Iqbal M, Laksono EP, Leal RS. Oral and perioral manifestations in monkeypox patients: A systematic review of case reports and case series. Diponegoro Med J. 2024;13:240&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casu C, Murgia MS, Orr&#xf9; G. Oral manifestations of monkeypox and potential tools for their management. Pan Afr Med J. 2023;45:137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10543898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37790160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tar&#xed;n-Vicente EJ, Alemany A, Agud-Dios M, Ubals M, Su&#xf1;er C, Ant&#xf3;n A, et al. Clinical presentation and virological assessment of confirmed human monkeypox virus cases in Spain: A prospective observational cohort study. Lancet. 2022;400:661&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9533900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35952705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph B, Anil S. Oral lesions in human monkeypox disease and their management-a scoping review. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol. 2023;135:510&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9715264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36737264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahdi SS, Yaqoob R, Allana R, Batteneni G, Sakina S, Agha D, et al. Monkeypox resurgence and its implications for dentistry &#x2013; A scoping review. Ig Sanita Pubbl. 2023;80:49&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37154808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng X. Clinical manifestations of the pharynx in human monkeypox. Travel Med Infect Dis. 2022;50:102465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9534084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36174912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagde H, Dhopte A, Bukhary F, Momenah N, Akhter F, Mahmoud O, et al. Monkeypox and oral lesions associated with its occurrence: A systematic review and meta-analysis. F1000Res. 2023;12:964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11153993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38845619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajmera KM, Goyal L, Pandit T, Pandit R. Monkeypox &#x2013; An emerging pandemic. IDCases. 2022;29:e01587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9352457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35938150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habib AM, Johns JD, Hakimi A, Maxwell JH. Upper airway manifestations of monkeypox: A case report and literature review. J Laparoendosc Adv Surg Tech A. 2023;33:287&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36383119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Dabbagh J, Mohammad Deeb E, Younis R, Eissa R. The dermatological manifestations and differential diagnosis of monkeypox: A narrative review. Medicine (Baltimore) 2024;103:e40359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11537653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39496026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>