<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38130656</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2332-8940</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Temperature (Austin, Tex.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Temperature (Austin)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effectiveness of heat preparation and alleviation strategies for cognitive performance: A systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>404</StartPage><EndPage>433</EndPage><MedlinePgn>404-433</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/23328940.2022.2157645</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>A range of occupational and performance contexts (e.g. military personnel operations, emergency services, sport) require the critical maintenance of cognitive performance in environmentally challenging environments. Several reviews exist which evaluate the effectiveness of heat preparation strategies to facilitate physical performance. To date, no review has explored the usefulness of heat preparation strategies for cognitive performance. Therefore, this systematic review aimed to evaluate a range of interventions for the maintenance of cognitive performance, during or following active or passive heat exposure. Studies to be included were assessed by two authors reviewing title, abstract, and full-text. Forty articles were identified which met the inclusion criteria. Interventions were categorised into chronic (i.e. acclimation/acclimatisation) and acute strategies (i.e. hydration, cooling, supplementation, psychological). The results indicate that medium-term consecutive heat acclimation may mitigate some cognitive deficits under heat stress, although heat acclimation effectiveness could be influenced by age. Further, pre-cooling appears the most effective cooling method for maintaining cognitive performance under heat stress, although results were somewhat ambiguous. The hydration literature showed that the most effective hydration strategies were those which individualised electrolyte fortified fluid volumes to match for sweat loss. Limited research exploring psychological interventions indicates that motivational self-talk could be facilitative for maintaining cognitive skills following exercise in hot conditions. These findings can be used to help inform strategies for maintaining critical cognitive and decision-making skills in hot environments.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Author(s). Published by Informa UK Limited, trading as Taylor &amp; Francis Group.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Donnan</LastName><ForeName>Kate J</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sport, Exercise, and Rehabilitation Sciences, University of Hull, Hull, HU6 7RX, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Williams</LastName><ForeName>Emily L</ForeName><Initials>EL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Human Performance, Carnegie School of Sport, Leeds Beckett University, Leeds, LS6 3QS, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bargh</LastName><ForeName>Melissa J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport and Exercise Science, College of Social Science of University of Lincoln, Lincoln, LN6 7TS, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Temperature (Austin)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101655855</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2332-8940</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acclimation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cooling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heat stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hyperthermia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-talk</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">supplementation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>No potential conflict of interest was reported by the authors.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38130656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10732620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23328940.2022.2157645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2157645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>NASA, NASA&#x2019;s Scientific Visualization Studio. Graphic: global Warming from 1880 to 2021. Viewed. http://climate.nasa.gov/climate_resources/139/graphic-global-warming-from-1880-to-2021. 17
June, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyon C, Saupe EE, Smith CJ, et al. Climate Change Research and Action Must Look beyond 2100. Glob Chang Biol. 2022;28(2):349&#x2013;361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34558764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahima RS. Global warming threatens human thermoregulation and survival. J Clin Invest. 2020;130(2):559&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6994120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31904587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christidis N, Jones GS, Stott PA. Dramatically increasing chance of extremely hot Summer since the 2003 European heatwave. Nat Clim Change. 2015;5(1):46&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perkins-Kirkpatrick SE, Lewis SC. Increasing trends in regional heatwaves. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):3357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7334217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32620857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry CM, Sheik-Nainer MA, Segall N, et al. Effects of physical workload on cognitive task performance and situation awareness. Theor Issues Ergon Sci. 2008;9(2):95&#x2013;113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girard O, Brocherie F, Bishop DJ. Sprint performance under heat stress: a review. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2015;25(1):79&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25943658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris NB, Piil JF, Morabito M, et al. The HEAT-SHIELD project&#x2014;Perspectives from an inter-sectoral approach to occupational heat stress. J Sci Med Sport. 2021;24(8):747&#x2013;755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33757698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebi KL, Capon A, Berry P, et al. Hot weather and heat extremes: health risks. Lancet. 2021;398(10301):698&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34419205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirreffs SM, Aragon-Varagas LF, Chamorro M, et al. The sweating response of elite professional soccer players to training in the heat. Int J Sports Med. 2005;26(2):90&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15726482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;riard JD, Eijsvogels TM, Daanen HA. Exercise under heat stress: thermoregulation, hydration, performance implications, and mitigation strategies. 2021. Physiol Rev. 2021;101(4):1873&#x2013;1979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33829868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawka MN, Montain SJ. Fluid and electrolyte supplementation for exercise heat stress. Am J Clin Nutr. 2000;72(2):564&#x2013;572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10919961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Shirreffs SM. Dehydration and rehydration in competitive sport. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;3:40&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21029189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nybo L, Rasmussen P, Sawks MN. Performance in the Heat-Physiological Factors of Importance for Hyperthermia-Induced Fatigue. Compr Physiol. 2014;4(2):657&#x2013;689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24715563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casa DJ. Exercise in the Heat. I. Fundamentals of Thermal Physiology, Performance Implications, and Dehydration. J Athl Train. 1999;34(3):246&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1322918</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16558572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Alonso J, Crandall CG, Johnson JM. The cardiovascular challenge of exercising in the heat. J Physiol. 2008;586(1):45&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2375553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17855754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ. Distance running in hot environments: a thermal challenge to the elite runner. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20(3):95&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21029196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen B, Nybo L. Cerebral changes during exercise in the heat. Sports Med. 2003;33(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12477374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hancock PA, Ross JM, Szalma JL. A Meta-Analysis of Performance Response Under Thermal Stressors. Hum Factors. 2007;49(5):851&#x2013;877.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17915603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnan K, Williams E, Morris J, et al. The effects of exercise at different temperatures on cognitive function: a systematic review. Psychol Sport Exerc. 2021;54(1):101908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meeusen R, Watson P, Dvorak J. The brain and fatigue: new opportunities for nutritional interventions? J Sports Sci. 2006;24(7):773&#x2013;782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16766505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams AM, Ford PR, Eccles DW, et al. Perceptual-Cognitive Expertise in Sport and its Acquisition: implications for Applied Cognitive Psychology. Appl Cogn Psychol. 2011;25(3):432&#x2013;442.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambourne K, Tomporowski P. The effect of exercise-induced arousal on cognitive task performance: a meta-regression analysis. Brain Res. 2010;1341:12&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20381468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMorris T, Hale BJ. Is there an acute exercise-induced physiological/biochemical threshold which triggers increased speed of cognitive functioning? A meta-analytic investigation. J Sport Health Sci. 2015;4(1):4&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieuwenhuys A, Oudejans RR. Anxiety and performance: perceptual-motor behavior in high-pressure contexts. Curr Opin Psychol. 2017;16:28&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28813350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson OJ, Vytal K, Cornwell BR, et al. The impact of anxiety upon cognition: perspectives from human threat of shock studies. Front Human Neurosci. 2013;7:203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3656338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23730279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazloumi A, Golbabaei F, Khani SM, et al. Evaluating Effects of Heat Stress on Cognitive Function among Workers in a Hot Industry. Health Promot Perspect. 2014;4(2):240&#x2013;246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4300451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25649311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor L, Watkins SL, Marshall H, et al. The Impact of Different Environmental Conditions on Cognitive Function: a Focused Review. Front Physiol. 2015;6:372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4701920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26779029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piil JF, Kingma B, Morris NB, et al. Proposed framework for forecasting heat-effects on motor-cognitive performance in the Summer Olympics. Temperature. 2021;8(3):262&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8409751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34485620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racinais S, Gaoua N, Grantham J. Hyperthermia impairs short-term memory and peripheral motor drive transmission. J Physiol. 2008;586(19):4751&#x2013;4762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2607529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18703579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piil JF, Lundbye-Jensen J, Trangmar SJ, et al. Performance in complex motor tasks deteriorates in hyperthermic humans. Temperature. 2017;4(4):420&#x2013;428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5800368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29435481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamin CL, Sekiguchi Y, Fry LA, et al. Performance Changes Following Heat Acclimation and the Factors That Influence These Changes: meta-Analysis and Meta-Regression. Front Physiol. 2019;10:1448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6890862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31827444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones PR, Barton C, Morrissey D, et al. Pre-cooling for endurance exercise performance in the heat: a systematic review. BMC Med. 2012;10(1):166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3568721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23249542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson OR, James CA, Mee JA, et al. Heat alleviation strategies for athletic performance: a review and practitioner guidelines. Temperature. 2020;7(1):3&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7053966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32166103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaoua N, Racinais S, Grantham J, et al. Alterations in cognitive performance during passive hyperthermia are task dependent. Int J Hyperthermia. 2011;27(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3082171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21070137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piil JF, Christiansen L, Morris NB, et al. Direct exposure of the head to solar heat radiation impairs motor-cognitive performance. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):7812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7210303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32385322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baars BJ. How does a serial, integrated and very limited stream of consciousness emerge from a nervous system that is mostly unconscious, distributed, parallel and of enormous capacity? Ciba Found Symp. 1993;174:282&#x2013;290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8319511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaoua N, Grantham J, Racinais S, et al. Sensory displeasure reduces complex cognitive performance in the heat. J Environ Psychol. 2012;32(2):158&#x2013;163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tawatsupa B, Yiengprugsawan V, Kjellstrom T, et al. Heat stress, health, and well-being: findings from a large national cohort of Thai adults. BMJ Open. 2012;2(6):e001396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3532977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23135538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meylan CM, Bowman K, Stellingwerff T, et al. The Efficacy of Heat Acclimatization Pre-World Cup in Female Soccer Players. Front Sports Act Living. 2021;25(3):614370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8185056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34113844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bongers CC, Hopman MT, Eiksvogels TM. Cooling interventions for athletes: an overview of effectiveness, physiological mechanisms and practical considerations. Temperature (Austin). 2017;4(1):60&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5356217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28349095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Shirreffs SM. Development of Individual Hydration Strategies for Athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2008;18(5):457&#x2013;472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19033609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JK, Kenefick RW, Cheuvront SN. Novel Cooling Strategies for Military Training and Operations. J Strength Cond Res. 2015;29(11):77&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26506203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luippold AJ, Charkoudin N, Kenefick RW, et al. Update: efficacy of Military Fluid Intake Guidance. Mil Med. 2018;183(9&#x2013;10):338&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29912380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashworth ET, Cotter JD, Kilding AE. Impact of elevated core temperature on cognition in hot environments within a military context. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2020;121(4):1061&#x2013;1071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7797274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33426575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heilmann F, Weigel P, Wollny R. Analysis of cognitive abilities measured in a laboratory-controlled 360&#xb0; simulation in soccer. Ger J Exerc Sport Res. 2021;51(3):302&#x2013;311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedl&#xe1;r M. Cognitive skills of emergency medical services crew members: a literature review. BMC Emerg Med. 2020;20(1):44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7257132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32471352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rastegar Z, Ravandi MR, Zare S, et al. Evaluating the effect of heat stress on cognitive performance of petrochemical workers: a field study. Heliyon. 2022;8(1):e08698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8741453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35028472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahimi GR, Albanaqi AL, Van der Touw T, et al. Physiological Responses to Heat Acclimation: a Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials. J Sports Sci Med. 2019;18(2):316&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6543994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31191102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heathcote SL, Hassm&#xe9;n P, Zhou S, et al. Passive Heating: reviewing Practical Heat Acclimation Strategies for Endurance Athletes. Front Physiol. 2018;9:1851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6306444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30618849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downs SH, Black N. The feasibility of creating a checklist for the assessment of the methodological quality both of randomized and non-randomized studies of health care interventions. J Epidemiol Community Health. 1998;52(6):377&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1756728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9764259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piil JF, Mikkelsen CJ, Junge N, et al. Heat Acclimation Does Not Protect Trained Males from Hyperthermia-Induced Impairments in Complex Task Performance. Int J Environ Res Public Heath. 2019;16(5):716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6427404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30823366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radakovic SS, Maric J, Surbatovic M, et al. Effects of acclimation on cognitive performance in soldiers during exertional heat stress. Mil Med. 2007;172(2):133&#x2013;136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17357764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamm M, Jakobson A, Havik M, et al. Effects of heat acclimation on time perception. Int J Psychophysiol. 2015;95(3):261&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25451787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijayanto T, Toramoto S, Maeda Y, et al. Cognitive performance during passive heat exposure in Japanese males and tropical Asian males from Southeast Asian living in Japan. J Physiol Anthropol. 2017;36(1):8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5217342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28057082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racinais S, Wilson MG, Gaoua N, et al. Heat acclimation has a protective effect on the central but not peripheral nervous system. J Appl Physiol. 2017;123(4):816&#x2013;824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28684590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandelow S, Maughan R, Shirreffs S, et al. The effects of exercise, heat, cooling and rehydration strategies on cognitive function in football players. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2010;20(3):148&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21029202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamin CL, Sekiguchi Y, Morrissey M, et al. The effects of hydration status and ice-water dousing on physiological and performance indices during a simulated soccer match in the heat. J Sci Med Sport. 2021;24(8):723&#x2013;728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34140229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldwell AR, Burchfield J, Moyen NE, et al. Obesity, but not hypohydration, mediates changes in mental task load during passive heating in females. PeerJ. 2018;6:e5394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6098944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30128190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cian C, Barraud PA, Melin B, et al. Effects of fluid ingestion on cognitive function after heat stress or exercise-induced dehydration. Int J Psychophysiol. 2001;42(3):243&#x2013;251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11812391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coudevylle GR, Sinnapah S, Hue O, et al. Impact of Cold Water Intake on Environmental Perceptions, Affect, and Attention Depends on Climate Condition. Am J Psychol. 2020;133(2):205&#x2013;219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ely BR, Sollanek KJ, Cheuvront SN, et al. Hypohydration and acute thermal stress affect mood state but not cognition or dynamic postural balance. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2013;113(4):1027&#x2013;1034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23064870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundgren-Kownacki K, Dahl M, Gao C, et al. Exploring how a traditional diluted yoghurt drink may mitigate heat strain during medium-intensity intermittent work: a multidisciplinary study of occupational heat strain. Ind Health. 2018;56(2):106&#x2013;121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5889929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29057769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacLeod H, Sunderland C. Previous-day hypohydration impairs skill performance in elite female field hockey players. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2012;22(3):430&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20973829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacLeod H, Cooper S, Bandelow S, et al. Effects of heat stress and dehydration on cognitive function in elite female field hockey players. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2018;10(1):12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6007074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29946473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piil JF, Lundbye-Jensen J, Christiansen L, et al. High prevalence of hypohydration in occupations with heat stress&#x2014;Perspectives for performance in combined cognitive and motor tasks. PLoS One. 2018;13(10):e0205321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6200230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30356308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serwah N, Marino FE. The combined effects of hydration and exercise heat stress on choice reaction time. J Sci Med Sport. 2006;9(1&#x2013;2):157&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16621710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tikuisis P, Keefe AA. Heat strain at high levels does not degrade target detection and rifle marksmanship. Aviat Space Environ Med. 2005;76(10):963&#x2013;969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16235880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Heuvel AM, Haberley BJ, Hoyle DJ, et al. The independent influences of heat strain and dehydration upon cognition. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117(5):1025&#x2013;1037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28343279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aljaroudi AM, Kadis DS, Bhattacharya A, et al. Effect of continuous cooling on inhibition and attention while wearing firefighter&#x2019;s PPE in a hot environment. J Occup Environ Hyg. 2020;17(5):243&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10037206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32150701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ando S, Komiyama T, Sudo M, et al. The effects of temporal neck cooling on cognitive function during strenuous exercise in a hot environment: a pilot study. BMS Res Notes. 2015;8(1):202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4467620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26025443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldwell JN, Patterson MJ, Taylor NA. Exertional thermal strain, protective clothing and auxiliary cooling in dry heat: evidence for physiological but not cognitive impairment. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112(10):3597&#x2013;3606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22328005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke ND, Maclaren DP, Reilly T, et al. Carbohydrate ingestion and pre-cooling improves exercise capacity following soccer-specific intermittent exercise performed in the heat. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111(7):1447&#x2013;1455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21161666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke ND, Duncan MJ, Smith M, et al. Pre-cooling moderately enhances visual discrimination during exercise in the heat. J Sports Sci. 2017;35(4):355&#x2013;360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27008467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujii RK, Horie S, Tsutsui T, et al. Effectiveness of a Head Wash Cooling Protocol Using Refrigerated Water in Reducing Heat Stress. J Occup Health. 2008;50(3):251&#x2013;261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18413974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemmatjo R, Motamedzade M, Aliabadi M, et al. The effect of practical cooling strategies on physiological response and cognitive function during simulated firefighting tasks. Health Promot Perspect. 2017;7(2):66&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5350552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28326286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JK, Koh AC, Koh SX, et al. Neck cooling and cognitive performance following exercise-induced hyperthermia. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2014;114(2):375&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24318656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maroni T, Dawson B, Barnett K, et al. Effectiveness of hand cooling and a colling jacket on post-exercise cooling rates in hyperthermic athletes. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;18(4):441&#x2013;449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29364083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maroni T, Dawson B, Landers G, et al. Hand and torso pre-cooling does not enhance subsequent high-intensity cycling or cognitive performance in heat. Temperature. 2019;7(2):165&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7518759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33015244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazalan NS, Landers GJ, Wallman KE, et al. Head Cooling Prior to Exercise in the Heat Does Not Improve Cognitive Performance. J Sports Sci Med. 2021;20(1):69&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7919360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33707989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Neal EK, Bishop P. Effects of work in a hot environment on repeated performances of multiple types of simple mental tasks. Int J Ind Ergon. 2010;40(1):77&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saldaris JM, Landers GJ, Lay BS. Physical and perceptual cooling: improving cognitive function, mood disturbance and time to fatigue in the heat. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2020;30(4):801&#x2013;811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31884683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibaski M, Namba M, Oshiro M, et al. Suppression of cognitive function in hyperthermia; From the viewpoint of executive and inhibitive cognitive processing. Sci Rep. 2017;7(1):43528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5353598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28497797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simmons SE, Saxby BK, McGlone FP, et al. The effect of passive heating and head cooling on perception, cardiovascular function and cognitive performance in the heat. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008;104(2):271&#x2013;280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18214520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coull NA, Watkins SL, Aldous JW, et al. Effect of tyrosine ingestion on cognitive and physical performance utilising an intermittent soccer performance test (iSPT) in a warm environment. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2015;115(2):373&#x2013;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25326727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coull N, Chrismas B, Watson P, et al. Tyrosine Ingestion and Its Effects on Cognitive and Physical Performance in the Heat. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48(2):277&#x2013;286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26285023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Balilionis G, Casaru C, et al. Effects of caffeine and menthol on cognition and mood during simulated firefighting in the heat. Appl Ergon. 2014;45(3):510&#x2013;514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23891504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokizawa K, Sawada S, Tai T, et al. Effects of partial sleep restriction and subsequent daytime napping on prolonged exertional heat strain. Occup Environ Med. 2015;72(7):521&#x2013;528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25907211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace PJ, McKinlay BJ, Coletta NA, et al. Effects of Motivational Self-Talk on Endurance and Cognitive Performance in the Heat. Med Sci in Sports Exerc. 2017;49(1):191&#x2013;199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27580154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flouris AD, Dinas PC, Ioannou LG, et al. Workers&#x2019; health and productivity under occupational heat strain: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Planet Health. 2018;2(12):521&#x2013;531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30526938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Le&#xf3;n D, Casanueva A, Standardi G, et al. Current and projected regional economic impacts of heatwaves in Europe. Nat Commun. 2021;12(5807). DOI: 10.1038/s41467-021-26050-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-26050-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8490455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34608159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill N, Sleivert G. Effect of daily versus intermittent exposure on heat acclimation. Aviat Space Environ Med. 2001;72(4):385&#x2013;390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11318020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tyler CJ, Reeve T, Hodges GJ, et al. The Effects of Heat Adaptation on Physiology, Perception and Exercise Performance in the Heat: a Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. 2016;46(11):1699&#x2013;1724.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27106556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daanen HA, Racinais S, P&#xe9;riard JD. Heat Acclimation Decay and Re-Induction: a Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48(2):409&#x2013;430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5775394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29129022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larose J, Boulay P, Wright-Beatty HE, et al. Age-related differences in heat loss capacity occur under both dry and humid heat stress conditions. J Appl Physiol. 2014;117(1):69&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4101584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24812643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadel ER, Pandolf KB, Roberts MF, et al. Mechanisms of thermal acclimation to exercise and heat. J Appl Physiol. 1974;37(4):515&#x2013;520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4414615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuwahara T, Inoue Y, Taniguchi M, et al. Effects of physical training on heat loss responses of young women to passive heating in relation to menstrual cycle. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2005;94(4):376&#x2013;385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15864636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravanelli NE, Gagnon D, Imbeault P, et al. A retrospective analysis to determine if exercise training-induced thermoregulatory adaptations are mediated by increased fitness or heat acclimation. Exper Physiol. 2020;106(1):282&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32118324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balmain BN, Sabapathy S, Louis M, et al. Aging and Thermoregulatory Control: the Clinical Implications of Exercising under Heat Stress in Older Individuals. BioMed Res Int. 2018;2018:8306154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6098859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30155483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijayanto T, Wakabayashi H, Lee J-Y, et al. Comparison of thermoregulatory responses to heat between Malaysian and Japanese males during leg immersion. Int J Biometeorol. 2011;55(4):491&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20824480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin &#xc9;W, Mullally S, Foley C, et al. Aerobic exercise improves hippocampal function and increases BDNF in the serum of young adult males. Physiol Behav. 2011;104(5):934&#x2013;941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21722657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnan KJ, Williams EL, Stanger N. The Effects of Heat Exposure During Intermittent Exercise on Physical and Cognitive Performance Among Team Sport Athletes. Percept Mot Skills. 2021;128(1):439&#x2013;466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7859587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33076764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMorris T, Sproule J, Turner A, et al. Acute, intermediate intensity exercise, and speed and accuracy in working memory tasks: a meta-analytical comparison of effects. Physiol Behav. 2011;102(3&#x2013;4):421&#x2013;428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21163278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eccles R. Role of cold receptors and menthol in thirst, the drive to breathe and arousal. Appetite. 2000;34(1):29&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10744889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flood TR, Waldron M, Jeffries O. Oral l-menthol reduces thermal sensation, increases work-rate and extends time to exhaustion, in the heat at a fixed rating of perceived exertion. Eur J App Physiol. 2017;117(7):1501&#x2013;1512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28508114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens CJ, Best R. Menthol: a Fresh Ergogenic Aid for Athletic Performance. Sports Med. 2017;47(6):1035&#x2013;1042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27858306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis JM. Nutrition, neurotransmitters and central nervous system fatigue. In: Maughan RJ, editor. Nutrition in Sport. Oxford; UK: Blackwell Science Ltd; 2000. p. 171&#x2013;183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jongkees B, Hommel B, K&#xfc;hn S, et al. Effect of tyrosine supplementation on clinical and healthy populations under stress or cognitive demands &#x2013; a review. J Psychiatr Res. 2015;70:50&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26424423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordeiro LM, Rabelo PC, Moraes MM, et al. Physical exercise-induced fatigue: the role of serotonergic and dopaminergic systems. Braz J Med Biol Res. 2017;50(12):e6432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5649871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29069229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson P, Hasegawa H, Roelands B, et al. Acute dopamine/noradrenaline reuptake inhibition enhances human exercise performance in warm, but not temperate conditions. J Physiol. 2005;565(3):873&#x2013;883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1464564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15831540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieoullon A. Dopamine and the regulation of cognition and attention. Prog Neurobiol. 2002;67(1):53&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12126656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tumilty L, Davison G, Beckmann M, et al. Oral tyrosine supplementation improves exercise capacity in the heat. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2011;111(12):2941&#x2013;2950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21437603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tumilty L, Davison G, Beckmann M, et al. Failure of oral tyrosine supplementation to improve exercise performance in the heat. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2014;46(7):1417&#x2013;1425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24389518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke Z, Yip SP, Li L, et al. The effects of voluntary, involuntary, and forced exercises on brain-derived neurotrophic factor and motor function recovery: a rat brain ischemia model. PLoS One. 2011;6(2):e16643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3035657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21347437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lander PJ, Butterly RJ, Edwards AM. Self-paced exercise is less physically challenging than enforced constant pace exercise of the same intensity: influence of complex central metabolic control. Br J Sports Med. 2009;43(10):789&#x2013;795.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19196729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malcolm RA, Cooper S, Folland JP, et al. Passive Heat Exposure Alters Perception and Executive Function. Front Physiol. 2018;9:585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5981197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29887804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hocking C, Silberstein RB, Lau WM, et al. Evaluation of cognitive performance in the heat by functional brain imaging and psychometric testing. Comp Biochem Physiol A Mol Integr Physiol. 2001;128(4):719&#x2013;734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11282316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Kwon JH, Kim J, et al. The effects of positive or negative self-talk on the alteration of brain functional connectivity by performing cognitive tasks. Sci Rep. 2021;11(1):14873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8295361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34290300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walter N, Nikoleizig L, Alfermann D. Effects of Self-Talk Training on Competitive Anxiety, Self-Efficacy, Volitional Skills, and Performance: an Intervention Study with Junior Sub-Elite Athletes. Sports (Basel). 2019;7(6):148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6628429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31248129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shannon V, Gentner NB, Patel A, et al. Striking gold: mental techniques and preparation strategies used by Olympic gold medallists. Athl Insight: Online J Sport Psychol. 2012;14(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanchfield AW, Hardy J, de Morree HM, et al. Talking Yourself Out of Exhaustion: the Effects of Self-talk on Endurance Performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2014;46(5):998&#x2013;1007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24121242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barwood MJ, Corbett J, Wagstaff CR, et al. Improvement of 10-km Time-Trial Cycling With Motivational Self-Talk Compared With Neutral Self-Talk. International J Sports Physiol Perform. 2015;10(2):166&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25010539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatzigeorgiadis A, Bartura K, Argiropoulos C, et al. Beat the Heat: effects of a Motivational Self-Talk Intervention on Endurance Performance. J Appl Sport Psychol. 2018;30(4):388&#x2013;401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutchins KP, Borg DN, Bach AJ, et al. Female (Under) Representation in Exercise Thermoregulation Research. Sports Med - Open. 2021;43(7):43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8219822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34156570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliot-Sale KJ, Minahan CL, Janse de Jonge XA, et al. Methodological Considerations for Studies in Sport and Exercise Science with Women as Participants: a Working Guide for Standards of Practice for Research on Women. Sports Med. 2021;51(5):843&#x2013;861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8053180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33725341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>