<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41541537</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2666-061X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Arthroscopy, sports medicine, and rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cartilage Scaffolds Implanted Without Subchondral Drilling Are Associated With Improved Outcomes and Fewer Complications Compared to Scaffolds Implanted With Subchondral Drilling in the Treatment of Isolated Patellar Cartilage Lesions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>101299</StartPage><MedlinePgn>101299</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">101299</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.asmr.2025.101299</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To compare clinical outcomes between augmented subchondral drilling (aSCD) and nonsubchondral drilling (NoSCD) techniques, both using a cartilage scaffold, in the treatment of isolated patellar cartilage lesions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A retrospective cohort study was conducted on patients who underwent surgical treatment for isolated patellar cartilage using either an aSCD technique (a subchondral drilling augmented with a particulated cartilage allograft scaffold or a flexible osteochondral allograft scaffold) or a NoSCD technique (a particulated juvenile articular cartilage scaffold or a flexible osteochondral allograft scaffold implanted without performing a subchondral drilling). Patients were included if they had a minimum 2-year follow-up and excluded if they underwent concomitant meniscal or ligamentous procedures. While tibial tubercle osteotomy (TTO) was commonly performed, it was not a strict inclusion criterion. All procedures were performed through arthrotomy with a standardized postoperative rehabilitation protocol. Clinical outcomes included International Knee Documentation Committee (IKDC) and Lysholm scores, reoperation rates, conversion to total knee arthroplasty, and complications.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 65 knees were included: 31 in the aSCD group and 34 in the NoSCD group, with a mean follow-up of 50.4 months (range, 24-88 months). In the aSCD group, particulated allograft cartilage hydrated with platelet-rich plasma was used in 80.7% of cases and flexible osteochondral allograft in 19.3%, while the NoSCD group was treated with Cartiform (Arthrex) in 70.6% and particulated juvenile articular cartilage in 29.4% of cases. TTO was performed in 87.0% of aSCD and 91.2% of NoSCD cases. Average defect sizes were 3.7 cm<sup>2</sup> (aSCD) and 4.0 cm<sup>2</sup> (NoSCD). At final follow-up, the NoSCD group had significantly better outcomes, with higher median IKDC scores (81.0 vs 74.0; <i>P</i> &lt; .001) and median Lysholm scores (83.0 vs 77.0; <i>P</i> &lt; .001). A significantly greater proportion of NoSCD patients exceeded the minimal clinically important difference for IKDC (100% vs 80.6%; <i>P</i> = .024) but not for Lysholm (97.1% vs 93.5%; <i>P</i> = .935) at final follow-up. In multivariable regression adjusting for scaffold type, TTO, and defect size, aSCD remained a significant independent predictor of lower final IKDC (&#x3b2; = -8.97; <i>P</i> = .001) and Lysholm (&#x3b2; = -12.71; <i>P</i> &lt; .001) scores. The aSCD group had a significantly higher rate of repeat surgery (45.2% vs 14.7%; <i>P</i> = .015). There was no significant difference in conversion to total knee arthroplasty between groups (<i>P</i> = .432).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">For the treatment of isolated patellar cartilage lesions, a nonsubchondral drilling technique with scaffolding was associated with improved patient-reported outcomes and fewer complications compared to a subchondral drilling technique with scaffolding, although there was no difference in the rate of conversion to total knee arthroplasty.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Level III, retrospective comparative study.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parmar</LastName><ForeName>Romir P</ForeName><Initials>RP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mayo Clinic Arizona Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Phoenix, Arizona, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tummala</LastName><ForeName>Sailesh V</ForeName><Initials>SV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mayo Clinic Arizona Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Phoenix, Arizona, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pathuri</LastName><ForeName>Sachin S</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Creighton University School of Medicine, Phoenix, Arizona, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shah</LastName><ForeName>Jainam</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Albert Einstein College of Medicine, Bronx, New York, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khurmi</LastName><ForeName>Jai</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mayo Clinic Arizona Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Phoenix, Arizona, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Economopoulos</LastName><ForeName>Kostas J</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mayo Clinic Arizona Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Phoenix, Arizona, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101765256</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2666-061X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: S.V.T. has received education support from ImpactOrtho and hospitality payments from Stryker. K.J.E. has received hospitality payments from ImpactOrtho and Zimmer Biomet Holdings. All other authors (R.P.P., S.S.P., J.S., J.K.) declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41541537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12800826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asmr.2025.101299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2666-061X(25)00225-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Camarero-Espinosa S., Rothen-Rutishauser B., Foster E.J., Weder C. Articular cartilage: From formation to tissue engineering. Biomater Sci. 2016;4:734&#x2013;767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26923076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickett A., Hensley D. Knee cell-based cartilage restoration. J Knee Surg. 2019;32:127&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30630211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinckel B.B., Pratte E.L., Baumann C.A., et al. Patellofemoral cartilage restoration: A systematic review and meta-analysis of clinical outcomes. Am J Sports Med. 2020;48:1756&#x2013;1772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31899868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steadman J.R., Rodkey W.G., Rodrigo J.J. Microfracture: Surgical technique and rehabilitation to treat chondral defects. Clin Orthop. 2001;391:S362&#x2013;S369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eldracher M., Orth P., Cucchiarini M., Pape D., Madry H. Small subchondral drill holes improve marrow stimulation of articular cartilage defects. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42:2741&#x2013;2750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25167994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraeutler M.J., Aliberti G.M., Scillia A.J., McCarty E.C., Mulcahey M.K. Microfracture versus drilling of articular cartilage defects: A systematic review of the basic science evidence. Orthop J Sports Med. 2020;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farr J., Tabet S.K., Margerrison E., Cole B.J. Clinical, radiographic, and histological outcomes after cartilage repair with particulated juvenile articular cartilage: A 2-year prospective study. Am J Sports Med. 2014;42:1417&#x2013;1425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24718790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fortier L.A., Chapman H.S., Pownder S.L., et al. BioCartilage improves cartilage repair compared with microfracture alone in an equine model of full-thickness cartilage loss. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44:2366&#x2013;2374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27298478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fortier L.M., Knapik D.M., Dasari S.P., et al. Clinical and magnetic resonance imaging outcomes after microfracture treatment with and without augmentation for focal chondral lesions in the knee: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Sports Med. 2023;51:2193&#x2013;2206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35736251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pa&#x142;ka K., Kubisa M., Akbas A., Kubisa M., Dobrakowski M. Does scaffold enhancement show significant superiority over microfracture alone for treating knee chondral defects? A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised clinical trials. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33:2027&#x2013;2043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39369429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mithoefer K., Venugopal V., Manaqibwala M. Incidence, degree, and clinical effect of subchondral bone overgrowth after microfracture in the knee. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44:2057&#x2013;2063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27190069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tompkins M., Hamann J.C., Diduch D.R., et al. Preliminary results of a novel single-stage cartilage restoration technique: Particulated juvenile articular cartilage allograft for chondral defects of the patella. Arthroscopy. 2013;29:1661&#x2013;1670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23876608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adkisson H.D., Martin J.A., Amendola R.L., et al. The potential of human allogeneic juvenile chondrocytes for restoration of articular cartilage. Am J Sports Med. 2010;38:1324&#x2013;1333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3774103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20423988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen B.B., Olesen M.L., Hede K.T.C., Bergholt N.L., Foldager C.B., Lind M. Particulated cartilage for chondral and osteochondral repair: A review. Cartilage. 2021;13(suppl):1047S&#x2013;1057S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8808866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32052642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altschuler N., Zaslav K.R., Di Matteo B., et al. Aragonite-based scaffold versus microfracture and debridement for the treatment of knee chondral and osteochondral lesions: Results of a multicenter randomized controlled trial. Am J Sports Med. 2023;51:957&#x2013;967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36779614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pa&#x142;ka K., Kubisa M., Akbas A., Kubisa M., Dobrakowski M. Does scaffold enhancement show significant superiority over microfracture alone for treating knee chondral defects? A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised clinical trials. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2025;33:2027&#x2013;2043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39369429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seewoonarain S., Ganesh D., Perera E., et al. Scaffold-associated procedures are superior to microfracture in managing focal cartilage defects in the knee: A systematic review &amp; meta-analysis. Knee. 2023;42:320&#x2013;338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37148615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellgren J.H., Lawrence J.S. Radiological assessment of osteo-arthrosis. Ann Rheum Dis. 1957;16:494&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1006995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13498604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohn M.D., Sassoon A.A., Fernando N.D. Classifications in brief: Kellgren-Lawrence classification of osteoarthritis. Clin Orthop. 2016;474:1886&#x2013;1893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4925407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26872913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Th&#xe9;venin-Lemoine C., Ferrand M., Courvoisier A., Damsin J.P., Ducou Le Pointe H., Vialle R. Is the Caton-Deschamps Index a valuable ratio to investigate patellar height in children? J Bone Jt Surg. 2011;93</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seil R., M&#xfc;ller B., Georg T., Kohn D., Rupp S. Reliability and interobserver variability in radiological patellar height ratios. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2000;8:231&#x2013;236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10975264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irrgang J.J., Anderson A.F., Boland A.L., et al. Development and validation of the International Knee Documentation Committee Subjective Knee Form. Am J Sports Med. 2001;29:600&#x2013;613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11573919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briggs K.K., Lysholm J., Tegner Y., Rodkey W.G., Kocher M.S., Steadman J.R. The reliability, validity, and responsiveness of the Lysholm score and Tegner Activity Scale for anterior cruciate ligament injuries of the knee: 25 Years later. Am J Sports Med. 2009;37:890&#x2013;897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19261899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gobbi A., Karnatzikos G., Kumar A. Long-term results after microfracture treatment for full-thickness knee chondral lesions in athletes. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2014;22:1986&#x2013;1996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24051505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solheim E., Hegna J., Inderhaug E., &#xd8;yen J., Harlem T., Strand T. Results at 10&#x2013;14 years after microfracture treatment of articular cartilage defects in the knee. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2016;24:1587&#x2013;1593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25416965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole B.J., Haunschild E.D., Carter T., et al. Clinically significant outcomes following the treatment of focal cartilage defects of the knee with microfracture augmentation using cartilage allograft extracellular matrix: A multicenter prospective study. Arthroscopy. 2021;37:1512&#x2013;1521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33539978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim M.S., Chun C.H., Wang J.H., et al. Microfractures versus a porcine-derived collagen-augmented chondrogenesis technique for treating knee cartilage defects: A multicenter randomized controlled trial. Arthroscopy. 2020;36:1612&#x2013;1624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31785390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopinatth V., Jackson G.R., Touhey D.C., et al. Microfracture for medium size to large knee chondral defects has limited long-term efficacy: A systematic review. J Exp Orthop. 2024;11</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langhans M.T., Strickland S.M., Gomoll A.H. Management of chondral defects associated with patella instability. Clin Sports Med. 2022;41:137&#x2013;155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34782070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyu J., Zhang Y., Zhu W., et al. Correlation between the subchondral bone marrow lesions and cartilage repair tissue after matrix-associated autologous chondrocyte implantation in the knee: A cross-sectional study. Acta Radiol. 2021;62:1072&#x2013;1079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33183061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minas T., Gomoll A.H., Rosenberger R., Royce R.O., Bryant T. Increased failure rate of autologous chondrocyte implantation after previous treatment with marrow stimulation techniques. Am J Sports Med. 2009;37:902&#x2013;908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19261905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearsall C., Chen A.Z., Reynolds A.W., et al. Particulated juvenile articular cartilage allograft transplantation for patellofemoral defects shows favorable return-to-sport rates and patient-reported outcomes. Arthroscopy. 2024;40:2875&#x2013;2883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38395270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marmor W.A., Dennis E.R., Buza S.S., et al. Outcomes of particulated juvenile articular cartilage and association with defect fill in patients with full-thickness patellar chondral lesions. Orthop J Sports Med. 2024;12</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonasia D.E., Martin J.A., Marmotti A., et al. The use of autologous adult, allogenic juvenile, and combined juvenile&#x2013;adult cartilage fragments for the repair of chondral defects. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2016;24:3988&#x2013;3996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4531112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25876104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae D.K., Song S.J., Yoon K.H., Heo D.B., Kim T.J. Survival analysis of microfracture in the osteoarthritic knee&#x2014;minimum 10-year follow-up. Arthroscopy. 2013;29:244&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23369477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller B., Steadman J., Briggs K., Rodrigo J., Rodkey W. Patient satisfaction and outcome after microfracture of the degenerative knee. J Knee Surg. 2010;17:13&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>