<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38066105</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of alkali metals on physical and spectroscopic properties of cellulose.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>21649</StartPage><MedlinePgn>21649</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">21649</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-023-48850-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>A 3-unit cellulose model molecule was built and optimized using DFT B3LYP/6-31G(d,p). The electronic properties of the optimized structure of cellulose were investigated in terms of total dipole moment (TDM), HOMO-LUMO band gap (&#x394;E), and molecular electrostatic potential (MESP). Cellulose demonstrated a TDM of 9.106 Debye and &#x394;E of 7.647&#xa0;eV. The hydrogen atom of the hydroxyl group of the CH<sub>2</sub>OH group of each cellulose unit was replaced by an alkali metal atom (X) such that the 3-unit cellulose once had 1X atom, then 2X, then 3X atoms, where X&#x2009;=&#x2009;Li, Na or K, both without and with 2, 4 and 6 water molecules (W), respectively, to study also the effect of hydration. Without hydration, the values of TDM decreased for all of the proposed interaction, but increased with hydration, while &#x394;E decreased in all interactions, confirming that interaction cellulose-alkali metal interaction, especially with hydration, resulted in more reactive structures. Mapping of HOMO-LUMO and MESP indicated significant change in the electron density distribution around cellulose under the effect of interaction with the alkali metals, both with and without hydration. The plots of projected density of states also clearly demonstrated the contribution of each alkali metal as well as water in the molecular orbitals, reflecting their effect on the electronic properties of cellulose and cellulose-alkali metals composites. The theoretical calculations were experimentally verified using FTIR and FT-Raman spectroscopy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Refaat</LastName><ForeName>Ahmed</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Spectroscopy Department, National Research Centre, 33 El-Bohouth St., Dokki, Giza, 12622, Egypt. am.refaat@nrc.sci.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Molecular Modeling and Spectroscopy Laboratory, Centre of Excellence for Advanced Science, National Research Centre, 33 El-Bohouth St., Dokki, Giza, 12622, Egypt. am.refaat@nrc.sci.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elhaes</LastName><ForeName>Hanan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physics Department, Faculty of Women for Arts, Science and Education, Ain Shams University, Cairo, 11757, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ibrahim</LastName><ForeName>Medhat A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Spectroscopy Department, National Research Centre, 33 El-Bohouth St., Dokki, Giza, 12622, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Molecular Modeling and Spectroscopy Laboratory, Centre of Excellence for Advanced Science, National Research Centre, 33 El-Bohouth St., Dokki, Giza, 12622, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38066105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10709645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-48850-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-023-48850-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aziz T, et al. Challenges associated with cellulose composite material: Facet engineering and prospective. Environ. Res. 2023;223:115429. doi: 10.1016/j.envres.2023.115429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2023.115429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36746207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klemm D, Heublein B, Fink HP, Bohn A. Cellulose: Fascinating biopolymer and sustainable raw material. Angew. Chem. Int. Edit. 2005;44(22):3358&#x2013;3393. doi: 10.1002/anie.200460587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.200460587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15861454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seddiqi H, Oliaei E, Honarkar H, et al. Cellulose and its derivatives: towards biomedical applications. Cellulose. 2021;28:1893&#x2013;1931. doi: 10.1007/s10570-020-03674-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10570-020-03674-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinze T. Cellulose: structure and properties. In: Rojas O, editor. Cellulose Chemistry and Properties: Fibers Nanocelluloses and Advanced Materials. Springer; 2015. pp. 1&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tayeb AH, Amini E, Ghasemi S, Tajvidi M. Cellulose nanomaterials&#x2014;binding properties and applications: A review. Molecules. 2018;23:2684. doi: 10.3390/molecules23102684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules23102684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6222763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30340374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubbe M, Rojas OJ, Lucia L. Green modification of surface characteristics of cellulosic materials at the molecular or nano scale: A review. BioResources. 2015;10:6095&#x2013;6206. doi: 10.15376/biores.10.3.Hubbe.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15376/biores.10.3.Hubbe</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalia S, Dufresne A, Cherian M, Kaith B, Av&#xe9;rous L, Njuguna J, Nassiopoulos E. Cellulose-based bio- and nanocomposites: A review. Int. J. Polym. Sci. 2011;2011:1&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishiyama Y. Molecular interactions in nanocellulose assembly. Philos. Trans. A Math. Phys. Eng. Sci. 2018;376(2112):20170047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29277744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wohlert M, et al. Cellulose and the role of hydrogen bonds: Not in charge of everything. Cellulose. 2022;29:1&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1007/s10570-021-04325-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10570-021-04325-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherian RM, et al. A review on the emerging applications of nano-cellulose as advanced coatings. Carbohydr. Polym. 2022;282:119123. doi: 10.1016/j.carbpol.2022.119123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbpol.2022.119123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35123749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu-Zurayk R, Alnairat N, Khalaf A, Ibrahim AA, Halaweh G. Cellulose acetate membranes: Fouling types and antifouling strategies&#x2014;A brief review. Processes. 2023;11:489. doi: 10.3390/pr11020489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pr11020489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan Y, Wu J, Qi W, Su R. Eco-friendly marine antifouling coating consisting of cellulose nanocrystals with bioinspired micromorphology. Carbohydr. Polym. 2023;304:120504. doi: 10.1016/j.carbpol.2022.120504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbpol.2022.120504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36641170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koh JJ, et al. 3D-printed anti-fouling cellulose mesh for highly efficient oil/water separation applications. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2019;11(14):13787&#x2013;13795. doi: 10.1021/acsami.9b01753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.9b01753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30884229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kollarigowda RH, Abraham S, Montemagno CD. Antifouling cellulose hybrid biomembrane for effective oil/water separation. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2017;9(35):29812&#x2013;29819. doi: 10.1021/acsami.7b09087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.7b09087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28796485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng W, et al. Sustainable cellulose and its derivatives for promising biomedical applications. Prog. Mater. Sci. 2023;138:101152. doi: 10.1016/j.pmatsci.2023.101152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pmatsci.2023.101152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelhamid HN, Mathew AP. Cellulose-based nanomaterials advance biomedicine: A review. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2022;23(10):5405. doi: 10.3390/ijms23105405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23105405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9140895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35628218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fatema N, Ceballos RM, Fan C. Modifications of cellulose-based biomaterials for biomedical applications. Front. Bioeng. Biotechnol. 2022;10:993711. doi: 10.3389/fbioe.2022.993711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fbioe.2022.993711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9669591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36406218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasanin MS. Cellulose-based biomaterials: chemistry and biomedical applications. Starch - St&#xe4;rke. 2022;74:2200060. doi: 10.1002/star.202200060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/star.202200060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Ng K, Warner RD, Stockmann R, Fang Z. Application of cellulose- and chitosan-based edible coatings for quality and safety of deep-fried foods. Compr. Rev. Food. Sci. F. 2023;22:1418&#x2013;1437. doi: 10.1111/1541-4337.13116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1541-4337.13116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36717375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spagnuolo L, D'Orsi R, Operamolla A. Nanocellulose for paper and textile coating: The importance of surface chemistry. ChemPlusChem. 2022;87:e202200204. doi: 10.1002/cplu.202200204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cplu.202200204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36000154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amoroso L, et al. Sustainable cellulose nanofiber films from carrot pomace as sprayable coatings for food packaging applications. ACS Sustainable Chem. Eng. 2022;10:342&#x2013;352. doi: 10.1021/acssuschemeng.1c06345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acssuschemeng.1c06345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camargos CHM, Poggi G, Chelazzi D, Baglioni P, Rezende CA. Protective coatings based on cellulose nanofibrils, cellulose nanocrystals, and lignin nanoparticles for the conservation of cellulosic artifacts. ACS Appl. Nano Mater. 2022;5:13245&#x2013;13259. doi: 10.1021/acsanm.2c02968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsanm.2c02968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F, Biagioni P, Bollani M, Maccagnan A, Piergiovanni L. Multi-functional coating of cellulose nanocrystals for flexible packaging applications. Cellulose. 2013;20:2491&#x2013;2504. doi: 10.1007/s10570-013-0015-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10570-013-0015-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, et al. Assembly of silver nanowires and PEDOT:PSS with hydrocellulose toward highly flexible, transparent and conductivity-stable conductors. J. Chem. Eng. 2020;392:123644. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2019.123644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2019.123644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park G, et al. Green nanoarchitectonics for next generation electronics devices: Patterning of conductive nanowires on regenerated cellulose substrates. Cellulose. 2022;29:2449&#x2013;2460. doi: 10.1007/s10570-022-04435-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10570-022-04435-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darabi S, et al. Green conducting cellulose yarns for machine-sewn electronic textiles. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2020;12:56403&#x2013;56412. doi: 10.1021/acsami.0c15399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.0c15399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7747218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33284024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu S, et al. Biodegradable, super-strong, and conductive cellulose macrofibers for fabric-based triboelectric nanogenerator. Nanomicro. Lett. 2022;14:115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9050994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35482231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Hu L. Nanocellulose toward advanced energy storage devices: Structure and electrochemistry. Acc. Chem. Res. 2018;51:3154&#x2013;3165. doi: 10.1021/acs.accounts.8b00391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.accounts.8b00391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30299086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng CP, et al. Advances in cellulose-based composites for energy applications. Materials. 2023;16:3856. doi: 10.3390/ma16103856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16103856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10221535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37241483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyamayaro K, Hatzikiriakos SG, Mehrkhodavandi P. Utilizing cellulose-based conducting hydrogels in iontronics. RSC Sustainability. 2023;1:1369. doi: 10.1039/D3SU00139C.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D3SU00139C</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu M, Jia C, Fang Z, Hu L. Nanocellulose-based composites: Optoelectronic applications. In: Yang G, Ullah MW, Shi Z, editors. Nanocellulose. World Scientific; 2021. pp. 377&#x2013;405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo Y, Zhang J, Li X, Liao C, Li X. The cellulose nanofibers for optoelectronic conversion and energy storage. J. Nanomater. 2014;2014:654512.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu H, et al. Extreme light management in mesoporous wood cellulose paper for optoelectronics. ACS Nano. 2016;10:1369&#x2013;1377. doi: 10.1021/acsnano.5b06781.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsnano.5b06781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26673796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarwar S, et al. Deciphering the role of alkali metals (Li, Na, K) doping for triggering nonlinear optical (NLO) properties of t-graphene quantum dots: Toward the development of giant NLO response materials. ACS Omega. 2022;7:24396&#x2013;24414. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.2c01746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.2c01746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9301704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35874249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu B, et al. Synthesis of alkali metals functionalized porous carbon for enhanced selective adsorption of carbon dioxide: A theoretically guided study. Energy Fuels. 2021;35:15962&#x2013;15968. doi: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.1c02313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.1c02313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobrota AS, et al. Stabilization of alkali metal ions interaction with OH-functionalized graphene via clustering of OH groups&#x2014;implications in charge storage applications. RSC Adv. 2016;6:57910&#x2013;57919. doi: 10.1039/C6RA13509A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C6RA13509A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain T, Pathak B, Maark TA, Ramzan M, Ahuja R. Functionalization of graphane with alkali and alkaline-earth metals: An insulator-to-metallic transition. EPL. 2012;99:47004. doi: 10.1209/0295-5075/99/47004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1209/0295-5075/99/47004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim MA, et al. Molecular modeling analyses for the effect of alkali metal oxides on graphene. Biointerface Res. Appl. Chem. 2018;8:3522&#x2013;3525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beni FA, Shahrak MN. Alkali metals-promoted capacity of ZIF-8 and ZIF-90 for carbon capturing: A molecular simulation study. Polyhedron. 2020;178:114338. doi: 10.1016/j.poly.2019.114338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.poly.2019.114338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badry R, et al. Effect of alkaline elements on the structure and electronic properties of glycine. Biointerface Res. Appl. Chem. 2018;8:3682&#x2013;3687.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badry R, et al. Effect of Li, Na, K, Be, Mg and Ca on the electronic properties, geometrical parameters of carboxylic acids. Biointerface Res. Appl. Chem. 2018;8:3657&#x2013;3660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badry R, Shaban H, Elhaes H, Refaat A, Ibrahim M. Molecular modeling analyses of polyaniline substituted with alkali and alkaline earth elements. Biointerface Res. Appl. Chem. 2018;8:3719&#x2013;3724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan X, Xu Y. Recent trends and applications of molecular modeling in GPCR&#x2013;ligand recognition and structure-based drug design. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2018;19:2105. doi: 10.3390/ijms19072105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms19072105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6073596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30036949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubbins KE, Liu YC, Moore JD, Palmer JC. The role of molecular modeling in confined systems: Impact and prospects. Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2011;13:58&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1039/C0CP01475C.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C0CP01475C</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21116563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiama TM, et al. Molecular and biological activities of metal oxide-modified bioactive glass. Sci Rep. 2023;13:10637. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-37017-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-37017-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10313761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37391463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safi ZS, Wazzan N. DFT calculations of 1H- and 13C-NMR chemical shifts of 3-methyl-1-phenyl-4-(phenyldiazenyl)-1H-pyrazol-5-amine in solution. Sci Rep. 2022;12:17798. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-22900-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-22900-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9588065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36273019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leng C, et al. Theoretical study of cellulose II nanocrystals with different exposed facets. Sci Rep. 2021;11:21871. doi: 10.1038/s41598-021-01438-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-01438-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8576008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34750490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava D, Ahopelto J, Karttunen AJ. Thermodynamic properties of crystalline cellulose allomorphs studied with dispersion-corrected density functional methods. Molecules. 2022;27:6240. doi: 10.3390/molecules27196240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules27196240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9570836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36234777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera-Morales J, et al. Examining the use of nanocellulose composites for the sorption of contaminants of emerging concern: An experimental and computational study. ACS Omega. 2017;2:7714&#x2013;7722. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.7b01053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.7b01053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6645408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31457328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jani&#x107;ijevi&#x107; A, et al. Structural characterization of nanocellulose/Fe3O4 hybrid nanomaterials. Polymers (Basel) 2022;14:1819. doi: 10.3390/polym14091819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym14091819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9101848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35566987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uto T, Yui T. DFT optimization of isolated molecular chain sheet models constituting native cellulose crystal structures. ACS Omega. 2018;3:8050&#x2013;8058. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.8b00834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.8b00834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6644672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31458942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu C, et al. Adsorption behavior of cellulose and its derivatives toward Ag(I) in aqueous medium: An AFM, spectroscopic, and DFT study. Langmuir. 2015;31:12390&#x2013;12400. doi: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.5b03228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.5b03228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26501836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubicki JD, Mohamed MN-A, Watts HD. Quantum mechanical modeling of the structures, energetics and spectral properties of I&#x3b1; and I&#x3b2; cellulose. Cellulose. 2013;20:9&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1007/s10570-012-9838-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10570-012-9838-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frisch M, Gaussian 09, Revision C.01 et al. Gaussian Inc. CT: Wallingford; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becke AD. Density-functional thermochemistry. III. The role of exact exchange. J. Chem. Phys. 1993;98:5648&#x2013;5652. doi: 10.1063/1.464913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.464913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee C, Yang W, Parr RG. Development of the Colle-Salvetti correlation-energy formula into a functional of the electron density. Phys. Rev. B Condens. Matter. 1988;37(2):785&#x2013;789. doi: 10.1103/PhysRevB.37.785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.37.785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9944570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miehlich B, Savin A, Stoll H, Preuss H. Results obtained with the correlation energy density functionals of becke and Lee. Yang and Parr. Chem. Phys. Lett. 1989;157(3):200&#x2013;206. doi: 10.1016/0009-2614(89)87234-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0009-2614(89)87234-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Boyle NM, Tenderholt AL, Langner KM. cclib: A library for package-independent computational chemistry algorithms. J. Comp. Chem. 2008;29:839&#x2013;845. doi: 10.1002/jcc.20823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcc.20823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17849392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen AB, Holder AJ. GaussView 5.0 User&#x2019;s Reference. GAUSSIAN Inc.; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Q, Dereka B, Vauthey E, Daku LML, Hauser A. Ultrafast transient IR spectroscopy and DFT calculations of ruthenium(II) polypyridyl complexes. Chem. Sci. 2017;8:223&#x2013;230. doi: 10.1039/C6SC01220E.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C6SC01220E</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5308284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28451169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cichosz S, Masek A, Dems-Rudnicka K. Original study on mathematical models for analysis of cellulose water content from absorbance/wavenumber shifts in ATR FT-IR spectrum. Sci Rep. 2022;12:19739. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-24097-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-24097-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9672360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36396855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barsberg S. Prediction of vibrational spectra of polysaccharides-simulated ir spectrum of cellulose based on density functional theory (DFT) J. Phys. Chem. B. 2010;114:11703&#x2013;11708. doi: 10.1021/jp104213z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp104213z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20726541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adeleye OA, et al. Characterizations of alpha-cellulose and microcrystalline cellulose isolated from cocoa pod husk as a potential pharmaceutical excipient. Materials. 2022;15:5992. doi: 10.3390/ma15175992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15175992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9457090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36079372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang M, et al. Synthesis mechanism of carbon microsphere from waste office paper via hydrothermal method. BioResources. 2022;17:5568&#x2013;5577. doi: 10.15376/biores.17.4.5568-5577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15376/biores.17.4.5568-5577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller DD, Smith MW, Shekhawat D. Microwave-induced selective decomposition of cellulose: Computational and experimental mechanistic study. J. Phys. Chem. Solids. 2021;150:109858. doi: 10.1016/j.jpcs.2020.109858.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpcs.2020.109858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lekha P, et al. Effect of mechanical treatment on properties of cellulose nanofibrils produced from bleached hardwood and softwood pulps. Maderas. Ciencia y tecnolog&#xed;a. 2016;18:457&#x2013;466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gea S, et al. Investigation into the structural, morphological, mechanical and thermal behaviour of bacterial cellulose after a two-step purification process. Bioresour. Technol. 2011;102:9105&#x2013;9110. doi: 10.1016/j.biortech.2011.04.077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biortech.2011.04.077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21835613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M, et al. Cross-flow deposited hydroxyethyl cellulose (HEC)/polypropylene (PP) thin-film composite membrane for aqueous and non-aqueous nanofiltration. Chemical Engineering Research and Design. 2020;153:572&#x2013;581. doi: 10.1016/j.cherd.2019.11.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cherd.2019.11.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, et al. Structure and properties of novel regenerated cellulose fibers prepared in NaOH complex solution. Carbohyd. Polym. 2013;98:1031&#x2013;1038. doi: 10.1016/j.carbpol.2013.06.076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carbpol.2013.06.076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23987444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shari S, et al. Subsolidus solution and ionic conductivity of rock-salt structured Li3+5xTa1&#x2212;xO4 electroceramics. Mater. Sci-Poland. 2020;38(3):465&#x2013;474. doi: 10.2478/msp-2020-0047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/msp-2020-0047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker SF, Revill-Hivet EJ, Nye DW, Gutmann MJ. Structure and vibrational spectroscopy of lithium and potassium methanesulfonates. R. Soc. Open Sci. 2020;7:200776. doi: 10.1098/rsos.200776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rsos.200776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7428240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32874662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian N, Hua C, Wang Z, Chen L. Reversible reduction of Li2CO3. J. Mater. Chem. A. 2015;3:14173&#x2013;14177. doi: 10.1039/C5TA02499D.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C5TA02499D</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halizan MZM, Mohamed Z, Yahya AK. Understanding the structural, optical, and dielectric characteristics of SrLaLiTe1&#x2212;xMnxO6 perovskites. Sci. Rep. 2021;11:9744. doi: 10.1038/s41598-021-89132-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-89132-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8105392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33963258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elkhoshkhany N, et al. Investigation of structural and luminescence properties of borosilicate glass doped with Dy2O3. Results Phys. 2021;27:104544. doi: 10.1016/j.rinp.2021.104544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rinp.2021.104544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao E, et al. Unraveling the promotional effects of K-doping on the mobility of surface oxygen species of CoCr2O4 for improved formaldehyde catalytic oxidation: The weakened metal-oxygen bond strength. Chem. Eng. J. 2023;474:145618. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2023.145618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2023.145618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagheri M, Komsa H-P. High-throughput computation of Raman spectra from first principles. Sci. Data. 2023;10:80. doi: 10.1038/s41597-023-01988-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41597-023-01988-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9908888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36755025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kou Z, Hashemi A, Puska MJ, Krasheninnikov AV, Komsa H-P. Simulating Raman spectra by combining first-principles and empirical potential approaches with application to defective MoS2. npj Comput. Mater. 2020;6:59. doi: 10.1038/s41524-020-0320-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41524-020-0320-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makarem M, et al. Probing cellulose structures with vibrational spectroscopy. Cellulose. 2019;26:35&#x2013;79. doi: 10.1007/s10570-018-2199-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10570-018-2199-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiley JH, Atalla RH. Band assignments in the raman spectra of celluloses. Carbohyd. Res. 1987;160:113&#x2013;129. doi: 10.1016/0008-6215(87)80306-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0008-6215(87)80306-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee CM, Mohamed NMA, Watts HD, Kubicki JD, Kim SH. Sum-frequency-generation vibration spectroscopy and density functional theory calculations with dispersion corrections (DFT-D2) for cellulose I&#x3b1; and I&#x3b2;. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2013;117:6681&#x2013;6692. doi: 10.1021/jp402998s.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp402998s</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23738844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal UP, Ralph SA, Baez C, Reiner RS. Detection and quantitation of cellulose II by Raman Spectroscopy. Cellulose. 2021;28:9069&#x2013;9079. doi: 10.1007/s10570-021-04124-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10570-021-04124-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan F, et al. Charge transfer effect on Raman and surface enhanced Raman spectroscopy of furfural molecules. Nanomaterials. 2017;7:210. doi: 10.3390/nano7080210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nano7080210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5575692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28767053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh D, Popp J, Singh R. Fourier transform Raman and DFT study of blue shift C&#x2013;H stretching vibration of diazines on hydrogen bond formation. Zeitschrift f&#xfc;r Physikalische Chemie. 2011;225:785&#x2013;798. doi: 10.1524/zpch.2011.0081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1524/zpch.2011.0081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong Z, Asher SA. Dependence of Raman and resonance Raman intensities on sample self-absorption. Appl. Spectrosc. 2015;69:75&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1366/14-07531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1366/14-07531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25506729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ourhzif E, Ketatni E, Akssira M, Troin Y, Khouili M. Crystal structure, Hirshfeld surface analysis and DFT studies of Euphorbioside monohydrate a major bisnorsesquiterpene isolated from Euphorbia resinifera latex. J. Mol. Struct. 2021;1241:130511. doi: 10.1016/j.molstruc.2021.130511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molstruc.2021.130511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiama TM, et al. Molecular and biological activities of metal oxide-modified bioactive glass. Sci. Rep. 2023;13:10637. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-37017-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-37017-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10313761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37391463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durka K, Kami&#x144;ski R, Luli&#x144;ski S, Serwatowski J, Wo&#x17a;niak K. On the nature of the B&#x22ef;N interaction and the conformational flexibility of arylboronic azaesters. Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2010;12:13126&#x2013;13136. doi: 10.1039/c0cp00030b.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c0cp00030b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20830378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezzat HA, et al. DFT and QSAR studies of PTFE/ZnO/SiO2 nanocomposite. Sci. Rep. 2023;13:9696. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-19490-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-19490-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10272118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37322021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lefi N, Kazachenko AS, Raja M, Issaoui N, Kazachenko AS. Molecular structure, spectral analysis, molecular docking and physicochemical studies of 3-bromo-2-hydroxypyridine monomer and dimer as bromodomain inhibitors. Molecules. 2023;28:2669. doi: 10.3390/molecules28062669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules28062669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10054851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36985641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>