<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41002912</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2077-0375</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Membranes</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Membranes (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Zn<sup>2+</sup>-Mediated Co-Deposition of Dopamine/Tannic Acid/ZIF-8 on PVDF Hollow Fiber Membranes for Enhanced Antifouling Performance and Protein Separation.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">277</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/membranes15090277</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The inherent hydrophobicity of poly(vinylidene fluoride) (PVDF) ultrafiltration membranes leads to severe membrane fouling when processing proteinaceous solutions and organic contaminants, significantly limiting their practical applications. This study presents a novel metal-ion mediated co-deposition strategy for fabricating high-performance antifouling poly(vinylidene fluoride) (PVDF) hollow fiber ultrafiltration membranes. Through Zn<sup>2+</sup> coordination-driven self-assembly, a uniform and stable composite coating of dopamine (DA), tannic acid (TA), and ZIF-8 nanoparticles was successfully constructed on the membrane surface under mild conditions. The modified membrane exhibited significantly enhanced hydrophilicity, with a water contact angle of 21&#xb0; and zeta potential of -29.68 mV, facilitating the formation of a dense hydration layer that effectively prevented protein adhesion. The membrane demonstrated exceptional separation performance, achieving a pure water permeability of 771 L/(m<sup>2</sup>&#x2219;h&#x2219;bar) and bovine serum albumin (BSA) rejection of 97.7%. Furthermore, it showed outstanding antifouling capability with flux recovery rates exceeding 83.6%, 74.7%, and 71.5% after fouling by BSA, lysozyme, and ovalbumin, respectively. xDLVO analysis revealed substantially increased interfacial free energy and stronger repulsive interactions between the modified surface and protein foulants. The antifouling mechanism was attributed to the synergistic effects of hydration layer formation, optimized pore structure, additional water transport pathways from ZIF-8 incorporation, and electrostatic repulsion from negatively charged surface groups. This work provides valuable insights into the rational design of high-performance antifouling membranes for sustainable water treatment and protein separation applications.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ni</LastName><ForeName>Lei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Material Science and Engineering, Tiangong University, Tianjin 300387, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Qiancheng</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tianjin Key Laboratory of Aquatic Science and Technology, School of Environmental and Municipal Engineering, Tianjin Chengjian University, Tianjin 300384, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zhe</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tianjin Key Laboratory of Aquatic Science and Technology, School of Environmental and Municipal Engineering, Tianjin Chengjian University, Tianjin 300384, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Xueting</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tianjin Key Laboratory of Aquatic Science and Technology, School of Environmental and Municipal Engineering, Tianjin Chengjian University, Tianjin 300384, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Urban Water Resource and Environment, Harbin Institute of Technology, Harbin 150090, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Wenjuan</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9346-1580</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tianjin Key Laboratory of Aquatic Science and Technology, School of Environmental and Municipal Engineering, Tianjin Chengjian University, Tianjin 300384, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Caihong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1888-6500</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Eco-Environments in Three Gorges Reservoir Region, Ministry of Education, College of Environment and Ecology, Chongqing University, Chongqing 400044, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>52100011</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Fund of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Membranes (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101577807</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2077-0375</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ZIF-8</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antifouling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dopamine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hollow fiber membrane</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tannin</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41002912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12471975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/membranes15090277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">membranes15090277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Deng J., Gong Y., Jin Y., Zhou J., Wang Y. Additive manufacturing of ultrafiltration membranes from block copolymer nanowires. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2025;368:132980. doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2025.132980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2025.132980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tai Z.S., Othman M.H.D., Tajul Arifin N.D., Shazana N.A., Iqbal R.M., Ab Rahman M., Wan Mustapa W.N.F., Kadirkhan F., Puteh M.H., Jaafar J., et al. Modification of PVDF hollow fiber membrane with ZnO structure via hydrothermal for enhanced antifouling property in membrane distillation. J. Membr. Sci. 2024;692:122294. doi: 10.1016/j.memsci.2023.122294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.memsci.2023.122294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W.-M., Chen X.-R., Mao H., Li S.-H., Zhang Y.-M., Xu L.-H., Zhao Z.-P. Construction of PDMS@ZIF-8 composite membrane on PVDF hollow fiber inner surface for ultrafast ethanol/water separation. J. Membr. Sci. 2024;704:122889. doi: 10.1016/j.memsci.2024.122889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.memsci.2024.122889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou C., Du L., Chen D., Zhao X., Zhou J., Qiao S. The preparation of electrically-enhanced and hydrophilic CNTs-PVDF composite hollow fiber membranes for fouling resistance. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2024;351:127968. doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsebaeai M.K., Ahmad A.L., Ooi B.S. Construction of wetting resistance surface of highly hydrophobic PVDF-HFP/rGO coated supported PVDF hollow fiber composite membrane for membrane distillation. Chem. Eng. J. 2024;493:152565. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.152565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.152565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie Z., Liu C., Jiang X., Zhou Y., Lin X., Zhao X., He Q., Chai H., Pang X., Ma J. Dopamine-triggered one-step codeposition of zwitterionic surfactants for anti-fouling polyethersulfone ultrafiltration membrane modification. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2022;598:153871. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2022.153871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2022.153871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wijers M.C., Jin M., Wessling M., Strathmann H. Supported liquid membranes modification with sulphonated poly(ether ether ketone)&#x2014;Permeability, selectivity and stability. J. Membr. Sci. 1998;147:117&#x2013;130. doi: 10.1016/S0376-7388(98)00131-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0376-7388(98)00131-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao J., Wang J., Xu Q., Wu S., Chen Y. Regenerated cellulose strongly adhered by a supramolecular adhesive onto the PVDF membrane for a highly efficient oil/water separation. Green Chem. 2021;23:5633&#x2013;5646. doi: 10.1039/D1GC01998H.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D1GC01998H</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng W., Lu X., Kaneda M., Zhang W., Bernstein R., Ma J., Elimelech M. Graphene Oxide-Functionalized Membranes: The Importance of Nanosheet Surface Exposure for Biofouling Resistance. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2020;54:517&#x2013;526. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.9b05335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.9b05335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31756099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang P., Li J., Zhang X., Lu X., Liu Q., Zhang T., Cheng W., Ma J. Utilization of Bidirectional Cation Transport in a Thin Film Composite Membrane: Selective Removal and Reclamation of Ammonium from Synthetic Digested Sludge Centrate via an Osmosis&#x2013;Distillation Hybrid Membrane Process. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2020;54:10313&#x2013;10322. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.0c01496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.0c01496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32706970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng W., Xu H., Wang P., Wang L., Szymczyk A., Crou&#xe9; J.-P., Zhang T. Modification Mechanism of Polyamide Reverse Osmosis Membrane by Persulfate: Roles of Hydroxyl and Sulfate Radicals. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2022;56:8864&#x2013;8874. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.2c00952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.2c00952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35622994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang P., Jin J., Hou R., Jin G., Qin L., Chen X., Wang H., Zhou Y., Gao C. From synergistic integration to advanced substitution: MOF-assisted biocatalytic membranes for emerging contaminants remediation. J. Environ. Manage. 2025;390:126261. doi: 10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.126261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.126261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40580865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Sun S., Wang M., Shen Q., Cong S., Zhao Y., Peng J., Pang H. Metal-organic framework (MOF) membranes for Mg2+/Li+ separation. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2025;374:133737. doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2025.133737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2025.133737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed E., Farghali A.A., Hmamm M.F.M. Development of Cu-MOF@PVDF&#x2013;PS hybrid membranes for high-temperature proton exchange membranes: Electrospinning, characterization, and fuel cell performance. RSC Adv. 2025;15:29777&#x2013;29798. doi: 10.1039/D5RA03667D.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D5RA03667D</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12376943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40860077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karthikeyan G., Devadiga V., Mohan S., Balakrishna R.G. Europium MOFs-enabled fluorescent membranes with optimized flux, filtration, and fouling resistance for wastewater treatment: A strategy to probe MOF distribution in membranes. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2025;13:118679. doi: 10.1016/j.jece.2025.118679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2025.118679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimi A., Vatanpour V., Khataee A., Safarpour M. Contra-diffusion synthesis of ZIF-8 layer on polyvinylidene fluoride ultrafiltration membranes for improved water purification. J. Ind. Eng. Chem. 2019;73:95&#x2013;105. doi: 10.1016/j.jiec.2019.01.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jiec.2019.01.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y., Wang X., Hu P., Peng X. ZIF-8 coated polyvinylidenefluoride (PVDF) hollow fiber for highly efficient separation of small dye molecules. Appl. Mater. Today. 2016;5:103&#x2013;110. doi: 10.1016/j.apmt.2016.07.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmt.2016.07.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li F., Bhushan B., Pan Y., Zhao X. Bioinspired superoleophobic/superhydrophilic functionalized cotton for efficient separation of immiscible oil-water mixtures and oil-water emulsions. J. Colloid. Interface Sci. 2019;548:123&#x2013;130. doi: 10.1016/j.jcis.2019.04.031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2019.04.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30986711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Yang H.-C., He F., Peng S., Li Y., Shao L., Darling S.B. Mussel-Inspired Surface Engineering for Water-Remediation Materials. Matter. 2019;1:115&#x2013;155. doi: 10.1016/j.matt.2019.05.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matt.2019.05.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang S., McDonald J.A., Kuchel R.P., Khan S.J., Leslie G., Tang C.Y., Mansouri J., Fane A.G. Surface modification of nanofiltration membranes to improve the removal of organic micropollutants: Linking membrane characteristics to solute transmission. Water Res. 2021;203:117520. doi: 10.1016/j.watres.2021.117520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2021.117520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34392040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng X.Q., Zhang C., Wang Z.X., Shao L. Tailoring nanofiltration membrane performance for highly-efficient antibiotics removal by mussel-inspired modification. J. Membr. Sci. 2016;499:326&#x2013;334. doi: 10.1016/j.memsci.2015.10.060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.memsci.2015.10.060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R., Liu J., Shi A., Luo X., Lin J., Zheng R., Fan H., Selasie S.V., Lin H. A facile method to modify polypropylene membrane by polydopamine coating via inkjet printing technique for superior performance. J. Colloid. Interface Sci. 2019;552:719&#x2013;727. doi: 10.1016/j.jcis.2019.05.108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2019.05.108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31176918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Zhang W., Wen S., Wang L., Wang S., Wang Y., Lu J., Ma J., Cheng W. Rapid co-deposition of dopamine and polyethyleneimine triggered by CuSO4/H2O2 oxidation to fabricate nanofiltration membranes with high selectivity and antifouling ability. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2023;305:122409. doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2022.122409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2022.122409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T., Zhang J., Wang Q., Zhang H., Wang Z., Wu Z. Evaluating of the performance of natural mineral vermiculite modified PVDF membrane for oil/water separation by membrane fouling model and XDLVO theory. J. Membr. Sci. 2022;641:119886. doi: 10.1016/j.memsci.2021.119886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.memsci.2021.119886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B., Hou D., Li C., Yun Y. Mussels-inspired design a carbon nanotube based underwater superoleophobic/hydrophobic Janus membrane with robust anti-oil-fouling for direct contact membrane distillation. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2022;294:121163. doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2022.121163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2022.121163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pz A., Wl A., Sr A., Yj A., Qin S.A., Cf B., Nk A., Hm A. Modification of PVDF hollow fiber membrane by co-deposition of PDA/MPC-co-AEMA for membrane distillation application with anti-fouling and anti-scaling properties. J. Membr. Sci. 2021;636:119596. doi: 10.1016/j.memsci.2021.119596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.memsci.2021.119596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye W., Liu H., Lin F., Lin J., Zhao S., Yang S., Hou J., Zhou S., Van der Bruggenf B. High-flux nanofiltration membranes tailored by bio-inspired co-deposition of hydrophilic g-C3N4 nanosheets for enhanced selectivity towards organics and salts. Environ. Sci. Nano. 2019;6:2958&#x2013;2967. doi: 10.1039/C9EN00692C.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C9EN00692C</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang S., Zhang Z., Yang H., Wang G., Zhu L. Mussel-inspired hydrophilic modification of polypropylene membrane for oil-in-water emulsion separation. Surf. Coat. Techol. 2020;403:126375. doi: 10.1016/j.surfcoat.2020.126375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.surfcoat.2020.126375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varol H.S., Herberger T., Kirsch M., Mikolei J., Veith L., Kannan-Sampathkumar V., Brand R.D., Synatschke C.V., Weil T., Andrieu-Brunsen A. Electropolymerization of Polydopamine at Electrode-Supported Insulating Mesoporous Films. Chem. Mater. 2023;35:9192&#x2013;9207. doi: 10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c01890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c01890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10653081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38027541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alfieri M.L., Weil T., Ng D.Y.W., Ball V. Polydopamine at biological interfaces. Adv. Colloid. Interface Sci. 2022;305:102689. doi: 10.1016/j.cis.2022.102689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cis.2022.102689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35525091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J., Rezzadori K., Petrus J., Luccio M., Li] Q. Modification of hydrophobic commercial PVDF microfiltration membranes into superhydrophilic membranes by the mussel-inspired method with dopamine and polyethyleneimine. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2019;212:641&#x2013;649. doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2018.10.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2018.10.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren J., Xia W., Feng X., Zhao Y. Surface modification of PVDF membrane by sulfonated chitosan for enhanced anti-fouling property via PDA coating layer. Mater. Lett. 2021;307:130981. doi: 10.1016/j.matlet.2021.130981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matlet.2021.130981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan K., Kim C., Sung K., Ejima H., Yoshie N. Tunicate-inspired gallol polymers for underwater adhesive: A comparative study of catechol and gallol. Biomacromolecules. 2017;18:2959&#x2013;2966. doi: 10.1021/acs.biomac.7b00921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.biomac.7b00921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28853566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie H., Shen L., Xu Y., Hong H., Yang L., Li R., Lin H. Tannic Acid (Ta)-Based Coating Modified Membrane Enhanced by Successive Inkjet Printing of Fe3+ and Sodium Periodate (Sp) for Efficient Oil-Water Separation. J. Membr. Sci. 2022;660:120873. doi: 10.1016/j.memsci.2022.120873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.memsci.2022.120873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y.Z., Kong X., Yin X., Zhang Y., Sun C.C., Yuan J.J., Zhu B., Zhu L.P. Tannin-inspired superhydrophilic and underwater superoleophobic polypropylene membrane for effective oil/water emulsions separation. Colloids Surf. Physicochem. Eng. Aspects. 2017;522:585&#x2013;592. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2017.03.023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2017.03.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y., Xiao Y., Zhang W., Lin H., Liao B.Q. Plant polyphenol intermediated metal-organic framework (MOF) membranes for efficient desalination. J. Membr. Sci. 2021;618:118726. doi: 10.1016/j.memsci.2020.118726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.memsci.2020.118726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao B., Guo Z., Wang H., Wang L., Qian Y., Long X., Ma C., Zhang Z., Li J., Zhang H. Enhanced water permeance of a polyamide thin-film composite nanofiltration membrane with a metal-organic framework interlayer. J. Membr. Sci. 2021;625:119154. doi: 10.1016/j.memsci.2021.119154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.memsci.2021.119154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye L., Liu X., Chen Y., Xu L., Fu S., Wu X. Fe3+/tannic acid assisted preparation of dynamic assembled hollow fiber nanofiltration membrane with salt tolerance. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2025;13:118378. doi: 10.1016/j.jece.2025.118378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2025.118378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z., Gao W., Zhao W., Yang Y., Shen H., Chang Y., Zhao S. Surface-functionalized composite hollow fiber membrane for extracorporeal membrane oxygenation. J. Membr. Sci. 2025;733:124377. doi: 10.1016/j.memsci.2025.124377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.memsci.2025.124377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohmed A.H., Isawi H., Elbehary S.A., El-Aassar A.H.M., Shawky H.A., Mehany M.A.S., Khalil M.M.H. Fabrication and characterization of nanocomposite hollow fiber membranes for wastewater treatment. Mater. Sci. Eng. B. 2025;321:118557. doi: 10.1016/j.mseb.2025.118557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mseb.2025.118557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varol H.S., Seeger S. Fluorescent Staining of Silicone Micro- and Nanopatterns for Their Optical Imaging. Langmuir. 2022;38:231&#x2013;243. doi: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c02436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c02436</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34932361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu T., Zhou B., Zhu T., Shi J., Xu Z., Hu C., Wang J. Facile and low-cost approach towards a PVDF ultrafiltration membrane with enhanced hydrophilicity and antifouling performance via graphene oxide/water-bath coagulation. RSC Adv. 2015;5:7880&#x2013;7889. doi: 10.1039/C4RA13476A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C4RA13476A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M.-P., Zhang X., Zhang H., Liu W.-L., Huang Z.-H., Xie F., Ma X.-H., Xu Z.-L. Hydrophilic yolk-shell ZIF-8 modified polyamide thin-film nanocomposite membrane with improved permeability and selectivity. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2020;247:116990. doi: 10.1016/j.seppur.2020.116990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seppur.2020.116990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao X., Zhang R., Liu Y., He M., Su Y., Gao C., Jiang Z. Antifouling membrane surface construction: Chemistry plays a critical role. J. Membr. Sci. 2018;551:145&#x2013;171. doi: 10.1016/j.memsci.2018.01.039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.memsci.2018.01.039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu X., Lin T., Xu H., Tao H., Chen W. Ultrafiltration of up-flow biological activated carbon effluent: Extracellular polymer biofouling mechanism and mitigation using pre-ozonation with H2O2 backwashing. Water Res. 2020;186:116391. doi: 10.1016/j.watres.2020.116391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2020.116391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32947101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan X.-T., Wu L., Geng H.-Z., Wang L., Wang W., Yuan X.-S., He B., Jiang Y.-X., Ning Y.-J., Zhu Z.-R., et al. Polyaniline/polysulfone ultrafiltration membranes with improved permeability and anti-fouling behavior. J. Water Process Eng. 2021;40:101903. doi: 10.1016/j.jwpe.2020.101903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jwpe.2020.101903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B., Tang H., Huang D., Gao X., Zhang B., Shen Y., Shi W. Effect of pH on anionic polyacrylamide adhesion: New insights into membrane fouling based on XDLVO analysis. J. Mol. Liq. 2020;320:114463. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2020.114463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2020.114463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M., Li J., Liu Y., Cao K., Zhu M., Liu H., Tang Y., Wang Q. Self-cleaning PDA/TA/FeOOH-PVDF membrane for efficient separation of volatile oil from water of traditional Chinese medicine. J. Membr. Sci. 2025;734:124467. doi: 10.1016/j.memsci.2025.124467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.memsci.2025.124467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., Wang Z., Zhao Z., Wang P., Wang S., Ma J., Cheng W. High-stable bimetallic AgCu nanoalloys with core-shell structures for sustainable antibacterial and biofouling mitigation in nanofiltration. Water Res. 2025;271:122986. doi: 10.1016/j.watres.2024.122986.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2024.122986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39705753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao F., Ge H., Wang Y., Bian S., Tong Y., Gao C., Zhu G. Novel thin-film composite membrane with polydopamine-modified polyethylene support and tannic acid-Fe3+ interlayer for forward osmosis applications. J. Membr. Sci. 2022;642:119976. doi: 10.1016/j.memsci.2021.119976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.memsci.2021.119976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thekkayil R., John H., Gopinath P. Grafting of self assembled polyaniline nanorods on reduced graphene oxide for nonlinear optical application. Synth. Met. 2013;185&#x2013;186:38&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1016/j.synthmet.2013.09.035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.synthmet.2013.09.035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang H., Song D.H., Kim I.C., Kwon Y.N. Fouling control through the hydrophilic surface modification of poly(vinylidene fluoride) membranes. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 2014;132:41712. doi: 10.1002/app.41712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/app.41712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou H., Wang X., Tang J., Yang Y.W. Surface Immobilization of pH-Responsive Polymer Brushes on Mesoporous Silica Nanoparticles by Enzyme Mimetic Catalytic ATRP for Controlled Cargo Release. Polymers. 2016;8:277. doi: 10.3390/polym8080277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym8080277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6432388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30974554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He G., Li Z., Liu Y., Liu M., Zhu C., Zhang L., Zhang H. A novel lithium ion-imprinted membrane with robust adsorption capacity and anti-fouling property based on the uniform multilayered interlayer. Desalination. 2022;539:115973. doi: 10.1016/j.desal.2022.115973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.desal.2022.115973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R., Jiang J., Liu Y., Li Y., Zhao C., Yang Z., Cai L., Yu J., Chen Z., Hu Z. Tannic acid/ethylenediamine/succinic acid graft modified PVDF anti-pollution membrane and its application in the field of organic pollutant separation. J. Mater. Sci. 2022;57:20156&#x2013;20173. doi: 10.1007/s10853-022-07789-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10853-022-07789-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen F., Dong S., Wang Z., Xu J., Xu R., Wang J. Preparation of mixed matrix composite membrane for hydrogen purification by incorporating ZIF-8 nanoparticles modified with tannic acid. Int. J. Hydrogen Energy. 2020;45:7444&#x2013;7454. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2019.04.050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2019.04.050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Battistoni C., Dormann J.L., Fiorani D., Paparazzo E., Viticoli S. An XPS and M&#xf6;ssbauer study of the electronic properties of ZnCrxGa2&#x2212;xO4 spinel solid solutions. Solid. State Commun. 1981;39:581&#x2013;585. doi: 10.1016/0038-1098(81)90326-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0038-1098(81)90326-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan H., Tang Y., Hou Z., Yang P., Liu C., Xie Z., Li S. Antimicrobial polymer-based zeolite imidazolate framework composite membranes for uranium extraction from wastewater and seawater. J. Colloid. Interface Sci. 2025;677:435&#x2013;445. doi: 10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39098277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S., Zhang M., Sun J., Sun J., Wang Y. Preparation and characterization of superior hydrophilic PVDF/DA membranes by the self-polymerization approach of dopamine. Front. Chem. 2023;11:1162348. doi: 10.3389/fchem.2023.1162348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fchem.2023.1162348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10097915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37065826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kan J., Zhang Z., Ren L., Han J., Zhang H., Li J., Wu H., Chen J. Hydrophilic modification of PVDF membranes for oily water separation with enhanced anti-fouling performance. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 2023;140:e53738. doi: 10.1002/app.53738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/app.53738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao Y., Yang J., Zhang J., Li J., Qin S., Wu X., Cui Z. Removal of heavy metal ions from acidic wastewater by constructing positively charged hollow fiber nanofiltration separating-layer based on Fe (III)/co deposition-quaternization. J. Water Process Eng. 2023;56:104450. doi: 10.1016/j.jwpe.2023.104450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jwpe.2023.104450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J., Sun W., Ju J., Tan Y., Yuan H. Facile Fabrication of Superwetting PVDF Membrane for Highly Efficient Oil/Water Separation. Polymers. 2023;15:327. doi: 10.3390/polym15020327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym15020327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9865060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36679208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Zhang W., Wang W., Wang P., Ni L., Wang S., Ma J., Cheng W. Amine-Modified ZIF Composite Membranes: Regulated Nanochannel Interactions for Enhanced Cation Transport and Precise Separation. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2025;59:4199&#x2013;4209. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.5c00132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.5c00132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39976453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han B., Sun Z., Jiang H., Sun X., Ma J., He M., Zhang W. Thin and defect-free ZIF-8 layer assisted enhancement of the monovalent perm-selectivity for cation exchange membrane. Desalination. 2022;529:115637. doi: 10.1016/j.desal.2022.115637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.desal.2022.115637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bi Q., Li Q., Tian Y., Lin Y., Wang X. Hydrophilic modification of poly(vinylidene fluoride) membrane with poly(vinyl pyrrolidone) via a cross-linking reaction. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 2012;127:394&#x2013;401. doi: 10.1002/app.37629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/app.37629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L., Wang Z., Zhang J. Zeolite imidazolate framework hybrid nanofiltration (NF) membranes with enhanced permselectivity for dye removal. J. Membr. Sci. 2017;532:76&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1016/j.memsci.2017.03.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.memsci.2017.03.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Song D., Zhang W., He Q., Huangfu X., Sun S., Sun Z., Cheng W., Ma J. Constructing zwitterionic polymer brush layer to enhance gravity-driven membrane performance by governing biofilm formation. Water Res. 2020;168:115181. doi: 10.1016/j.watres.2019.115181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2019.115181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31630018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>