<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40429100</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Research on the Optimization and Regulation Mechanism of Waterproofing, Impermeability, and Water Vapor Transmission Property of Mortar Based on Different Modifiers.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2363</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma18102363</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>It is challenging for mortar to simultaneously enhance the transmission property of water vapor while maintaining excellent waterproofness and impermeability. However, in some applications, both are necessary. Therefore, three different kinds of modifiers, i.e., cementitious capillary crystalline waterproof materials (XYPEX), &#x3b3;-methacryloxy-propyl-trimethoxy-silane (KH570), and styrene-butadiene rubber latex (SB), are employed to explore how modified mortar can possess excellent waterproofness, impermeability, and the water vapor transmission property simultaneously. Combining characterization techniques, the influencing factors of these three properties are studied. The results indicate that XYPEX promotes the formation of hydration products within pores, improves waterproofness and impermeability, but decreases the water vapor transmission property. KH570 introduces numerous pores ranging from 0.1 to 5 micrometers and enhances the hydrophobicity of mortar; at 1.25% and 2.5% contents, the modified mortar exhibits excellent waterproofness and water vapor transmission property but poor impermeability. SB introduces numerous air pores and forms polymer films; at 20% content, the modified mortar exhibits excellent waterproofness and water vapor transmission property, with impermeability remaining unchanged, making SB a favorable modifier that combines these three properties. Finally, the mechanisms of these three properties are discussed, which provides a theoretical reference for the control of mortar's waterproofing, impermeability, and water vapor transmission. The selection of modifiers is based on the actual performance requirements.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zelei</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Advanced Civil Engineering Materials of Ministry of Education, School of Materials Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 201804, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Chuanchuan</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Henan Institute of Science and Technology, Xinxiang 453003, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Lanlan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Advanced Civil Engineering Materials of Ministry of Education, School of Materials Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 201804, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Ru</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Advanced Civil Engineering Materials of Ministry of Education, School of Materials Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 201804, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Grant No. 51872203</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022-3-YB-17</GrantID><Agency>Top Discipline Plan of Shanghai Universities-Class I</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">capillary water absorption</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cement mortar</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">impermeability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">low-field nuclear magnetic resonance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">porosity and pore characteristics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">water contact angle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">water vapor transmission property</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40429100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12113140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma18102363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma18102363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abdou Ibro M., Verdier J., Geoffroy S., Cagnon H., Bourbon X. Prediction of moisture transfer in cement-based materials: Use of a porous network model to access transfer parameters. Cem. Concr. Res. 2021;142:106310. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2020.106310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2020.106310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damle R.M., Singh A., Bhesaniya N. On the hygrothermal environment of spaces with exposed walls&#x2014;Thermal bridging effect of mortar layers of cement and lime. J. Build. Eng. 2024;98:111513. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.111513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.111513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q., Gao L., Gao Z. Discussion on waterproofing and air permeability of external wall coatings. Wall Mater. Innov. Energy Sav. Build. 2016;02:39&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J., Gao X., Chen S., Lin H., Li Z., Lin X. Hydrophobic or superhydrophobic modification of cement-based materials: A systematic review. Compos. Part B Eng. 2022;243:110104. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2022.110104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2022.110104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X., Xiao J., Zhang Z., Wang C., Long C., Dai L. Effects of CCCW on properties of cement-based materials: A review. J. Build. Eng. 2022;50:104184. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahandari S., Tao Z., Alim M.A., Li W. Integral waterproof concrete: A comprehensive review. J. Build. Eng. 2023;78:107718. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2023.107718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.107718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao L., Feng P., Liu Q., Zhang Y., Yu Z., Yan S. In-situ polymerization-modified cement composites: A critical review. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;449:138294. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.138294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.138294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menglu L., Peng L., Jun W., Zhiwu Y., Ying C., Xiang C. Study on improvement of waterproofing performance of CCCW with silicone waterproof material and waterbased capillary inorganic waterproofer. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;400:132842. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodul J., &#x17d;i&#x17e;kov&#xe1; N., Drochytka R., Borg R.P., Dvor&#xe1;k K., Gazdic D. Solid State Phenomena. Brno University of Technology; Brno, The Czech Republic: 2019. Influence of crystallization admixture on mechanical parameters and microstructure of polymer-cement mortars with waste limestone; pp. 27&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G., Huang X., Lin J., Jiang X., Zhang X. Activated chemicals of cementitious capillary crystalline waterproofing materials and their self-healing behaviour. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;200:36&#x2013;45. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.12.093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.12.093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong J., Zhang H., Mao J., Zhang Y., Lian S., Wang J., Zhou H., Song Y., Hu J., Wu H., et al. Influences of cementitious capillary crystalline waterproofing on the hydration products and properties of cement-based materials. J. Build. Eng. 2024;98:111451. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.111451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.111451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao H., Xie Z., Huang C., Yuan Q., Yu Z. Recent progress of hydrophobic cement-based materials: Preparation, characterization and properties. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;299:124255. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>She W., Yang J., Hong J., Sun D., Mu S., Miao C. Superhydrophobic concrete with enhanced mechanical robustness: Nanohybrid composites, strengthen mechanism and durability evaluation. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;247:118563. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F., Lei S., Ou J., Li W. Effect of PDMS on the waterproofing performance and corrosion resistance of cement mortar. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2020;507:145016. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2019.145016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2019.145016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han S., Wang Y., Wang Q., Han L., Han G. Film-formation processes of polymer emulsions in polymer-cement waterproof coatings and their effect on coatings&#x2019; macroscopic properties. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;438:137137. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohama Y. Polymer-based admixtures. Cem. Concr. Composites. 1998;20:189&#x2013;212. doi: 10.1016/S0958-9465(97)00065-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0958-9465(97)00065-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beeldens A., Van Gemert D., Schorn H., Ohama Y., Czarnecki L. From microstructure to macrostructure: An integrated model of structure formation in polymer-modified concrete. Mater. Struct. Mater. Constr. 2005;38:601&#x2013;607. doi: 10.1007/BF02481591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02481591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Zhang G., Wang Z., Huang T., Wang P. Effect of defoaming agent on the properties of cement mortars with hydroxyethyl methyl cellulose through adjusting air content gradient. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2023;139:105024. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2023.105024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2023.105024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang G., Wang P. Effects of Ethylene/Vinyl Chloride/Vinyl laurate redispersible terpolymer on pore structure and properties of cement mortar. J. Build. Mater. 2013;16:111&#x2013;114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L., Wang R., Lu Q. Influence of polymer latex on the setting time, mechanical properties and durability of calcium sulfoaluminate cement mortar. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;169:911&#x2013;922. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.03.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.03.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun K., Wang S., Zeng L., Peng X. Effect of styrene-butadiene rubber latex on the rheological behavior and pore structure of cement paste. Compos. Part B Eng. 2019;163:282&#x2013;289. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2018.11.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2018.11.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramli M., Akhavan Tabassi A. Effects of polymer modification on the permeability of cement mortars under different curing conditions: A correlational study that includes pore distributions, water absorption and compressive strength. Constr. Build. Mater. 2012;28:561&#x2013;570. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2011.09.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2011.09.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R., Wang P., Li X. Physical and mechanical properties of styrene-butadiene rubber emulsion modified cement mortars. Cem. Concr. Res. 2005;35:900&#x2013;906. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2004.07.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2004.07.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pascal S., Alliche A., Pilvin P. Mechanical behaviour of polymer modified mortars. Mater. Sci. Eng. A. 2004;380:1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.msea.2004.03.049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msea.2004.03.049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Du M., Fang H., Shi M., Zhang C., Wang F. Polymer-modified cement mortars: Their enhanced properties, applications, prospects, and challenges. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;299:124290. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Test Method for Fluidity of Cement Mortar. Inspection and Quarantine of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China; Beijing, China: 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Test Method of Cement Mortar Strength (ISO method) Inspection and Quarantine of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China; Beijing, China: 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Test Methods for Water Requirement of Normal Consistency, Setting Time and Soundness of the Portland Cement. Inspection and Quarantine of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China; Beijing, China: 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hygrothermal Performance of Building Materials and Products&#x2014;Determination of Water Absorption Coefficient by Partial Immersion. International Organization for Standardization; Geneva, Switzerland: 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inorganic Waterproof and Leakage-Preventing Materials. Inspection and Quarantine of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China; Beijing, China: 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Test Methods for Water Vapour Transmission Properties of Building Materials and Products. Inspection and Quarantine of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China; Beijing, China: 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Mei J., Liao Y., Li H., Niu Y. Durability of Cement-Based Materials with Nano SiO2 and VAE Composite Modification. J. Build. Mater. 2023;26:687&#x2013;696. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1007-9629.2023.06.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1007-9629.2023.06.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan Q., Zhong F., Zuo S., Xie Z., Xue K., Yao H. Understanding the water transport behaviors of hydrophobic cement mortar by paraffin modification. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;435:136845. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J., Zuo W., She W. Towards a further understanding of cement hydration at the early-age stage in the presence of hydrophobic silane IBTEO. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2024;153:105712. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2024.105712.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2024.105712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J., Wang H., Sun X., Chen Z., Dong W. Characterizing connectivity and tortuosity of pore network based on LF-NMR method to assess the water permeability of white cement mortar. J. Build. Eng. 2024;93:109862. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Matos P.R., Andrade Neto J.S., Tambara L.U., Rodr&#xed;guez E.D., Kirchheim A.P., Campos C.E.M. Measuring the early-age volumetric change of cement paste through in-situ XRD. Mater. Today Commun. 2023;36:106857. doi: 10.1016/j.mtcomm.2023.106857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtcomm.2023.106857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martys N.S., Ferraris C.F. Capillary transport in mortars and concrete. Cem. Concr. Res. 1997;27:747&#x2013;760. doi: 10.1016/S0008-8846(97)00052-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0008-8846(97)00052-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosquera M.J., Silva B., Prieto B., Ruiz&#x2013;Herrera E. Addition of cement to lime-based mortars: Effect on pore structure and vapor transport. Cem. Concr. Res. 2006;36:1635&#x2013;1642. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2004.10.041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2004.10.041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>