<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41019667</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1744-988X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of research in nursing : JRN</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Res Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Challenges and facilitators of implementing a participatory nutrition project in residential aged care.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>17449871251369412</StartPage><MedlinePgn>17449871251369412</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">17449871251369412</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/17449871251369412</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Malnutrition and dehydration in residential aged care (nursing homes) are problematic worldwide, particularly for residents with dementia. However, conducting research to improve residents' nutritional health can be challenging.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This paper describes challenges, facilitators and recommendations following an intervention to enhance nutrition and hydration care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Meaningful Engagement in Nutritional Understanding (MENU; 2018-2021) was a participatory nutrition support intervention initiated in two Tasmanian care homes. Mixed methods evaluation explored nutrition and hydration status, knowledge and care practices with residents with dementia, staff and family; and the challenges to, and facilitators of, project implementation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study found nutrition and hydration to be problematic. However, despite multiple challenges, a participatory approach may help engage stakeholders and encourage action in this area. Challenges included resident recruitment, care home and staff engagement, and external factors. Facilitators included Nutrition Champions, the participatory research approach, and tailored resources and education.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The study has implications for conducting more effective nutrition research in residential aged care, particularly with people with dementia, nursing and other care staff, to better understand their experiences and enhance care practices. Nursing staff are key to effective participatory research in residential aged care and to ensuring residents' optimal nutrition and hydration.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2025.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lea</LastName><ForeName>Emma</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7346-5667</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Senior Lecturer, Wicking Dementia Research and Education Centre, University of Tasmania, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goldberg</LastName><ForeName>Lynette R</ForeName><Initials>LR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Associate Professor, Wicking Dementia Research and Education Centre, University of Tasmania, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McInerney</LastName><ForeName>Fran</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Adjunct Professor, Dementia Studies &amp; Education, Wicking Dementia Research and Education Centre, University of Tasmania, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beattie</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emeritus Professor, School of Nursing, Queensland University of Technology, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Res Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101234311</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1744-9871</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>doi: 10.1177/17449871251362646</RefSource></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">community-based participatory research</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dehydration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dementia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">in-service training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">malnutrition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nursing homes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41019667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12460289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17449871251369412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_17449871251369412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Agarwal E, Ferguson M, Banks M, et al. (2013) Malnutrition and poor food intake are associated with prolonged hospital stay, frequent readmissions, and greater in-hospital mortality: Results from the Nutrition Care Day Survey 2010. Clinical Nutrition 32: 737&#x2013;745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23260602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anantapong K, Davies N, Sampson EL. (2022) Communication between the multidisciplinary team and families regarding nutrition and hydration for people with severe dementia in acute hospitals: A qualitative study. Age and Ageing 51: afac230. DOI: 10.1093/ageing/afac230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ageing/afac230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9701106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36434801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson K, Blair A. (2021) What have staff got to do with it? Untangling complex relationships between residential aged care staff, the quality of care they provide, and the quality of life of people with dementia. Archives of Gerontology and Geriatrics 94: 104378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33631693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews S, Lea E, Haines T, et al. (2012) Reducing staff isolation and developing evidence-informed practice in the aged care environment through an action research approach to falls prevention. Advances in Nursing Science 35(1): 3&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22228387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Australian Government, Department of Health and Aged Care (2024) National Dementia Action Plan 2024-2034. Available at: https://www.health.gov.au/resources/publications/national-dementia-action-plan-2024-2034 (accessed 30 May 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Australian Government, Department of Health and Aged Care (2025) Strengthened Aged Care Quality Standards. Available at: https://www.health.gov.au/resources/publications/strengthened-aged-care-quality-standards-february-2025 (accessed 4 June 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee S. (2022) Dementia &#x2013; so much done, so much to do, so much to gain by doing so. Age and Ageing 51: 1&#x2013;7. DOI: 10.1093/ageing/afac204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ageing/afac204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beattie E. (2009) Research participation of individuals with dementia. Research in Gerontological Nursing 2: 94&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20077970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beattie E, Fielding E, O'Reilly M, et al. (2018) Recruitment of individuals with dementia and their carers for social research: Lessons learned from nine studies. Research in Gerontological Nursing 11(3): 119&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29634849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beattie E, O'Reilly M, Fetherstonhaugh D, et al. (2019) Supporting autonomy of nursing home residents with dementia in the informed consent process. Dementia (London) 18(7&#x2013;8): 2821&#x2013;2835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29512408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beattie E, O'Reilly M, Strange E, et al. (2014) How much do residential aged care staff members know about the nutritional needs of residents? International Journal of Older People Nursing 9(1): 54&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23398776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beattie ER, Fielding E, He W, et al. (2017) Unpacking the influence of dementia-related symptoms on quality of life of nursing home residents. Innovation in Aging 1(Suppl. 1): 281&#x2013;282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell CL, Lee ASW, Tamura BK. (2015) Malnutrition in the nursing home. Current Opinion in Clinical Nutrition and Metabolic Care 18: 17&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25394167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borders JC, Blanke S, Johnson S, et al. (2020) Efficacy of mealtime interventions for malnutrition and oral intake in persons with dementia: A systematic review. Alzheimer Disease and Associated Disorders 34: 366&#x2013;379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7679285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32530831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruno C, Collier A, Holyday M, et al. (2021) Interventions to improve hydration in older adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutrients 13: 3640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8537864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34684642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byles J, Perry L, Gibson R, et al. (2009) Encouraging Best Practice Nutrition and Hydration in Residential Aged Care: Final Report. Canberra, Australia: Department of Health and Ageing.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cartwright J, Roberts K, Oliver E, et al. (2022) Montessori mealtimes for dementia: A pathway to person-centred care. Dementia 21: 1098&#x2013;1119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35259303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cave D, Abbey K, Capra S. (2021) Food and nutrition champions in residential aged care homes are key for sustainable systems change within foodservices; Results from a qualitative study of stakeholders. Nutrients 13: 3566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8541169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34684566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatindiara I, Allen J, Hettige D, et al. (2020) High prevalence of malnutrition and frailty among older adults at admission to residential aged care. Journal of Primary Health Care 12: 305&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33349318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. (1988) Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences, 2nd edn. New York: Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collingridge Moore D, Payne S, Van den Block L, et al. (2019) Research, recruitment and observational data collection in care homes: Lessons from the PACE study. BMC Research Notes 12: 508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6694478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31412910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook G, Hodgson P, Hope C, et al. (2019) Hydration practices in residential and nursing care homes for older people. Journal of Clinical Nursing 28: 1205&#x2013;1215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30520190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobson AJ, Waller MJ, Hockey R, et al. (2020) Impact of dementia on health service use in the last 2&#x2009;years of life for women with other chronic conditions. Journal of the American Medical Directors Association 21: 1651&#x2013;1657.e1651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32303422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards H, Chapman H, Forster E, et al. (2003) Challenges associated with implementing an education program in a residential aged care setting. Australian Health Review 26: 107&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15368826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etherton-Beer C, Horner B, Venturato L, et al. (2021) Development of a toolkit to support sustainable culture change in residential aged care. Australasian Journal on Ageing 40: 77&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33336517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Everink IHJ, van Haastregt JCM, Manders M, et al. (2021) Malnutrition prevalence rates among Dutch nursing home residents: What has changed over one decade? A comparison of the years 2009, 2013 and 2018. The Journal of Nutrition, Health &amp; Aging 25: 999&#x2013;1005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34545920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaskill D, Black LJ, Isenring EA, et al. (2008) Malnutrition prevalence and nutrition issues in residential aged care facilities. Australasian Journal on Ageing 27: 189&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19032620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaskill D, Isenring EA, Black LJ, et al. (2009) Maintaining nutrition in aged care residents with a train-the-trainer intervention and nutrition coordinator. The Journal of Nutrition, Health and Aging 13: 913&#x2013;917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19924353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall S, Longhurst S, Higginson IJ. (2009) Challenges to conducting research with older people living in nursing homes. BMC Geriatrics 9: 38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2745410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19703277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holden TR, Keller S, Kim A, et al. (2018) Procedural framework to facilitate hospital-based informed consent for dementia research. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society 66: 2243&#x2013;2248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6289792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30246863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hugo C, Isenring E, Sinclair D, et al. (2018) What does it cost to feed aged care residents in Australia? Nutrition &amp; Dietetics 75: 6&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28741752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isherwood L, Mavromaras K, Moskos M, et al. (2018) Attraction, retention and utilisation of the aged care workforce. Adelaide: University of Adelaide.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iuliano S, Poon S, Wang X, et al. (2017) Dairy food supplementation may reduce malnutrition risk in institutionalised elderly. British Journal of Nutrition 117: 142&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5350609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28098050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller H, Vucea V, Slaughter SE, et al. (2019) Prevalence of malnutrition or risk in residents in long term care: Comparison of four tools. Journal of Nutrition in Gerontology and Geriatrics 38: 329&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31335280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller HH, Wu SA, Iraniparast M, et al. (2021) Relationship-centered mealtime training program demonstrates efficacy to improve the dining environment in long-term care. Journal of the American Medical Directors Association 22: 1933&#x2013;1938.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33306996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koh RTG, Thirumanickam A, Attrill S. (2022) How are the mealtime experiences of people in residential aged care facilities informed by policy and best practice guidelines? A scoping review. BMC Geriatrics 22: 737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9463738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36085034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam HR, Chow S, Taylor K, et al. (2018) Challenges of conducting research in long-term care facilities: A systematic review. BMC Geriatrics 18: 242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6186062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30314472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Law E, Ashworth R. (2022) Facilitators and barriers to research participation in care homes: Thematic analysis of interviews with researchers, staff, residents and residents&#x2019; families. Journal of Long-term Care 2022: 49&#x2013;60. DOI: 10.31389/jltc.87. 2022: 49&#x2013;60</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31389/jltc.87</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lea EJ, Goldberg LR, Price AD, et al. (2017) Staff awareness of food and fluid care needs for older people with dementia in residential care: A qualitative study. Journal of Clinical Nursing 26: 5169&#x2013;5178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28880410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lea EJ, Goldberg LR, Price AD, et al. (2019) Best intentions or best practice? A case study of the nutritional needs and outcomes of a person with dementia living in a residential aged care home. International Journal of Nursing Practice 25: e12692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30094901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leij-Halfwerk S, Verwijs MH, van Houdt S, et al. (2019) Prevalence of protein-energy malnutrition risk in European older adults in community, residential and hospital settings, according to 22 malnutrition screening tools validated for use in adults &#x2a7e;65 years: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Maturitas 126: 80&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31239123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masot O, Laved&#xe1;n A, Nuin C, et al. (2018) Risk factors associated with dehydration in older people living in nursing homes: Scoping review. International Journal of Nursing Studies 82: 90&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29626702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masot O, Miranda J, Santamar&#xed;a A, et al. (2020) Fluid intake recommendation considering the physiological adaptations of adults over 65 years: A critical review. Nutrients 12: 3383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7694182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33158071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masso M, Westera A, Quinsey K, et al. (2011) Encouraging Best Practice in Residential Aged Care program: Final evaluation report. Wollongong: Centre for Health Service Development.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mavromaras K, Knight G, Isherwood L, et al. (2017) 2016 National Aged Care Workforce Census and Survey &#x2013; The Aged Care Workforce, 2016. Canberra: Australian Government Department of Health.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meijers JM, Schols JMGA, Halfens RJG. (2014) Malnutrition in care home residents with dementia. The Journal of Nutrition, Health and Aging 18: 595&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24950150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Micklewright K. (2024) Why nursing voices matter in shaping care home research. Royal College of Nursing Blog. Available at: https://www.rcn.org.uk/news-and-events/Blogs/why-nursing-voices-matter-in-shaping-care-home-research-230824 (accessed 4 June 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitoku K, Shimanouchi S. (2014) The decision-making and communication capacities of older adults with dementia: A population-based study. Open Nursing Journal 8: 17&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4083186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25002912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy JL, Holmes J, Brooks C. (2017) Nutrition and dementia care: Developing an evidence-based model for nutritional care in nursing homes. BMC Geriatrics 17: 55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5309970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28196475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connor CMC, Liddle J, O&#x2019;Reilly M, et al. (2022) Advocating the rights of people with dementia to contribute to research: Considerations for researchers and ethics committees. Australasian Journal on Ageing 41: 309&#x2013;313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34821448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pagone T, Briggs L. (2021) Royal commission into aged care quality and safety. Final Report: Care, Dignity and Respect. Canberra: Commonwealth of Australia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulis SJC, Everink IHJ, Halfens RJG, et al. (2018) Prevalence and risk factors of dehydration among nursing home residents: A systematic review. Journal of the American Medical Directors Association 19: 646&#x2013;657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30056949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulis SJC, Everink IHJ, Halfens RJG, et al. (2022) Dehydration in the nursing home: Recognition and interventions taken by Dutch nursing staff. Journal of Advanced Nursing 78: 1044&#x2013;1054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9290809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34462958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry L, Bellchambers H, Howie A, et al. (2011) Examination of the utility of the promoting action on research implementation in health services framework for implementation of evidence based practice in residential aged care settings. Journal of Advanced Nursing 67: 2139&#x2013;2150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21535089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peryer G, Kelly S, Blake J, et al. (2022) Contextual factors influencing complex intervention research processes in care homes: A systematic review and framework synthesis. Age and Ageing 51: afac014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8887840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35231097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ries N, Mansfield E. (2021) Advance research directives: Dementia researchers&#x2019; views on a prototype directive and implementation strategies. Ethics and Human Research 43: 10&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34019338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ries NM, Mansfield E, Sanson-Fisher R. (2020) Ethical and legal aspects of research involving older people with cognitive impairment: A survey of dementia researchers in Australia. International Journal of Law and Psychiatry 68: 101534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32033698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowley J, Taylor B. (2011) Dying in a rural residential aged care facility: An action research and reflection project to improve end-of-life care to residents with a non-malignant disease. International Journal of Nursing Practice 17: 591&#x2013;598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22103825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubenstein LZ, Harker JO, Salv&#xe0; A, et al. (2001) Screening for undernutrition in geriatric practice: Developing the short-form Mini-Nutritional Assessment (MNA-SF). The Journals of Gerontology: Series A 56: M366&#x2013;M372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11382797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soofi H. (2022) Ethical aspects of facilitating the recruitment of people with dementia for clinical trials: A call for further debate. British Journal of Clinical Pharmacology 88: 22&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34192378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephens M, Knight A. (2022) &#x2018;Things won&#x2019;t improve if they&#x2019;re just left to fester&#x2019;: A qualitative study exploring how UK care home staff perceive and experience engagement in health research. Journal of Long-term Care 2022: 268&#x2013;276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usher K, Durkin J, Gyamfi N, et al. (2021) Preparedness for viral respiratory infection pandemic in residential aged care facilities: a review of the literature to inform post-COVID-19 response. Journal of Clinical Nursing. Epub ahead of print 22 May 2021. DOI: 10.1111/jocn.15863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.15863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8242770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34021650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Utsumi M, Makimoto K, Quroshi N, et al. (2010) Types of infectious outbreaks and their impact in elderly care facilities: A review of the literature. Age and Ageing 39: 299&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20332371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson K, Hatcher D, Good A. (2020) Influencing factors that support and build aged care research capacity: Staff perspectives. Collegian 27: 34&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu XS, Miles A, Braakhuis A. (2022) The effectiveness of international dysphagia diet standardization initiative&#x2013;tailored interventions on staff knowledge and texture-modified diet compliance in aged care facilities: A pre-post study. Current Developments in Nutrition 6: nzac032. DOI: 10.1093/cdn/nzac032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cdn/nzac032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8994209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35415388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>