<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39459770</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>20</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Review on Research Progress of Corrosion Resistance of Alkali-Activated Slag Cement Concrete.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5065</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma17205065</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>China is the largest producer and user of Ordinary Silicate Cement (OPC), and rapid infrastructure development requires more sustainable building materials for concrete structures. Portland cement emits large amounts of CO<sub>2</sub> in production. Given proposals for "carbon peaking and carbon neutralization", it is extremely important to study alternative low-carbon cementitious materials to reduce emissions. Alkali-activated slag (AAS) cement, a new green cementitious material, has high application potential. The chemical corrosion resistance of AAS concrete is important for ensuring durability and prolonging service life. This paper reviews the hydration mechanism of AAS concrete and discusses the composition of hydration products on this basis, examines the corrosion mechanism of AAS concrete in acid, sulfate, and seawater environments, and reviews the impact of its performance due to the corrosion of AAS concrete in different solutions. Further in-depth understanding of its impact on the performance of concrete can provide an important theoretical basis for its use in different environments and provides an important theoretical basis for the application of AAS concrete, so that we can have a certain understanding of the durability of AAS concrete.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Qiushuang</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chongqing Telecommunications Polytechnic College, Chongqing 402247, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Xinlu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chongqing Telecommunications Polytechnic College, Chongqing 402247, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Lanfang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Chongqing Jiaotong University, Chongqing 400074, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Haiyan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chongqing Telecommunications Polytechnic College, Chongqing 402247, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No.KJZD-K202405501</GrantID><Agency>the Major project of science and technology research program of Chongqing Education Commission of China.</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No&#xff1a;KJQN202105501</GrantID><Agency>the Youth project of science and technology research program of Chongqing Education Commission of China.</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No&#xff1a;KJQN202105502</GrantID><Agency>the Youth project of science and technology research program of Chongqing Education Commission of China.</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">alkali-activated slag cement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chemical corrosion mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">seawater</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sulfate</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author declares no conflict of interest. </CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39459770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11509794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17205065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma17205065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gartner E. Industrially interesting approaches to &#x201c;low-CO2&#x201d; cements. Cem. Concr. Res. 2004;34:1489&#x2013;1498. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2004.01.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2004.01.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J., Wang Y., Li K., Yao X., Zhu B., Wang J., Dong Q., Wang X. Molecular interfacial properties and engineering performance of conductive fillers in cementitious composites. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2022;19:591&#x2013;604. doi: 10.1016/j.jmrt.2022.05.061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmrt.2022.05.061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J., Wang Y., Liu S., Dehghani A., Xiang X., Wei J., Wang X. Mechanical, chemical and hydrothermal activation for waste glass reinforced cement. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;301:124361. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J., Lin S., Zhang G., Sun Y., Zhang J., Chen C., Morsy A., Wang X. The effect of graphite and slag on electrical and mechanical properties of electrically conductive cementitious composites. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;281:122606. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ba&#x161;&#x10d;arev&#x107; Z. Handbook of Alkali-Activated Cements, Mortars and Concretes. Woodhead Publishing; Sawston, UK: 2015. 14&#x2014;The resistance of alkali-activated cement-based binders to chemical attack; pp. 373&#x2013;396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Z., Sun J., Zeng X., Chen X., Wang Y., Tang W., Wang X. Research on the electrical conductivity and mechanical properties of copper slag multiphase nano-modified electrically conductive cementitious composite. Constr. Build. Mater. 2022;339:127650. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.127650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.127650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Z., Sun J., Tang W., Zeng X., Zeng H., Wang Y., Wang X. Mechanical and electrical properties investigation for electrically conductive cementitious composite containing nano-graphite activated magnetite. J. Build. Eng. 2022;57:104847. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valencia-Saavedra W.G., Mej&#xed;a de Guti&#xe9;rrez R. Resistance to Chemical Attack of Hybrid Fly Ash-Based Alkali-Activated Concretes. Molecules. 2020;25:3389. doi: 10.3390/molecules25153389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules25153389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7435788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32726959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rostami M., Behfarnia K. The effect of silica fume on durability of alkali activated slag concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2017;134:262&#x2013;268. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.12.072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.12.072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernal S.A., San Nicolas R., Provis J.L., Guti&#xe9;rrez R.M., Deventer J.S. Natural carbonation of aged alkali-activated slag concretes. Mater. Struct. 2013;47:693&#x2013;707. doi: 10.1617/s11527-013-0089-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1617/s11527-013-0089-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehi H., Mazloom M. Opposite effects of ground granulated blast-furnace slag and silica fume on the fracture behavior of self-compacting lightweight concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;222:622&#x2013;632. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.06.183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.06.183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chol H., Lee J., Lee B., Nam J. Shrinkage properties of concretes using blast furnace slag and frost-resistant accelerator. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;220:1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.05.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.05.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y., Feng W., Chen Z., Nong Y., Guan S., Sun J. Fracture behavior of a sustainable material: Recycled concrete with waste crumb rubber subjected to elevated temperatures. J. Clean. Prod. 2021;318:128553. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.128553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2021.128553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aslani F., Sun J., Huang G. Mechanical Behavior of Fiber-Reinforced Self-Compacting Rubberized Concrete Exposed to Elevated Temperatures. J. Mater. Civ. Eng. 2019;31:04019302. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0002942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0002942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi M., Ke G., Zou P., Song B., Tang X., Jin D. Progress of hydration, mechanical and shrinkage properties of alkali-slag cement. Bull. Chin. Ceram. Soc. 2022;41:162&#x2013;173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang F. Ph.D. Thesis. Xi&#x2019;an University of Architecture and Technology; Xi&#x2019;an, China: 2008. Research on the Composition Structure and Performance of Alkali-Activated Slag Micro-Powder Cementitious Materials.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang N. Physicochemical basis for the formation of alkali cementitious materials (&#x2161;) J. Chin. Ceram. Soc. 1996;24:459&#x2013;465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo Y. Ph.D. Thesis. Shenzhen University; Shenzhen, China: 2018. Research on the Reaction Process of Alkali-Activated Slag Cementitious Material and Its Modification.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang T., Yu Q., Wei J., Gong C., Zhang P. Hydration of Granulated Blast Furnace Slag in Different Environments; Proceedings of the First Annual Meeting of the Cement Branch of the China Silicate Society; Jiaozuo, China. 22 August 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mastali M., Kinnunen P., Dalvand A., Mohammadi Firouz R., Illikainen M. Drying shrinkage in alkali-activated binders&#x2014;A critical review. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;190:533&#x2013;550. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.09.125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.09.125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Gao M., Lei Z., Tong L., Sun J., Wang Y., Wang X., Jiang X. Ternary cementless composite based on red mud, ultra-fine fly ash, and GGBS: Synergistic utilization and geopolymerization mechanism. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2023;19:e02410. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2023.e02410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacheco-Torgal F. Handbook of Alkali-Activated Cements, Mortars and Concretes. Woodhead Publishing; Oxford, UK: 2015. 1&#x2014;Introduction to Handbook of Alkali-activated Cements, Mortars and Concretes; pp. 1&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang N., Du Y., Liu K. Durability of lightweight alkali-activated ground granulated blast furnace slag (GGBS) stabilized clayey soils subjected to sulfate attack. Appl. Clay Sci. 2018;161:70&#x2013;75. doi: 10.1016/j.clay.2018.04.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clay.2018.04.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B., Zhu H., Shah K.W., Dong Z., Wu J. Performance evaluation and microstructure characterization of seawater and coral/sea sand alkali-activated mortars. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;259:120403. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Q., Huang L., Niu Z., Guo R., Yan F., Lin Z., Du H. Study on the effects of alkali activator concentration and modulus on compressive properties and hydration products of alkali slag cementitious materials. Bull. Chin. Ceram. Soc. 2018;37:2002&#x2013;2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi C., Krivenko P.V., Roy D. Alkali-Activated Cement and Concrete. Chemical Industry Press; Beijing, China: 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X., Shen F., Zheng H., Guo Y., Jiang X., Gao Q. Effect of melt structure property on Al2O3 activity in CaO-SiO2-Al2O3-MgO system for blast furnace slag with different Al2O3 content. Metall. Res. Technol. 2021;118:515. doi: 10.1051/metal/2021076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1051/metal/2021076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adesanya E., Perumal P., Luukkonen T., Yliniemi J., Ohenoja K., Kinnunen P., Illikainen M. Opportunities to improve sustainability of alkali-activated materials: A review of side-stream based activators. J. Clean. Prod. 2021;286:125558. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.125558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.125558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Liao Y. Research on acid corrosion mechanism of concrete. Sci. Technol. Inf. 2010;35:1085&#x2013;1095.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ling J., Ping S., Min P., Yan Z., Dong J., Tian X., Sun J. Acid corrosion damage phenomenon of cementitious materials and measures to improve acid corrosion resistance. China Concr. 2020;4:44&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdel-Gawwad H.A., Abd El-Aleem S. Effect of reactive magnesium oxide on properties of alkali activated slag geopolymer cement pastes. Ceramics. 2015;59:37&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allahverdi A., &#x160;kv&#xe1;ra F. Nitric acid attack on hardened paste of geopolymeric cements. Ceram.&#x2014;Silik. 2001;45:143&#x2013;149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Idrissi A.C., Rozi&#xe8;re E., Darson-Balleur S., Loukili A. Resistance of alkali-activated grouts to acid leaching. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;228:116681. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.116681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.116681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Jim&#xe9;nez A., Garc&#xed;a-Lodeiro I., Palomo A. Durability of alkali-activated fly ashcementitious matcrials. J. Mater. Sci. 2007;9:3055&#x2013;3065. doi: 10.1007/s10853-006-0584-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10853-006-0584-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W., Yao X., Yang T., Zhang Z. The degradation mechanisms of alkali-activated fly ash/slag blend cements exposed to sulphuric acid. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;186:1177&#x2013;1187. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.08.050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.08.050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliques-Granero J., Tognonvi T.M., Tagnit-Hamou A. Durability test methods and their application to AAMs: Case of sulfuric-acid resistance. Mater. Struct. 2016;50:36. doi: 10.1617/s11527-016-0904-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1617/s11527-016-0904-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren J., Zhang L., San Nicolas R. Degradation process of alkali-activated slag/fly ash and Portland cement-based pastes exposed to phosphoric acid. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;232:117209. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y., Lin X., Pan W., Ji T., Liang Y., Zhang H. Study on corrosion mechanism of alkali-activated concrete with biogenic sulfuric acid. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;188:9&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.08.105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.08.105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y., Lin X., Ji T., Liang Y., Pan W. Comparison of corrosion resistance mechanism between ordinary Portland concrete and alkali-activated concrete subjected to biogenic sulfuric acid attack. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;228:117071. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L. Ph.D. Thesis. Chongqing University; Chongqing, China: 2006. Research on the Properties of Alkali-Activated Composite Cinder (AAW) Concrete.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asaad M.A., Huseien G.F., Memon R.P., Ghoshal S.K., Mohammadhosseini H., Alyousef R. Enduring performance of alkali-activated mortars with metakaolin as granulated blast furnace slag replacement. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2022;16:e845. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee N.K., Lee H.K. Influence of the slag content on the chloride and sulfuric acid resistances of alkali-activated fly ash/slag paste. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2016;72:168&#x2013;179. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2016.06.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2016.06.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sturm P., Gluth G.J.G., J&#xe4;ger C., Brouwers H.J.H., K&#xfc;hne H.-C. Sulfuric acid resistance of one-part alkali-activated mortars. Cem. Concr. Res. 2018;109:54&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2018.04.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2018.04.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huseien G.F., Shah K.W. Durability and life cycle evaluation of self-compacting concrete containing fly ash as GBFS replacement with alkali activation. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;235:117458. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan M.N.N., Kuri J.C., Sarker P.K. Sustainable use of waste glass in alkali activated materials against H2SO4 and HCl acid attacks. Clean. Eng. Technol. 2022;6:100354. doi: 10.1016/j.clet.2021.100354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clet.2021.100354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mithun B.M., Narasimhan M.C. Performance of alkali activated slag concrete mixes incorporating copper slag as fine aggregate. J. Clean. Prod. 2016;112:837&#x2013;844. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2015.06.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2015.06.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren J., Zhang L., San Nicolas R. Degradation of Alkali-Activated Slag and Fly Ash Mortars under Different Aggressive Acid Conditions. J. Mater. Civil. Eng. 2021;33:04021140. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0003713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0003713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander M.G., Fourie C. Performance of sewer pipe concrete mixtures with portland and calcium aluminate cements subject to mineral and biogenic acid attack. Mater. Struct. 2011;44:313&#x2013;330. doi: 10.1617/s11527-010-9629-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1617/s11527-010-9629-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao W., Fan Z., Li X., Kong L., Zhang L. Characterization and Comparison of Corrosion Layer Microstructure between Cement Mortar and Alkali-Activated Fly Ash/Slag Mortar Exposed to Sulfuric Acid and Acetic Acid. Materials. 2022;15:1527. doi: 10.3390/ma15041527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15041527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8880145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35208067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afridi S., Sikandar M.A., Waseem M., Nasir H., Naseer A. Chemical durability of superabsorbent polymer (SAP) based geopolymer mortars (GPMs) Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;217:530&#x2013;542. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.05.101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.05.101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandit P., Prashanth S., Katpady D.N. Durability of alkali-activated fly ash-slag concrete- state of art. Innov. Infrastruct. Solut. 2024;9:222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd R.R., Provis J.L., van Deventer J.S.J. Acid resistance of inorganic polymer binders. 1. Corrosion rate. Mater. Struct. 2011;45:1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1617/s11527-011-9744-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1617/s11527-011-9744-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellado A., P&#xe9;rez-Ramos M.I., Monz&#xf3; J., Borrachero M.V., Pay&#xe1; J. Resistance to acid attack of alkali-activated binders: Simple new techniques to measure susceptibility. Constr. Build. Mater. 2017;150:355&#x2013;366. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.05.224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.05.224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teymouri M., Behfarnia K., Shabani A. Mix Design Effects on the Durability of Alkali-Activated Slag Concrete in a Hydrochloric Acid Environment. Sustainability. 2021;13:8096. doi: 10.3390/su13148096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su13148096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thunuguntla C.S., Rao T.G. Effect of mix design parameters on mechanical and durability properties of alkali activated slag concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;193:173&#x2013;188. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.10.189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.10.189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernal S.A., Rodr&#xed;guez E.D., Guti&#xe9;rrez R.M., Provis J.L. Performance of alkali-activated slag mortars exposed to acids. J. Sustain. Cem.-Based Mater. 2012;1:138&#x2013;151. doi: 10.1080/21650373.2012.747235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21650373.2012.747235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T., Sun Z., Ding K. Research progress on mechanical properties and erosion products of sulfate-eroded concrete. China Concr. Cem. Prod. 2019;1:1&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogawa S., Nozaki T., Yamada K., Hirao H., Hooton R.D. Improvement on sulfate resistance of blended cement with high alumina slag. Cem. Concr. Res. 2012;42:244&#x2013;251. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2011.09.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2011.09.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Qin Q., Sun J., Ma Y., Li Q. Mechanical and conductive performance of electrically conductive cementitious composite using graphite, steel slag, and GGBS. Struct. Concr. 2020;23:533&#x2013;547. doi: 10.1002/suco.202000617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/suco.202000617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Y., Dong Z., Stephan D., Li M. Experimental study on the durability of alkali-stimulated slag concrete under the action of erosive media. Concrete. 2021;9:82&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye H., Chen Z., Huang L. Mechanism of sulfate attack on alkali-activated slag: The role of activator composition. Cem. Concr. Res. 2019;125:105868. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira L.B., de Azevedo A.R.G., Marvila M.T., Elaine C., Pereira E.C., Fediuk R., Vieira C.M.F. Durability of geopolymers with industrial waste. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2022;16:e839. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2021.e00839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Jim&#xe9;nez A., Puertas F., Sobrados I., Sanz J. Structure of Calcium Silicate Hydrates Formed in Alkaline-Activated Slag: Influence of the Type of Alkaline Activator. J. Am. Ceram. Soc. 2003;86:1389&#x2013;1394. doi: 10.1111/j.1151-2916.2003.tb03481.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1151-2916.2003.tb03481.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail I., Bernal S.A., Provis J.L., Hamdan S., Deventer V. Microstructural changes in alkali activated fly ash/slag geopolymers with sulfate exposure. Mater. Struct. 2013;46:361&#x2013;373. doi: 10.1617/s11527-012-9906-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1617/s11527-012-9906-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng R., Yang C., Chen Y. Discussion on the mechanism of alkali-inspired cementitious materials against sulfate erosion. J. Zhengzhou Univ. 2012;33:1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang J., Liu L., He Y., Zhang N., Cui X. Early mechanical properties and microstructural evolution of slag/metakaolin-based geopolymers exposed to karst water. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2019;99:140&#x2013;150. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2019.03.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2019.03.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashad A.M., Bai Y., Basheer P.A.M., Milestone N.B., Collier N.C. Hydration and properties of sodium sulfate activated slag. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2013;37:20&#x2013;29. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2012.12.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2012.12.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binici H., Kapur S., Arocena J., Kaplan H. The sulphate resistance of cements containing red brick dust and ground basaltic pumice with sub-microscopic evidence of intra-pore gypsum and ettringite as strengtheners. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2012;34:279&#x2013;287. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2011.10.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2011.10.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X. Study on the microstructure of hydrated C-A-S-H gel of alkali-activated slag cement. Silic. Bull. 2019;38:1062&#x2013;1067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Provis J.L., Myers R.J., White C.E., Rose V., Deventer J.S.J.V. X-ray microtomography shows pore structure and tortuosity in alkali-activated binders. Cem. Concr. Res. 2012;42:855&#x2013;864. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2012.03.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2012.03.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coppola L., Coffetti D., Crotti E., Gazzaniga G., Pastore T. The Durability of One-Part Alkali-Activated Slag-Based Mortars in Different Environments. Sustainability. 2020;12:3561. doi: 10.3390/su12093561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su12093561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Shi C., Zhang Z., Hu X. Reaction mechanism of sulfate attack on alkali-activated slag/fly ash cements. Constr. Build. Mater. 2022;318:126052. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.126052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.126052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayd&#x131;n S., Baradan B. Sulfate resistance of alkali-activated slag and Portland cement based reactive powder concrete. J. Build. Eng. 2021;43:103205. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J. Carbonation, Chloride Binding and Sulfate Erosion Resistance of Alkali Slag/Fly Ash Cement. Hunan University; Changsha, China: 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang A., Zheng Y., Zhang Z., Liu K., Li Y., Shi L., Sun D. The Durability of Alkali-Activated Materials in Comparison with Ordinary Portland Cements and Concretes: A Review. Engineering. 2020;6:695&#x2013;706. doi: 10.1016/j.eng.2019.08.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eng.2019.08.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad M.R., Chen B., Shah S.F.A. Influence of different admixtures on the mechanical and durability properties of one-part alkali-activated mortars. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;265:120320. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q., Li X., Yang K., Zhu X., Gevaudan J.P., Yang C., Basheer M. The long-term failure mechanisms of alkali-activated slag mortar exposed to wet-dry cycles of sodium sulphate. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2021;116:103893. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2020.103893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2020.103893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y., Huang Z., Chen Z., Chen M., Zhou H., Zhang H., Sun J. Novel visual crack width measurement based on backbone double-scale features for improved detection automation. Eng. Struct. 2023;274:115158. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2022.115158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2022.115158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun S., Ye Z., Liu K., Wang A., Guan Y., Chen D. Sand consolidation characteristics and sulfate erosion resistance of alkali slag cementitious materials. Mater. Rep. 2020;34:10061&#x2013;10067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang G. Sand consolidation characteristics and sulfate erosion resistance of alkali slag cementitious materials. Chem. Eng. Manag. 2020;33:64&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Y. Research on Service Performance Mechanism and Pore Solution of Alkali-Activated Slag Concrete under Sulfate Dry and Wet Cycles. Qingdao University of Technology; Qingdao, China: 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu H., Liang G., Li H., Wu Q., Zhang C., Yin Z., Hua S. Insights to the sulfate resistance and microstructures of alkali-activated metakaolin/slag pastes. Appl. Clay Sci. 2021;202:105968. doi: 10.1016/j.clay.2020.105968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clay.2020.105968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heikal M., Nassar M.Y., El-Sayed G., Ibrahim S.M. Physico-chemical, mechanical, microstructure and durability characteristics of alkali activated Egyptian slag. Constr. Build. Mater. 2014;69:60&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.07.026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.07.026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karako&#xe7; M.B., T&#xfc;rkmen &#x130;., Mara&#x15f; M.M., Kantarci F., Demirbo&#x11f;a R. Sulfate resistance of ferrochrome slag based geopolymer concrete. Ceram. Int. 2016;42 Pt B:1254&#x2013;1260. doi: 10.1016/j.ceramint.2015.09.058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceramint.2015.09.058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai Y., Yu S., Chen W. Research on sulfate erosion resistance of alkali slag concrete. Concrete. 2019;9:43&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Z., Yu X. Study on sulfate erosion resistance of alkali slag concrete and cement concrete. Concr. Cem. Prod. 2021;9:21&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong K., White C.E. Nanoscale Chemical Degradation Mechanisms of Sulfate Attack in Alkali-activated Slag. J. Phys. Chem. 2018;122:5992&#x2013;6004. doi: 10.1021/acs.jpcc.7b11270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.7b11270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakharev T., Sanjayan J.G., Cheng Y.B. Sulfate attack on alkali-activated slag concrete. Cem. Concr. Res. 2002;32:211&#x2013;216. doi: 10.1016/S0008-8846(01)00659-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0008-8846(01)00659-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komljenovic M., Bascarevic Z., Marjanovic N., Nikoli&#x107; V. External sulfate attack on alkali-activated slag. Constr. Build. Mater. 2013;49:31&#x2013;39. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2013.08.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2013.08.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirezci E., Young I.R., Ranasinghe R., Sanne M., Robert J.N., Daniel L., Jochen H. Projections of global-scale extreme sea levels and resulting episodic coastal flooding over the 21st Century. Sci. Rep. 2020;10:11629. doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-67736-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-67736-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7393110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32732976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta P.K., Monteiro P. Concrete: Microstructure, Properties, and Materials. McGraw-Hill Publishing; New York, NY, USA: 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aslani F., Sun J., Bromley D., Ma G. Fiber-reinforced lightweight self-compacting concrete incorporating scoria aggregates at elevated temperatures. Struct. Concr. 2019;20:1022&#x2013;1035. doi: 10.1002/suco.201800231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/suco.201800231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh B.H., Jang S.Y. Effects of material and environmental parameters on chloride penetration profiles in concrete structures. Cem. Concr. Res. 2007;37:47&#x2013;53. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2006.09.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2006.09.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi J., Wu M., Ming J. Long-term corrosion resistance of reinforcing steel in alkali-activated slag mortar after exposure to marine environments. Corros. Sci. 2021;179:109175. doi: 10.1016/j.corsci.2020.109175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.corsci.2020.109175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Y., Huang X. Experiment on the effect of chloride salt on the strength of alkali-activated slag paste. J. Beijing Univ. Aeronaut. Astronaut. 2015;41:693&#x2013;700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babaee M., Castel A. Chloride diffusivity, chloride threshold, and corrosion initiation in reinforced alkali-activated mortars: Role of calcium, alkali, and silicate content. Cem. Concr. Res. 2018;111:56&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2018.06.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2018.06.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jun Y., Yoon S., Oh J. A Comparison Study for Chloride-Binding Capacity between Alkali-Activated Fly Ash and Slag in the Use of Seawater. Appl. Sci. 2017;7:971. doi: 10.3390/app7100971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app7100971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mengasini L., Mavroulidou M., Gunn M.J. Alkali-activated concrete mixes with ground granulated blast furnace slag and paper sludge ash in seawater environments. Sustain. Chem. Pharm. 2021;20:100380. doi: 10.1016/j.scp.2021.100380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scp.2021.100380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nikolic I., Tadic M., Jankovic-Castvan I., Radmilovi&#x107; V.V., Radmilovi&#x107; V.R. Durability of alkali activated slag in a marine environment: Influence of alkali ion. J. Serbian Chem. Soc. 2018;83:1143&#x2013;1156. doi: 10.2298/JSC180328057N.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2298/JSC180328057N</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y.-L., Zhao X.-L., Raman R.K.S., Al-Saadi S. Thermal and mechanical properties of alkali-activated slag paste, mortar and concrete utilising seawater and sea sand. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;159:704&#x2013;724. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.10.104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.10.104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S., Xu J., Zang C., Li R., Yang Q., Sun S. Mechanical properties of alkali-activated slag concrete mixed by seawater and sea sand. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;196:395&#x2013;410. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.11.113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.11.113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dasar A., Patah D., Hamada H., Sagawa Y., Yamamoto D. Applicability of seawater as a mixing and curing agent in 4-year-old concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;259:119692. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melchers R. Pitting Corrosion of Mild Steel in Marine Immersion Environment--Part 2: Variability of Maximum Pit Depth. Corros. J. Sci. Eng. 2004;60:937&#x2013;944. doi: 10.5006/1.3287827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5006/1.3287827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Wei Y., Liu Z., Cui Z. Effects of seawater corrosion on compression-induced buckling performance of FRP-CFST columns. Eng. Fail. Anal. 2024;162:108441. doi: 10.1016/j.engfailanal.2024.108441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2024.108441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed T., Hamada H., Yamaji T. Performance of seawater-mixed concrete in the tidal environment. Cem. Concr. Res. 2004;34:593&#x2013;601. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2003.09.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2003.09.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Liu W., Mi T., Ding X., Tang L., Xing F. Durability study of seawater and sea-sand concrete under the combined effects of carbonation and chloride redistribution. J. Build. Eng. 2024;89:109294. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chalee W., Jaturapitakkul C., Chindaprasirt P. Predicting the chloride penetration of fly ash concrete in seawater. Mar. Struct. 2008;22:341&#x2013;353. doi: 10.1016/j.marstruc.2008.12.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.marstruc.2008.12.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ting M.Z.Y., Yi Y. Durability of cementitious materials in seawater environment: A review on chemical interactions, hardened-state properties and environmental factors. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;367:130224. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.130224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.130224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Y., Tao Y., Xuan D., Sun Y., Poon C.S. Effect of seawater on the morphology, structure, and properties of synthetic ettringite. Cem. Concr. Res. 2023;163:107034. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2022.107034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2022.107034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashad A.M., Sadek D.M. An Exploratory Study on Alkali-Activated Slag Blended with Microsize Metakaolin Particles Under the Effect of Seawater Attack and Tidal Zone. Arab. J. Sci. Eng. 2022;47:4499&#x2013;4510. doi: 10.1007/s13369-021-06151-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13369-021-06151-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>