<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40215222</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Research on the influence of waterproof layer on lining mechanical performance under early temperature load.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0321143</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0321143</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0321143</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0321143</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The installation of waterproof layer in the composite lining will change the tangential constraint conditions on the initial support side of lining, affecting the lining mechanical performance under early temperature loads. Based on a loess double track railway tunnel, the influence of tangential constraints on lining mechanical performance under concrete hydration heat temperature load was studied by numerical simulation. Interactions between surrounding rock, initial support, waterproof layer and lining were taken into consideration in the simulation model. The influences of concrete initial pouring temperature, surface heat dissipation coefficient on thermal stress of lining were analyzed and engineering suggestions for preventing early crack were proposed as well. The results show that the greater tangential constraints imposed by the waterproof layer on lining, the greater lining thermal tensile stress, and the higher the risk of through crack. Lining springing constrained by inverted arch is prone to cracking and should be paid more attention in the construction process. Lining thermal stress is significantly affected by concrete initial pouring temperature, and appropriately reducing the pouring temperature is conducive to prevent the occurrence of early cracks. For waterless tunnels, the waterproof layer may be considered to be omitted, and the tangential constraints on the lining can be reduced by installing a thin polyethylene plastic film. The research results can be useful for the design of the composite lining structure.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Sun et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Mingshe</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-8616-1992</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Hydraulic and Civil Engineering, Ludong University, Yantai, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guan</LastName><ForeName>Zhenxiang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>China Railway 19th Bureau Group Corporation Limited, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Caixia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Urban Security and Disaster Engineering of Ministry of Education, Beijing University of Technology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xi</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Construction Engineering Affairs Service Center of Laishan, Yantai, Shandong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tian</LastName><ForeName>Sen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Urban Security and Disaster Engineering of Ministry of Education, Beijing University of Technology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013696" MajorTopicYN="Y">Temperature</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003252" MajorTopicYN="Y">Construction Materials</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013314" MajorTopicYN="N">Stress, Mechanical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008962" MajorTopicYN="N">Models, Theoretical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003198" MajorTopicYN="N">Computer Simulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40215222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11990643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0321143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-24-49917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang J. Discussion on the composite shell lining. Mod Tunnelling Technol. 2019;56(01):1&#x2013;5. doi: 10.13807/j.cnki.mtt.2019.01.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13807/j.cnki.mtt.2019.01.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X, Shi C, Ge Y. Experimental investigation and cohesive zone modeling of the interface mechanical behavior in composite tunnel linings. Tunnelling Undergr Space Technol. 2024;150:105837. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2024.105837</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2024.105837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinlein U, Thienel K-C, Freimann T. Pre-applied bonded waterproofing membranes: a review of the history and state-of-the-art in Europe and North America. Constr Build Materials. 2021;296:123751. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123751</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luciani A, Peila D. Tunnel waterproofing: available technologies and evaluation through risk analysis. Int J Civ Eng. 2018;17(1):45&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1007/s40999-018-0328-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40999-018-0328-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin Y, Lai J, Li C, Fan F, Liu T. Negative pressure testing standard for welded scar airtightness of waterproofing sheet for tunnels: experimental and numerical investigation. Tunnelling Undergr Space Technol. 2023;133:104930. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2022.104930</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2022.104930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong C, Xie C, Zhu H, Ding W, Song J, Ge Y. Time-varying compressive properties and constitutive model of EPDM rubber materials for tunnel gasketed joint. Constr Build Materials. 2024;433:136734. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136734</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong C, Cheng M, Peng Y, Ding W. Seepage propagation simulation of a tunnel gasketed joint using the cohesive zone model. Tunnelling Undergr Space Technol. 2024;147:105726. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2024.105726</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2024.105726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Fu W, Hu X, Liu C, Yang Q, Ju JW. Experimental study on the long-term behaviors of spray-applied acrylate waterproofing membrane for tunnels exposed to aggressive ions. Constr Build Materials. 2020;258:119603. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119603</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holter KG, Geving S. Moisture transport through sprayed concrete tunnel linings. Rock Mech Rock Eng. 2015;49(1):243&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1007/s00603-015-0730-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-015-0730-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holter KG. Performance of EVA-based membranes for SCL in hard rock. Rock Mech Rock Eng. 2015;49(4):1329&#x2013;58. doi: 10.1007/s00603-015-0844-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00603-015-0844-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson RP, Swallow FE, Psomas S. Structural properties and durability of a sprayed waterproofing membrane for tunnels. Tunnelling Undergr Space Technol. 2016;60:41&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2016.07.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2016.07.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X, Shi C, Xiao G, Ge Y, Cao C. A novel tunnel waterproof-drainage system based on double-bonded waterproofing materials and its seepage characteristics. Front Struct Civ Eng. 2024;18(9):1321&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1007/s11709-024-1100-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11709-024-1100-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X, Shi C, Xiao G, Ge Y, Cao C. A new tunnel drainage system using double-adhesive spray-applied membrane: key parameters and applicable scope. Discov Civ Eng. 2024;1(1). doi: 10.1007/s44290-024-00105-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s44290-024-00105-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelz U, Karlov&#x161;ek J. Spray-applied waterproofing membranes in tunnelling: application and research directions in Australia. Tunnelling Undergr Space Technol. 2022;122:104364. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2022.104364</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2022.104364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelz U, Karlov&#x161;ek J. Spray-applied waterproofing membranes in tunnelling: a construction perspective. Tunnelling Undergr Space Technol. 2023;142:105409. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2023.105409</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2023.105409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen SG, Guan BS. Finite element simulation of mechanical action of waterproof board[C]//Proceedings of the 2th tunnel and underground engineering society. Beijing: China Civil Engineering Society; 1992. p. 456&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng H, Zhang Q, Sun J. Deformation and mechanic transmission of water-proof tube of complexing tunnel lining. West-China Exploration Engineering. 1998;10(3):1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang P. Study on the concrete thermal stress and crack control of a tunnel final lining. Xi&#x2019;an: Chang&#x2019;an University; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang HF. Research on thermal stress cracking of tunnel lining concrete with consideration of constraint condition. Xi&#x2019;an: Chang&#x2019;an University; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloodworth A, Su J. Numerical analysis and capacity evaluation of composite sprayed concrete lined tunnels. Underground Space. 2018;3(2):87&#x2013;108. doi: 10.1016/j.undsp.2017.12.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.undsp.2017.12.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su J, Bloodworth A. On composite action and tunnel lining design; is composite action beneficial in reducing lining thickness? Tunnelling J. 2019:38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su J, Bloodworth A. Simulating composite behaviour in SCL tunnels with sprayed waterproofing membrane interface: a state-of-the-art review. Eng Struct. 2019;191:698&#x2013;710. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2019.04.067</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2019.04.067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su J, Bloodworth A. Determination of the stress-strain demand curve of the sprayed waterproofing membrane interface in composite SCL tunnels. Tunnelling Undergr Space Technol. 2023;142:105408. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2023.105408</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2023.105408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Y, He B, Zhao J, Pei H, Liu J, Wang H. Influence of novel polymer waterproofing membrane on mechanical properties of tunnel lining structure. Constr Build Materials. 2022;360:129579. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129579</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao F, Bobet A. Effect of temperature on deep lined circular tunnels in transversely anisotropic elastic rock. Undergr Space. 2016;1(2):79&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1016/j.undsp.2016.11.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.undsp.2016.11.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H, Zhang K, Zhu X, Tian Z, Zhang Q. Study on the freeze&#x2010;thaw process of the lining structures of a tunnel on qinghai&#x2010;tibet plateau with the consideration of lining frost damage. Adv Materials Sci Eng. 2021;2021(1). doi: 10.1155/2021/4921365</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/4921365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Z, Chen J, Luo Y, Zhu H, Liu W, Shi Z, et al. Geomechanical model test for mechanical properties and cracking features of large-section tunnel lining under periodic temperature. Tunnelling Undergr Space Technol. 2022;123:104319. doi: 10.1016/j.tust.2021.104319</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tust.2021.104319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua Y, Yu L, Lv C, Zhao Y, Wang M. Analysis of influence of demolding strength of high speed railway tunnel lining on structure safety. Railway Standard Design. 2018;62(12):98&#x2013;105. doi: 10.13238/j.issn.1004-2954.201712190006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13238/j.issn.1004-2954.201712190006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The International Federation for Structural Concrete (FIB). FIB model code for concrete structures 2010. Munchen: Ernst and Sohn Publishing House; 2013. p. 128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Liu Z, Lu J. Experimental study on coefficient of thermal conductivity and specific volume heat of loess. Rock and Soil Mechanics. 2007;28(4):655&#x2013;8. doi: 10.16285/j.rsm.2007.04.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16285/j.rsm.2007.04.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura A, Kunichika M, Kameya H, Nakamura H. Identification of thermal properties in the initial crack prediction of the tunnel lining concrete and its analysis. J Japan Soc Civil Eng Ser. 2015;70(3):1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.2208/jscejte.70.I_1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2208/jscejte.70.I_1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B, Chalaturnyk R, Boisvert J. Sequentially coupled thermal-hydraulic-mechanical simulation for geomechanical assessments of caprock integrity in SAGD. Can Geotech J. 2024;61(6):1242&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1139/cgj-2023-0228</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/cgj-2023-0228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song X, Lu Y, Peng Y, Zhang Y, Zhou H. Sequentially coupled thermal-stress analysis of traditional timber mortise-tenon joints with damage. J Build Eng. 2024;86:108781. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.108781</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.108781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>