<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38398504</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1420-3049</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Molecules (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Molecules</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of the Side-Chain Length in Polycarboxylic Superplasticizer on the Competition Adsorption in the Presence of Montmorillonite: A Density Functional Theory Study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">752</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/molecules29040752</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Polycarboxylic superplasticizers (PCEs) exhibit numerous advantages as concrete additives, effectively improving the stability and strength of concrete. However, competitive adsorption of PCEs occurs in the presence of clay, which may affect the cement dispersion and water-reducing performance. Extensive research has been conducted on the physical and mechanical properties of PCEs; however, the effect of the diverse structures of PCEs on the competitive adsorption on clay and cement hydration products has been rarely studied. This study employs Ca-montmorillonite (CaMMT) as a clay representative, by constructing adsorption models of PCEs on CaMMT and cement hydration products. A comparison of the adsorption energies considering different side-chain lengths of PCEs is included. Typically, the adsorption energy on CaMMT is lower than that on hydration products, leading PCEs to preferentially adsorb on the clay, thereby reducing its effective dosage in the cement particles. The challenge of PCE adsorption on CaMMT increases with the polymerization degree, and methylallyl polyoxyethylene ether (HPEG) exhibits lower adsorption energies on CaMMT. The density of states (DOS) analysis indicated the highest peak values of allyl polyethylene ether (APEG) as well as the peak area at n (polymerization degree) = 1. The total number of transferred electrons for APEG was 0.648, surpassing those of other PCEs. The interaction mechanism of PCEs with clay and hydration products is further elucidated through electronic gain/loss analysis, also providing a basis for the theoretical analysis on how to reduce the adsorption of PCEs on clay and the structural design of mud-resistant PCEs.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Zhihao</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Emergency Management, Xihua University, Chengdu 610039, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Geohazard Prevention and Geoenvironment Protection, Chengdu University of Technology, Chengdu 610059, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Teng</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Environment and Resource, Southwest University of Science and Technology, Mianyang 621010, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Waste Treatment and Resource Recycle, Southwest University of Science and Technology, Ministry of Education, Mianyang 621010, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Meiben</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Emergency Management, Xihua University, Chengdu 610039, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Geohazard Prevention and Geoenvironment Protection, Chengdu University of Technology, Chengdu 610059, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kong</LastName><ForeName>Desong</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Environment and Resource, Southwest University of Science and Technology, Mianyang 621010, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Meng</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Environment and Resource, Southwest University of Science and Technology, Mianyang 621010, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>GHBK-2023-03</GrantID><Agency>Open fund of State Environmental Protection Key Laboratory of Synergetic Control and Joint Remediation for Soil &amp; Water Pollution (Chengdu University of Technology)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>SKLGP2023K006</GrantID><Agency>Opening fund of State Key Laboratory of Geohazard Prevention and Geoenvironment Protection (Chengdu University of Technology)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>SKLGP2022K011</GrantID><Agency>Opening fund of State Key Laboratory of Geohazard Prevention and Geoenvironment Protection (Chengdu University of Technology)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Molecules</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100964009</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1420-3049</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PCEs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cement concrete</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clay</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">compatibility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">molecular simulation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38398504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10892659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules29040752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">molecules29040752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Yang C., Zhang Y., Zheng J., Guo H., Lu M. Study on dispersion, adsorption and flow retaining behaviors of cement mortars with TPEG-type polyether kind polycarboxylate superplasticizers. Constr. Build. Mater. 2014;64:324&#x2013;332. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.04.050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.04.050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C., Tang X., Chen X., Guo H., Li X. Progress on the Clay Tolerance of Polycarboxylate Superplasticizers. Mater. Rep. 2022;36:22040251. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng H., Pan L., Zheng Q., Li J., Xu N., Pang S. Effects of molecular structure of polycarboxylate superplasticizers on their dispersion and adsorption behavior in cement paste with two kinds of stone powder. Construct. Build. Mater. 2018;170:182&#x2013;192. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.02.195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.02.195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing G., Wang W., Fang G. Cement dispersion performance of superplasticisers in the presence of clay and interaction between superplasticisers and clay. Adv. Cem. Res. 2017;29:194&#x2013;205. doi: 10.1680/jadcr.16.00068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1680/jadcr.16.00068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong F.-R., Pan L.-S., Wang C.-M., Zhang D.-L., Xu N. Effects of polycarboxylate superplasticizers with different molecular structure on the hydration behavior of cement paste. Constr. Build. Mater. 2016;105:545&#x2013;553. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.12.178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.12.178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ran Q., Liu J., Yang Y., Shu X., Zhang J., Mao Y. Effect of molecular weight of polycarboxylate superplasticizer on its dispersion, adsorption, and hydration of a cementitious system. J. Mater. Civ. Eng. 2016;28:04015184. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0001460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0001460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen X.-D., Feng L., Hu D.-Y., Wang K., Zhang Z. Effect of side-chain length in polycarboxylic superplasticizer on the early-age performance of cement-based materials. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;211:26&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.03.124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.03.124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang S. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Chongqing University; Chongqing, China: 2018. Improvements on Effect of Mud on Polycarboxylate Superplasticizer in Concrete. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen G., Lei J., Du Y., Du X., Chen X. A polycarboxylate as a superplasticizer for montmorillonite clay in cement: Adsorption and tolerance studies. Arab. J. Chem. 2018;11:747&#x2013;755. doi: 10.1016/j.arabjc.2017.12.027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arabjc.2017.12.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X.K., Zheng D.F., Zheng T., Lin X.L., Lou H.M., Qiu X.Q. Enhancement clay tolerance of PCE by lignin-based polyoxyethylene ether in montmorillonite-contained paste. J. Ind. Eng. Chem. 2017;49:168&#x2013;175. doi: 10.1016/j.jiec.2017.01.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jiec.2017.01.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H., Liao B., Nian F., Wang K., Guo Y., Pang H. Investigation of the Clay Sensitivity and Cement Hydration Process of Modified HPEG-type Polycarboxylate Superplasticizers. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 2018;135:46572. doi: 10.1002/app.46572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/app.46572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng H., He Z., Meiben G., Zhang J. DFT Study on the Compatibility Between Bentonite Clay Mineral and Hydration Products With the Polycarboxylate Water Reducer in the Cement Hydration Process. Front. Earth Sci. 2022;10:890968. doi: 10.3389/feart.2022.890968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/feart.2022.890968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z. Ph.D. Thesis. China University of Mining &amp; Technology; Beijing, China: 2013. Research on Synthesis, Properties and Mechanism of Different Carboxyl Density and Functionallizing Polycarboxylate Superplasticizer. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu H., Fu C.E., Yang W., Yang Z., Zhang L. Preparation, application and water reducing mechanism of a novel fluorescent superplasticizer with improved flow retaining ability and clay tolerance. J. Disper. Sci. Technol. 2018;39:1829&#x2013;1839. doi: 10.1080/01932691.2018.1462197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01932691.2018.1462197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Guan J., Lai G., Zheng Y., Wang Z., Cui S., Lan M., Li H. Novel designs of polycarboxylate superplasticizers for improving resistance in clay-contaminated concrete. J. Ind. Eng. Chem. 2017;55:80&#x2013;90. doi: 10.1016/j.jiec.2017.06.031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jiec.2017.06.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing G., Wang W., Xu J. Grafting tertiary amine groups into the molecular structures of polycarboxylate superplasticizers lowers their clay sensitivity. RSC Adv. 2016;6:106921&#x2013;106927. doi: 10.1039/C6RA22027D.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C6RA22027D</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan H., Guo Y., Ma B., Gu B., Zou F. Effect of sodium gluconate on clay tolerance of polycarboxylate superplasticiser. Adv. Cem. Res. 2017;29:278&#x2013;286. doi: 10.1680/jadcr.16.00176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1680/jadcr.16.00176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouellet-Plamondon C., Scherb S., K&#xf6;berl M., Thienel K.-C. Acceleration of cement blended with calcined clays. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;245:118439. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erzengin S.G., Kaya K., &#xd6;zkorucuklu S.P., &#xd6;zdemir V., Y&#x131;ld&#x131;r&#x131;m G. The properties of cement systems superplasticized with methacrylic ester-based polycarboxylates. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;166:96&#x2013;109. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.01.088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.01.088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mudaser A.H., Shahzad K.M., Al-Harthi M. Polymeric and low molecular weight shale inhibitors: A review. Fuel. 2019;251:187&#x2013;217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong D. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Wuhan University of Technology; Wuhan, China: 2019. Study on Modification and Chemical Mechanism of Polycarboxylate Superplasticizers for Enhanced Clay Tolerance. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma Y., Shi C., Lei L., Sha S., Zhou B., Liu Y., Xiao Y. Research progress on polycarboxylate based superplasticizers with tolerance to clays-a review. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;255:119386. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng C., Min F., Liu L. Effect of pH on the Adsorption of Dodecylamine on Montmorillonite: Insights from Experiments and Molecular Dynamics Simulations. App. Surf. Sci. 2017;425:996&#x2013;1005. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2017.07.085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2017.07.085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Z., Pei X., Zhang J., Huang R., Deng M., Gao Y., Gao M., Xie L. Molecular simulation for the relationship between the functional groups of chemical admixtures and cement hydration product Ca (OH)2 in the grouting process. Ecol. Indic. 2023;153:110404. doi: 10.1016/j.ecolind.2023.110404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolind.2023.110404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng Y., Zhao G., Wang P., Liu X., Zhang G. Study on the retardation of re-dispersible polymer powders on cement hydration based on morphologies of Ca(OH)2. J. Chin. Electron Microsc. Soc. 2016;35:490&#x2013;495. (In Chinese)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song Y., Zhang Y., Shen S., Pan C., Yan D., Wang Z. Effects of Ca(OH)2 on the reinforcement corrosion of sulfoaluminate cement mortar. Mater. Struct. 2023;56:26. doi: 10.1617/s11527-023-02110-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1617/s11527-023-02110-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei L., Zhang Y., Li R. Specific molecular design of polycarboxylate polymers exhibiting optimal compatibility with clay contaminants in concrete. Cem. Concr. Res. 2021;147:106504. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2021.106504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2021.106504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koteeswaran S., Pashin J.C., Ramsey J.D., Clark P.E. Quantitative characterization of polyacrylamide&#x2013;shale interaction under various saline conditions. Pet. Sci. 2017;14:586&#x2013;596. doi: 10.1007/s12182-017-0166-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12182-017-0166-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babaei Z., Najafi Chermahini A., Dinari M., Dinari M. Glycerol Adsorption and Mechanism of Dehydration to Acrolein over TiO2 Surface: A Density Functional Theory Study. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2020;563:1&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1016/j.jcis.2019.12.051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2019.12.051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31865043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;rk&#xe7;&#xfc; C., Merdan Z., Yam&#xe7;i&#xe7;ier &#x4aa;. Structural phase transition and electronic properties of CaO under high pressure. Mater. Res. Express. 2018;5:125903. doi: 10.1088/2053-1591/aae012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/2053-1591/aae012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taifan W.E., Bu&#x10d;ko T., Baltrusaitis J. Catalytic conversion of ethanol to 1,3-butadiene on MgO: A comprehensive mechanism elucidation using DFT calculations. J. Catal. 2017;346:78&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1016/j.jcat.2016.11.042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcat.2016.11.042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang B., Kang J., Kang T. Effect of water on methane adsorption on the kaolinite (0 0 1) surface based on molecular simulations. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2018;439:792&#x2013;800. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2017.12.239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2017.12.239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng C., Zhong Y., Min F. Adsorption of alkylamine cations on montmorillonite (001) surface: A density functional theory study. Appl. Clay Sci. 2018;152:249&#x2013;258. doi: 10.1016/j.clay.2017.11.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clay.2017.11.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J., Min F.-F., Liu L., Liu C., Lu F. Experimental investigation and DFT calculation of different amine/ammonium salts adsorption on kaolinite. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2017;419:241&#x2013;251. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2017.04.213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2017.04.213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B., Liu S., Guo J., Zhang L. Interaction between low rank coal and kaolinite particles: A DFT simulation. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2018;456:215&#x2013;220. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2018.06.121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2018.06.121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan Y., Zhuo Y., Li L. SeO2 adsorption on CaO surface: DFT and experimental study on the adsorption of multiple SeO2 molecules. App. Surf. Sci. 2017;420:465&#x2013;471. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2017.04.233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2017.04.233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sodeifian G., Nikooamal H.R., Yousefi A.A. Molecular dynamics study of epoxy/clay nanocomposites: Rheology and molecular confinement. J. Polym. Res. 2012;19:9897. doi: 10.1007/s10965-012-9897-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10965-012-9897-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weng Z., Song Y., Cheng C., Tong D., Xu M., Wang M., Xie Y. Possible underestimation of the coal-fired power plants to air pollution in China. Resour. Conserv. Recycl. 2023;198:107208. doi: 10.1016/j.resconrec.2023.107208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resconrec.2023.107208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orazi V., Juan A., Gonz&#xe1;lez E.A., Marchetti Jorge M., Jasen P.V. DFT study of ethanol adsorption on CaO (0 0 1) surface. App. Surf. Sci. 2020;500:144254. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2019.144254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2019.144254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y., Zhang L., Liu Y., Qu Y. Adsorption mechanisms of metal ions on the potassium dihydrogen phosphate (1 0 0) surface: A density functional theory-based investigation. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2018;522:256&#x2013;263. doi: 10.1016/j.jcis.2018.03.073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2018.03.073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29604444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing J., Wang C., Zou C., Zhang Y. DFT Study of Se and SeO2 adsorbed on CaO (001) Surface: Role of Oxygen. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2020;510:145488. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2020.145488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2020.145488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sodeifian G. Non-Linear Rheology of Polymer Melts: Constitutive Equations, Rheological Properties of Polymer Blends, Shear Flow, Sliding Plate Rheometers. LAP Lambert Academic; London, UK: 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logsdail A.J., Mora-Fonz D., Scanlon D.O., Catlow CR A., Sokol A.A. Structural, energetic and electronic properties of (100) surfaces for alkaline earth metal oxides as calculated with hybrid density functional theory. Surf. Sci. 2015;642:58&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1016/j.susc.2015.06.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.susc.2015.06.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>