<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40521480</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-1343</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>22</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS omega</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Omega</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Separation of Enantiomers of the Chiral Arginine System: Solid-Phase Characterization, Solubility Phase Diagrams, and Preferential Crystallization.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>23673</StartPage><EndPage>23683</EndPage><MedlinePgn>23673-23683</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsomega.5c02584</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The separation of enantiomers is of significant interest for various industrial sectors, such as pharmaceutical production and agrochemistry. The technology requires a comprehensive understanding of chiral structures, thermodynamics, and kinetics to develop sustainable separation strategies. In this work, a systematic investigation was undertaken to characterize the solid phases of both the enantiomer l- and the racemate dl-arginine in aqueous solutions by employing powder X-ray diffraction, thermogravimetry, differential scanning calorimetry, and microscopy analyses. This study discovered the formation of a complex hydrate system of the enantiomer and racemate of arginine. The solubilities of these compounds were determined across a broad range of temperatures and solvent mixtures composed of water and ethanol. Hereby, ethanol acts as an antisolvent in aqueous arginine solutions. The different interactions between the enantiomer, the racemate, and the solvents resulted in varying solubility ratios and had an influence on the eutectic compositions in ternary phase diagrams (TPDs). TPDs were constructed by taking into account different hydrate formations. Observed shifts in the eutectic composition offer possibilities for chiral separation via crystallization. Guided by the TPDs determined, an approach for the enantioseparation of arginine enantiomers was proposed and validated, exploiting isothermal seeded preferential crystallization.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Le Minh</LastName><ForeName>Tam</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5372-346X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology and Education, Ho Chi Minh City 700000, Vietnam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seidel-Morgenstern</LastName><ForeName>Andreas</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Max Planck Institute for Dynamics of Complex Technical Systems, Magdeburg, Saxony-Anhalt D-39106, Germany.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">28307</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Otto von Guericke University, Magdeburg, Saxony-Anhalt D-39106, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lorenz</LastName><ForeName>Heike</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7608-0092</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Max Planck Institute for Dynamics of Complex Technical Systems, Magdeburg, Saxony-Anhalt D-39106, Germany.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">28307</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Omega</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101691658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-1343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40521480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12163660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.5c02584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Castro F. L. S., Kim W. K.. Secondary Functions of Arginine and Sulfur Amino Acids in Poultry Health: Review. Animals. 2020;10(11):2106. doi: 10.3390/ani10112106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani10112106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7697735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33202808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu G., Bazer F. W., Satterfield M. C., Gilbreath K. R., Posey E. A., Sun Y.. L-Arginine Nutrition and Metabolism in Ruminants. Adv. Exp. Med. Biol. 2022;1354:177&#x2013;206. doi: 10.1007/978-3-030-85686-1_10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-85686-1_10</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34807443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>John J. S., Kumar M. S., Joy L. K., Sajan D., Vinitha G., Vijayan N., John N. L.. Crystal growth, dielectric studies, charge transfer and ionic hydrogen-bonding interactions of L-arginine hydrobromide monohydrate single crystal: A novel third order nonlinear optical material for optoelectronic applications. Opt. Laser Technol. 2020;125:106043. doi: 10.1016/j.optlastec.2019.106043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.optlastec.2019.106043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahadevan M., Sankar P. K., Vinitha G., Arivanandhan M., Ramachandran K., Anandan P.. Nonlinear optical studies on semiorganic single crystal: L-arginine 4-nitrophenalate 4-nitrophenol dihydrate (LAPP) Opt. Laser Technol. 2017;92:168&#x2013;172. doi: 10.1016/j.optlastec.2017.01.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.optlastec.2017.01.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kar T.. Amino acids-precursors for synthesizing nonlinear optical materials. Progress in Crystal Growth and Characterization of Materials. 2012;58(2&#x2013;3):74&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1016/j.pcrysgrow.2012.03.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pcrysgrow.2012.03.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ejgenberg M., Mastai Y.. L-Glu Hierarchical Structure Crystallization Using Inorganic Ions. Crystals. 2023;13(1):121. doi: 10.3390/cryst13010121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cryst13010121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolzhenkova E. F., Kostenyukova E. I., Bezkrovnaya O. N., Pritula I. M.. Effect of doping of KDP crystal with amino acid l-arginine on the strength properties and character of laser damage. J. Cryst. Growth. 2017;478:111&#x2013;116. doi: 10.1016/j.jcrysgro.2017.08.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcrysgro.2017.08.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5656088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29151615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D. R., Martin S., Desai K.. The effects of a comparatively higher dose of 1000 mg/kg/d of oral L- or D-arginine on the L-arginine metabolic pathways in male Sprague-Dawley rats. PLoS One. 2023;18(8):e0289476. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0289476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0289476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10393177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37527267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta M. N., Uversky V. N.. Biological importance of arginine: Roles in structure, disorder, and functionality of peptides and proteins. Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 2024;257:128646. doi: 10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2023.128646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2023.128646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38061507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabah H.. Synthetic Methods for the Construction of Chiral Molecules: Enantioselective Catalysis and Asymmetric Synthesis. Chem. Sci. J. 2023;14:363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wibowo C.. Solid-liquid equilibrium: The foundation of crystallization process design. Chem. Eng. Prog. 2014;110(3):37&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karpinski P. H., N&#xfd;vlt J.. Metastable zone width in salting-out crystallization. Cryst. Res. Technol. 1983;8(7):959&#x2013;965. doi: 10.1002/crat.2170180722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/crat.2170180722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacques, J. ; Collet, A. ; Wilen, S. H. . Enantiomers, Racemates and Resolutions; Krieger Publishing Company: Malabar, FL, 1994; pp 3&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorenz H., Perlberg A., Sapoundjiev D., Elsner M. P., Seidel-Morgenstern A.. Crystallization of enantiomers. Chem. Eng. Process. Process Intensif. 2006;45(10):863&#x2013;873. doi: 10.1016/j.cep.2005.11.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cep.2005.11.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Minh T., Lorenz H., Seidel-Morgenstern A.. Enantioselective crystallization exploiting the shift of the eutectic compositions in solid-liquid phase diagrams. Chem. Eng. Technol. 2012;35(6):1003&#x2013;1008. doi: 10.1002/ceat.201100689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ceat.201100689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaemmerer K., Jones M. J., Lorenz H., Seidel-Morgenstern A.. Selective crystallisation of a chiral compound-forming system - Solvent screening. Fluid Phase Equilib. 2010;296(2):192&#x2013;205. doi: 10.1016/j.fluid.2010.05.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fluid.2010.05.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Minh, T. ; Lorenz, H. ; Seidel-Morgenstern, A. . Thermodynamic description of solid liquid equilibria for the enantiomers of 3-chloromandelic acid. In BIWIC 2011-18th International Workshop on Industrial Crystallization; Delft, the Netherlands. 2011. 260&#x2013;265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorenz H., Le Minh T., Kaemmerer H., Buchholz H., Seidel-Morgenstern A.. Exploitation of shifts of eutectic compositions in crystallization-based enantioseparation. Chem. Eng. Res. Des. 2013;91:1890&#x2013;1902. doi: 10.1016/j.cherd.2013.08.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cherd.2013.08.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polenske D., Lorenz H., Seidel-Morgenstern A.. Separation of Propranolol Hydrochloride Enantiomers by Preferential Crystallization: Thermodynamic Basis and Experimental Verification. Crystal Growth &amp; Design. 2007;7(9):1628&#x2013;1634. doi: 10.1021/cg0700770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/cg0700770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn A. S., Svoboda V., Sefcik J., ter Horst J.. H, Resolution Control in a continuous Preferential Crystallization Process. Org. Process Res. Dev. 2019;23(9):2031&#x2013;2041. doi: 10.1021/acs.oprd.9b00275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.oprd.9b00275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant D. J. W., Mehdizadeh M., Chow A. H. L, Fairbrother J. E.. Non-linear van&#x2019;t Hoff solubility-temperature plots and their pharmaceutical interpretation. Int. J. Pharm. 1984;18:25&#x2013;38. doi: 10.1016/0378-5173(84)90104-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0378-5173(84)90104-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallik T., Kar T.. Growth and characterization of nonlinear optical L-arginine dihydrate single crystals. J. Cryst. Growth. 2005;285:178&#x2013;182. doi: 10.1016/j.jcrysgro.2005.08.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcrysgro.2005.08.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courvoisier E., Williams P. A., Lim G. K., Hughes C. E., Harris K. D. M.. The crystal structure of L-arginine. Chem. Commun. 2012;48:2761&#x2013;2763. doi: 10.1039/c2cc17203h.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c2cc17203h</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22297609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes C. E., Boughdiri I., Bouakkaz C., Williams P. A., Harris K. D. M.. Elucidating the Crystal Structure of DL-Arginine by Combined Powder X-ray Diffraction Data Analysis and Periodic DFT-D Calculations. Cryst. Growth Des. 2018;18(1):42&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1021/acs.cgd.7b01412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.cgd.7b01412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suresh S., Padmanabhan S., Vijayan M.. X-ray Studies on Crystalline Complexes Involving Amino Acids and Peptides. XXVII. Effect of Chirality, Specific Interactions and Characteristic Aggregation Patterns in the Structures of Arginine and its Complexes with Formic Acid. J. Biomol. Struct. Dyn. 1994;11(6):1425&#x2013;1435. doi: 10.1080/07391102.1994.10508077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07391102.1994.10508077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7946083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le T. M., Nguyen T. D., Nguyen G. T., Tran N. T.. Antisolvent Effects of C1&#x2013;C4 Primary Alcohols on Solid-Liquid Equilibria of Potassium Dihydrogen Phosphate in Aqueous Solutions. ChemEngineering. 2023;7(5):99. doi: 10.3390/chemengineering7050099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/chemengineering7050099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe1;zquez Marrero V. R., Pi&#xf1;ero Berr&#xed;os C., De Dios Rodr&#xed;guez L., Stelzer T., L&#xf3;pez-Mej&#xed;as V.. In the Context of Polymorphism: Accurate Measurement, and Validation of Solubility Data. Cryst. Growth Des. 2019;19(7):4101&#x2013;4108. doi: 10.1021/acs.cgd.9b00529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.cgd.9b00529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7453630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32863778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakisaka A., Komatsu S., Usui Y.. Solute-solvent and solvent-solvent interactions evaluated through clusters isolated from solutions: Preferential solvation in water-alcohol mixtures. J. Mol. Liq. 2001;90(1&#x2013;3):175&#x2013;184. doi: 10.1016/S0167-7322(01)00120-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0167-7322(01)00120-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingsford-Adaboh R., Grosche M., Dittrich B., Luger P.. DL-arginine monohydrate at 100 K. Acta Cryst. C. 2000;56:1274&#x2013;1276. doi: 10.1107/S0108270100010325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1107/S0108270100010325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11025324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilmaz H.. Excess Properties of Alcohol - Water Systems at 298.15 K. Turk. J. Phys. 2002;26:243&#x2013;246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klussmann M., Iwamura H., Mathew S. P., Wells D. H. Jr., Pandya U., Armstrong A., Blackmond D. G.. Thermodynamic control of asymmetric amplification in amino acid catalysis. Nature. 2006;441:621&#x2013;623. doi: 10.1038/nature04780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature04780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16738656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coquerel G.. Preferential crystallization. Top Curr. Chem. 2006;269:1&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1007/128_2006_077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/128_2006_077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23605348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polenske D., Lorenz H., Seidel-Morgenstern A.. Potential of different techniques of preferential crystallization for enantioseparation of racemic compound forming systems. Chirality. 2009;21(8):728&#x2013;737. doi: 10.1002/chir.20672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/chir.20672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18989897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>