<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37360463</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-1343</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>24</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS omega</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Omega</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>QbD-Engineered Development and Validation of a RP-HPLC Method for Simultaneous Estimation of Rutin and Ciprofloxacin HCl in Bilosomal Nanoformulation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>21618</StartPage><EndPage>21627</EndPage><MedlinePgn>21618-21627</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsomega.3c00956</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In the given study, a new reverse-phase high-performance liquid chromatography (RP-HPLC) method has been reported for the simultaneous estimation of ciprofloxacin hydrochloride (CPX) and rutin (RUT) using quality by design (QbD) approach. The analysis was carried out by applying the Box-Behnken design having fewer design points and less experimental runs. It relates between factors and responses and gives statistically significant values, along with enhancing the quality of the analysis. CPX and RUT were separated on the Kromasil C<sub>18</sub> column (4.6 &#xd7; 150 mm, 5 &#x3bc;m) using an isocratic mobile phase combination of phosphoric acid buffer (pH 3.0) and acetonitrile with the ratio of 87:13% v/v at a flow rate of 1.0 mL/min. CPX and RUT were detected at their respective wavelengths of 278 and 368 nm using a photodiode array detector. The developed method was validated according to guideline ICH Q2 R (1). The validation parameters taken were linearity, system suitability, accuracy, precision, robustness, sensitivity, and solution stability which were in the acceptable range. The findings suggest that the developed RP-HPLC method can be successfully applied to analyze novel CPX-RUT-loaded bilosomal nanoformulation prepared by thin-film hydration technique.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shamim</LastName><ForeName>Athar</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6142-8778</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics, School of Pharmaceutical Education and Research, Jamia Hamdard, New Delhi 110062, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ansari</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad Javed</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9266-7133</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics, College of Pharmacy, Prince Sattam Bin Abdulaziz University, Al-Kharj 11942, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aodah</LastName><ForeName>Alhussain</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics, College of Pharmacy, Prince Sattam Bin Abdulaziz University, Al-Kharj 11942, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iqbal</LastName><ForeName>Muzaffar</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Chemistry, College of Pharmacy, King Saud University, Riyadh 11451,Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aqil</LastName><ForeName>Mohd</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics, School of Pharmaceutical Education and Research, Jamia Hamdard, New Delhi 110062, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mirza</LastName><ForeName>Mohd Aamir</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5780-7601</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics, School of Pharmaceutical Education and Research, Jamia Hamdard, New Delhi 110062, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iqbal</LastName><ForeName>Zeenat</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2788-9420</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics, School of Pharmaceutical Education and Research, Jamia Hamdard, New Delhi 110062, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ali</LastName><ForeName>Asgar</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-8780-522X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics, School of Pharmaceutical Education and Research, Jamia Hamdard, New Delhi 110062, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Omega</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101691658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-1343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing financial interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37360463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10286274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.3c00956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hall-Stoodley L.; Costerton J. W.; Stoodley P.; Hall-Stoodley L.; Costerton J. W.; Stoodley P. Bacterial Biofilms: From the Natural Environment to Infectious Diseases. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 2004, 2004, 95&#x2013;108. 10.1038/Nrmicro821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/Nrmicro821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15040259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira A. S.; Rolo J.; Gaspar C.; Cavaleiro C.; Salgueiro L.; Palmeira-de-Oliveira R.; Ferraz C.; Coelho S.; Pastorinho M. R.; Sousa A. C.; Teixeira J. P.; Martinez-de-Oliveira J.; Palmeira-de-Oliveira A. Chemical Characterization and Bioactive Potential of Thymus &#xd7; Citriodorus (Pers.) Schreb. Preparations for Anti-Acne Applications: Antimicrobial, Anti-Biofilm, Anti-Inflammatory and Safety Profiles. J. Ethnopharmacol. 2022, 287, 114935 10.1016/j.jep.2021.114935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2021.114935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34954264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penesyan A.; Gillings M.; Paulsen I. T. Antibiotic Discovery: Combatting Bacterial Resistance in Cells and in Biofilm Communities. Molecules 2015, 20, 5286. 10.3390/molecules20045286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules20045286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6272253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25812150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raju D. V.; Nagarajan A.; Pandit S.; Nag M.; Lahiri D.; Upadhye V. Effect of Bacterial Quorum Sensing and Mechanism of Antimicrobial Resistance. Biocatal. Agric. Biotechnol. 2022, 43, 102409 10.1016/j.bcab.2022.102409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bcab.2022.102409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamim A.; Ali A.; Iqbal Z.; Mirza M. A.; Aqil M.; Kawish S. M.; Siddiqui A.; Kumar V.; Naseef P. P.; Alshadidi A. A. F.; Saheer Kuruniyan M. Natural Medicine a Promising Candidate in Combating Microbial Biofilm. Antibiotics 2023, 12, 299. 10.3390/antibiotics12020299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/antibiotics12020299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9952808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36830210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vega N. M.; Gore J. Collective Antibiotic Resistance: Mechanisms and Implications. Curr. Opin. Microbiol. 2014, 21, 28. 10.1016/j.mib.2014.09.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mib.2014.09.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4367450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25271119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gebreyohannes G.; Nyerere A.; Bii C.; Sbhatu D. B. Challenges of Intervention, Treatment, and Antibiotic Resistance of Biofilm-Forming Microorganisms. Heliyon 2019, 5, e02192 10.1016/j.heliyon.2019.e02192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2019.e02192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6709409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31463386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verderosa A. D.; Totsika M.; Fairfull-Smith K. E. Bacterial Biofilm Eradication Agents: A Current Review. Front. Chem. 2019, 7, 824. 10.3389/fchem.2019.00824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fchem.2019.00824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6893625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31850313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman F.; Tabrez S.; Ali R.; Alqahtani A. S.; Ahmed M. Z.; Rub A. Molecular Docking Analysis of Rutin Reveals Possible Inhibition of SARS-CoV-2 Vital Proteins. J. Tradit. Complement. Med. 2021, 11, 173. 10.1016/j.jtcme.2021.01.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtcme.2021.01.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7825826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33520682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alonso-Castro A. J.; Dom&#xed;nguez F.; Garc&#xed;a-Carranc&#xe1; A. Rutin Exerts Antitumor Effects on Nude Mice Bearing SW480 Tumor. Arch. Med. Res. 2013, 44, 346. 10.1016/j.arcmed.2013.06.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arcmed.2013.06.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23867787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guardia T.; Rotelli A. E.; Juarez A. O.; Pelzer L. E. Anti-Inflammatory Properties of Plant Flavonoids. Effects of Rutin, Quercetin and Hesperidin on Adjuvant Arthritis in Rat. Farmaco 2001, 56, 683. 10.1016/S0014-827X(01)01111-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0014-827X(01)01111-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11680812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong D. O. C.; Saker S. R.; Chellappan D. K.; Madheswaran T.; Panneerselvam J.; Choudhury H.; Pandey M.; Chan Y. L.; Collet T.; Gupta G.; Oliver B. G.; Wark P.; Hansbro N.; Hsu A.; Hansbro P. M.; Dua K.; Zeeshan F. Molecular and Immunological Mechanisms Underlying the Various Pharmacological Properties of the Potent Bioflavonoid, Rutin. Endocrine, Metab. Immune Disord. Drug Targets 2020, 20, 1590. 10.2174/1871530320666200503053846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1871530320666200503053846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32359343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motallebi M.; Khorsandi K.; Sepahy A. A.; Chamani E.; Hosseinzadeh R. Effect of Rutin as Flavonoid Compound on Photodynamic Inactivation against P. Aeruginosa and S. Aureus. Photodiagn. Photodyn. Ther. 2020, 32, 102074 10.1016/j.pdpdt.2020.102074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pdpdt.2020.102074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33137496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu Q.; Cui W.; Xing X.; Zou R.; Huang X.; Wang X.; Wu T.; Bello-Onaghise G.; Yuan S.; Li Y. Rutin, A Natural Inhibitor of IGPD Protein, Partially Inhibits Biofilm Formation in Staphylococcus Xylosus ATCC700404 in Vitro and in Vivo. Front. Pharmacol. 2021, 12, 728354 10.3389/fphar.2021.728354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2021.728354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8385535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34456739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel K. Y.; Dedania Z. R.; Dedania R. R.; Patel U. QbD Approach to HPLC Method Development and Validation of Ceftriaxone Sodium. Futur. J. Pharm. Sci. 2021, 7, 141. 10.1186/s43094-021-00286-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s43094-021-00286-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dedania Z. R.; Dedania R. R.; Sheth N. R.; Patel J. B.; Patel B. Stability Indicating HPLC Determination of Risperidone in Bulk Drug and Pharmaceutical Formulations. Int. J. Anal. Chem. 2011, 2011, 124917 10.1155/2011/124917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2011/124917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3191733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22007220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talele S. G.; Derle D. V. Stability-Indicating High-Performance Liquid Chromatography (HPLC) Method Development and Validation for the Determination of Quetiapine Fumarate in Bulk and Dosage Form by HPLC. Int. J. Green Pharm. 2018, 12, S188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nuchtavorn N.; Leanpolchareanchai J.; Chanton D.; Supapsophon P.; Chongruchiroj S.; Chatmapanrangsee J.; Suksiriworapong J. A Rapid Stability Indicating HPLC Method for Determination of Quetiapine Fumarate in Tablets and Extemporaneous Formulations. Pharm. Chem. J. 2021, 13, 845. 10.1007/s11094-021-02505-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11094-021-02505-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijaya Kumar M.; Muley P. R.. Stability Indicating Hplc Method for Determination of Quetiapine Fumarate in Bulk Drug and Solid Dosage Forms. Indian Drugs 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostovan A.; Ghaedi M.; Arabi M.; Yang Q.; Li J.; Chen L. Hydrophilic Multitemplate Molecularly Imprinted Biopolymers Based on a Green Synthesis Strategy for Determination of B-Family Vitamins. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2018, 10, 4140. 10.1021/acsami.7b17500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsami.7b17500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29299926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishna M. V.; Dash R. N.; Jalachandra Reddy B.; Venugopal P.; Sandeep P.; Madhavi G. Quality by Design (QbD) Approach to Develop HPLC Method for Eberconazole Nitrate: Application Oxidative and Photolytic Degradation Kinetics. J. Saudi Chem. Soc. 2016, 20, S313. 10.1016/j.jscs.2012.12.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jscs.2012.12.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pascual-Reguera M. I.; Parras G. P.; D&#xed;az A. M. Solid-Phase UV Spectrophotometric Method for Determination of Ciprofloxacin. Microchem. J. 2004, 77, 79. 10.1016/j.microc.2004.01.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.microc.2004.01.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emami J.; Rezazadeh M. A Simple and Sensitive High-Performance Liquid Chromatography Method for Determination of Ciprofloxacin in Bioavailability Studies of Conventional and Gastroretentive Prolonged-Release Formulations. Adv. Biomed. Res. 2016, 5, 163. 10.4103/2277-9175.190995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/2277-9175.190995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5137234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27995102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imre S.; Dogaru M. T.; Vari C. E.; Muntean T.; Kelemen L. Validation of an HPLC Method for the Determination of Ciprofloxacin in Human Plasma. J. Pharm. Biomed. Anal. 2003, 33, 125. 10.1016/S0731-7085(03)00151-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0731-7085(03)00151-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12946539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alajmi M. F.; Alam P.; Rehman M. T.; Husain F. M.; Khan A. A.; Siddiqui N. A.; Hussain A.; Kalam M. A.; Parvez M. K. Interspecies Anticancer and Antimicrobial Activities of Genus Solanum and Estimation of Rutin by Validated UPLC-PDA Method. Evidence-based Complement. Altern. Med. 2018, 2018, 6040815 10.1155/2018/6040815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/6040815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6051100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30057644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attia T. Z. Simultaneous Determination of Rutin and Ascorbic Acid Mixture in Their Pure Forms and Combined Dosage Form. Spectrochim. Acta, Part A 2016, 169, 82. 10.1016/j.saa.2016.06.030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.saa.2016.06.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27341400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunti&#x107; V.; Peji&#x107; N.; Ivkovi&#x107; B.; Vuji&#x107; Z.; Ili&#x107; K.; Mi&#x107;i&#x107; S.; Vukojevi&#x107; V. Isocratic RP-HPLC Method for Rutin Determination in Solid Oral Dosage Forms. J. Pharm. Biomed. Anal. 2007, 43, 718. 10.1016/j.jpba.2006.07.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpba.2006.07.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16920326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishii K.; Furuta T.; Kasuya Y. Determination of Rutin in Human Plasma by High-Performance Liquid Chromatography Utilizing Solid-Phase Extraction and Ultraviolet Detection. J. Chromatogr. B: Biomed. Sci. Appl. 2001, 759, 161. 10.1016/S0378-4347(01)00224-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0378-4347(01)00224-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11499620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y.; Li W.; Wang J.; Bi J.; Su S. Determination of Rutin in Cigarette Tobacco, Filters, Mainstream Smoke and Burned Ash of Different Branded Cigarettes by High Performance Liquid Chromatography. Molecules 2012, 17, 3751. 10.3390/molecules17043751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules17043751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6269046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22450684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kicel A.; Owczarek A.; Michel P.; Skalicka-Wo&#x17a;niak K.; Kiss A. K.; Olszewska M. A. Application of HPCCC, UHPLC-PDA-ESI-MS3 and HPLC-PDA Methods for Rapid, One-Step Preparative Separation and Quantification of Rutin in Forsythia Flowers. Ind. Crops Prod. 2015, 76, 86. 10.1016/j.indcrop.2015.06.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.indcrop.2015.06.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tome T.; &#x17d;igart N.; &#x10c;asar Z.; Obreza A. Development and Optimization of Liquid Chromatography Analytical Methods by Using AQbD Principles: Overview and Recent Advances. Org. Process Res. Dev. 2019, 23, 1784. 10.1021/acs.oprd.9b00238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.oprd.9b00238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thi Thuy Linh D.; Thanh Duong H.; Tuan Hiep N.; Thanh Huyen P.; Minh Khoi N.; Doan Long D. Simultaneous Quantification of Hederacoside C and &#x3b1;-Hederin in Hedera Nepalensis K.Koch Using HPLC-UV. VNU J. Sci. Med. Pharm. Sci. 2020, 36, 4227. 10.25073/2588-1132/vnumps.4227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25073/2588-1132/vnumps.4227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serfaty D.25 Years ESC. Eur. J. Contracept. Reprod. Health Care 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuang M. T. 1983 United States Pharmacopia Dispensing Information. J. Urol. 1983, 129, 683. 10.1016/s0022-5347(17)52316-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0022-5347(17)52316-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyea L.Big Savings &amp; Fast Paybacks in Existing Laboratory Buildings. In 33rd West Coast Energy Management Congress, EMC 2015, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganorkar S. B.; Dhumal D. M.; Shirkhedkar A. A. Development and Validation of Simple RP-HPLC-PDA Analytical Protocol for Zileuton Assisted with Design of Experiments for Robustness Determination. Arab. J. Chem. 2017, 10, 273. 10.1016/j.arabjc.2014.03.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arabjc.2014.03.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beg S.; Panda S. S.; Katare O. P.; Singh B. Applications of Monte-Carlo Simulation and Chemometric Techniques for Development of Bioanalytical Liquid Chromatography Method for Estimation of Rosuvastatin Calcium. J. Liq. Chromatogr. Relat. Technol. 2017, 40, 907. 10.1080/10826076.2017.1382377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10826076.2017.1382377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai Y.; Zhou R.; Liu L.; Lu Y.; Qi J.; Wu W. Liposomes Containing Bile Salts as Novel Ocular Delivery Systems for Tacrolimus (FK506): In Vitro Characterization and Improved Corneal Permeation. Int. J. Nanomed. 2013, 8, 1921. 10.2147/IJN.S44487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJN.S44487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3656938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23690687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Mahallawi A. M.; Abdelbary A. A.; Aburahma M. H. Investigating the Potential of Employing Bilosomes as a Novel Vesicular Carrier for Transdermal Delivery of Tenoxicam. Int. J. Pharm. 2015, 485, 329. 10.1016/j.ijpharm.2015.03.033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2015.03.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25796122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>