<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39045770</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1758-5910</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Asian journal of endoscopic surgery</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Asian J Endosc Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Development and validation of a high-quality simulator with exchangeable peritoneum for transabdominal preperitoneal laparoscopic inguinal hernia repair.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e13362</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e13362</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ases.13362</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Practical simulation training with proper haptic feedback and the fragility of the human body is required to overcome the long learning curve associated with laparoscopic inguinal hernia repair (LIHR). However, few hernia models accurately reflect the texture and fragility of the human body. Therefore, in this study, we developed a novel model for transabdominal preperitoneal (TAPP) LIHR training and evaluated its validity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We developed a high-quality mock peritoneum with a hydrated polyvinyl alcohol layer and a unique two-way crossing cellulose fiber layer. To complete the simulation, the peritoneum was adhered to a urethane foam inguinal base with surgical landmarks. Participants could perform all the procedures required for the TAPP LIHR. Twenty-four surgeons performed TAPP LIHR simulation using a novel simulator. Their opinions were rated on a 5-point Likert scale. Additionally, 6 surgical residents and 10 surgical experts performed the procedure. Their performance was evaluated using the TAPP checklist score and procedure time.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Most participants strongly agreed that the TAPP LIHR simulator with an exchangeable peritoneum model was useful. The participants agreed on the model fidelity for tactile sensation, forceps handling, and humanlike anatomy. In comparisons between surgical residents and experts, the experts had significantly higher scores (10.6 vs. 17.2, p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05) and shorter procedure times (92.3 vs. 55.9&#x2009;min; p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.05) than did surgical residents.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">We developed a high-quality exchangeable peritoneal model that mimics the human peritoneum's texture and fragility. This model enhances laparoscopic simulation training, potentially shortening TAPP LIHR learning curves.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Author(s). Asian Journal of Endoscopic Surgery published by Asia Endosurgery Task Force and Japan Society of Endoscopic Surgery and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shibuya</LastName><ForeName>Ayako</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgical Oncology, Nagasaki University Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences, Nagasaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, National Hospital Organization (NHO) Tokyo Medical Center, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Isobe</LastName><ForeName>Yoh</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-4350-2399</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Clinical Medicine, International University of Health and Welfare, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishihara</LastName><ForeName>Yuichi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0018-8763</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Sassa General Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsumoto</LastName><ForeName>Sumio</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, National Hospital Organization (NHO) Tokyo Medical Center, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nagayasu</LastName><ForeName>Takeshi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgical Oncology, Nagasaki University Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences, Nagasaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsumoto</LastName><ForeName>Keitaro</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgical Oncology, Nagasaki University Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences, Nagasaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D023361">Validation Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>Asian J Endosc Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101506753</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1758-5902</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006552" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hernia, Inguinal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010535" MajorTopicYN="Y">Laparoscopy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000193" MajorTopicYN="N">education</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059685" MajorTopicYN="Y">Herniorrhaphy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000193" MajorTopicYN="N">education</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010537" MajorTopicYN="Y">Peritoneum</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000066908" MajorTopicYN="Y">Simulation Training</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002983" MajorTopicYN="Y">Clinical Competence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008953" MajorTopicYN="N">Models, Anatomic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007396" MajorTopicYN="N">Internship and Residency</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inguinal hernia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">simulation training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surgical education</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39045770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ases.13362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Kingsnorth A, LeBlanc K. Hernias: inguinal and incisional. Lancet. 2003;362:1561&#x2010;1571.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HerniaSurge Group. International guidelines for groin hernia management. Hernia. 2018;22:1&#x2010;165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayakawa T, Eguchi T, Kimura T, et al. Hernia. Asian J Endosc Surg. 2015;8:382&#x2010;389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez&#x2010;Alberti J, Mata L, Orrego F, et al. Laparoscopic inguinal hernia repair: impact of surgical time in the learning curve. Surg Endosc. 2023;37:2826&#x2010;2832.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brucchi F, Ferraina F, Masci E, Ferrara D, Bottero L, Faillace GG. Standardization and learning curve in laparoscopic hernia repair: experience of a high&#x2010;volume center. BMC Surg. 2023;28(23):212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivakumar J, Chen Q, Hii MH, et al. Learning curve of laparoscopic inguinal hernia repair: systematic review, meta&#x2010;analysis, and meta&#x2010;regression. Surg Endosc. 2023;37:2453&#x2010;2475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovisetto F, Zonta S, Rota E, et al. Laparoscopic transabdominal preperitoneal (TAPP) hernia repair: surgical phases and complications. Surg Endosc. 2007;21:646&#x2010;652.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simons MP, Aufenacker T, Bay&#x2010;Nielsen M, et al. European hernia society guidelines on the treatment of inguinal hernia in adult patients. Hernia. 2009;13:343&#x2010;403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto S, Hayakawa T, Kawarada Y, et al. Proper training in laparoscopic hernia repair is necessary to minimize the rising recurrence rate in Japan. Asian J Endosc Surg. 2018;11:151&#x2010;154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutta S, Gaba D, Krummel TM. To simulate or not to simulate: what is the question? Ann Surg. 2006;243:301&#x2010;303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen SY, Lo HY, Hung SK. What is the impact of the COVID&#x2010;19 pandemic on residency training: a systematic review and analysis. BMC Med Educ. 2021;21:618.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelly T, J. Vance&#x2010;Daniel J, Linder C. Characteristics of laparoscopic and open hernia repair simulation models: a systematic review. Hernia. 2022;26:39&#x2010;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishihara Y, Isobe Y, Kitagawa Y. Validation of newly developed physical laparoscopy simulator in transabdominal preperitoneal (TAPP) inguinal hernia repair. Surg Endosc. 2017;31:5429&#x2010;5435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishihara Y, Isobe Y. Preoperative skill evaluation in transabdominal preperitoneal (TAPP) inguinal hernia repair using a three&#x2010;dimensional printed TAPP repair simulator. Surg Endosc. 2021;35:270&#x2010;274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poudel S, Kurashima Y, Kawarada Y, et al. Development and validation of a checklist for assessing recorded performance of laparoscopic inguinal hernia repair. Am J Surg. 2016;212:468&#x2010;474.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakai Y, Kitano S. Practice guidelines on endoscopic surgery for qualified surgeons by the endoscopic surgical skill qualification system. Asian J Endosc Surg. 2015;8:103&#x2010;113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanigawa N, Lee SW, Kimura T, et al. The endoscopic surgical skill Qualilication system for gastric surgery in Japan. Asian J Endosc Surg. 2011;4:112&#x2010;115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurashima Y, Feldman L, Al&#x2010;Sabah S, Kaneva P, Fried G, Vassiliou M. Novel low&#x2010;cost simulator for laparoscopic inguinal hernia repair. Surg Innov. 2011;18:171&#x2010;175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivakhov G, Kolygin A, Titkova S, Anurov M, Sazhin A. Development and evaluation of a novel simulation model for transabdominal preperitoneal (TAPP) inguinal hernia repair. Hernia. 2020;24:159&#x2010;166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melo Filho LP, Almeida AM, Barros Filho EM, Borges GCO. Simulated training model in a low cost for laparoscopic inguinal hernioplasty. Acta Cir Bras. 2021;36:e360108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Light D, Bawa S, Gallagher P, Horgan L. Outcomes of an innovative training course in laparoscopic hernia repair. Ann R Coll Surg Engl. 2017;99:614&#x2010;616.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagendran M, Gurusamy KS, Aggarwal R, Loizidou M, Davidson BR. Virtual reality training for surgical trainees in laparoscopic surgery. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2013;2013:CD006575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botden SM, Torab F, Buzink SN, Jakimowicz JJ. The importance of haptic feedback in laparoscopic suturing training and the additive value of virtual reality simulation. Surg Endosc. 2008;22:1214&#x2010;1222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuge H, Yokoo T, Uchida H, Yamaoka K, Yoshikawa S. Learning curve for laparoscopic transabdominal preperitoneal repair: a single&#x2010;surgeon experience of consecutive 105 procedures. Asian J Endosc Surg. 2020;13:205&#x2010;210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurashima Y, Feldman LS, Al&#x2010;Sabah S, Kaneva PA, Fried GM, Vassiliou MC. A tool for training and evaluation of laparoscopic inguinal hernia repair: the global operative assessment of laparoscopic skills&#x2010;groin hernia (GOALS&#x2010;GH). Am J Surg. 2011;201:54&#x2010;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uemura M, Yamashita M, Tomikawa M, et al. Objective assessment of the suture ligature method for the laparoscopic intestinal anastomosis model using a new computerized system. Surg Endosc. 2015;29:444&#x2010;452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilgic E, Gorgy A, Yang A, et al. Exploring the roles of artificial intelligence in surgical education: a scoping review. Am J Surg. 2022;224:205&#x2010;216.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>