<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37961837</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-0010</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>104</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the science of food and agriculture</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Sci Food Agric</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Retrogradation-induced physicochemical changes in pre-cooked rice noodles stored at different temperatures: a viewpoint from water dynamics and structure.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2406</StartPage><EndPage>2416</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2406-2416</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jsfa.13125</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">There has been significant interest in pre-cooked noodles that have a long shelf life and are convenient to cook. However, the thermal processes during preparation, and their high moisture content, can lead to significant quality deterioration during storage. Nevertheless, a comprehensive evaluation of these quality losses has not yet been conducted.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The effects of different storage temperatures (25, 4, and -20&#x2009;&#xb0;C) on the retrogradation-related physicochemical changes in pre-cooked rice noodles were elucidated mainly from the water dynamics and structural viewpoints. Thermal analysis demonstrated that amylopectin recrystallization took place in the noodles stored at refrigerated temperature, followed by room temperature. The refrigerated storage accelerated the starch retrogradation that caused the water molecules to become entrapped within the crystalline structure by lowering the water hydration properties and weighted T<sub>2</sub> relaxation times of the pre-cooked noodles. These water mobility patterns were correlated with the textural changes in the noodles (greater hardness and R<sub>max</sub> /extensibility). Furthermore, the higher structural density and thickness derived from starch retrogradation were observed in the tomographic and microscopic images of the refrigerated noodles. The principal component analysis demonstrated that various physicochemical changes of the pre-cooked noodles during storage showed high correlations with the degree of starch retrogradation (r&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;0.83).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The physicochemical features of the precooked noodles stored under refrigerated conditions were involved in the molecular dynamics of water, showing a notable water mobility reduction derived from the starch retrogradation, which contributed to their thermal, tomographical, and textural changes. &#xa9; 2023 Society of Chemical Industry.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Society of Chemical Industry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jeong</LastName><ForeName>Sungmin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science &amp; Biotechnology and Carbohydrate Bioproduct Research Center, Sejong University, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Suyong</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1284-211X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Science &amp; Biotechnology and Carbohydrate Bioproduct Research Center, Sejong University, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>NRF-2022R1A6A1A03055869</GrantID><Agency>Korean Government</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2020R1A6A3A13076083</GrantID><Agency>Ministry of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Sci Food Agric</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0376334</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-5142</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9005-25-8</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013213">Starch</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9037-22-3</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000687">Amylopectin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013696" MajorTopicYN="N">Temperature</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012275" MajorTopicYN="Y">Oryza</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="N">Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013213" MajorTopicYN="N">Starch</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000687" MajorTopicYN="N">Amylopectin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microstructure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recrystallization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">storage condition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tomography</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37961837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jsfa.13125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Grote U, Fasse A, Nguyen TT and Erenstein O, Food security and the dynamics of wheat and maize value chains in Africa and Asia. Front Sustain Food Syst 4:617009 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Y, Jiang J, Chen Q, Wang Z, Zeng M, Qin F et al., Radio-frequency treatment of medium-gluten wheat: effects of tempering moisture and treatment time on wheat quality. J Sci Food Agric 103:4441-4449 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin F, Li X, Jia N, Feng F, Huang H, Huang J et al., The impact of Russia-Ukraine conflict on global food security. Glob Food Sec 36:100661 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bresciani A, Vaglia V, Saitta F, Fessas D, Casiraghi MC, Erba D et al., High-amylose and Tongil type Korean rice varieties: physical properties, cooking behaviour and starch digestibility. Food Sci Biotechnol 31:681-690 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Ma M, Yang T, Li M and Sun Q, Dynamic distribution and transition of gluten proteins during noodle processing. Food Hydrocoll 123:107114 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suwannaporn P and Wiwattanawanich K, Effects of water requirement and substitution level on wheat-rice noodles with hydrocolloids. St&#xe4;rke 63:493-502 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charutigon C, Jitpupakdree J, Namsree P and Rungsardthong V, Effects of processing conditions and the use of modified starch and monoglyceride on some properties of extruded rice vermicelli. LWT 41:642-651 (2008).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loubes MA, Flores SK and Tolaba MP, Effect of formulation on rice noodle quality: selection of functional ingredients and optimization by mixture design. LWT 69:280-286 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi SY, Cho JH and Koh BK, A rice noodle making procedure for evaluating rice flour noodle-making potential. J Korean Soc Food Sci Nutr 41:1823-1829 (2012).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou G, Kruk M and Center WM, Asian noodle technology. Technical. Bulletin 20:1-10 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y-H, Zhang Y-R, Wang X, Yang Y-Y, Guo W-M, Fei Y-X et al., Improving the surface tackiness of frozen cooked noodles by the addition of glutenin, gliadin, and gluten. LWT 179:114637 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ueda M, Tsukamoto S, Tabuchi M and Akamatsu N, Long-life noodle and retort noodle and its production. [Online]. Google Patent (1998). Available: https://patents.google.com/patent/JPH11192063A/en [02 May 2023].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong J-H, Effects of organic acids on textural properties and storage stabilities of long life noodles. J Korean Soc Food Cult 13:191-196 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsueh-Liang L, Der-Sheng C, Chin-Hung T and Shie-Jea L, Effects of acidification on the extension of shelf life of Japanese wet-type noodles (woo-long noodle). Afr J Microbiol Res 10:1918-1925 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang Q, Zheng B, Zhang Y and Zeng H, A comprehensive review of the factors influencing the formation of retrograded starch. Int J Biol Macromol 186:163-173 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian Y, Li M and Liu X, Jane J-l, Guo B and Dhital S, storage temperature and time affect the enzyme resistance starch and glycemic response of cooked noodles. Food Chem 344:128702 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang M, Hong Y, Gu Z, Zhang Y and Cai X, The effect of xanthan on short and long-term retrogradation of rice starch. St&#xe4;rke 65:702-708 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu R, Zhang Y, Hu H, Gan T and Huang Z, Retrogradation behavior of starch dough prepared from damaged cassava starch and its application in functional gluten-free noodles. Int J Biol Macromol 236:123996 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alpers T, Kerpes R, Frioli M, Nobis A, Hoi KI, Bach A et al., Impact of storing condition on staling and microbial spoilage behavior of bread and their contribution to prevent food waste. Foods 10:76 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross AS, Instrumental measurement of physical properties of cooked Asian wheat flour noodles. Cereal Chem 83:42-51 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang S, Dhital S, Shan C-S, Zhang M-N and Chen Z-G, Ordered structural changes of retrograded starch gel over long-term storage in wet starch noodles. Carbohydr Polym 270:118367 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roh JP, Jeong S, Oh I and Lee S, Micro-computed tomographic and proton NMR characterization of cooked noodles and their correlation with conventional methods. J Food Eng 270:109765 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kojima T, Horigane A, Yoshida M, Nagata T and Nagasawa A, Change in the status of water in Japanese noodles during and after boiling observed by NMR micro imaging. J Food Sci 66:1361-1365 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diantom A, Carini E, Curti E, Cassotta F, D'Alessandro A and Vittadini E, Effect of water and gluten on physico-chemical properties and stability of ready to eat shelf-stable pasta. Food Chem 195:91-96 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon S, Yang G, Kwon H and Lee S, Effects of wheat flour supplemented with soy protein concentrate on the rheology, microstructure and water mobility of protein-fortified precooked noodles. Int J Food Sci Technol 57:4107-4118 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okuda M, Aramaki I, Koseki T, Inouchi N and Hashizume K, Structural and retrogradation properties of rice endosperm starch affect enzyme digestibility of steamed milled-rice grains used in sake production. Cereal Chem 83:143-151 (2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heo S, Lee SM, Shim J-H, Yoo S-H and Lee S, Effect of dry-and wet-milled rice flours on the quality attributes of gluten-free dough and noodles. J Food Eng 116:213-217 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee KY, Park SY, Lee S and Lee HG, Suitability of TEMPO-oxidized oat b-glucan for noodle preparation. Food Sci Biotechnol 23:1897-1901 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng CS and Lai HM, Physicochemical properties of wheat flour dough modified by microbial transglutaminase. J Food Sci 67:750-755 (2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertrand R, Holmes W, Orgeron C, McIntyre C, Hernandez R and Revellame ED, Rapid estimation of parameters for gelatinization of waxy corn starch. Foods 8:556 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abd Karim A, Norziah M and Seow C, Methods for the study of starch retrogradation. Food Chem 71:9-36 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Soto RA, Mora-Escobedo R, Hernandez-Sanchez H, Sanchez-Rivera M and Bello-Perez LA, The influence of time and storage temperature on resistant starch formation from autoclaved debranched banana starch. Food Res Int 40:304-310 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jankowski T, Influence of starch retrogradation on the texture of cooked potato tuber. Int J Food Sci Technol 27:637-642 (1992).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Sun Y, Obadi M, Jiang Y, Chen Z, Jiang S et al., Effects of vacuum mixing and mixing time on the processing quality of noodle dough with high oat flour content. J Cereal Sci 91:102885 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei M, Huang J, Tian X, Zhou P, Zhu Q, Li L et al., Effects of insoluble dietary fiber from wheat bran on noodle quality. Grain Oil Sci Technol 4:1-9 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Z and Seetharaman K, 1H nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) and differential scanning calorimetry (DSC) studies of water mobility in dough systems containing barley flour. Cereal Chem 90:120-126 (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang A, Li M, Wang R, Dhital S and Lu D, Manipulating raw noodle crystallinity to control the hardness of cooked noodle. LWT 109:305-312 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gulia N, Dhaka V and Khatkar B, Instant noodles: processing, quality, and nutritional aspects. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr 54:1386-1399 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H, Tang M, Wu W, Ding W, Ding B and Wang X, Study on inhibition effects and mechanism of wheat starch retrogradation by polyols. Food Hydrocoll 121:106996 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Q, Guo X-N and Zhu K-X, Effects of frozen storage on the quality characteristics of frozen cooked noodles. Food Chem 283:522-529 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Parrilli A, Jaedig F, Fuhrmann A, Staedeli C, Fischer P et al., Micro-computed tomography study on bread dehydration and structural changes during ambient storage. J Food Eng 296:110462 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jolliffe IT and Cadima J, Principal component analysis: a review and recent developments. Philos Trans A Math Phys Eng Sci 374:20150202 (2016).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>