<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40133842</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2662-7671</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC complementary medicine and therapies</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Complement Med Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Optimization of Phellinus hartigii extracts: Biological activities, and phenolic content analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>113</StartPage><MedlinePgn>113</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">113</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12906-025-04851-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Medicinal mushrooms are sources of natural substances with diverse biological functions. The study evaluated the biological activity of Phellinus hartigii (Allesch. &amp; Schnabl) Pat. and optimized extraction conditions to the maximize its bioactive potential.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Extraction was performed using a Soxhlet apparatus under varying conditions: temperatures (30, 50, and 70&#xa0;&#xb0;C), durations (1, 5.5, and 10&#xa0;h), and ethanol/water ratios (0%, 50%, and 100%). Total antioxidant status (TAS) was analyzed across 17 experiments, and the optimal conditions were identified using response surface methodology (RSM). Extracts from optimal conditions were further analyzed for antioxidant capacity (Rel assay kits, DPPH, FRAP), anticholinesterase activity (acetyl- and butyrylcholinesterase inhibition), antiproliferative activity (A549 lung cancer cell line), total phenolic content (Folin-Ciocalteu method), and phenolic compound profile (LC-MS/MS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Optimal extraction conditions were determined to be 48.22 &#x2da;C, 9.04&#xa0;h, and an ethanol/water ratio of 52.22%. The extract exhibited significant antiproliferative effects against the A549 lung cancer cells, with activity increasing in a concentration-dependent manner. The inhibition values (IC<sub>50</sub>) of acetylcholinesterase and butyrylcholinesterase were 21.29&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.41 and 35.51&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.53&#xa0;&#x3bc;g/mL, respectively. The TPC (total phenolic content) value of the optimized extract was determined as 88.21&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.50&#xa0;mg/g, FRAP value as 137.81&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.72&#xa0;mg/g, DPPH value as 106.07&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.44&#xa0;mg/g, TOS (total oxidant status) value as 9.27&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.06&#xa0;&#xb5;mol/L, TAS value as 4.98&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.03&#xa0;mmol/L and OSI (oxidative stress index) value as 0.19&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.002. LC-MS/MS analysis identified nine phenolic compounds, with gallic acid and catechin hydrate as the most abundant.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The extract of P. hartigii obtained under optimal conditions demonstrated substantial antioxidant, anticholinesterase, and antiproliferative activities, highlighting its therapeutic potential.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#xdc;nal</LastName><ForeName>Orhan</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science, Department of Biology, Akdeniz University, Antalya, 07058, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>G&#xfc;rgen</LastName><ForeName>Ay&#x15f;enur</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Engineering and Natural Sciences, Department of Industrial Engineering, Osmaniye Korkut Ata University, Osmaniye, 80000, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krupodorova</LastName><ForeName>Tetiana</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Plant Food Products and Biofortification, Institute of Food Biotechnology and Genomics, National Academy of Sciences of Ukraine, Kiev, 04123, Ukraine. krupodorova@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sevindik</LastName><ForeName>Mustafa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Engineering and Natural Sciences, Department of Biology, Osmaniye Korkut Ata University, Osmaniye, 80000, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kabaktepe</LastName><ForeName>&#x15e;anl&#x131;</ForeName><Initials>&#x15e;</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Battalgazi Vocational School of Higher Education, Malatya Turgut Ozal University, Malatya, 44210, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akata</LastName><ForeName>Ilgaz</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Science, Department of Biology, Ankara University, Ankara, 06100, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Complement Med Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101761232</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2662-7671</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010636">Phenols</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000975">Antioxidants</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002800">Cholinesterase Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010936">Plant Extracts</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Phenols</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000975" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antioxidants</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002800" MajorTopicYN="N">Cholinesterase Inhibitors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072283" MajorTopicYN="N">A549 Cells</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001487" MajorTopicYN="Y">Basidiomycota</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010936" MajorTopicYN="N">Plant Extracts</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Phellinus hartigii</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antialzheimer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anticancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antioxidant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Phenolic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Response surface method</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This research does not involve any ethical issues. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40133842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11934515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12906-025-04851-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12906-025-04851-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mushtaq W, Hayri B, Akata &#x130;, Sevindik M. Antioxidant potential and element contents of wild edible mushroom <i>Suillus granulatus</i>. Kahramanmara&#x15f; S&#xfc;t&#xe7;&#xfc; &#x130;mam &#xdc;niversitesi Tar&#x131;m ve Do&#x11f;a Dergisi. 2020;23(3):592&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Joshi I. Button mushroom-potential source of vitamin d2 and possibilities of value addition. Curr Nutri Food Sci. 2023;19(2):114&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krupodorova T, Barshteyn V, Tsygankova V, Sevindik M, Blume Y. Strain-specific features of <i>Pleurotus ostreatus</i> growth <i>in vitro</i> and some of its biological activities. BMC Biotechnol. 2024;24(1): 9.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10851480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38331794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Islek C, Saridogan BGO, Sevindik M, Akata I. Biological activities and heavy metal contents of some <i>Pholiota</i> species. Fresenius Environ Bull. 2021;30(6):6109&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risha ME, Arafa MA, Aboraya AO, Ibrahem ES. hepatoprotective and antioxidant activities of the edible mushroom, (<i>Agaricus bisporus</i>) on carbon tetrachloride-induced chronic hepatitis in rats. J Pharm Negat<i>.</i> 2023; 14(1):329&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Xun H, Gao Q, Qi F, Sun J, Tang F. Chemical constituents of the mushroom <i>Dictyophora indusiata</i> and their anti-inflammatory activities. Molecules. 2023;28(6): 2760.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10052543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36985732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apparoo Y, Phan CW, Kuppusamy UR, Chan EWC. Potential role of ergothioneine rich mushroom as anti-aging candidate through elimination of neuronal senescent cells. Brain Res J. 2024;1824: 148693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38036238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai G, Tong Y, Chen X, Ren Z, Yang F. In vitro anticancer activity of myricanone in human lung adenocarcinoma A549 cells. Chemotherapy. 2015;60(2):81&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25720464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalotas AC. Aboriginal knowledge and use of fungi. Fungi Australia. 1996;1:269&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin K-S. Identification of some <i>Phellinus</i> spp. Mycobiology. 2001;29(4):190&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azeem U, Dhingra GS, Shri R. Pharmacological potential of wood inhabiting fungi of genus Phellinus Qu&#xe9;l.: An overview. J Pharmacogn Phytochem. 2018;7(2):1161&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luan F, Peng X, Zhao G, Zeng J, Zou J, Rao Z, Liu Y, Zhang X, Ma H, Zeng N. Structural diversity and bioactivity of polysaccharides from medicinal mushroom Phellinus spp.: A review. Food Chem. 2022;397: 133731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35908464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Jiang F, Li L, Liu X, Yan J-K. Recent advances in the bioactive polysaccharides and other key components from Phellinus spp. and their pharmacological effects: A review. Int J Biol Macromol. 2022;222:3108&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36243155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su&#x142;kowska-Ziaja K, Ma&#x15b;lanka A, Szewczyk A, Muszy&#x144;ska B. Physiologically active compounds in four species of Phellinus. Nat Prod Commun. 2017;12(3):1934578X1701200313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30549886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su&#x142;kowska-Ziaja K, Balik M, Muszy&#x144;ska B. Selected species of the genus <i>Phellinus</i>&#x2013;chemical composition, biological activity, and medicinal applications. Chem Biodivers. 2021;18(11): e2100609.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34705323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gafforov Y, Yarasheva M, Wang XW, Ra&#x161;eta M, Rakhimova Y, Kyzmetova L, Bavlankulova K, Rapior S, Chen JJ, Langer E, Munnavarov B, Aslonov Z, Bakokhoja B, Zhou LW. Annotated checklist of poroid Hymenochaetoid fungi in Central Asia: taxonomic diversity, ecological roles, and potential distribution patterns. J Fungi. 2025;11:37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11767013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39852456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gafforov Y, Ra&#x161;eta M, Rapior S, Yarasheva M, Wang X, Zhou L, Wan-Mohtar WAAQI, Zafar M, Lim YW, Wang M, Bekhzod A, Bussmann RW, Zengin G, Chen J. Macrofungi as medicinal resources in Uzbekistan: biodiversity, ethnomycology, and ethnomedicinal practices. J Fungi. 2023;9:922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10532728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37755030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vazquez-Armenta FJ, Leyva JM, Mata-Haro V, Gonzalez-Aguilar GA, Cruz-Valenzuela MR, Esqueda M, Gutierrez A, Nazzaro F, Fratianni F, Gait&#xe1;n-Hern&#xe1;ndez R. Phenolic compounds of Phellinus spp. with antibacterial and antiviral activities. Braz J Microbiol. 2022;53(3):1187&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9433629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35380361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seephonkai P, Samchai S, Thongsom A, Sunaart S, Kiemsanmuang B, Chakuton K. DPPH radical scavenging activity and total phenolics of <i>Phellinus</i> mushroom extracts collected from northeast of Thailand. Chin J Nat Med. 2011;9(6):441&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dokhaharani SC, Ghobad-Nejhad M, Moghimi H, Farazmand A, Rahmani H. Biological activities of two polypore macrofungi (Basidiomycota) and characterization of their compounds using HPLC&#x2013;DAD and LC&#x2013;ESI&#x2013;MS/MS. Folia Microbiol. 2021;66:775&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34120307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibata S, Nishikawa Y, Cheng FM, Fukuoka F, Nakanishi M. Antitumor studies on some extracts of Basidiomycetes. GANN. Jpn J Cancer Res. 1968;59(2):159&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5723061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alalaqi N, Akata I, Altuner EM. Observation of the antibacterial activity and time-kill kinetics of some polypores macrofungi extracts. Fresenius Environ Bull. 2022;31(9):9346&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Said KAM, Amin MAM. Overview on the response surface methodology (RSM) in extraction processes. J Appl Sci Process Eng. 2015;2(1):8&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bal C, Akgul H, Sevindik M, Akata I, Yumrutas O. Determination of the anti-oxidative activities of six mushrooms. Fresenius Envir Bull. 2017;26(10):6246&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellman GL, Courtney KD, Andres V Jr, Featherstone RM. A new and rapid colorimetric determination of acetylcholinesterase activity. Biochem Pharmacol. 1961;7(2):88&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13726518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bal C, Eraslan EC, Sevindik M. Antioxidant, antimicrobial activities, total phenolic and element contents of wild edible mushroom <i>Bovista nigrescens</i>. Prospects in Pharmaceutical Sciences. 2023;21(2):37&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erel O. A novel automated direct measurement method for total antioxidant capacity using a new generation, more stable ABTS radical cation. Clin Biochem. 2004;37(4):277&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15003729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erel O. A new automated colorimetric method for measuring total oxidant status. Clin Biochem. 2005;38(12):1103&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16214125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sevindik M. The novel biological tests on various extracts of <i>Cerioporus varius</i>. Fresenius Envir Bull. 2019;28(5):3713&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akkaya OB, &#xc7;elik &#x130;S, Erta&#x15f; E, &#xc7;&#xf6;mlekcio&#x11f;lu N, Aygan A. Determination of antimicrobial, anticarcinogenic activity of bioactive components of <i>Hypericum Perforatum</i> L. Plant Int J Chem Technol. 2024;8(1):73&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dastan SD. Chemical and functional composition and biological activities of Anatolian Hypericum scabrum L. plant. J Mol Struct. 2023;1275: 134561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comlekcioglu N. Bioactive compounds and antioxidant activity in leaves of endemic and native Isatis spp. in Turkey. Braz Arch Biol Technol. 2019;62: e19180330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mickky B, Elsaka H, Abbas M, Gebreil A, Shams ER. Orange peel-mediated synthesis of silver nanoparticles with antioxidant and antitumor activities. BMC Biotechnol. 2024;24(1):66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11428432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39334269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bal C. Antioxidative and antimicrobial activities of Phellinus igniarius and Phellinus rimosus. Fresen Environ Bul. 2020;29(5):3428&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sevindik M, G&#xfc;rgen A, Khassanov VT, Bal C. Biological activities of ethanol extracts of <i>Hericium erinaceus</i> obtained as a result of optimization analysis. Foods. 2024;13(10): 1560.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11121622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38790860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krupodorova T, Sevindik M. Antioxidant potential and some mineral contents of wild edible mushroom <i>Ramaria stricta</i>. AgroLife Scientific Journal. 2020;9(1):186&#x2013;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eraslan EC, Altuntas D, Baba H, Bal C, Akg&#xfc;l H, Akata I, Sevindik M. Some biological activities and element contents of ethanol extract of wild edible mushroom <i>Morchella esculenta</i>. Sigma Journal of Engineering and Natural Sciences. 2021;39(1):24&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karalt&#x131; &#x130;, Eraslan EC, Sar&#x131;do&#x11f;an BG&#xd6;, Akata I, Sevindik M. Total antioxidant, antimicrobial, antiproliferative potentials and element contents of wild mushroom <i>Candolleomyces candolleanus</i> (Agaricomycetes) from Turkey. Int J Med Mushrooms. 2022;24(12):69&#x2013;76.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36374983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad Z, &#xd6;zdemir B, Sevindik M, Eraslan EC, Selamoglu Z, Bal C. Phenolic compound and antioxidant potential of <i>Hebeloma sinapizans</i> mushroom. AgroLife Scientific Journal. 2023;12(2):12&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabik AE, Sevindik M, Mohammed FS, Dogan M. A new natural source against A549 lung cancer cells <i>Anthemis cotula</i> and its biological activities and phenolic contents. Pharm Chem J. 2024;58(7):1134&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laovachirasuwan P, Judprakob C, Sinaphet B, Phadungkit M. In vitro antioxidant and antimutagenic activities of different solvent extracts of <i>Phellinus</i> spp. Int Food Res J. 2016;23(6):2608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaaban MT, Mohamed BS, Zayed M, El-Sabbagh SM. Antibacterial, antibiofilm, and anticancer activity of silver-nanoparticles synthesized from the cell-filtrate of <i>Streptomyces enissocaesilis</i>. BMC Biotechnol. 2024;24(1):8.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10848522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38321442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Cui S, Dan C, Li W, Xie H, Li C, Shi L. <i>Phellinus baumii</i> polyphenol: a potential therapeutic candidate against lung cancer cells. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23(24): 16141.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9782521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36555782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han KW, Lee SW, Han KS, Lee DJ, Lee BE, Jang WC. Antitumor activities to cytotoxicity of <i>Phellinus linteus</i>. J Toxicol Pub Health. 2003;19(2):147&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alshammari SO. Computational insight of oleracone L, portulacatone B, and portulacatal from Portulaca oleracea L. as potential anticholinesterase inhibitors for Alzheimer&#x2019;s. Processes. 2024;12(7):1456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penumala M, Zinka RB, Shaik JB, Mallepalli SKR, Vadde R, Amooru DG. Phytochemical profiling and in vitro screening for anticholinesterase, antioxidant, antiglucosidase and neuroprotective effect of three traditional medicinal plants for alzheimer&#x2019;s disease and diabetes mellitus dual therapy. BMC Complement Altern Med. 2018;18:1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5834903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29499679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon KN, Jang HS. Anti-xanthine oxidase, anti-cholinesterase, and anti-inflammatory activities of fruiting bodies of <i>Phellinus gilvus</i>. Korean J Clin Lab Sci. 2018;50(3):225&#x2013;35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin G-H, Lee MW, Im KH, Lee TS. Antioxidant, anti-acetylcholinesterase and xanthine oxidase inhibitory activities of three extracts from <i>Phellinus igniarius</i>. J Mushroom. 2014;12(1):1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen TK, Shin DB, Lee KR, Shin PG, Cheong JC, Yoo YB, Lee MW, Jin G-H, Kim HY, Im KH. Antioxidant, anti-inflammatory and anti-acetylcholinesterase activities of fruiting bodies of <i>Phellinus xeranticus</i>. J Mushroom. 2013;11(4):278&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15a;wi&#x105;tek &#x141;, Sieniawska E, Sinan KI, Maciejewska-Turska M, Boguszewska A, Polz-Dacewicz M, Senkardes I, Guler GO, Bibi Sadeer N, Mahomoodally MF. LC-ESI-QTOF-MS/MS analysis, cytotoxic, antiviral, antioxidant, and enzyme inhibitory properties of four extracts of Geranium pyrenaicum Burm. f.: A good gift from the natural treasure. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(14):7621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8307321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34299238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayala-Zavala JF, Silva-Espinoza BA, Cruz-Valenzuela MR, Villegas-Ochoa MA, Esqueda M, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Aguilar GA, Calder&#xf3;n-L&#xf3;pez Y. Antioxidant and antifungal potential of methanol extracts of <i>Phellinus</i> spp. from Sonora, Mexico. Revista Iberoam Micol. 2012;29(3):132&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22100531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Chu M, Ahmadi F, Agar OT, Barrow CJ, Dunshea FR, Suleria HA. A comprehensive review on phytochemical profiling in mushrooms: occurrence, biological activities, applications and future prospective. Food Rev Int. 2024;40(3):924&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon YE, Lee YS, Lim SS, Kim S-J, Jung SH, Bae Y-S, Yi J-S, Kang I-J. Evaluation of the antioxidant activity of the fruiting body of Phellinus linteus using the on-line HPLC-DPPH method. Journal Korean Soc for Appl Biol Chem. 2009;52:472&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>