<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41030919</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2220-6124</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of nephrology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Nephrol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Role of heat shock proteins in renal function and adaptation to heat stress: Implications for global warming.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>107571</StartPage><MedlinePgn>107571</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">107571</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5527/wjn.v14.i3.107571</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The escalating global temperature, with 2024 as the hottest year, emphasizes the critical link between climate change and kidney health. Extreme heat, a consequence of global warming, causes multifaceted effects on human physiology, including renal function alterations. This review investigates physiological and molecular mechanisms of heat stress-induced kidney injury, including acute kidney injury, chronic kidney disease (CKD), and urinary stone formation. It highlights how heat stress contributes to renal dysfunction <i>via</i> dehydration, electrolyte imbalances, and activation of the renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system and antidiuretic hormone pathways, particularly in vulnerable populations like outdoor workers, the elderly, and pregnant women. The review also emphasizes the roles of heat shock proteins (HSPs)-HSP27, HSP60, HSP70, and HSP90-in maintaining cellular integrity by preventing protein aggregation and repairing damaged proteins in renal tissues. Dysregulation of these proteins under prolonged heat stress is implicated in CKD progression. This review highlights the urgent need for targeted public health interventions: (1) Hydration; (2) Workplace cooling; (3) Community education; and (4) Developing pharmacological therapies targeting HSPs. A multidisciplinary approach involving nephrology, environmental science, and public health is essential to mitigate the increasing burden of heat-related kidney disease in the era of global climate change.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2025. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tran</LastName><ForeName>Tam Thai Thanh</ForeName><Initials>TTT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Faculty of Medicine, Can Tho University of Medicine and Pharmacy, Can Tho 900000, Viet Nam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Functional Exploration, Can Tho University of Medicine and Pharmacy Hospital, Can Tho 900000, Viet Nam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tran</LastName><ForeName>Khang Vi</ForeName><Initials>KV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Can Tho University of Medicine and Pharmacy, Can Tho 900000, Viet Nam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nguyen</LastName><ForeName>Tri Duc</ForeName><Initials>TD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Can Tho University of Medicine and Pharmacy, Can Tho 900000, Viet Nam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pham</LastName><ForeName>Ngan Tuong Thien</ForeName><Initials>NTT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Can Tho University of Medicine and Pharmacy, Can Tho 900000, Viet Nam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nguyen</LastName><ForeName>Tin Hoang</ForeName><Initials>TH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Faculty of Medicine, Can Tho University of Medicine and Pharmacy, Can Tho 900000, Viet Nam.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Functional Exploration, Can Tho University of Medicine and Pharmacy Hospital, Can Tho 900000, Viet Nam. nhtin@ctump.edu.vn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Nephrol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101610229</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2220-6124</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acute kidney injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic kidney disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Global warming</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heat shock proteins</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heat stress</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: All the authors report no relevant conflicts of interest for this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41030919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12477759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5527/wjn.v14.i3.107571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Romanovsky AA. Thermoregulation: some concepts have changed. Functional architecture of the thermoregulatory system. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2007;292:R37&#x2013;R46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17008453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brengelmann GL, Savage MV. Temperature regulation in the neutral zone. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 1997;813:39&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9100860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen J, Sato M, Ruedy R, Lo K, Lea DW, Medina-Elizade M. Global temperature change. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2006;103:14288&#x2013;14293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1576294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17001018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barraclough KA, Blashki GA, Holt SG, Agar JWM. Climate change and kidney disease-threats and opportunities. Kidney Int. 2017;92:526&#x2013;530.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28807256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crandall CG, Wilson TE. Human cardiovascular responses to passive heat stress. Compr Physiol. 2015;5:17&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4950975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25589263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Rivas PA, Chauhan SS, Ha M, Fegan N, Dunshea FR, Warner RD. Effects of heat stress on animal physiology, metabolism, and meat quality: A review. Meat Sci. 2020;162:108025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31841730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman CL, Johnson BD, Parker MD, Hostler D, Pryor RR, Schlader Z. Kidney physiology and pathophysiology during heat stress and the modification by exercise, dehydration, heat acclimation and aging. Temperature (Austin) 2020;8:108&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8098077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33997113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansson E, Glaser J, Jakobsson K, Weiss I, Wesseling C, Lucas RAI, Wei JLK, Ekstr&#xf6;m U, Wijkstr&#xf6;m J, Bodin T, Johnson RJ, Wegman DH. Pathophysiological Mechanisms by which Heat Stress Potentially Induces Kidney Inflammation and Chronic Kidney Disease in Sugarcane Workers. Nutrients. 2020;12:1639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7352879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32498242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song R, Li Q, Hu J, Yi H, Mao Z, Zhou F. A mouse model of exertional heatstroke-related acute kidney injury. Ann Transl Med. 2022;10:276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9011261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35434019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg M, Bi P, Nitschke M, Williams S, McDonald S. The impact of daily temperature on renal disease incidence: an ecological study. Environ Health. 2017;16:114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5659014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29078794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen B, Xu R, Wu Y, Co&#xea;lho MSZS, Saldiva PHN, Guo Y, Li S. Association between ambient temperature and hospitalization for renal diseases in Brazil during 2000-2015: A nationwide case-crossover study. Lancet Reg Health Am. 2022;6:100101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9904055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36777886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Bueno JA, D&#xed;az J, Padr&#xf3;n-Monedero A, Mart&#xed;n MAN, Linares C. Short-term impact of extreme temperatures, relative humidity and air pollution on emergency hospital admissions due to kidney disease and kidney-related conditions in the Greater Madrid area (Spain) Sci Total Environ. 2023;903:166646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37652385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu L, Phung D, Crowley S, Dubrow R. Relationships between short-term ambient temperature exposure and kidney disease hospitalizations in the warm season in Vietnam: A case-crossover study. Environ Res. 2022;209:112776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35074348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim E, Kim H, Kim YC, Lee JP. Association between extreme temperature and kidney disease in South Korea, 2003-2013: Stratified by sex and age groups. Sci Total Environ. 2018;642:800&#x2013;808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29920466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Remigio RV, Jiang C, Raimann J, Kotanko P, Usvyat L, Maddux FW, Kinney P, Sapkota A. Association of Extreme Heat Events With Hospital Admission or Mortality Among Patients With End-Stage Renal Disease. JAMA Netw Open. 2019;2:e198904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6692691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31397862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Weather Attribution.  Extreme heat in North America, Europe and China in July 2023 made much more likely by climate change. 2023. Available from: https://www.worldweatherattribution.org/extreme-heat-in-north-america-europe-and-china-in-july-2023-made-much-more-likely-by-climate-change/ </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petropoulos ZE, Ramirez-Rubio O, Scammell MK, Laws RL, Lopez-Pilarte D, Amador JJ, Ballester J, O'Callaghan-Gordo C, Brooks DR. Climate Trends at a Hotspot of Chronic Kidney Disease of Unknown Causes in Nicaragua, 1973-2014. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:5418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8159092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34069421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tigchelaar M, Battisti DS, Spector JT. Work Adaptations Insufficient to Address Growing Heat Risk for U.S. Agricultural Workers. Environ Res Lett. 2020;15:094035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7594196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33133229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venugopal V, Damavarapu N, Shanmugam R, Latha PK. Occupational heat exposure and its impact on kidney health among cashew workers. J Nephrol. 2024;37:2007&#x2013;2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39068375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holm&#xe9;r I. Protective clothing in hot environments. Ind Health. 2006;44:404&#x2013;413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16922184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spector JT, Masuda YJ, Wolff NH, Calkins M, Seixas N. Heat Exposure and Occupational Injuries: Review of the Literature and Implications. Curr Environ Health Rep. 2019;6:286&#x2013;296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6923532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31520291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith DJ, Pius LM, Plantinga LC, Thompson LM, Mac V, Hertzberg VS. Heat Stress and Kidney Function in Farmworkers in the US: A Scoping Review. J Agromedicine. 2022;27:183&#x2013;192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33691597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wesseling C, Glaser J, Rodr&#xed;guez-Guzm&#xe1;n J, Weiss I, Lucas R, Peraza S, da Silva AS, Hansson E, Johnson RJ, Hogstedt C, Wegman DH, Jakobsson K. Chronic kidney disease of non-traditional origin in Mesoamerica: a disease primarily driven by occupational heat stress. Rev Panam Salud Publica. 2020;44:e15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6984407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31998376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricc&#xf2; M. Air temperature exposure and agricultural occupational injuries in the Autonomous Province of Trento (2000-2013, North-Eastern Italy) Int J Occup Med Environ Health. 2018;31:317&#x2013;331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29165429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spector JT, Bonauto DK, Sheppard L, Busch-Isaksen T, Calkins M, Adams D, Lieblich M, Fenske RA. A Case-Crossover Study of Heat Exposure and Injury Risk in Outdoor Agricultural Workers. PLoS One. 2016;11:e0164498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5055365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27716794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu C, Yang J, Qi Z, Wu H, Wang B, Zou F, Mei H, Liu J, Wang W, Liu Q. Heat shock proteins: Biological functions, pathological roles, and therapeutic opportunities. MedComm (2020) 2022;3:e161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9345296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35928554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritossa F. A new puffing pattern induced by temperature shock and DNP in Drosophila. Experientia. 1962;18:571&#x2013;573.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritossa FM. Experimental activation of specific loci in polytene chromosomes of drosophila. Exp Cell Res. 1964;35:601&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14208747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Srivastava P. Heat-shock proteins. Curr Protoc Immunol. 2004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18432918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh MK, Shin Y, Ju S, Han S, Choe W, Yoon KS, Kim SS, Kang I. Heat Shock Response and Heat Shock Proteins: Current Understanding and Future Opportunities in Human Diseases. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25:4209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11050489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38673794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubey A, Prajapati KS, Swamy M, Pachauri V. Heat shock proteins: a therapeutic target worth to consider. Vet World. 2015;8:46&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4777810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27046995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsumoto T, Urushido M, Ide H, Ishihara M, Hamada-Ode K, Shimamura Y, Ogata K, Inoue K, Taniguchi Y, Taguchi T, Horino T, Fujimoto S, Terada Y. Small Heat Shock Protein Beta-1 (HSPB1) Is Upregulated and Regulates Autophagy and Apoptosis of Renal Tubular Cells in Acute Kidney Injury. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0126229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4427334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25962073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Ni&#xf1;o MD, Sanz AB, Sanchez-Lopez E, Ruiz-Ortega M, Benito-Martin A, Saleem MA, Mathieson PW, Mezzano S, Egido J, Ortiz A. HSP27/HSPB1 as an adaptive podocyte antiapoptotic protein activated by high glucose and angiotensin II. Lab Invest. 2012;92:32&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21931298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller E, Neuhofer W, Ohno A, Rucker S, Thurau K, Beck FX. Heat shock proteins HSP25, HSP60, HSP72, HSP73 in isoosmotic cortex and hyperosmotic medulla of rat kidney. Pflugers Arch. 1996;431:608&#x2013;617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8596706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krivoruchko A, Storey KB. Regulation of the heat shock response under anoxia in the turtle, Trachemys scripta elegans. J Comp Physiol B. 2010;180:403&#x2013;414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19834715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benoit JB, Lopez-Martinez G, Phillips ZP, Patrick KR, Denlinger DL. Heat shock proteins contribute to mosquito dehydration tolerance. J Insect Physiol. 2010;56:151&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2861860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19782687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B, Yang B, Zhu J, Wu J, Sha J, Sun J, Bao E, Zhang X. Hsp90 Relieves Heat Stress-Induced Damage in Mouse Kidneys: Involvement of Antiapoptotic PKM2-AKT and Autophagic HIF-1&#x3b1; Signaling. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:1646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7084842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32121259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang BJ, Guerrero ME, Prince TL, Okusha Y, Bonorino C, Calderwood SK. The functions and regulation of heat shock proteins; key orchestrators of proteostasis and the heat shock response. Arch Toxicol. 2021;95:1943&#x2013;1970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34003342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster JM, Darling AL, Uversky VN, Blair LJ. Small Heat Shock Proteins, Big Impact on Protein Aggregation in Neurodegenerative Disease. Front Pharmacol. 2019;10:1047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6759932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31619995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chebotareva N, Bobkova I, Shilov E. Heat shock proteins and kidney disease: perspectives of HSP therapy. Cell Stress Chaperones. 2017;22:319&#x2013;343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5425374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28409327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nayak Rao S. The role of heat shock proteins in kidney disease. J Transl Int Med. 2016;4:114&#x2013;117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5290888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28191532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma A, Sumi S, Seervi M. Heat shock proteins-driven stress granule dynamics: yet another avenue for cell survival. Apoptosis. 2021;26:371&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33978921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlader ZJ, Hostler D, Parker MD, Pryor RR, Lohr JW, Johnson BD, Chapman CL. The Potential for Renal Injury Elicited by Physical Work in the Heat. Nutrients. 2019;11:2087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6769672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31487794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y, Voegeli TS, Liu PP, Noble EG, Currie RW. Heat shock paradox and a new role of heat shock proteins and their receptors as anti-inflammation targets. Inflamm Allergy Drug Targets. 2007;6:91&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17692032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srivastava P. Interaction of heat shock proteins with peptides and antigen presenting cells: chaperoning of the innate and adaptive immune responses. Annu Rev Immunol. 2002;20:395&#x2013;425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11861608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vidyasagar A, Wilson NA, Djamali A. Heat shock protein 27 (HSP27): biomarker of disease and therapeutic target. Fibrogenesis Tissue Repair. 2012;5:7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3464729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22564335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim KK, Kim R, Kim SH. Crystal structure of a small heat-shock protein. Nature. 1998;394:595&#x2013;599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9707123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran L, Mirault ME, Arrigo AP, Goldschmidt-Clermont M, Tissi&#xe8;res A. Heat shock of Drosophila melanogaster induces the synthesis of new messenger RNAs and proteins. Philos Trans R Soc Lond B Biol Sci. 1978;283:391&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakob U, Gaestel M, Engel K, Buchner J. Small heat shock proteins are molecular chaperones. J Biol Chem. 1993;268:1517&#x2013;1520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8093612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogalla T, Ehrnsperger M, Preville X, Kotlyarov A, Lutsch G, Ducasse C, Paul C, Wieske M, Arrigo AP, Buchner J, Gaestel M. Regulation of Hsp27 oligomerization, chaperone function, and protective activity against oxidative stress/tumor necrosis factor alpha by phosphorylation. J Biol Chem. 1999;274:18947&#x2013;18956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10383393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arrigo AP, Virot S, Chaufour S, Firdaus W, Kretz-Remy C, Diaz-Latoud C. Hsp27 consolidates intracellular redox homeostasis by upholding glutathione in its reduced form and by decreasing iron intracellular levels. Antioxid Redox Signal. 2005;7:414&#x2013;422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15706088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehlen P, Hickey E, Weber LA, Arrigo AP. Large unphosphorylated aggregates as the active form of hsp27 which controls intracellular reactive oxygen species and glutathione levels and generates a protection against TNFalpha in NIH-3T3-ras cells. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 1997;241:187&#x2013;192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9405255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charette SJ, Landry J. The interaction of HSP27 with Daxx identifies a potential regulatory role of HSP27 in Fas-induced apoptosis. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2000;926:126&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11193028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruey JM, Ducasse C, Bonniaud P, Ravagnan L, Susin SA, Diaz-Latoud C, Gurbuxani S, Arrigo AP, Kroemer G, Solary E, Garrido C. Hsp27 negatively regulates cell death by interacting with cytochrome c. Nat Cell Biol. 2000;2:645&#x2013;652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10980706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havasi A, Li Z, Wang Z, Martin JL, Botla V, Ruchalski K, Schwartz JH, Borkan SC. Hsp27 inhibits Bax activation and apoptosis via a phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase-dependent mechanism. J Biol Chem. 2008;283:12305&#x2013;12313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2431006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18299320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calderwood SK, Khaleque MA, Sawyer DB, Ciocca DR. Heat shock proteins in cancer: chaperones of tumorigenesis. Trends Biochem Sci. 2006;31:164&#x2013;172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16483782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen RK, Parra I, Lemieux P, Oesterreich S, Hilsenbeck SG, Fuqua SA. Hsp27 overexpression inhibits doxorubicin-induced apoptosis in human breast cancer cells. Breast Cancer Res Treat. 1999;56:187&#x2013;196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10573111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakashima M, Adachi S, Yasuda I, Yamauchi T, Kawaguchi J, Itani M, Yoshioka T, Matsushima-Nishiwaki R, Hirose Y, Kozawa O, Moriwaki H. Phosphorylation status of heat shock protein 27 plays a key role in gemcitabine-induced apoptosis of pancreatic cancer cells. Cancer Lett. 2011;313:218&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21999932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benndorf R, Hayess K, Ryazantsev S, Wieske M, Behlke J, Lutsch G. Phosphorylation and supramolecular organization of murine small heat shock protein HSP25 abolish its actin polymerization-inhibiting activity. J Biol Chem. 1994;269:20780&#x2013;20784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8051180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guay J, Lambert H, Gingras-Breton G, Lavoie JN, Huot J, Landry J. Regulation of actin filament dynamics by p38 map kinase-mediated phosphorylation of heat shock protein 27. J Cell Sci. 1997;110:357&#x2013;368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9057088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huot J, Houle F, Spitz DR, Landry J. HSP27 phosphorylation-mediated resistance against actin fragmentation and cell death induced by oxidative stress. Cancer Res. 1996;56:273&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8542580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochberg GK, Ecroyd H, Liu C, Cox D, Cascio D, Sawaya MR, Collier MP, Stroud J, Carver JA, Baldwin AJ, Robinson CV, Eisenberg DS, Benesch JL, Laganowsky A. The structured core domain of &#x3b1;B-crystallin can prevent amyloid fibrillation and associated toxicity. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2014;111:E1562&#x2013;E1570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4000792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24711386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holguin BA, Hildenbrand ZL, Bernal RA. Insights Into the Role of Heat Shock Protein 27 in the Development of Neurodegeneration. Front Mol Neurosci. 2022;15:868089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9005852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35431800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi SK, Kam H, Kim KY, Park SI, Lee YS. Targeting Heat Shock Protein 27 in Cancer: A Druggable Target for Cancer Treatment? Cancers (Basel) 2019;11:1195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6721579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31426426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jovcevski B, Kelly MA, Rote AP, Berg T, Gastall HY, Benesch JL, Aquilina JA, Ecroyd H. Phosphomimics destabilize Hsp27 oligomeric assemblies and enhance chaperone activity. Chem Biol. 2015;22:186&#x2013;195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25699602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lelj-Garolla B, Mauk AG. Self-association and chaperone activity of Hsp27 are thermally activated. J Biol Chem. 2006;281:8169&#x2013;8174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16436384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes D, Napoli V, Mazurkie A, Stafford WF, Graceffa P. Phosphorylation dependence of hsp27 multimeric size and molecular chaperone function. J Biol Chem. 2009;284:18801&#x2013;18807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19411251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartl FU, Bracher A, Hayer-Hartl M. Molecular chaperones in protein folding and proteostasis. Nature. 2011;475:324&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21776078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saibil H. Chaperone machines for protein folding, unfolding and disaggregation. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2013;14:630&#x2013;642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4340576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24026055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brinker A, Pfeifer G, Kerner MJ, Naylor DJ, Hartl FU, Hayer-Hartl M. Dual function of protein confinement in chaperonin-assisted protein folding. Cell. 2001;107:223&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11672529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf6;ttinger L, Oeljeklaus S, Guiard B, Rospert S, Warscheid B, Becker T. Mitochondrial heat shock protein (Hsp) 70 and Hsp10 cooperate in the formation of Hsp60 complexes. J Biol Chem. 2015;290:11611&#x2013;11622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4416864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25792736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh MK, Shin Y, Han S, Ha J, Tiwari PK, Kim SS, Kang I. Molecular Chaperonin HSP60: Current Understanding and Future Prospects. Int J Mol Sci. 2024;25:5483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11121636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38791521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubaqui&#xe9; Y, Looser R, Rospert S. Significance of chaperonin 10-mediated inhibition of ATP hydrolysis by chaperonin 60. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1997;94:9011&#x2013;9016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC23004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9256426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neupert W. Protein import into mitochondria. Annu Rev Biochem. 1997;66:863&#x2013;917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9242927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogenhagen D, Clayton DA. Mouse L cell mitochondrial DNA molecules are selected randomly for replication throughout the cell cycle. Cell. 1977;11:719&#x2013;727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">560914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson B, Pockley AG. Molecular chaperones and protein-folding catalysts as intercellular signaling regulators in immunity and inflammation. J Leukoc Biol. 2010;88:445&#x2013;462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20445014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohashi K, Burkart V, Floh&#xe9; S, Kolb H. Cutting edge: heat shock protein 60 is a putative endogenous ligand of the toll-like receptor-4 complex. J Immunol. 2000;164:558&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10623794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vabulas RM, Ahmad-Nejad P, da Costa C, Miethke T, Kirschning CJ, H&#xe4;cker H, Wagner H. Endocytosed HSP60s use toll-like receptor 2 (TLR2) and TLR4 to activate the toll/interleukin-1 receptor signaling pathway in innate immune cells. J Biol Chem. 2001;276:31332&#x2013;31339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11402040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchama A, Knochel JP. Heat stroke. N Engl J Med. 2002;346:1978&#x2013;1988.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12075060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morimoto RI. Proteotoxic stress and inducible chaperone networks in neurodegenerative disease and aging. Genes Dev. 2008;22:1427&#x2013;1438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2732416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18519635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alberti G, Paladino L, Vitale AM, Caruso Bavisotto C, Conway de Macario E, Campanella C, Macario AJL, Marino Gammazza A. Functions and Therapeutic Potential of Extracellular Hsp60, Hsp70, and Hsp90 in Neuroinflammatory Disorders. Appl Sci. 2021;11:736.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braxton JR, Shao H, Tse E, Gestwicki JE, Southworth DR. Asymmetric apical domain states of mitochondrial Hsp60 coordinate substrate engagement and chaperonin assembly. Nat Struct Mol Biol. 2024;31:1848&#x2013;1858.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11638070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38951622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caruso Bavisotto C, Alberti G, Vitale AM, Paladino L, Campanella C, Rappa F, Gorska M, Conway de Macario E, Cappello F, Macario AJL, Marino Gammazza A. Hsp60 Post-translational Modifications: Functional and Pathological Consequences. Front Mol Biosci. 2020;7:95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7289027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32582761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horwich AL, Farr GW, Fenton WA. GroEL-GroES-mediated protein folding. Chem Rev. 2006;106:1917&#x2013;1930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16683761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nisemblat S, Yaniv O, Parnas A, Frolow F, Azem A. Crystal structure of the human mitochondrial chaperonin symmetrical football complex. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2015;112:6044&#x2013;6049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4434751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25918392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartl FU, Martin J. Molecular chaperones in cellular protein folding. Curr Opin Struct Biol. 1995;5:92&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7773752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bukau B, Horwich AL. The Hsp70 and Hsp60 chaperone machines. Cell. 1998;92:351&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9476895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayer MP. Hsp70 chaperone dynamics and molecular mechanism. Trends Biochem Sci. 2013;38:507&#x2013;514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24012426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radons J. The human HSP70 family of chaperones: where do we stand? Cell Stress Chaperones. 2016;21:379&#x2013;404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4837186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26865365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogel M, Mayer MP, Bukau B. Allosteric regulation of Hsp70 chaperones involves a conserved interdomain linker. J Biol Chem. 2006;281:38705&#x2013;38711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17052976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu X, Zhao X, Burkholder WF, Gragerov A, Ogata CM, Gottesman ME, Hendrickson WA. Structural analysis of substrate binding by the molecular chaperone DnaK. Science. 1996;272:1606&#x2013;1614.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5629921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8658133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison CJ, Hayer-Hartl M, Di Liberto M, Hartl F, Kuriyan J. Crystal structure of the nucleotide exchange factor GrpE bound to the ATPase domain of the molecular chaperone DnaK. Science. 1997;276:431&#x2013;435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9103205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Smith DF. Hop as an adaptor in the heat shock protein 70 (Hsp70) and hsp90 chaperone machinery. J Biol Chem. 1998;273:35194&#x2013;35200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9857057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrido C, Brunet M, Didelot C, Zermati Y, Schmitt E, Kroemer G. Heat shock proteins 27 and 70: anti-apoptotic proteins with tumorigenic properties. Cell Cycle. 2006;5:2592&#x2013;2601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17106261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hageman J, Rujano MA, van Waarde MA, Kakkar V, Dirks RP, Govorukhina N, Oosterveld-Hut HM, Lubsen NH, Kampinga HH. A DNAJB chaperone subfamily with HDAC-dependent activities suppresses toxic protein aggregation. Mol Cell. 2010;37:355&#x2013;369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20159555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu B, Garrido N, Spelbrink JN, Suzuki CK. Tid1 isoforms are mitochondrial DnaJ-like chaperones with unique carboxyl termini that determine cytosolic fate. J Biol Chem. 2006;281:13150&#x2013;13158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16531398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller AP, Reichow SL. Mechanism of small heat shock protein client sequestration and induced polydispersity. Nat Commun. 2025;16:3635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12003685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40240363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shehata AM, Saadeldin IM, Tukur HA, Habashy WS. Modulation of Heat-Shock Proteins Mediates Chicken Cell Survival against Thermal Stress. Animals (Basel) 2020;10:2407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7766623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33339245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connell P, Ballinger CA, Jiang J, Wu Y, Thompson LJ, H&#xf6;hfeld J, Patterson C. The co-chaperone CHIP regulates protein triage decisions mediated by heat-shock proteins. Nat Cell Biol. 2001;3:93&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11146632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beere HM, Wolf BB, Cain K, Mosser DD, Mahboubi A, Kuwana T, Tailor P, Morimoto RI, Cohen GM, Green DR. Heat-shock protein 70 inhibits apoptosis by preventing recruitment of procaspase-9 to the Apaf-1 apoptosome. Nat Cell Biol. 2000;2:469&#x2013;475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10934466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang D, Niwa M, Koong AC. Targeting the IRE1&#x3b1;-XBP1 branch of the unfolded protein response in human diseases. Semin Cancer Biol. 2015;33:48&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4523453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25986851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, Yarmey VR, Yang OJ, Soderblom EJ, San-Miguel A, Yan D. Heat shock proteins function as signaling molecules to mediate neuron-glia communication in C. elegans during aging. Nat Neurosci. 2025;28:1635&#x2013;1648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40533573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landry J, Chr&#xe9;tien P, Lambert H, Hickey E, Weber LA. Heat shock resistance conferred by expression of the human HSP27 gene in rodent cells. J Cell Biol. 1989;109:7&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2115456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2745558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrizo LC, Ruete CM, Manucha WA, Ciocca DR, Vall&#xe9;s PG. Heat shock protein 70 expression is associated with inhibition of renal tubule epithelial cell apoptosis during recovery from low-protein feeding. Cell Stress Chaperones. 2006;11:309&#x2013;324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1712679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17278880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Gall JM, Bonegio RG, Havasi A, Hunt CR, Sherman MY, Schwartz JH, Borkan SC. Induction of heat shock protein 70 inhibits ischemic renal injury. Kidney Int. 2011;79:861&#x2013;870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8006160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21270764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basu N, Todgham AE, Ackerman PA, Bibeau MR, Nakano K, Schulte PM, Iwama GK. Heat shock protein genes and their functional significance in fish. Gene. 2002;295:173&#x2013;183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12354651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goto H, Nakashima M, Nakashima H, Noguchi M, Imakiire T, Oshima N, Kinoshita M, Kumagai H. Heat acclimation ameliorated heat stress-induced acute kidney injury and prevented changes in kidney macrophages and fibrosis. Am J Physiol Renal Physiol. 2022;323:F243&#x2013;F254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9394728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35796461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer TN, Silva ALD. A simple experimental model of heat shock response in rats. Acta Cir Bras. 1998;13:217&#x2013;221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Butler-Dawson J, Johnson RJ, Krisher L, Jaramillo D, Cruz A, Pilloni D, Brindley S, Rodriguez-Iturbe B, Sanchez-Lozada LG, Dally M, Newman LS. A longitudinal assessment of heat exposure and biomarkers of kidney function on heat shock protein 70 and antibodies among agricultural workers. BMC Nephrol. 2024;25:277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11351828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39198762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Park S, Kim WK. Exercise preconditioning reduces acute ischemic renal injury in Hsp70.1 knockout mouse. Histol Histopathol. 2013;28:1223&#x2013;1233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23780557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manucha W. HSP70 Family in the Renal Inflammatory Response. Inflamm Allergy Drug Targets. 2014;13:235&#x2013;240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25091208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzei L, Docherty NG, Manucha W. Mediators and mechanisms of heat shock protein 70 based cytoprotection in obstructive nephropathy. Cell Stress Chaperones. 2015;20:893&#x2013;906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4595437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26228633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sriram M, Osipiuk J, Freeman B, Morimoto R, Joachimiak A. Human Hsp70 molecular chaperone binds two calcium ions within the ATPase domain. Structure. 1997;5:403&#x2013;414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9083109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayer MP, Bukau B. Hsp70 chaperones: cellular functions and molecular mechanism. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2005;62:670&#x2013;684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2773841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15770419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flaherty KM, McKay DB, Kabsch W, Holmes KC. Similarity of the three-dimensional structures of actin and the ATPase fragment of a 70-kDa heat shock cognate protein. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1991;88:5041&#x2013;5045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC51803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1828889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuiderweg ER, Hightower LE, Gestwicki JE. The remarkable multivalency of the Hsp70 chaperones. Cell Stress Chaperones. 2017;22:173&#x2013;189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5352603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28220454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferraro M, D'Annessa I, Moroni E, Morra G, Paladino A, Rinaldi S, Compostella F, Colombo G. Allosteric Modulators of HSP90 and HSP70: Dynamics Meets Function through Structure-Based Drug Design. J Med Chem. 2019;62:60&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30048133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Csermely P, Schnaider T, Soti C, Proh&#xe1;szka Z, Nardai G. The 90-kDa molecular chaperone family: structure, function, and clinical applications. A comprehensive review. Pharmacol Ther. 1998;79:129&#x2013;168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9749880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitesell L, Lindquist SL. HSP90 and the chaperoning of cancer. Nat Rev Cancer. 2005;5:761&#x2013;772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16175177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearl LH. Review: The HSP90 molecular chaperone-an enigmatic ATPase. Biopolymers. 2016;105:594&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4879513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26991466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhat R, Tummalapalli SR, Rotella DP. Progress in the discovery and development of heat shock protein 90 (Hsp90) inhibitors. J Med Chem. 2014;57:8718&#x2013;8728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25141341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamal A, Thao L, Sensintaffar J, Zhang L, Boehm MF, Fritz LC, Burrows FJ. A high-affinity conformation of Hsp90 confers tumour selectivity on Hsp90 inhibitors. Nature. 2003;425:407&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14508491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayer MP, Le Breton L. Hsp90: breaking the symmetry. Mol Cell. 2015;58:8&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25839432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahalingam D, Swords R, Carew JS, Nawrocki ST, Bhalla K, Giles FJ. Targeting HSP90 for cancer therapy. Br J Cancer. 2009;100:1523&#x2013;1529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2696754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19401686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearl LH, Prodromou C. Structure and in vivo function of Hsp90. Curr Opin Struct Biol. 2000;10:46&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10679459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prodromou C, Pearl LH. Structure and functional relationships of Hsp90. Curr Cancer Drug Targets. 2003;3:301&#x2013;323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14529383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biebl MM, Buchner J. Structure, Function, and Regulation of the Hsp90 Machinery. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol. 2019;11:a034017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6719599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30745292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karag&#xf6;z GE, R&#xfc;diger SG. Hsp90 interaction with clients. Trends Biochem Sci. 2015;40:117&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25579468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YS, Alarcon SV, Lee S, Lee MJ, Giaccone G, Neckers L, Trepel JB. Update on Hsp90 inhibitors in clinical trial. Curr Top Med Chem. 2009;9:1479&#x2013;1492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7241864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19860730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitesell L, Lindquist S. Inhibiting the transcription factor HSF1 as an anticancer strategy. Expert Opin Ther Targets. 2009;13:469&#x2013;478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19335068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorger PK, Pelham HR. Purification and characterization of a heat-shock element binding protein from yeast. EMBO J. 1987;6:3035&#x2013;3041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC553740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3319580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eustace BK, Sakurai T, Stewart JK, Yimlamai D, Unger C, Zehetmeier C, Lain B, Torella C, Henning SW, Beste G, Scroggins BT, Neckers L, Ilag LL, Jay DG. Functional proteomic screens reveal an essential extracellular role for hsp90 alpha in cancer cell invasiveness. Nat Cell Biol. 2004;6:507&#x2013;514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15146192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pridgeon JW, Olzmann JA, Chin LS, Li L. PINK1 protects against oxidative stress by phosphorylating mitochondrial chaperone TRAP1. PLoS Biol. 2007;5:e172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1892574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17579517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Li Z. Roles of heat shock protein gp96 in the ER quality control: redundant or unique function? Mol Cells. 2005;20:173&#x2013;182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16267390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tassone G, Mazzorana M, Mangani S, Petricci E, Cini E, Giannini G, Pozzi C, Maramai S. Structural Characterization of Human Heat Shock Protein 90 N-Terminal Domain and Its Variants K112R and K112A in Complex with a Potent 1,2,3-Triazole-Based Inhibitor. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23:9458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9409116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36012721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prodromou C, Panaretou B, Chohan S, Siligardi G, O'Brien R, Ladbury JE, Roe SM, Piper PW, Pearl LH. The ATPase cycle of Hsp90 drives a molecular 'clamp' via transient dimerization of the N-terminal domains. EMBO J. 2000;19:4383&#x2013;4392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC302038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10944121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verbalis JG. Disorders of body water homeostasis. Best Pract Res Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2003;17:471&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14687585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knepper MA. The aquaporin family of molecular water channels. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1994;91:6255&#x2013;6258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC44179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7517546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhondup T, Qian Q. Electrolyte and Acid-Base Disorders in Chronic Kidney Disease and End-Stage Kidney Failure. Blood Purif. 2017;43:179&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28114143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coe FL, Evan A, Worcester E. Kidney stone disease. J Clin Invest. 2005;115:2598&#x2013;2608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1236703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16200192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foxman B. Epidemiology of urinary tract infections: incidence, morbidity, and economic costs. Am J Med. 2002;113 Suppl 1A:5S&#x2013;13S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12113866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lameire N, Van Biesen W, Vanholder R. Acute renal failure. Lancet. 2005;365:417&#x2013;430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15680458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heras MM, Rodr&#xed;guez NDC, Gonz&#xe1;lez JFN. The renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system in renal and cardiovascular disease and the effects of its pharmacological blockade. J Diabetes Metab. 2012;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meneton P, Loffing J, Warnock DG. Sodium and potassium handling by the aldosterone-sensitive distal nephron: the pivotal role of the distal and connecting tubule. Am J Physiol Renal Physiol. 2004;287:F593&#x2013;F601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15345493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carey RM, Padia SH. Role of angiotensin AT(2) receptors in natriuresis: Intrarenal mechanisms and therapeutic potential. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol. 2013;40:527&#x2013;534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4011555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23336117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brater DC. Effects of nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs on renal function: focus on cyclooxygenase-2-selective inhibition. Am J Med. 1999;107:65S&#x2013;70S; discussion 70S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10628595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee CW, Perng CL, Huang YS, Luo JC, Hung CL, Lin HC. Multiple organ failure caused by non-exertional heat stroke after bathing in a hot spring. J Chin Med Assoc. 2010;73:212&#x2013;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20457444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsapatsaris NP, Breslin DJ. Physiology of the adrenal medulla. Urol Clin North Am. 1989;16:439&#x2013;445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2665270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bianchi ME. DAMPs, PAMPs and alarmins: all we need to know about danger. J Leukoc Biol. 2007;81:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17032697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S. Cellular and molecular pathways of renal repair after acute kidney injury. Kidney Int. 2018;93:27&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29291820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petreski T, Ekart R, Hojs R, Bevc S. Hyperuricemia, the heart, and the kidneys - to treat or not to treat? Ren Fail. 2020;42:978&#x2013;986.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7534372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32972284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gherghina ME, Peride I, Tiglis M, Neagu TP, Niculae A, Checherita IA. Uric Acid and Oxidative Stress-Relationship with Cardiovascular, Metabolic, and Renal Impairment. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23:3188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8949471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35328614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung SW, Kim SM, Kim YG, Lee SH, Moon JY. Uric acid and inflammation in kidney disease. Am J Physiol Renal Physiol. 2020;318:F1327&#x2013;F1340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32223310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu MA, S&#xe1;nchez-Lozada LG, Johnson RJ, Kang DH. Oxidative stress with an activation of the renin-angiotensin system in human vascular endothelial cells as a novel mechanism of uric acid-induced endothelial dysfunction. J Hypertens. 2010;28:1234&#x2013;1242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20486275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen L, Hojman P. Muscle-to-organ cross talk mediated by myokines. Adipocyte. 2012;1:164&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3609091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23700527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coresh J, Selvin E, Stevens LA, Manzi J, Kusek JW, Eggers P, Van Lente F, Levey AS. Prevalence of chronic kidney disease in the United States. JAMA. 2007;298:2038&#x2013;2047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17986697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter K, Haslbeck M, Buchner J. The heat shock response: life on the verge of death. Mol Cell. 2010;40:253&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20965420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calderwood SK, Mambula SS, Gray PJ Jr, Theriault JR. Extracellular heat shock proteins in cell signaling. FEBS Lett. 2007;581:3689&#x2013;3694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17499247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pockley AG, Muthana M, Calderwood SK. The dual immunoregulatory roles of stress proteins. Trends Biochem Sci. 2008;33:71&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18182297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schrier RW, Hano J, Keller HI, Finkel RM, Gilliland PF, Cirksena WJ, Teschan PE. Renal, metabolic, and circulatory responses to heat and exercise. Studies in military recruits during summer training, with implications for acute renal failure. Ann Intern Med. 1970;73:213&#x2013;223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5454258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schrier RW, Henderson HS, Tisher CC, Tannen RL. Nephropathy associated with heat stress and exercise. Ann Intern Med. 1967;67:356&#x2013;376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6036395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Z, Hu X, Tong S, Cheng J. Heat and risk of acute kidney injury: An hourly-level case-crossover study in queensland, Australia. Environ Res. 2020;182:109058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31869688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman CL, Johnson BD, Vargas NT, Hostler D, Parker MD, Schlader ZJ. Both hyperthermia and dehydration during physical work in the heat contribute to the risk of acute kidney injury. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2020;128:715&#x2013;728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7191500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32078468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart GR, Anderson RJ, Crumpler CP, Shulkin A, Reed G, Knochel JP. Epidemic classical heat stroke: clinical characteristics and course of 28 patients. Medicine (Baltimore) 1982;61:189&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7078400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satirapoj B, Kongthaworn S, Choovichian P, Supasyndh O. Electrolyte disturbances and risk factors of acute kidney injury patients receiving dialysis in exertional heat stroke. BMC Nephrol. 2016;17:55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4895821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27267762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brikowski TH, Lotan Y, Pearle MS. Climate-related increase in the prevalence of urolithiasis in the United States. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2008;105:9841&#x2013;9846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2474527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18626008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stamatelou KK, Francis ME, Jones CA, Nyberg LM, Curhan GC. Time trends in reported prevalence of kidney stones in the United States: 1976-1994. Kidney Int. 2003;63:1817&#x2013;1823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12675858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borghi L, Meschi T, Amato F, Novarini A, Romanelli A, Cigala F. Hot occupation and nephrolithiasis. J Urol. 1993;150:1757&#x2013;1760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8230496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roncal-Jimenez C, Garc&#xed;a-Trabanino R, Barregard L, Lanaspa MA, Wesseling C, Harra T, Arag&#xf3;n A, Grases F, Jarquin ER, Gonz&#xe1;lez MA, Weiss I, Glaser J, S&#xe1;nchez-Lozada LG, Johnson RJ. Heat Stress Nephropathy From Exercise-Induced Uric Acid Crystalluria: A Perspective on Mesoamerican Nephropathy. Am J Kidney Dis. 2016;67:20&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26455995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallo-Ruiz L, Sennett CM, S&#xe1;nchez-Delgado M, Garc&#xed;a-Urbina A, G&#xe1;mez-Altamirano T, Basra K, Laws RL, Amador JJ, Lopez-Pilarte D, Tripodis Y, Brooks DR, McClean MD, Kupferman J, Friedman D, Arag&#xf3;n A, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Quiroz M, Scammell MK. Prevalence and Risk Factors for CKD Among Brickmaking Workers in La Paz Centro, Nicaragua. Am J Kidney Dis. 2019;74:239&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30826087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koh ASH. A cross sectional study of heat stress exposure, heat-related symptoms, and kidney health among kitchen workers in Kampar, Perak Malaysia. PhD Thesis. Tunku Abdul Rahman University.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tidmas V, Brazier J, Bottoms L, Muniz D, Desai T, Hawkins J, Sridharan S, Farrington K. Ultra-Endurance Participation and Acute Kidney Injury: A Narrative Review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:16887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9779673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36554767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaser J, Lemery J, Rajagopalan B, Diaz HF, Garc&#xed;a-Trabanino R, Taduri G, Madero M, Amarasinghe M, Abraham G, Anutrakulchai S, Jha V, Stenvinkel P, Roncal-Jimenez C, Lanaspa MA, Correa-Rotter R, Sheikh-Hamad D, Burdmann EA, Andres-Hernando A, Milagres T, Weiss I, Kanbay M, Wesseling C, S&#xe1;nchez-Lozada LG, Johnson RJ. Climate Change and the Emergent Epidemic of CKD from Heat Stress in Rural Communities: The Case for Heat Stress Nephropathy. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2016;11:1472&#x2013;1483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4974898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27151892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson RJ, S&#xe1;nchez-Lozada LG, Newman LS, Lanaspa MA, Diaz HF, Lemery J, Rodriguez-Iturbe B, Tolan DR, Butler-Dawson J, Sato Y, Garcia G, Hernando AA, Roncal-Jimenez CA. Climate Change and the Kidney. Ann Nutr Metab. 2019;74 Suppl 3:38&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31203298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran TTT, Ha TK, Phan NM, Le MV, Nguyen TH. Detection of decline in estimated glomerular filtration rate in patients with type 2 diabetes by cystatin C-based equations. World J Nephrol. 2024;13:95761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11572656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39723358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moronge D, Sullivan JC, Faulkner JL. Physiology of Pregnancy-Related Acute Kidney Injury. Compr Physiol. 2023;13:4869&#x2013;4878.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11694322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37358509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leon LR, Bouchama A. Heat stroke. Compr Physiol. 2015;5:611&#x2013;647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25880507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wesseling C, Crowe J, Hogstedt C, Jakobsson K, Lucas R, Wegman DH. The epidemic of chronic kidney disease of unknown etiology in Mesoamerica: a call for interdisciplinary research and action. Am J Public Health. 2013;103:1927&#x2013;1930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3828726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24028232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nerbass FB, Pecoits-Filho R, Clark WF, Sontrop JM, McIntyre CW, Moist L. Occupational Heat Stress and Kidney Health: From Farms to Factories. Kidney Int Rep. 2017;2:998&#x2013;1008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5733743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29270511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venugopal V, Chinnadurai JS, Lucas RA, Kjellstrom T. Occupational Heat Stress Profiles in Selected Workplaces in India. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2015;13:89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4730480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26729144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson RJ, Wesseling C, Newman LS. Chronic Kidney Disease of Unknown Cause in Agricultural Communities. N Engl J Med. 2019;380:1843&#x2013;1852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31067373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseng MF, Chou CL, Chung CH, Chen YK, Chien WC, Feng CH, Chu P. Risk of chronic kidney disease in patients with heat injury: A nationwide longitudinal cohort study in Taiwan. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0235607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7332078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32614909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peraza S, Wesseling C, Aragon A, Leiva R, Garc&#xed;a-Trabanino RA, Torres C, Jakobsson K, Elinder CG, Hogstedt C. Decreased kidney function among agricultural workers in El Salvador. Am J Kidney Dis. 2012;59:531&#x2013;540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22300650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Mar&#xed;n L, Ch&#xe1;vez Y, Garc&#xed;a XA, Flores WM, Garc&#xed;a YM, Herrera R, Almaguer M, Orantes CM, Calero D, Bayarre HD, Amaya JC, Maga&#xf1;a S, Espinoza PA, Serpas L. Histopathology of chronic kidney disease of unknown etiology in Salvadoran agricultural communities. MEDICC Rev. 2014;16:49&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24878649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wesseling C, Arag&#xf3;n A, Gonz&#xe1;lez M, Weiss I, Glaser J, Bobadilla NA, Roncal-Jim&#xe9;nez C, Correa-Rotter R, Johnson RJ, Barregard L. Kidney function in sugarcane cutters in Nicaragua--A longitudinal study of workers at risk of Mesoamerican nephropathy. Environ Res. 2016;147:125&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26866450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habibi P, Razmjouei J, Badzohreh A, Heydari A. Climate change and chronic kidney disease (CKD) among outdoor workers: a systematic review. Int J Biometeorol. 2025;69:1207&#x2013;1236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40186676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elinder CG. Heat-induced kidney disease: Understanding the impact. J Intern Med. 2025;297:101&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11636433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39607397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Torre G, Sestili C, Mannocci A, Sinopoli A, De Paolis M, De Francesco S, Rapaccini L, Barone M, Iodice V, Lojodice B, Sernia S, De Sio S, Del Cimmuto A, De Giusti M. Association between Work Related Stress and Health Related Quality of Life: The Impact of Socio-Demographic Variables. A Cross Sectional Study in a Region of Central Italy. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2018;15:159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5800258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29351222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao A, Sun Y, Avila C, Chiu V, Slezak J, Sacks DA, Abatzoglou JT, Molitor J, Chen JC, Benmarhnia T, Getahun D, Wu J. Analysis of Heat Exposure During Pregnancy and Severe Maternal Morbidity. JAMA Netw Open. 2023;6:e2332780.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10485728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37676659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>