<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37277437</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Influence of inorganic and organic salts on the hydration mechanism of montmorillonite based on molecular simulation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>9090</StartPage><MedlinePgn>9090</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">9090</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-023-36137-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The molecular dynamics method is used to further reveal, from the molecular point of view, the mechanisms of salt inhibiting the hydration of Na-MMT. The interaction between water molecules, salt molecules, and montmorillonite are calculated by establishing the adsorption models. According to the simulation results, the adsorption conformation, interlayer concentration distribution, self-diffusion coefficient, ion hydration parameters, and other data are compared and analyzed. The simulation results show that the volume and basal spacing increase in a stepwise manner with the increase of water content, and water molecules have different hydration mechanisms. The addition of salt will enhance the hydration properties of compensating cations of montmorillonite and affect the mobility of particles. The addition of inorganic salts mainly reduces the adsorption tightness between water molecules and crystal surfaces, thereby reducing the thickness of water molecules layer, while the organic salts can better inhibit migration by controlling interlayer water molecules. The results of molecular dynamics simulations reveal the microscopic distribution of particles and the influence mechanism when the swelling properties of montmorillonite are modified by chemical reagents.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Lianjun</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Hydraulics and Mountain River Engineering, College of Water Resource and Hydropower, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610065, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiang</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sichuan Provincial Transport Department Highway Planning, Survey, Design and Research Institute, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Haisong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sichuan Provincial Transport Department Highway Planning, Survey, Design and Research Institute, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Kai</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sichuan Provincial Transport Department Highway Planning, Survey, Design and Research Institute, Chengdu, 610041, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Enlong</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Hydraulics and Mountain River Engineering, College of Water Resource and Hydropower, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610065, China. liuenlong@scu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Ge</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Geological Hazards On Three Gorges Reservoir Area, Ministry of Education, China Three Gorges University, Yichang, 443002, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37277437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10241947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-36137-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-023-36137-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mostafa NY, El-Hemaly S, Al-Wakeel EI, El-Korashy SA, Brown PW. Characterization and evaluation of the pozzolanic activity of Egyptian industrial by-products: I: Silica fume and dealuminated Kaolin. Cem. Concr. Res. 2001;31(3):467&#x2013;474. doi: 10.1016/S0008-8846(00)00485-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0008-8846(00)00485-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Wang QQ. Preparation and flame retardancy of montmorillonite/polyurethane composites. Guangzhou Chem. Ind. Technol. 2020;48(06):63&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abduljauwad SN, Al-Sulaimani GJ, Al-Buraim I, Basunbul IA. Laboratory and field studies of response of structures to heave of expansive clay. Geotechnique. 2000;50(1):197&#x2013;198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin ZZ, et al. Influences of fissures on slope stability of expansive soil. Chin. J. Geotech. Eng. 2012;34(12):2155&#x2013;2161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu PC, et al. The mineral physics characteristics of crystal structure and water structure in the montmorillonite. Northwest Geosci. 1991;32:14&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang FRC, Skipper NT, Sposito G. Computer simulation of interlayer molecular structure in sodium montmorillonite hydrates. Langmuir. 1995;11(7):2734&#x2013;2741. doi: 10.1021/la00007a064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la00007a064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun LL, et al. Influence of layer charge and charge location on the swelling pressure of dioctahedral smectites. Chem. Phys. 2016;476:40&#x2013;45. doi: 10.1016/j.chemphys.2016.05.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemphys.2016.05.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi SC, Vana SK. Influence of swelling behavior on the stability of an infinite unsaturated expansive soil slope. Comput. Geotech. 2016;76(6):154&#x2013;169. doi: 10.1016/j.compgeo.2016.02.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compgeo.2016.02.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Zeng FG, Wang JX. Molecular mechanics and molecular dynamics simulation studies of interlayer structure in montmorillonites. Acta Chim. Sin. 2006;64(16):1654&#x2013;1658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Na P, Zhang F, Li YN. Molecular dynamics simulation of Na-montmorillonite and Na/Mg-montmorillonite hydrates. Acta Phys. Chim. Sin. 2006;22(09):1137&#x2013;1142. doi: 10.1016/S1872-1508(06)60053-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1872-1508(06)60053-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang XJ, Xu JF. Molecular simulation on the inhibition mechanism of organic amine to montmorillonite. Oil Drill. Prod. Technol. 2017;39(04):442&#x2013;448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao HH, Jiang SQ, Ge YY, Liu C. Molecular dynamics simulation of water molecules adsorption by different cations based montmorillonite. Sci. Sin. (Technol.) 2019;49(06):703&#x2013;715. doi: 10.1360/N092018-00291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1360/N092018-00291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo YF. Molecular Simulation of the Mechanism of Hydration Inhibition on the Surface of Na-Montmorillonite. Xi&#x2019;an Shiyou University; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skipper NT, Sposito G, Chang FRC. Monte Carlo simulation of interlayer molecular structure in swelling clay minerals; 1. Methodology. Clays Clay Miner. 1995;43(3):285&#x2013;293. doi: 10.1346/CCMN.1995.0430303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1346/CCMN.1995.0430303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman ACD, Brown G, Newman J, Newmantancredi A. Chemistry of Clay and Clay Minerals. Mineralogical Society; 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Y, Zaoui A, Shahrour I. A theoretical study of swelling and shrinking of hydrated wyoming montmorillonite. Appl. Clay Sci. 2011;51(1):177&#x2013;181. doi: 10.1016/j.clay.2010.10.027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clay.2010.10.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Wang JX, Zeng FG, Xiu-Ling WU. Molecular simulations of crystal structure conformation, x-ray diffraction and infra-red spectrum in montmorillonites. Acta Mineral. Sin. 2011;31(1):133&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi LL. Molecular Simulation of Uranyl Adsorption on (0 0 1) Surfaces of Na-Montmorillonite. Taiyuan University of Technology; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young DA, Smith DE. Simulations of clay mineral swelling and hydration: Dependence upon interlayer ion size and charge. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2000;104(39):9163&#x2013;9170. doi: 10.1021/jp000146k.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp000146k</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rappe AK, Casewit CJ, Colwell KS, Goddard WAI, Skiff WMJ. UFF, a full periodic table force field for molecular mechanics and molecular dynamics simulations. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 1992;114(25):10024&#x2013;10035. doi: 10.1021/ja00051a040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ja00051a040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun RY, Zhang YF, Fan KK, Shi YH, Yang SK. Molecular simulations of adsorption characteristics of clay minerals in shale. CIESC J. 2015;66(4):2118&#x2013;2122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cases JM, Berend I, Besson G, Francois M, Poirier JE. Mechanism of adsorption and desorption of water vapor by homoionic montmorillonite. 1. The sodium-exchanged form. Langmuir. 1992;8(11):2730&#x2013;2739. doi: 10.1021/la00047a025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la00047a025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu HJ. Molecular Dynamics Simulation Study on Na-Montmorillonite. China University of Petroleum; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu JF, et al. Influence simulation of inorganic salts on montmorillonite elastic mechanical parameters and experimental study. J. China Univ. Pet. 2016;40(2):8.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>