<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39347175</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effective Management of Leptospirosis: A Case Report of Combined Doxycycline and Ceftriaxone Therapy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e67909</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e67909</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e67909</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.67909</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Leptospirosis is a bacterial infection caused by the pathogen Leptospira. The disease is primarily transmitted through contact with animals (mainly rats) or through exposure to contaminated water or soil. Underdeveloped countries and places with poor housing and sanitation are at higher risk. Leptospirosis often presents with nonspecific symptoms, making it difficult to diagnose. This can delay the initiation of appropriate treatment. In the case presented, the patient had a history of cough, high fever, and a rash over various parts of the body. This combination of respiratory symptoms, systemic fever, and dermatological manifestations led to the suspicion of an infection. Initial blood examinations revealed a significantly increased white blood cell&#xa0;(WBC) count, indicating an infection. Further enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) testing was confirmed by active immunoglobulin M (IgM) antibodies specific to leptospira species, followed by a chest X-ray scan. The antibiotics doxycycline (for seven days) and ceftriaxone (two weeks) were used to treat the leptospirosis. The patient was also given antipyretics to bring down fever and antitussive agents to suppress the cough. Hydration and breathing exercises were also given high priority in healing from this illness. After treatment, the patient did very well, he sweated less before dawn, the rash started to go away, and finally, even coughing was controlled. Further blood tests have shown that now the WBC is in the normal range and the IgM antibody level has dropped. In other words, the infection has been eradicated. For detailed information, refer to the case study "A Moral Call," which argues that early treatment and intervention are critical in managing leptospirosis. Getting this severe infection with early antibiotic therapy and nursing care gives people a chance for complete recovery from their illness. There must be more studies into this disease's long-term effects and how to prevent it when the risk group is more significant.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024, Timande et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Timande</LastName><ForeName>Chetan A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital Administration, Datta Meghe Institute of Higher Education and Research, Wardha, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kanyal</LastName><ForeName>Deepika R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital Administration, Datta Meghe Institute of Higher Education and Research, Wardha, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhargava</LastName><ForeName>Aditya K</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital Administration, Datta Meghe Institute of Higher Education and Research, Wardha, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sabale</LastName><ForeName>Shantanu R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital Administration, Datta Meghe Institute of Higher Education and Research, Wardha, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mahajan</LastName><ForeName>Sanket</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Embryology, Datta Meghe Institute of Higher Education and Research, Wardha, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dakre</LastName><ForeName>Sudhanshu M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Embryology, Datta Meghe Institute of Higher Education and Research, Wardha, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antibiotic therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bacterial infection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ceftriaxone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">doxycycline</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">leptospirosis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Consent was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39347175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11436254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.67909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Leptospirosis in human: biomarkers in host immune responses. Chin VK, Lee TY, Lim WF, Ywy WS, Syafinaz AN, Zamberi S, Maha A. Microbiol Res. 2018;207:108&#x2013;115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29458845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leptospirosis. Levett PN. Clin Microbiol Rev. 2001;14:296&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11292640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leptospirosis in humans. Haake DA, Levett PN. Curr Top Microbiol Immunol. 2015;387:65&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4442676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25388133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effectiveness of ceftriaxone plus doxycycline in the treatment of patients hospitalized with community-acquired pneumonia. Flanders SA, Dudas V, Kerr K, McCulloch CE, Gonzales R. J Hosp Med. 2006;1:7&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17219465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceftriaxone: an update of its use in the management of community-acquired and nosocomial infections. Lamb HM, Ormrod D, Scott LJ, Figgitt DP. Drugs. 2002;62:1041&#x2013;1089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11985490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doxycycline versus azithromycin for treatment of leptospirosis and scrub typhus. Phimda K, Hoontrakul S, Suttinont C, et al. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2007;51:3259&#x2013;3263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2043199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17638700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceftriaxone compared with sodium penicillin g for treatment of severe leptospirosis. Panaphut T, Domrongkitchaiporn S, Vibhagool A, Thinkamrop B, Susaengrat W. Clin Infect Dis. 2003;36:1507&#x2013;1513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12802748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparing antibiotic treatment for leptospirosis using network meta-analysis: a tutorial. Naing C, Reid SA, Aung K. BMC Infect Dis. 2017;17:29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5217240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28056834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doxycycline therapy for leptospirosis. McClain JB, Ballou WR, Harrison SM, Steinweg DL. Ann Intern Med. 1984;100:696&#x2013;698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6712032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antibiotics for the treatment of leptospirosis: systematic review and meta-analysis of controlled trials. Charan J, Saxena D, Mulla S, Yadav P. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3733179/ Int J Prev Med. 2013;4:501&#x2013;510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3733179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23930159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>