<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41293667</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0976-4879</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Season>Jul-Sep</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of pharmacy &amp; bioallied sciences</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Pharm Bioallied Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Inductively Coupled Plasma Mass Spectrometry Analysis (ICP-MS) and Particle Size Distribution of Commercially Available Herbal and Nonherbal Toothpastes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>179</StartPage><EndPage>181</EndPage><MedlinePgn>179-181</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/jpbs.jpbs_1157_25</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The effectiveness and safety of toothpaste formulations, both herbal and nonherbal, are influenced by a number of ingredients, such as detergents, sweeteners, and abrasives.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Using Inductively Coupled Plasma mass spectrometry, this study examined the chemical makeup of two widely available toothpastes in India: Dabur Red, which is herbal, and Colgate Strong Teeth, nonherbal. The analysis concentrated on the amounts of sweeteners, abrasive agents, and other important components.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The findings showed that nonherbal toothpastes, especially Colgate Strong Care, had higher concentrations of sodium saccharine, sorbitol, hydrated silica, and calcium carbonate, all of which increased abrasivity. Lower amounts of these compounds were found in herbal toothpastes, indicating a softer formulation. The anticariogenic and antihypersensitive qualities of potassium nitrate and fluoride were unique to Colgate.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study emphasizes the unique qualities of herbal and nonherbal toothpaste formulations, highlighting the necessity of striking a balance between cleansing effectiveness and safety.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Journal of Pharmacy and Bioallied Sciences.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muthu</LastName><ForeName>R M Therraddi</ForeName><Initials>RMT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dental Science, Bharath Institute of Higher Education and Research, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manigandan</LastName><ForeName>T</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oral Medicine and Radiology, Sree Balaji Dental College and Hospital, Bharath Institute of Higher Education and Research, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jones</LastName><ForeName>Sumathi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, Sree Balaji Dental College and Hospital, Bharath Institute of Higher Education and Research, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jayalakshmi</LastName><ForeName>S</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Associate Professor, Chief Scientist, Department of Conservative Dentistry and Endodontics, White Lab-Material Research Centre, Saveetha Dental College and Hospital, Saveetha Institute of Medical and Technical Sciences, Saveetha University, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>J Pharm Bioallied Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101537209</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0975-7406</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Abrasive particle size</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">herbal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nonherbal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">toothpaste</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41293667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12643162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jpbs.jpbs_1157_25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JPBS-17-179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Vranic E, Lacevic A, Mehmedagic A, Uzunovic A. Formulation ingredients for toothpastes and mouthwashes. Bosn J Basic Med Sci. 2004;4:51&#x2013;8. [doi: 10.17305/bjbms.2004.3362]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7245492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15628997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marraffa JM, Holland MG, Stork CM, Hoy CD, Hodgman MJ. Diethylene Glycol: Widely Used Solvent Presents Serious Poisoning Potential. J Emergency Med. 2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18024066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wejnerowska G, Gackowska A, Gaca J. Determination of Linoleic Acid in Toothpaste by Gas Chromatography with Flame Ionization Detection. Anal Sci. 2008;24:758&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18544865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal A, Krishan S, Midha V, Kaur S, Bala D, Singh P, et al. Abrasive action of herbal vs nonherbal toothpaste: A profilometric analysis. J Pharm Biomed Sci. 2017;07:132&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiani M, Firoozian F, Moradkhani S. Formulation and physicochemical evaluation of toothpaste formulated with Thymus vulgaris essential oil. J Herbmed Pharmacol. 2017;6:130&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishna Kumar K, Gowda Y, Pai VS, Ashwath H, Nadig RR. Abrasivity of herbal and non-herbal tooth paste: A profilometric study. Int J Current Res. 2018;10:75716&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correia M, Uusim&#xe4;ki T, Philippe A. Challenges in Determining the Size Distribution of Nanoparticles in Consumer Products by Asymmetric Flow Field-Flow Fractionation Coupled to Inductively Coupled Plasma-Mass Spectrometry: The Example of Al2O3, TiO2, and SiO2 Nanoparticles in Toothpaste. 2018;5:56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra D, Patnaik S. GC-MS Analysed Phyto-Chemicals and Antibacterial Activity of Withania Somnifera (L.) Dunal Extract in the Context of Treatment to Liver Cirrhosis. Biomed Pharmacol J. 2020;13:71&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korsuwannawong S, Vajrabhaya L, Teinchai C, Salee W. Comparison of enamel surface roughness after brushing with herbal and non-herbal toothpastes. World J Dent. 2020:11. [doi: 10.5005/jp-journals-10015-1732]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravi C, Muthappan S, Ponnaiah M, Chandrasekaran S, Murugavel S, Samson J. Presence of heavy metals in over the counter teeth whitening products &#x2013; An evaluative study. Indian J Dent Res. 2023;34:142&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37787200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maji RM, Roy C, Sinha SK. Gas chromatography&#x2013;mass spectrometry (GC-MS): A comprehensive review of synergistic combinations and their applications in the past two decades. J Anal Sci Appl Biotechnol. 2023;5:72&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kopru S, Soylak M. Inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry (ICP MS) detection of trace metal contents of children cosmetics. Opt Quantum Electron. 2024;56:399.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>