<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39993132</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>104</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of participation in sports safety education on sports injuries, sports safety awareness, and sports activity habits among young Korean athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e41589</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e41589</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e41589</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000041589</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Safety education is important for young athletes because it reduces injuries and serves as a stepping stone to becoming a professional athlete. Mandatory safety education and legislation for sports players are being discussed, but no progress has been made thus far. Therefore, this study investigated how young Korean athletes' participation in sports safety education is related to sports injuries, sports safety awareness, and sports activity habits. We sourced all the data of 3262 professional athletes aged 13 to 18 years from the 2019 Sports Safety Accident Survey. We analyzed the data using SPSS for Windows (version 23.0; IBM Corp., Armonk, NY). Frequency analysis, chi-square analysis, and multivariate logistic regression were performed. The results revealed that the more athletes participate in safety education, the less likely they are to have sports injuries and the more likely they are to develop safety awareness and beneficial activity habits such as managing accidents. Additionally, those who participate in safety education are more likely to carry enough water to stay hydrated during exercise than those who do not. Overall, the results suggest that safety education should be emphasized for athletes from a young age, as it helps prevent injuries and improve performance. A governance-based safety education system must be established so young athletes can participate in safety education. Furthermore, safety education must be regular and sports-specific.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kwon</LastName><ForeName>Jeonga</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-9571-1501</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Elementary Education, College of First, Korea National University of Education, Cheongju-si, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jang</LastName><ForeName>Jusun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6099-5132</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports for All, College of Arts, Cheongju University, Cheongju-si, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001265" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Injuries</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056910" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Republic of Korea</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000193" MajorTopicYN="N">education</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006266" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Education</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013177" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sports</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007722" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Knowledge, Attitudes, Practice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012449" MajorTopicYN="Y">Safety</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no funding and conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39993132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11857000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000041589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202502210-00072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Maslow. Motivation and Personality. Harper; 1954.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon JA, Park JJ. Elementary safety education awareness through big data. J Learner-Centered Curriculum Instr. 2020;20:1351&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korea Ministry of Education. Seven Safety Education Standards. Korea Ministry of Education; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korea Sports Safety Foundation. Comprehensive Report on the Status of Sports Safety Accidents; Korea Sports Safety Foundation; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SJ. Meta-analysis on the effects of safety education program school age children. J Learner-Centered Curriculum Instr. 2022;22:197&#x2013;208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott RJS, Batiste O, Hitto I, Walker B, Leary LD. Pediatric sport-related concussion education: effectiveness and long-term retention of the head safety in youth sports (HSYS) program for youth athletes aged 11&#x2013;16. Cogent Educ. 2016;3:1256141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee IJ, Lee SY, Ha SH. Differences in sports safety awareness between recreational and elite soccer players. Korean J Phys Educ. 2021;60:45&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prieto-Gonz&#xe1;lez P, Mart&#xed;nez-Castillo JL, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Galv&#xe1;n LM, Casado A, Soporki S, S&#xe1;nchez-Infante J. Epidemiology of sports-related injuries and associated risk factors in adolescent athletes: an injury surveillance. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:4857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8125505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34063226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batista MB, Romanzini CLP, Barbosa CCL, Blasquez Shigaki G, Romanzini M, Ronque ERV. Participation in sports in childhood and adolescence and physical activity in adulthood: a systematic review. J Sports Sci. 2019;37:2253&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31179841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choo JH. Verification of effectiveness of virtual reality (VR) program for safety education of marine leisure sport. J Mar Tour Res. 2022;15:265&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee DJ, Kim MK, Oh DJ. The study about effect of CPR educational of badminton club member on knowledge, attitude, and safety consciousness. Korean J Sports Sci. 2018;27:657&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abernethy L, Bleakley C. Strategies to prevent injury in adolescent sport: a systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2007;41:627&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2465167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17496070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eitzen DS, Sage GH. Sociology of North American Sport, Madison, WI: Brown &amp; Benchmark. Empirical Considerations. Soc Sport J. 1997;2:101&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YS. A study on retirement preparation and career support for national athlete in Korea. Korean J Sport Sci. 2008;19:136&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>An KJ, Jang SW. A study on the necessity of mandatory safety education for ensuring safety in sports activities: focusing on the current law. Korean J Phys Educ. 2023;62:261&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho IS, Jung PW. A critical analysis of safety education in school. J Hum Rights Law-relat Educ. 2015;8:43&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korea Sports Safety Foundation. Comprehensive Report on the Status of Sports Safety Accidents. Korea Sports Safety Foundation; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black AM, Meeuwisse DW, Eliason PH, Hagel BE, Emery CA. Sport participation and injury rates in high school students: a Canadian survey of 2029 adolescents. J Safety Res. 2021;78:314&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34399928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goossens L, De Ridder R, Cardon G, Witvrouw E, Verrelst R, De Clercq D. Injury prevention in physical education teacher education students: lessons from sports. A systematic review. Eur Phys Educ Rev. 2019;25:156&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emery CA, Pasanen K. Current trends in sport injury prevention. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol. 2019;33:3&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31431273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf6;ssler R, Donath L, Verhagen E, Junge A, Schweizer T, Faude O. Exercise-based injury prevention in child and adolescent sport: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sports Med. 2014;44:1733&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25129698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojala A, Jussila AM, Pasanen K, Parkkari J. 743 Healthy athlete nationwide sport safety implementation case to sport clubs. Inj Prev. 2016;22:266&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caine D, Maffulli N, Caine C. Epidemiology of injury in child and adolescent sports: injury rates, risk factors, and prevention. Clin Sports Med. 2008;27:19&#x2013;50, vii.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18206567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crane J, Temple V. A systematic review of dropout from organized sport among children and youth. Eur Phys Educ Rev. 2015;21:114&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobsson J, Mirkovic D, Hansson PO, Lundqvist C, Mann RH, Tranaeus U. Youth athletes at Swedish sports high schools with an athletics specialism emphasize environmental support for injury risk management: a focus group study. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2023;9:e001527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10186414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37200774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park HC, Cho KJ. Correlation among knowledge of safety, compliance with safety rules, and ability to cope with emergency situations of scuba divers. Korean J Emerg Med Serv. 2015;19:35&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nurjayanti R, Romadoni S. Educational influence with role play about first aid rice in sports injury ankle sprain on student knowledge school. J Inspirasi Kesehatan. 2023;1:58&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kum EH. The effects of simulation method using book art on safety knowledge and safety behaviors. Korea National University of Education, Chungcheongbuk-do, Repubilc of Korea. Master&#x2019;s thesis. 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YJ. Elementary school children&#x2019;s experience of safety education and their knowledge, attitude, and behavior in safety. J Educ. 2018;38:327&#x2013;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woollard M, Whitfield R, Smith A, et al. Skill acquisition and retention in automated external defibrillator (AED) use and CPR by lay responders: a prospective study. Resuscitation. 2004;60:17&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15002485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroshus E, Baugh CM. Concussion education in US collegiate sport: what is happening and what do athletes want? Health Educ Behav. 2016;43:182&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4761331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26293460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabato TM, Walch TJ, Caine DJ. The elite young athlete: strategies to ensure physical and emotional health. Open Access J Sports Med. 2016;7:99&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5012846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27621677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foss KDB, Le Cara E, McCambridge T, Hinton RY, Kushner A, Myer GD. Epidemiology of injuries in women&#x2019;s lacrosse: implications for sport-, level-, and sex-specific injury prevention strategies. Clin J Sport Med. 2018;28:406&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28742608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeffreys I. The warm-up. In Advanced Personal Training. Routledge; 2021. pp 129&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraak W, Coetzee L, Kruger A, Stewart R, van Vuuren H. Knowledge and attitudes towards concussion in Western Province rugby union senior club rugby players. Int J Sports Med. 2019;40:825&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31574545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon GP, Park SH, Kim B. Influence of risk perceived and hedonic value of a swimming club members on safety attitude, exercise commitment &amp; intention to continue exercise. Korean J Sport. 2020;18:261&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Backe S, Janson S, Timpka T. Governance and implementation of sports safety practices by municipal offices in Swedish communities. Int J Inj Contr Saf Promot. 2012;19:163&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22126404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youk HC. A Comparative study on swimming education in the elementary and middle school between Korea and Germany. Sports Sci. 2018;35:17&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim IG, Kwon HW, Choi JH. Safety management network of sports facilities abroad and system status. J Digital Convergence. 2016;14:547&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ju SS, Park SB. Establishment of local-based collaborative governance for development elementary school sport. J Korea Elem Educ. 2022;33:51&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurgis JJ, Kerr GA. Sport administrators&#x2019; perspectives on advancing safe sport. Front Sports Act Living. 2021;3:630071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8217753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34169275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao Y. The effect of online and offline sports safety education combined with MOOC platforms in physical education teaching in colleges and universities. Scalable Comput Pract Exp. 2023;24:585&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanderlei FM, Vanderlei L, Bastos FN, Netto J&#xfa;nior J, Pastre CM. Characteristics and associated factors with sports injuries among children and adolescents. Braz J Phys Ther. 2014;18:530&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4311597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25590445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owoeye OB, Palacios-Derflingher LM, Emery CA. Prevention of ankle sprain injuries in youth soccer and basketball: effectiveness of a neuromuscular training program and examining risk factors. Clin J Sport Med. 2018;28:325&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29864071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nam SK, Kim DH. The study on real condition of the safety accident and countermeasures for safety management of man&#x2019;s artistic gymnasts. Korean J Sport. 2016;14:37&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim RH, Seo IH. A study on the importance of sports safety education, continuity of participation, and awareness of safety culture: focusing on sports leaders. Korean J Phys Educ. 2023;62:529&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon JA, Jang JJ. Factors influencing injury severity and frequency among Korean sports participants in their 20s and 30s. Healthcare (Basel). 2024;12:664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10970244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38540628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jo KH, Lee SM, So WY, Lee EJ. Mediating effect of sports safety awareness between sports activity habits and the intention to complete safety education among Korean adolescents. Healthcare. 2024;11:1891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10341132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37444725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>