<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41281094</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Electromyostimulation-Induced Rhabdomyolysis: A Case Report and Comprehensive Literature Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e95125</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e95125</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e95125</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.95125</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Whole-body electromyostimulation (WB-EMS) is a training method that activates multiple muscle groups through electrical impulses, offering time-efficient benefits for fitness and rehabilitation. However, improper use, particularly at high intensities, poses risks, including rhabdomyolysis. We report the case of a 36-year-old male who developed WB-EMS-induced rhabdomyolysis, which is a complication that may be induced by a single 25-minute session at high intensity. Laboratory findings revealed significantly elevated creatine kinase (19,534 IU/L) and liver enzymes without renal impairment. The patient was managed with rest and oral hyperhydration, leading to a progressive decline in muscle enzyme levels by the fourth day and total normalization after six days. Users and health professionals should be aware that rhabdomylysis is a complication of WB-EMS and should mitigate risks by monitoring and emphasizing adequate hydration.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Mallek et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mallek</LastName><ForeName>Ward</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Fattouma Bourguiba University Hospital, University of Monastir, Monastir, TUN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kechida</LastName><ForeName>Melek</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Fattouma Bourguiba University Hospital, University of Monastir, Monastir, TUN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jellad</LastName><ForeName>Anis</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Faculty of Medicine, University of Monastir, Monastir, TUN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electromyostimulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise-induced rhabdomyolysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle enzyme elevation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">musculoskeletal rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical exercise</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41281094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12635786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.95125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of whole-body electromyostimulation (WB-EMS) on body composition and muscle strength in non-athletic adults. A systematic review and meta-analysis. Kemmler W, Shojaa M, Steele J, et al. Front Physiol. 2021;12:640657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7952886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33716787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of electromyostimulation on performance parameters in sportive and trained athletes: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Micke F, Held S, Lindenthal J, Donath L. Eur J Sport Sci. 2023;23:1570&#x2013;1580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35913269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Non-athletic cohorts enrolled in longitudinal whole-body electromyostimulation trials-an evidence map. Beier M, Schoene D, Kohl M, von Stengel S, Uder M, Kemmler W. Sensors (Basel) 2024;24:972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10857049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38339689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy and safety of low frequency whole-body electromyostimulation (WB-EMS) to improve health-related outcomes in non-athletic adults. A systematic review. Kemmler W, Weissenfels A, Willert S, et al. Front Physiol. 2018;9:573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5974506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29875684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bibliometric analysis of studies on whole body electromyostimulation. Rodrigues-Santana L, Adsuar JC, Denche-Zamorano &#xc1;, et al. Biology (Basel) 2022;11:1205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9405447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36009832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Side effects of whole-body electro-myo-stimulation. St&#xf6;llberger C, Finsterer J. Wien Med Wochenschr. 2019;169:173&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30141113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>(Whole-body) electromyostimulation, muscle damage, and immune system: a mini review. Teschler M, Mooren FC. Front Physiol. 2019;10:1461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6895567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31849709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>[(Very) high creatinkinase concentration after exertional whole-body electromyostimulation application: health risks and longitudinal adaptations] Kemmler W, Teschler M, Bebenek M, von Stengel S. Wien Med Wochenschr. 2015;165:427&#x2013;435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26498468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhabdomyolysis caused by knee push-ups with whole body electromyostimulation. Hong JY, Hyeok Oh J, Shin JH. Br J Hosp Med (Lond) 2016;77:542&#x2013;543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27640660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Two cases of rhabdomyolysis after training with electromyostimulation by 2 young male professional soccer players. K&#xe4;stner A, Braun M, Meyer T. Clin J Sport Med. 2015;25:0&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25353720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhabdomyolysis in an elite dancer after training with electromyostimulation: a case report. Johannsen AD, Krogh TP. https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/tsm2.91 Transl Sports Med. 2019;2:294&#x2013;297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of whole-body electromyostimulation on health and performance: a systematic review. Pano-Rodriguez A, Beltran-Garrido JV, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Gonz&#xe1;lez V, Reverter-Masia J. BMC Complement Altern Med. 2019;19:87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6480820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31014310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whole-body electromyostimulation training for body composition, muscle strength, and general health outcomes: a brief review of the benefits and side effects. de Camargo JBB, Volpi Braz T, Kemmler W, Lopes Evangelista A, Sales Bocalini D. Strength Cond J. 2024;46:659&#x2013;666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Changes in physical fitness after 12 weeks of structured concurrent exercise training, high intensity interval training, or whole-body electromyostimulation training in sedentary middle-aged adults: a randomized controlled trial. Amaro-Gahete FJ, De-la-O A, Jurado-Fasoli L, Dote-Montero M, Guti&#xe9;rrez &#xc1;, Ruiz JR, Castillo MJ. Front Physiol. 2019;10:451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6492765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31105580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Therapeutic potential of electromyostimulation (EMS) in critically ill patients-a systematic review. Balke M, Teschler M, Sch&#xe4;fer H, Pape P, Mooren FC, Schmitz B. Front Physiol. 2022;13:865437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9124773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35615672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of whole-body electromyostimulation versus high-intensity resistance exercise on body composition and strength: a randomized controlled study. Kemmler W, Teschler M, Wei&#xdf;enfels A, Bebenek M, Fr&#xf6;hlich M, Kohl M, von Stengel S. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2016;2016:9236809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4789460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27034699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Revised contraindications for the use of non-medical WB-electromyostimulation. Evidence-based German consensus recommendations. von Stengel S, Fr&#xf6;hlich M, Ludwig O, et al. Front Sports Act Living. 2024;6:1371723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11058671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38689869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Influence of electrical stimulation frequency on skeletal muscle force and fatigue. Dreibati B, Lavet C, Pinti A, Poumarat G. Ann Phys Rehabil Med. 2010;53:266&#x2013;271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20430713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Position statement and updated international guideline for safe and effective whole-body electromyostimulation training-the need for common sense in WB-EMS application. Kemmler W, Fr&#xf6;hlich M, Ludwig O, et al. Front Physiol. 2023;14:1174103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10075322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37035684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>