<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39215732</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0273-1223</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>90</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Water science and technology : a journal of the International Association on Water Pollution Research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Water Sci Technol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cation interception and permeability characteristics of bentonite barriers exposed to NaCl and NH<sub>4</sub>Cl solutions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1198</StartPage><EndPage>1209</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1198-1209</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2166/wst.2024.241</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>High concentrations of Na<sup>+</sup> and NH<sub>4</sub><sup>+</sup> in landfill leachate lead to deterioration of bentonite barrier and pose a threat to the environment. This study focused on the pollution interception and permeability characteristics of the bentonite barrier exposed to NaCl and NH<sub>4</sub>Cl solutions. Based on previous findings, salt solution concentrations were established at 74.80, 37.40, 18.70, and 9.4 mmol/L. The bentonite contents in the mixture were set at 0, 5, 10, and 15%. The results indicate that the samples exhibit better interception of NH<sub>4</sub><sup>+</sup> compared to Na<sup>+</sup>. This difference arises from the cation exchange sequence, the size of the hydration radius, and the hydrogen bonding of the two cations. Additionally, the difference in hydration enthalpy between the two cations leads to variations in the swelling of bentonite, resulting in a higher hydraulic conductivity coefficient in NH<sub>4</sub>Cl solution. This study shows that although bentonite barriers have better interception for NH<sub>4</sub><sup>+</sup>, they exhibit greater hydraulic conductivity in NH<sub>4</sub>Cl solution, increasing the risk of leachate carrying other contaminants.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Authors This is an Open Access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution Licence (CC BY-NC-ND 4.0), which permits copying and redistribution for non-commercial purposes with no derivatives, provided the original work is properly cited (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Wen-Jing</ForeName><Initials>WJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Donghua University, Shanghai 201620, China; Key Laboratory of Ministry of Education on Safe Mining of Deep Metal Mines, Northeastern University, Shenyang 110819, China E-mail: wjsun@dhu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Qian-Tong</ForeName><Initials>QT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Donghua University, Shanghai 201620, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Ri-Dong</ForeName><Initials>RD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Donghua University, Shanghai 201620, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Ai-Wu</ForeName><Initials>AW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Environmental Science and Engineering, Donghua University, Shanghai 201620, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Yun-Zi</ForeName><Initials>YZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil Engineering and Architecture, China Three Gorges University, Yichang 443002, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leung</LastName><ForeName>A K</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Clear Water Bay, Kowloon, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>41572284</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>51908121</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>22ZR1401800</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Foundation of Shanghai Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022KJZ01</GrantID><Agency>Open Funds of Hubei Key Laboratory of Disaster Prevention and Mitigation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>KF2023-06</GrantID><Agency>Open Funds of Engineering Research Center of Ecoenvironment in Three Gorges Reservoir Region, Ministry of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Water Sci Technol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9879497</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0273-1223</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>1302-78-9</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001546">Bentonite</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>451W47IQ8X</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012965">Sodium Chloride</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>01Q9PC255D</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000643">Ammonium Chloride</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002412">Cations</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014874">Water Pollutants, Chemical</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001546" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bentonite</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012965" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sodium Chloride</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010539" MajorTopicYN="Y">Permeability</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000643" MajorTopicYN="N">Ammonium Chloride</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002412" MajorTopicYN="N">Cations</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014874" MajorTopicYN="N">Water Pollutants, Chemical</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bentonite</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cation exchange</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cation interception</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">permeability characteristics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">swelling index</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare there is no conflict.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39215732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/wst.2024.241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">wst_2024_241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Akinwunmi B., Hirvi J. T., Kasa S. &amp; Pakkanen T. A. 2020 Swelling pressure of Na- and Ca-montmorillonites in saline environments: A molecular dynamics study. Chemical Physics 528, 110511. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemphys.2019.110511.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anh H. N., Ahn H., Jo H. Y. &amp; Kim G. Y. 2017 Effect of alkaline solutions on bentonite properties. Environmental Earth Sciences 76, 374. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12665-017-6704-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aryal D. &amp; Ganesan V. 2018 Diffusivity of mono-and divalent salts and water in polyelectrolyte desalination membranes. The Journal of Physical Chemistry B 122 (33), 8098&#x2013;8110. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcb.8b05979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30106583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casal B., Ruiz-Hitzky E. &amp; Serratosa J. M. 1984 Vibrational spectra of ammonium ions in crown-ether-NH<sub>4</sub><sup>+</sup>-montmorillonite complexes. Journal of the Chemical Society, Faraday Transactions 1: Physical Chemistry in Condensed Phases 80, 2225&#x2013;2232. https://doi.org/10.1039/F19848002225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J. N., Benson C. H. &amp; Edil T. B. 2018 Hydraulic conductivity of geosynthetic clay liners with sodium bentonite to coal combustion product leachates. Journal of Geotechnical and Geoenvironmental Engineering 144 (4), 04018008. https://doi.org/10.1061/(ASCE)GT.1943-5606.0001844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa A. M., Alfaia R. G. D. S. M. &amp; Campos J. C. 2019 Landfill leachate treatment in Brazil &#x2013; an overview. Journal of Environmental Management 232, 110&#x2013;116. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2018.11.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30471544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong T., Yao J., Wang Y., Luo T. &amp; Han L. 2020 On the permselectivity of di-and mono-valent cations: Influence of applied current density and ionic species concentration. Desalination 488, 114521. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.desal.2020.114521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dutta J. &amp; Mishra A. K. 2015 A study on the influence of inorganic salts on the behaviour of compacted bentonites. Applied Clay Science 116-117, 85&#x2013;92. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.clay.2015.08.018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gautier M., Muller F., Forestier L. L., Beny J. M. &amp; Guegan R. 2010 NH<sub>4</sub><sup>+</sup>-smectite: characterization, hydration properties and hydro mechanical behaviour. Applied Clay Science 49, 247&#x2013;254. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.clay.2010.05.013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A. &amp; Paulraj R. 2017 Leachate composition and toxicity assessment: An integrated approach correlating physicochemical parameters and toxicity of leachates from MSW landfill in Delhi. Environmental Technology 38, 1599&#x2013;1605. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09593330.2016.1238515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27735215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havukainen J., Zhan M., Dong J., Liikanen M., Deviatkin I., Li X. D. &amp; Horttanainen M. 2017 Environmental impact assessment of municipal solid waste management incorporating mechanical treatment of waste and incineration in Hangzhou, China. Journal of Cleaner Production 141, 453&#x2013;461. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2016.09.146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helle T. E., Aagaard P., Nordal S., Long M. &amp; Bazin S. 2019 A geochemical, mineralogical and geotechnical characterization of the low plastic, highly sensitive glaciomarine clay at Dragvoll, Norway. AIMS Geosciences 5, 704&#x2013;722. https://doi.org/10.3934/geosci.2019.4.704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang D., Song B. Y., He Y. L., Ren Q. L. &amp; Yao S. 2017 Cations diffusion in nafion117 membrane of microbial fuel cells. Electrochimica Acta 245, 654&#x2013;663. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2017.06.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain S. &amp; Ali S. 2021 Removal of heavy metal by ion exchange using bentonite clay. Journal of Ecological Engineering 22, 104&#x2013;111. https://doi.org/10.12911/22998993/128865.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A. &amp; Lingfa P. 2020 Physicochemical characterization of sodium bentonite clay and its significance as a catalyst in plastic wastes valorization. American Journal of Electronics &amp; Communication 1, 6&#x2013;9. https://doi.org/10.15864/ajec.1202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai H. J., Ding X. Z., Cui M. J., Zheng J. J., Chen Z. B., Pei J. L. &amp; Zhang J. W. 2023 Mechanisms and influencing factors of biomineralization based heavy metal remediation: A review. Biogeotechnics 1 (3), 100039. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bgtech.2023.100039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lou Z. Y., Chai X. L., Zhao Y. C., Song Y., Li X. &amp; Liu Z. Y. 2007 Leachate compostion changes over time: Data from the laogang landfill in Shanghai. Acta Scientiae Circumstantiae 27 (6), 987&#x2013;992. https://doi.org/0.13671/j.hjkxxb.2007.06.014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo H., Zeng Y., Cheng Y., He D. &amp; Pan X. 2020 Recent advances in municipal landfill leachate: A review focusing on its characteristics, treatment, and toxicity assessment. Science of the Total Environment 703, 135468. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2019.135468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31753496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morida K., Fukushi K., Sakuma H. &amp; Tamura K. 2023 Systematic comparison of the hydration and dehydration of Na<sup>+</sup>-, K<sup>+</sup>-, and NH<sub>4</sub><sup>+</sup>-saturated montmorillonite, nontronite, hectorite, saponite, and Fe-saponite by in situ X-ray diffraction measurements. Applied Clay Science 237, 106898. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clay.2023.106898.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naveen B. P., Mahapatra D. M., Sitharam T. G., Sivapullaiah P. V. &amp; Ramachandra T. V. 2017 Physico-chemical and biological characterization of urban municipal landfill leachate. Environmental Pollution 220, 1&#x2013;12. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2016.09.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27616651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negi P., Mor S. &amp; Ravindra K. 2020 Impact of landfill leachate on the groundwater quality in three cities of North India and health risk assessment. Environment, Development and Sustainability 22, 1455&#x2013;1474. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10668-018-0257-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;z&#xe7;oban M. &#x15e;., Acarer S. &amp; T&#xfc;fekci N. 2022 Effect of solid waste landfill leachate contaminants on hydraulic conductivity of landfill liners. Water Science and Technology 85 (5), 1581&#x2013;1599. https://doi.org/10.2166/wst.2022.033.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng J., Lou K., Goenaga G. &amp; Zawodzinski T. A. 2018 Transport properties of perfluorosulfonate membranes ion exchanged with cations. ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces 10 (44), 38418&#x2013;38430. https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.8b12403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng C., Wang G., Qin L., Luo S., Min F. &amp; Zhu X. 2020 Molecular dynamics simulation of NH<sub>4</sub>-montmorillonite interlayer hydration: Structure, energetics, and dynamics. Applied Clay Science 195, 105657. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clay.2020.105657.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petit S., Righi D. &amp; Madejov&#xe1; J. 2006 Infrared spectroscopy of NH<sub>4</sub><sup>+</sup>-bearing and saturated clay minerals: A review of the study of layer charge. Applied Clay Science 34, 22&#x2013;30. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clay.2006.02.007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Setz M. C., Tian K., Benson C. H. &amp; Bradshaw S. L. 2017 Effect of ammonium on the hydraulic conductivity of geosynthetic clay liners. Geotextiles and Geomembranes 45, 665&#x2013;673. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geotexmem.2017.08.008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun D. A., Zhang J. Y., Zhang J. R. &amp; Zhang L. 2013 Swelling characteristics of GMZ bentonite and its mixtures with sand. Applied Clay Science 83&#x2013;84, 224&#x2013;230. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clay.2013.08.042.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun D. A., Zhang L., Li J. &amp; Zhang B. C. 2015 Evaluation and prediction of the swelling pressures of GMZ bentonites saturated with saline solution. Applied Clay Science 105, 207&#x2013;216. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clay.2014.12.032.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun W. J., Xu G., Wei G., Zhang W. J. &amp; Sun D. A. 2021 Effects of ammonium ion and bentonite content on permeability of bentonite-clay mixture. Environmental Earth Sciences 80, 151. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12665-021-09440-w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadimeti J. G. D. &amp; Chattopadhyay S. 2016 Physico-chemical local equilibrium influencing cation transport in electrodialysis of multi-ionic solutions. Desalination 385, 93&#x2013;105. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.desal.2016.02.016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang G., Ye W., Xu Y. &amp; Jalal F. E. 2020 Swelling deformation of Na-bentonite in solutions containing different cations. Engineering Geology 277, 105757. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enggeo.2020.105757.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye W. M., Zhang F., Chen Y. G., Chen B. &amp; Cui Y. J. 2017 Influences of salt solutions and salinization-desalinization processes on the volume change of compacted GMZ01 bentonite. Engineering Geology 222, 140&#x2013;145. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enggeo.2017.04.002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zazoua A., Kazane I., Khedimallah N., Dernane C., Errachid A. &amp; Jaffrezic-Renault N. 2013 Evidence of ammonium ion-exchange properties of natural bentonite and application to ammonium detection. Materials Science and Engineering: C 33, 5084&#x2013;5089. http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.msec.2013.09.005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R., Wang X., Sun Y., Zhang J., Hu W., Du W. &amp; Chen G. 2020 Preparation and performance of ammonium-malic salts as shale swelling inhibitor and a mechanism study. Inorganic and Nano-Metal Chemistry 50, 1027&#x2013;1031. http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/24701556.2020.1732418.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>