<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37378656</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-4095</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>40</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advanced materials (Deerfield Beach, Fla.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Mater</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Porous, Ultrathin PtAgBiTe Nanosheets for Direct Hydrazine Hydrate Fuel Cell Devices.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2303672</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2303672</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/adma.202303672</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Ultrathin 2D&#xa0;nanomaterials have attracted extensive attention due to their fascinating applications in sustainable and clean-energy-related devices, but obtaining ultrathin 2D multimetallic polycrystalline structures with large lateral dimensions remains a challenge. In this study, ultrathin 2D porous PtAgBiTe and PtBiTe polycrystalline nanosheets (PNSs) are obtained via a visible-light-photoinduced Bi<sub>2</sub> Te<sub>3</sub> -nanosheet-mediated route. The PtAgBiTe PNSs are assembled by sub-5&#xa0;nm grains with widths beyond 700&#xa0;nm. Strain and ligand effects originating from the porous, curly polycrystalline structure endow the PtAgBiTe PNSs with robust hydrazine hydrate oxidation reaction activity. Theoretical research demonstrates that the modified Pt activates the N-H bonds in N<sub>2</sub> H<sub>4</sub> during the reaction, and strong hybridization between Pt-5d and N-2p facilitates dehydrogenation while reducing energy consumption. The peak power densities of the PtAgBiTe PNSs in actual hydrazine-O<sub>2</sub> /air fuel cell devices are boosted to 532.9/315.9&#xa0;mW cm<sup>-2</sup> , while those of the commercial Pt/C are 394.7/157.9&#xa0;mW cm<sup>-2</sup> . This work provides a strategy not only for preparing ultrathin multimetallic PNSs but also for finding promising electrocatalysts for actual hydrazine fuel cells.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley-VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Fengling</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State-Local Joint Laboratory for Comprehensive Utilization of Biomass, Center for R&amp;D of Fine Chemicals, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Guizhou University, Guiyang, Guizhou Province, 550025, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nie</LastName><ForeName>Siyang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Lab of Organic Optoelectronics &amp; Molecular Engineering, Tsinghua University, Beijing, 100084, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Liang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, 200240, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Qiang</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3022-9925</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State-Local Joint Laboratory for Comprehensive Utilization of Biomass, Center for R&amp;D of Fine Chemicals, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Guizhou University, Guiyang, Guizhou Province, 550025, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xun</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Lab of Organic Optoelectronics &amp; Molecular Engineering, Tsinghua University, Beijing, 100084, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>21571038</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>22035004</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2021312</GrantID><Agency>Education Department of Guizhou Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2019-5666</GrantID><Agency>Foundation of Guizhou Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2017YFA0700101</GrantID><Agency>National Key R&amp;D Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>202009</GrantID><Agency>Xiamen University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Mater</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9885358</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0935-9648</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pt-based nanoalloys</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">direct hydrazine hydrate fuel cells</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydrazine hydrate oxidation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">porous structures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ultrathin 2D nanosheets</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37378656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202303672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>C. L. Tan, X. H. Cao, X. J. Wu, Q. Y. He, J. Yang, X. Zhang, J. Z. Chen, W. Zhao, S. K. Han, G. Nam, M. Sindoro, H. Zhang, Chem. Rev. 2017, 117, 6225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. A. Z. G. Sial, M. A. U. Din, X. Wang, Chem. Soc. Rev. 2018, 47, 6175.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Y. Jin, T. H. Gu, K. G. Lee, M. J. Kim, M. d. S. Islam, S. J. Hwang, Coordin. Chem. Rev. 2020, 415, 213280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. R. Stamenkovic, B. S. Mun, M. Arenz, K. J. J. Mayrhofer, C. A. Lucas, G. F. Wang, P. N. Ross, N. M. Markovic, Nat. Mater. 2007, 6, 241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. F. Chang, G. Z. Wang, C. Li, Y. Q. He, Y. M. Zhu, W. Zhang, M. Sajid, A. Kara, M. Gu, Y. Yang, Joule 2023, 7, 587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Kodama, T. Nagai, K. Kuwaki, R. Jinnouchi, Y. Morimoto, Nat. Nanotechnol. 2021, 16, 140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Zhou, J. N. Guo, B. Zhao, C. Li, L. H. Zhang, J. Y. Fang, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2021, 143, 15891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Greeley, I. E. A. Stephens, A. S. Bondarenko, T. P. Johansson, H. A. Hansen, T. A. Jaramillo, J. Rossmeis, I. Chorkendorff, J. K. N&#xf8;rskov, Nat. Chem. 2009, 1, 552.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. C. Luo, Z. L. Zhao, Y. L. Zhang, Y. J. Sun, Y. Xing, F. Lv, Y. Yang, X. Zhang, S. Hwang, Y. G. Qin, J. Y. Ma, F. Lin, D. Su, G. Lu, S. J. Guo, Nature 2019, 574, 81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhang, B. L. Huang, G. Luo, T. Sun, Y. G. Feng, Y. C. Wang, Y. H. Ma, Q. Shao, Y. F. Li, Z. Y. Zhou, X. Q. Huang, Sci. Adv. 2020, 6, eaba9731.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. M. Ren, C. B. Yu, Z. H. Chen, Y. X. Xu, Nano Res. 2021, 14, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Chen, T. Shu, F. L. Zhao, Y. F. Li, X. T. Yang, J. W. Li, D. L. Zhang, L. Y. Gan, K. X. Yao, Q. Yuan, Nano Res. 2022, 15, 9010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. L. Huang, L. Z. Bu, F. D. Ning, J. Zhou, C. H. Zhan, M. Z. Sun, L. G. Li, Y. M. Zhu, Z. W. Hu, Q. Shao, X. C. Zhou, X. Q. Huang, Energy Environ. Sci. 2022, 15, 3877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Choi, Y. J. Lee, D. Park, H. Jeong, S. Shin, H. Yun, J. Lim, J. Han, E. J. Kim, S. S. Jeon, Y. Jung, H. Lee, B. J. Kim, Energy Environ. Sci. 2020, 13, 4921.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Y. Jung, S. Kim, J. G. Kim, M. J. Kim, K. S. Lee, Y. E. Sung, P. Kim, S. J. Yoo, H. K. Lim, N. D. Kim, Nano Energy 2022, 97, 107206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Li, W. H. Niu, Z. Z. Yang, N. Zaman, W. Samarakoon, M. Y. Wang, A. Kara, M. Lucero, M. V. Vyas, H. Cao, H. Zhou, G. E. Sterbinsky, Z. X. Feng, Y. G. Du, Y. Yang, Energy Environ. Sci. 2020, 13, 884.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Deng, Q. Q. Mao, W. X. Wang, P. Wang, Z. Q. Wang, Y. Xu, X. N. Li, H. J. Wang, L. Wang, Appl. Catal., B 2022, 310, 121338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Saleem, B. Xu, B. Ni, H. L. Liu, F. Nosheen, H. Y. Li, X. Wang, Adv. Mater. 2015, 27, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. W. Hong, Y. Kim, D. H. Wi, S. Lee, S. U. Lee, Y. W. Lee, S. Choi, S. W. Han, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2016, 55, 2753.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. H. Xie, B. W. Zhang, Z. Y. Jin, P. P. Li, G. H. Yu, ACS Nano 2022, 16, 13715.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. C. Wang, H. Zhao, J. Liu, D. Zhang, X. K. Wu, N. Z. Nie, D. Wu, W. X. Xu, J. P. Lai, L. Wang, Chem. Eng. J. 2022, 450, 137951.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. L. Zhao, L. R. Zheng, Q. Yuan, X. T. Yang, Q. H. Zhang, H. Xu, Y. L. Guo, S. Yang, Z. Y. Zhou, L. Gu, X. Wang, Adv. Mater. 2021, 33, 2103383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Zhang, Y. C. He, R. Y. Guo, W. C. Wang, Q. Zhan, R. Li, T. O. He, C. Wu, M. S. Jin, ACS Energy Lett. 2022, 7, 3329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. S. Chen, Q. Yuan, X. Wang, Chem. Commun. 2023, 59, 2473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Q. Huang, S. H. Tang, X. L. Mu, Y. Dai, G. X. Chen, Z. Y. Zhou, F. X. Ruan, Z. L. Yang, N. F. Zheng, Nat. Nanotechnol. 2011, 6, 28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Saleem, Z. C. Zhang, B. Xu, X. B. Xu, P. L. He, X. Wang, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2013, 135, 18304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Z. Gu, D. D. Wang, C. Xie, T. H. Wang, G. Huang, Y. B. Liu, Y. Q. Zou, L. Tao, S. Y. Wang, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2021, 60, 20253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Z. Qian, J. H. Zhang, J. M. Li, Y. P. Li, X. Jin, Y. Zhu, Y. Liu, Z. Y. Li, A. El-Harairy, C. Xiao, G. Q. Zhang, Y. Xie, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2021, 60, 5984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Liu, X. B. Liao, Y. H. Tang, J. H. Wang, X. Z. Lv, X. L. Pan, R. H. Lu, Y. Zhao, X. Y. Yu, H. B. Wu, Energy Environ. Sci. 2022, 15, 3246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Feng, L. An, B. Li, Y. X. Zuo, J. Song, F. H. Ning, N. Jiang, X. P. Cheng, Y. F. Zhang, D. G. Xia, Nat. Commun. 2019, 10, 4514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. P. Li, J. H. Zhang, Y. Liu, Q. Z. Qian, Z. Y. Li, Y. Zhu, G. Q. Zhang, Sci. Adv. 2020, 6, eabb4197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Cui, J. Q. Chi, J. W. Zhu, X. M. Sun, J. P. Lai, Z. J. Li, L. Wang, Appl. Catal., B 2022, 319, 121950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. H. Wu, Y. Wang, Z. S. Wu, Chem 2022, 8, 2594.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. N. Wang, L. M. Zhao, X. J. Li, Y. Liu, Y. S. Wang, Q. F. Yao, J. P. Xie, Q. Z. Xue, Z. F. Yan, X. Yuan, W. Xing, Nat. Commun. 2022, 13, 1596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. M. Han, Y. Ma, Q. B. Yun, A. L. Wang, Q. S. Zhu, H. Zhang, C. H. He, J. Xia, X. M. Meng, L. Gao, W. B. Cao, Q. P. Lu, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2022, 32, 2208760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Wang, D. S. Wang, Y. D. Li, SmartMat 2021, 2, 56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. L. Tian, X. Zhao, Y. Q. Su, L. J. Wang, H. M. Wang, D. Dang, B. Chi, H. F. Liu, E. J. M. Hensen, X. W. (David) Lou, B. Y. Xia, Science 2019, 366, 850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. S. Liang, N. Li, Z. L. Zhao, L. Ma, X. M. Wang, S. Z. Li, X. Liu, T. Y. Wang, Y. P. Du, G. Lu, J. T. Han, Y. H. Huang, D. Su, Q. Li, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2019, 58, 15471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. H. Zhan, L. Z. Bu, H. R. Sun, X. W. Huang, Z. P. Zhu, T. Yang, H. B. Ma, L. G. Li, Y. C. Wang, H. B. Geng, W. Z. Wang, H. Z. Zhu, C. W. Pao, Q. Shao, Z. Q. Yang, W. Liu, Z. X. Xie, X. Q. Huang, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2023, 62, e202213783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Liu, T. Li, X. C. Dai, J. Zhao, D. C. He, G. M. Li, B. Wang, X. J. Cui, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2022, 144, 4913.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. H. Zu, X. Y. Qian, S. L. Zhao, Q. H. Liang, Y. E. Chen, M. Liu, B. J. Su, K. H. Wu, L. B. Qu, L. L. Duan, H. L. Zhan, J. Y. Zhang, C. Li, W. Li, J. Y. Juang, J. W. Zhu, D. Li, A. B. Yu, D. Y. Zhao, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2022, 144, 2208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. J. Sun, W. S. Zhang, Q. H. Zhang, Y. J. Li, L. Gu, S. J. Guo, Matter 2023, 6, 193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Boyes, A. P. LaGrow, M. R. Ward, R. W. Mitchell, P. L. Gai, Acc. Chem. Res. 2020, 53, 390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. J. Zhu, L. Zhang, P. P. Yang, C. L. Hu, Z. B. Luo, X. X. Chang, Z. J. Zhao, J. L. Gong, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2018, 57, 11544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Wang, X. Zhang, Y. H. Zhang, X. W. Chen, J. Y. Ye, J. Y. Chen, Z. X. Lyu, X. J. Chen, Q. Kuang, S. F. Xie, Z. X. Xie, Nano Lett. 2020, 20, 5458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Wang, M. Vara, M. Luo, H. W. Huang, A. Ruditskiy, J. Park, S. X. Bao, J. Y. Liu, J. Howe, M. F. Chi, Z. X. Xie, Y. N. Xia, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2015, 137, 15036.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. L. Zhao, L. R. Zheng, Q. Yuan, Q. H. Zhang, T. Sheng, X. T. Yang, L. Gu, X. Wang, Nano Res. 2023, 16, 2252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Yang, L. T. Roling, M. Vara, A. O. Elnabawy, M. Zhao, Z. D. Hood, S. X. Bao, M. Mavrikakis, Y. N. Xia, Nano Lett. 2016, 16, 6644.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Chen, S. P. Luo, M. Z. Sun, M. Tang, X, K., Fan, Y. C., X. Y. Wu, Y. J. Liao, B. L. Huang, Z. W. Quan, Small 2022, 18, 2107803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. An, H. J. Yan, B. Li, J. Ma, H. Wei, D. G. Xia, Nano Energy 2015, 15, 24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Y. Fu, C. Z. Wan, A. X. Zhang, Z. P. Zhao, H. X. Huyan, X. Q. Pan, S. J. Du, X. F. Duan, Y. Huang, Nano Res. 2020, 13, 1472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. S. Wang, X. Y. Guan, H. B. Li, S. Y. Zeng, R. Li, Q. X. Yao, H. Y. Chen, Y. Zheng, K. G. Qu, Nano Energy 2022, 100, 107467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. K. Katiyar, S. Dhakar, A. Parui, P. Gakhad, A. K. Singh, K. Biswas, C. S. Tiwary, S. Sharma, ACS Catal. 2021, 11, 14000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Yu, S. J. Lee, J. Theerthagiri, Y. Lee, M. Y. Choi, Appl. Catal., B 2022, 316, 121603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Yan, J. Y. Zhang, X. R. Shi, Y. T. Zhu, C. F. Xia, S. Zaman, X. Hu, X. Y. Wang, B. Y. Xia, ACS Nano 2021, 15, 10286.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. L. Xie, Z. Q. Niu, D. Kim, M. F. Li, P. D. Yang, Chem. Rev. 2020, 120, 1184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. C. Chen, M. H. Liu, J. S. Du, B. Meckes, S. Z. Wang, H. X. Lin, V. P. Dravid, C. Wolverton, C. A. Mirkin, Science 2019, 363, 959.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>