<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37833446</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Experimental investigation on the effect of nano-silica on reinforced concrete Beam-column connection subjected to Cyclic Loading.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>17392</StartPage><MedlinePgn>17392</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">17392</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-023-43882-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Beam-column joints&#xa0;are crucial load transmission zones because they face concentrated forces from both the beams and the columns. High shear and axial stresses caused by these concentrated forces in the area of the joint may result in decreased joint strength. This article proposes a new beam-to-column connection developed for precast concrete-resisting frames. Concrete mixtures are enhanced mechanically by adding nano silica as it increases compressive strength, flexural strength, and abrasion resistance. Within the concrete, it creates a solid, gel-like matrix that fills voids and strengthens the whole construction. In this study, three reinforced concrete beam-column joint specimens were cast with fly ash, the other three with nano-silica and fly ash, and one sample with nano-silica and a control mix without admixtures was cast. Specimen cast using fly ash and nano-silica is subjected to cyclic loading after 28&#xa0;days of curing. A load capacity of 100 kN was imposed on the column during testing. It was observed that a gradual increase in fly ash decreased the compressive and flexural strength of the beam-column joints. This decrease in strength was addressed by adding 2.5% nano-silica. Nano silica acts as a nucleus to bond tightly with cement particles during hydration. The results showed that the flexural strength equivalent to that of a controlled specimen can be achieved by adding nano-silica at 2.5% and fly ash at 60%. The highest loading of 38.1 kN can be applied to the specimen with nano-silica without fly ash. Although a higher axial compression ratio can improve the bearing capacity and initial stiffness, it can also reduce deformation capacity and flexibility.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. Springer Nature Limited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shyamala</LastName><ForeName>G</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, SR University, Warangal, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hemalatha</LastName><ForeName>B</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, St Peter's Institute of Higher Education and Research, Chennai, Tamilnadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Devarajan</LastName><ForeName>Yuvarajan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Saveetha School of Engineering, SIMATS, Saveetha University, Chennai, Tamilnadu, India. yuvarajand.sse@saveetha.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lakshmi</LastName><ForeName>Chairma</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics and Instrumentation Engineering, R.M.K. Engineering College, Chennai, Tamilnadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Munuswamy</LastName><ForeName>Dinesh Babu</ForeName><Initials>DB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Rajalakshmi Institute of Technology, Chembarambakkam, Chennai, 600124, Tamil Nadu, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaliappan</LastName><ForeName>Nandagopal</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Haramaya Institute of Technology, Haramaya University, Dire Dawa, Ethiopia. nandagopal.kaliappan@haramaya.edu.et.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37833446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10576045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-43882-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-023-43882-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Devarajan Y, Nagappan B, Choubey G, Vellaiyan S, Mehar K. Renewable pathway and twin fueling approach on ignition analysis of a dual-fuelled compression ignition engine. Energy &amp; Fuels. 2021;35(12):9930&#x2013;9936. doi: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.0c04237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.0c04237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murthi P, Poongodi K, Awoyera PO. Enhancing the strength properties of high-performance concrete using ternary blended cement: OPC, nano-silica, bagasse ash. Silicon. 2019;1:1. doi: 10.1007/s12633-019-00324-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12633-019-00324-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adhaye AM, Jolhe DA, Loyte AR, et al. Biomechanical investigation of tasks concerning manual materials handling using response surface methodology. Sci Rep. 2023;13:16718. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-43645-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-43645-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10550981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37794098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tawfik TA, Aly Metwally K, EL-Beshlawy SA, et al. Exploitation of the nanowaste ceramic incorporated with nano silica to improve concrete properties. J. King Saud Univ. Eng. Sci. 2020 doi: 10.1016/j.jksues.2020.06.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jksues.2020.06.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakhshi H, Ahmadi R. Influence of nano-silica and silica fume in the steel corrosion embedded in concrete. J. Rehabil. Civ. Eng. 2018;6:51&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li LG, Zheng JY, Zhu J, Kwan AKH. Combined usage of micro-silica and nano-silica in concrete: SP demand, cementing efficiencies and synergistic effect. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;168:622&#x2013;632. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.02.181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.02.181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma R, Khan RA. Sustainable use of copper slag in self compacting concrete containing supplementary cementitious materials. J. Clean. Prod. 2017 doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2017.03.031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2017.03.031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saini G, Vattipalli U. Case studies in construction materials assessing properties of alkali activated GGBS based self-compacting geopolymer concrete using nano-silica. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2020;12:e00352. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2020.e00352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2020.e00352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shyamala G, Kumarasamy K, Ramesh S, et al. Influence of nano-silica in beam-column joint flextural properties. IOP Conf. Ser. Mater. Sci. Eng. 2020;872:012169. doi: 10.1088/1757-899x/872/1/012169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1757-899x/872/1/012169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng W, Zhao Y, Zheng H. Improvement in corrosion resistance of recycled aggregate concrete by nano silica suspension modification on recycled aggregates. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2020;106:103476. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2019.103476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2019.103476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed BS, Syed ZI, Khed V, Qasim MS. Evaluation of nano-silica modified ECC based on ultrasonic pulse velocity and rebound hammer. Open Civ. Eng. J. 2017;11:638&#x2013;649. doi: 10.2174/1874149501711010638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1874149501711010638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo W, Guo X, Sun M, Dai W. Evaluation of the durability and the property of an asphalt concrete with nano hydrophobic silane silica in spring-thawing season. Appl. Sci. 2018;8:1&#x2013;19. doi: 10.3390/app8091475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app8091475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabhat E, Singh K, Ipsita E. Future of sustainable concrete through nanotechnology. Int. J. Eng. Res. Technol. 2019;8:177&#x2013;178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukharjee BB, Barai SV. Development of construction materials using nano-silica and aggregates recycled from construction and demolition waste. Waste Manag. Res. 2015 doi: 10.1177/0734242X15584840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0734242X15584840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25986048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gobinath R, Akinwumi II, Afolayan OD, Karthikeyan S. Banana fibre-reinforcement of a soil stabilized with sodium silicate. Silicon. 2019 doi: 10.1007/s12633-019-00124-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12633-019-00124-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatami F, Mousavi SH. The stud of nano technology utilization in upgrading the quality of construction industry with fire-engineering approach. J. Fundam. Appl. Sci. 2016 doi: 10.4314/jfas.8vi2s.70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/jfas.8vi2s.70</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Y, Shi Z. Experimental study on nano-SiO2 improving concrete durability of bridge deck pavement in cold regions. Adv. Civ. Eng. 2019 doi: 10.1155/2019/5284913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2019/5284913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan Y, Xie J, Wu Y, Wang Y. Synergetic effect of nano-ZnO and trinidad lake asphalt for antiaging properties of SBS-modified asphalt. Adv. Civ. Eng. 2020 doi: 10.1155/2020/3239793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/3239793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajesh Kumar K, Karthik S, Ramamohan R, et al. Shear resistance of portal frame reinforced with bamboo and steel rebar: Experimental and numerical evaluation. Int. J. Recent Technol. Eng. 2019;8:445&#x2013;452.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernal J, Reyes E, Massana J, et al. Fresh and mechanical behavior of a self-compacting concrete with additions of nano-silica, silica fume and ternary mixtures. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;160:196&#x2013;210. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.11.048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.11.048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breccolotti M, Gentile S, Tommasini M, et al. Beam-column joints in continuous RC frames: Comparison between cast-in-situ and precast solutions. Eng. Struct. 2016;127:129&#x2013;144. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2016.08.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2016.08.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raja T, Devarajan Y, Thanappan S. Studies on the mechanical and thermal stability of Calotropis gigantea fibre-reinforced bran nano particulates epoxy composite. Sci Rep. 2023;13:16291. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-42316-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-42316-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10539299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37770492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farhan MS. Behavior of cantilever beams in R. C. Frames with effect of steel fibers in beam-column joint. Diyala J. Eng. Sci. 2018;11:14&#x2013;19. doi: 10.26367/DJES/VOL.11/NO.4/3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26367/DJES/VOL.11/NO.4/3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Najafgholipour MA, Dehghan SM, Dooshabi A, Niroomandi A. Finite element analysis of reinforced concrete beam-column connections with governing joint shear failure mode. Lat. Am. J. Solids Struct. 2017 doi: 10.1590/1679-78253682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1679-78253682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nurjannah SA, Budiono B, Imran I, Sugiri S. The hysteretic behavior of partially pre-stressed beam-column joint sub-assemblages made of reactive powder concrete. J. Eng. Technol. Sci. 2016;48:550&#x2013;570. doi: 10.5614/j.eng.technol.sci.2016.48.5.4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5614/j.eng.technol.sci.2016.48.5.4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelwahed B. Beam-column joints reinforcement detailing adequacy in case of a corner column loss-numerical analysis. Lat. Am. J. Solids Struct. 2019;16:1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1590/1679-78255536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1679-78255536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowes LN, Altoontash A. Modeling reinforced-concrete beam-column joints subjected to cyclic loading. J. Struct. Eng. 2003;129:1686&#x2013;1697. doi: 10.1061/(asce)0733-9445(2003)129:12(1686).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(asce)0733-9445(2003)129:12(1686)</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleh A, Hamad M, Elzeny S, et al. The behavior of RC exterior beam-column joint with nearby beam unreinforced web opening under cyclic loading&#x2014;Experimental study. IOSR J. Mech. Civ. Eng. 2017;14:22&#x2013;30. doi: 10.9790/1684-1404072230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9790/1684-1404072230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesan B, Ilangovan R, Jayabalan P, et al. Finite element analysis (FEA) for the beam-column joint subjected to cyclic loading was performed using ANSYS. Circuits Syst. 2016;7:1581&#x2013;1597. doi: 10.4236/cs.2016.78138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/cs.2016.78138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghatte HF. Evaluation of reinforcing bars ratio effects on SCC beam-column joint performance. Uluda&#x11f; Univ. J. Fac. Eng. 2019;24:141&#x2013;152. doi: 10.17482/uumfd.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17482/uumfd</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Marino EM, Pan P, et al. Experimental study of a novel precast prestressed reinforced concrete beam-to-column joint. Eng. Struct. 2018;156:68&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2017.11.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2017.11.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz-Pinilla JG, Cladera A, Pallar&#xe9;s FJ, et al. Joint strengthening by external bars on RC beam-column joints. J. Build. Eng. 2022;45:103445. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolski M, Ricles JM, Sause R. Experimental study of a self-centering beam-column connection with bottom flange friction device. J. Struct. Eng. 2009;135:479&#x2013;488. doi: 10.1061/(asce)st.1943-541x.0000006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(asce)st.1943-541x.0000006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan D, Guo Z, Xiao Q, Zheng Y. Experimental study of a new beam-tocolumn connection for precast concrete frames under reversal cyclic loading. Adv. Struct. Eng. 2016;19:529&#x2013;545. doi: 10.1177/1369433216630122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1369433216630122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devarajan Y, Munuswamy D, Arunkumar D, et al. Application of potential green algal for power generation as a likely and fractional alternative. Biomass Conv. Bioref. 2023 doi: 10.1007/s13399-023-04870-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13399-023-04870-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Z, Liu Y, Li J. Study of seismic behavior of rc beam-column joints strengthened by sprayed FRP. Adv. Mater. Sci. Eng. 2018 doi: 10.1155/2018/3581458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/3581458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>