<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40112754</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-3557</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>336</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Spectrochimica acta. Part A, Molecular and biomolecular spectroscopy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Spectrochim Acta A Mol Biomol Spectrosc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Terahertz waves promote Ca<sup>2+</sup> transport in the Ca<sub>v</sub>2.1 channel.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>126039</StartPage><MedlinePgn>126039</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.saa.2025.126039</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1386-1425(25)00345-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Ca<sub>V</sub>2.1 channels are the structural foundation for neurotransmitter transmission and other vital biological processes. If autoimmune-mediated reduction in presynaptic Ca<sub>V</sub>2.1 leads to a decrease in calcium influx during a presynaptic action potential, which decreases chemical neurotransmission, leading to a debilitating neuromuscular weakness, also known as Lambert-Eaton myasthenia syndrome. The selectivity filter is a core structural component of Ca<sub>V</sub>2.1 channels, with a pivotal role in regulating the selective permeation of Ca<sup>2+</sup> ions. Due to the vibration and rotation frequencies of the selectivity filter of Ca<sub>V</sub>2.1 being located in the terahertz band, terahertz waves at specific frequencies may resonate with it, thereby affecting Ca<sup>2+</sup> current passing through Ca<sub>V</sub>2.1. Therefore, it is highly worthwhile to study how the terahertz waves regulate the Ca<sub>V</sub>2.1 channel. In this study, we investigate the structure of Ca<sub>V</sub>2.1 channels using molecular dynamics simulations. The effect of external terahertz waves on the channel has been examined at different resonant frequencies of the selectivity filter. We found that when the frequency of terahertz waves applied is around the symmetrical vibration frequency of the carboxyl group in the selectivity filter, the PMF of Ca<sub>V</sub>2.1 significantly decreases, promoting the transport of Ca<sup>2+</sup> ions through Ca<sub>V</sub>2.1. The reason behind this is that the terahertz waves resonate with the carboxyl groups of the selectivity filter, affecting the hydrogen network between the hydrated water of Ca<sup>2+</sup> ions and the selectivity filter. These findings open up new treatment avenues for channel diseases such as Lambert-Eaton myasthenic syndrome treated with terahertz waves.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Yuankun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronic Science and Engineering, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, Sichuan 610054, China; National Key Lab on Vacuum Electronics, Medico-Engineering Cooperation on Applied Medicine Research Center, School of Electronic Science and Engineering, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, Sichuan 610054, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yangmei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Innovation Laboratory of Terahertz Biophysics, National Innovation Institute of Defense Technology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Yaxiong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Biomechanics and Mechanobiology (Beihang University), Ministry of Education, Beijing Advanced Innovation Center for Biomedical Engineering, School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering, Beihang University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Shaomeng</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronic Science and Engineering, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, Sichuan 610054, China; National Key Lab on Vacuum Electronics, Medico-Engineering Cooperation on Applied Medicine Research Center, School of Electronic Science and Engineering, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, Sichuan 610054, China. Electronic address: wangsm@uestc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gong</LastName><ForeName>Yubin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronic Science and Engineering, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, Sichuan 610054, China; National Key Lab on Vacuum Electronics, Medico-Engineering Cooperation on Applied Medicine Research Center, School of Electronic Science and Engineering, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, Sichuan 610054, China. Electronic address: ybgong@uestc.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Spectrochim Acta A Mol Biomol Spectrosc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9602533</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1386-1425</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>SY7Q814VUP</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002118">Calcium</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D020864">Calcium Channels, N-Type</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002118" MajorTopicYN="Y">Calcium</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056004" MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular Dynamics Simulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020864" MajorTopicYN="Y">Calcium Channels, N-Type</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017136" MajorTopicYN="N">Ion Transport</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ca(v)2.1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resonate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Terahertz waves</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vibration spectrum</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: Yubin Gong reports financial support was provided by National Natural Science Foundation of China. Shaomeng Wang reports financial support was provided by National Science Foundation of China Major Project. Yangmei Li reports financial support was provided by National Natural Science Foundation of China. Yaxiong Yang reports financial support was provided by National Natural Science Foundation of China. If there are other authors, they declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>57</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40112754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.saa.2025.126039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1386-1425(25)00345-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>