<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41735172</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-0010</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the science of food and agriculture</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Sci Food Agric</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluation of the hydration kinetics of chia mucilage and its impact on food matrix application.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jsfa.70536</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The mucilage extracted from chia seeds has been successfully used in various food products, acting as emulsifier and stabilizer. Despite its potential, the methods of applying this mucilage are not fully understood. One area that requires further investigation is the influence of the hydration time of chia mucilage on the quality of the final product. Thus, this study aimed to evaluate the hydration kinetics of chia mucilage and assess its influence on the technological properties of a fermented dairy product.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">After extraction in an aqueous medium, followed by lyophilization, the mucilage showed a yield of 8.52% and an average particle diameter of 904.8&#x2009;nm. Solubility increased with temperature, while agitation time had no significant influence at temperatures above 45&#x2009;&#xb0;C. Viscosity of the mucilage increased significantly during the first 60&#x2009;min of hydration and stabilized thereafter. The hydration kinetics followed the Weibull model. The hydration index of 80% viscosity was achieved in 37&#x2009;min; however, it took 108&#x2009;min to reach 90% of that viscosity. Fermented milk formulations were developed using mucilage hydrated for different times (9, 37 and 108&#x2009;min). Among these, the formulation hydrated for 37&#x2009;min showed the most promising results in terms of viscosity, acceptable water holding capacity, and low syneresis values. In contrast, extended hydration times negatively affected these parameters.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These findings highlight the importance of optimizing hydration time to maximize the functional performance of chia mucilage in food systems, particularly in dairy-based matrices, where excessive hydration may compromise product stability and texture. &#xa9; 2026 Society of Chemical Industry.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 Society of Chemical Industry.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Frohlich</LastName><ForeName>Patricia</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Post Graduate Program of Food Engineering, State University of Maringa, Parana, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Botan</LastName><ForeName>Nathalia Gouveia</ForeName><Initials>NG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Engineering, State University of Maringa, Parana, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bar&#xe3;o</LastName><ForeName>Carlos Eduardo</ForeName><Initials>CE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Federal Institute of Education, Science and Technology Paran&#xe1; (IFPR), Paran&#xe1;, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gomes</LastName><ForeName>Raquel Guttierres</ForeName><Initials>RG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Post Graduate Program of Food Engineering, State University of Maringa, Parana, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bergamasco</LastName><ForeName>Rita de C&#xe1;ssia</ForeName><Initials>RC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Post Graduate Program of Food Engineering, State University of Maringa, Parana, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Conselho Nacional de Desenvolvimento Cient&#xed;fico e Tecnol&#xf3;gico</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Sci Food Agric</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0376334</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-5142</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fermented milk</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydration rate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rheological properties</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">solubility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">viscosity</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41735172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jsfa.70536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Campo C, Santos PP, costa TMH, Paese K, Guterres SS, Rios A d O et al., Nanoencapsulation of chia seed oil with chia mucilage (Salvia hispanica L.) as wall material: Characterization and stability evaluation. Food Chem 234:1&#x2013;9 (2017). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodchem.2017.04.153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur S and Bains K, Chia (Salvia hispanica L.) &#x2013; a rediscovered ancient grain, from Aztecs to food laboratories. Nutr Food Sci 50:463&#x2013;479 (2019). https://doi.org/10.1108/NFS-06-2019-0181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coelho MS and Salas&#x2010;Mellado M d LMR, Composi&#xe7;&#xe3;o qu&#xed;mica, propriedades funcionais e aplica&#xe7;&#xf5;es tecnol&#xf3;gicas da semente de chia (Salvia hispanica L) em alimentos. Braz J Food Technol 17:259&#x2013;268 (2014). https://doi.org/10.1590/1981-6723.1814.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orifici SC, Capitani MI, Tom&#xe1;s MC and Nolasco SM, Optimization of mucilage extraction from chia seeds (Salvia hispanica L.) using response surface methodology. J Sci Food Agric 98:4495&#x2013;4500 (2018). https://doi.org/10.1002/jsfa.8974.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes SS and Salas&#x2010;Mellado M d l M, Addition of chia seed mucilage for reduction of fat content in bread and cakes. Food Chem 227:237&#x2013;244 (2017). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodchem.2017.01.075.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darwish AMG, Khalifa RE and el Sohaimy SA, Functional Properties of Chia Seed Mucilage Supplemented In Low Fat Yoghurt. Alex Sci Exch J 39:450&#x2013;459 (2018). https://doi.org/10.21608/asejaiqjsae.2018.13882.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribes S, Pe&#xf1;a N, Fuentes A, Talens P and Barat JM, Chia (Salvia hispanica L.) seed mucilage as a fat replacer in yogurts: effect on their nutritional, technological, and sensory properties. J Dairy Sci 104:2822&#x2013;2833 (2021). https://doi.org/10.3168/jds.2020-19240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollard MA and Fischer P, Partial aqueous solubility of low&#x2010;galactose&#x2010;content galactomannans&#x2014;what is the quantitative basis? Curr Opin Colloid Interface Sci 11:184&#x2013;190 (2006). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cocis.2005.12.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q, Ellis PR and Ross&#x2010;Murphy SB, Dissolution kinetics of guar gum powders. I. Methods for commercial polydisperse samples. Carbohydr Polym 49:131&#x2013;137 (2002). https://doi.org/10.1016/S0144-8617(01)00327-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jian H&#x2010;L, Lin X&#x2010;J, Zhang W&#x2010;M, Sun D&#x2010;F and Jiang J&#x2010;X, Physico&#x2010;chemical characterization of the temperature dependent hydration kinetics of Gleditsia sinensis gum. Int J Biol Macromol 62:596&#x2013;602 (2013). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2013.09.046.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antigo JLD, Bergamasco R d C and Madrona GS, How drying methods can influence the characteristics of mucilage obtained from chia seed and psyllium husk. Ci&#xea;nc Rural 50:e20190913 (2020). https://doi.org/10.1590/0103-8478cr20190913.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association of Official Agricultural Chemists &#x2010; AOAC, Official Methods of Analysis of the Association of the Agricultural Chemists. AOAC, Gaithersburg (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DuBois M, Gilles KA, Hamilton JK, Rebers PT and Smith F, Colorimetric method for determination of sugars and related substances. Anal Chem 28:350&#x2013;356 (1956).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maldonade IR, De Carvalho PGB and Ferreira NA, Protocolo para determina&#xe7;&#xe3;o de a&#xe7;&#xfa;cares totais em hortali&#xe7;as pelo m&#xe9;todo de DNS. Embrapa Hortali&#xe7;as, Bras&#xed;lia, DF (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seow EK, Muthu V, Che Muhamed AM, Ooi CH, Singh R, Mat Easa A et al., Influence of low&#x2010;level gelling agents on the dissolution and in&#x2010;vitro nutrient release study of coconut water&#x2010;based hydrogel. J Food Sci Technol 59:589&#x2013;596 (2022). https://doi.org/10.1007/s13197-021-05045-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gray VA and Rosanske TW, Dissolution. Specification of Drug Substances and Products. Elsevier, Amsterdam, pp. 481&#x2013;503 (2020). https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-08-102824-7.00018-X.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venugopal KN and Abhilash M, Study of hydration kinetics and rheological behaviour of guar gum. Int J Pharma Sci Res 1:28&#x2013;39 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folch J, Lees M and Sloane Stanley GH, A simple method for the isolation and purification of total lipides from animal tissues. J Biol Chem 226:497&#x2013;509 (1957).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harte F, Luedecke L, Swanson B and Barbosa&#x2010;C&#xe1;novas GV, Low&#x2010;fat set yogurt made from Milk subjected to combinations of high hydrostatic pressure and thermal processing. J Dairy Sci 86:1074&#x2013;1082 (2003). https://doi.org/10.3168/jds.S0022-0302(03)73690-X.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladjevardi ZS, Gharibzahedi SMT and Mousavi M, Development of a stable low&#x2010;fat yogurt gel using functionality of psyllium (Plantago ovata Forsk) husk gum. Carbohydr Polym 125:272&#x2013;280 (2015). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbpol.2015.02.051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathias TR d S, Andrade KCS, Rosa CL d S and Silva BA, Avalia&#xe7;&#xe3;o do comportamento reol&#xf3;gico de diferentes iogurtes comerciais. Braz J Food Technol 16:12&#x2013;20 (2013). https://doi.org/10.1590/S1981-67232013005000004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilmaz&#x2010;Ersan L and Topcuoglu E, Evaluation of instrumental and sensory measurements using multivariate analysis in probiotic yogurt enriched with almond milk. J Food Sci Technol 59:133&#x2013;143 (2022). https://doi.org/10.1007/s13197-021-04994-w.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva BP, Anuncia&#xe7;&#xe3;o PC, da Silva Matyelka JC, Della Lucia CM, Martino HSD and Pinheiro&#x2010;Sant'Ana HM, Chemical composition of Brazilian chia seeds grown in different places. Food Chem 221:1709&#x2013;1716 (2017). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodchem.2016.10.115.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos FSD, Figueir&#xea;do RMFD, de Melo Queiroz AJ, Paiva YF, Ara&#xfa;jo ACD, Lima TLBD et al., Physical, chemical, and thermal properties of chia and okra mucilages. J Therm Anal Calorim 148:7463&#x2013;7475 (2023). https://doi.org/10.1007/s10973-023-12179-0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khursheed T, Fatima T, Qadri T, Rafiq A, Malik A, Naseer B et al., Biochemical, nutraceutical and phytochemical characterization of chia and basil seeds: A comparative study. Int J Food Prop 26:1&#x2013;13 (2023). https://doi.org/10.1080/10942912.2022.2151617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mensah EO, Oludipe EO, Gebremeskal YH, Nadtochii LA and Baranenko D, Evaluation of extraction techniques for chia seed mucilage; A review on the structural composition, physicochemical properties and applications. Food Hydrocoll 153:110051 (2024). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodhyd.2024.110051.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courtin CM, Van den Broeck H and Delcour JA, Determination of reducing end sugar residues in oligo&#x2010;and polysaccharides by gas&#x2013;liquid chromatography. J Chromatogr A 866:97&#x2013;104 (2000). https://doi.org/10.1016/S0021-9673(99)01064-X.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saporittis K, Morales R and Martinez MJ, High pressure homogenization: A promising approach to expand food applications of chia mucilage. Int J Biol Macromol 263:129787 (2024). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2024.129787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parvathy KS, Susheelamma NS and Tharanathan RN, Hydration characteristics of guar gum samples and their fractions. Food Hydrocoll 21:630&#x2013;637 (2007). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodhyd.2006.07.006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellis PR and Morris ER, Importance of the rate of hydration of pharmaceutical preparations of guar gum; a new in vitro monitoring method. Diabet Med 8:378&#x2013;381 (1991). https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1464-5491.1991.tb01613.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sciarini LS, Maldonado F, Ribotta PD, P&#xe9;rez GT and Le&#xf3;n AE, Chemical composition and functional properties of Gleditsia triacanthos gum. Food Hydrocoll 23:306&#x2013;313 (2009). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodhyd.2008.02.011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capitani MI, Nolasco SM and Tom&#xe1;s MC, Effect of mucilage extraction on the functional properties of chia meals. In Food Industry InTech 1:421&#x2013;437 (2013). https://doi.org/10.5772/53171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu&#xf1;oz LA, Vera CN, Z&#xfa;&#xf1;iga&#x2010;L&#xf3;pez MC, Moncada M and Haros CM, Physicochemical and functional properties of soluble fiber extracted from two phenotypes of chia (Salvia hispanica L.) seeds. J Food Compos Anal 104:104138 (2021). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfca.2021.104138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prajapati VD, Jani GK, Moradiya NG, Randeria NP, Nagar BJ, Naikwadi NN et al., Galactomannan: A versatile biodegradable seed polysaccharide. Int J Biol Macromol 60:83&#x2013;92 (2013). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2013.05.017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timilsena YP, Adhikari R, Kasapis S and Adhikari B, Molecular and functional characteristics of purified gum from Australian chia seeds. Carbohydr Polym 136:128&#x2013;136 (2016). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbpol.2015.09.035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu&#xf1;oz LA, Cobos A, Diaz O and Aguilera JM, Chia seeds: microstructure, mucilage extraction and hydration. J Food Eng 108:216&#x2013;224 (2012). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfoodeng.2011.06.037.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh B, Chauhan GS, Kumar S and Chauhan N, Synthesis, characterization and swelling responses of pH sensitive psyllium and polyacrylamide based hydrogels for the use in drug delivery (I). Carbohydr Polym 67:190&#x2013;200 (2007). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbpol.2006.05.006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yekta M and Ansari S, Jujube mucilage as a potential stabilizer in stirred yogurt: improvements in the physiochemical, rheological, and sensorial properties. Food Sci Nutr 7:3709&#x2013;3721 (2019). https://doi.org/10.1002/fsn3.1230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad N, Manzoor MF, Shabbir U, Ahmed S, Ismail T, Saeed F et al., Health lipid indices and physicochemical properties of dual fortified yogurt with extruded flaxseed omega fatty acids and fibers for hypercholesterolemic subjects. Food Sci Nutr 8:273&#x2013;280 (2020). https://doi.org/10.1002/fsn3.1302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baba WN, Jan K, Punoo HA, Wani TA, Dar MM and Masoodi FA, Techno&#x2010;functional properties of yoghurts fortified with walnut and flaxseed oil emulsions in guar gum. LWT 92:242&#x2013;249 (2018). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lwt.2018.02.007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen AT&#x2010;B, Nigen M, Jimenez L, Ait&#x2010;Abderrahim H, Marchesseau S and Picart&#x2010;Palmade L, Performances of different protocols for exocellular polysaccharides extraction from milk acid gels: application to yogurt. Food Chem 239:742&#x2013;750 (2018). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodchem.2017.06.121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xdc;nal B, Metin S and I&#x15f;&#x131;kl&#x131; ND, Use of response surface methodology to describe the combined effect of storage time, locust bean gum and dry matter of milk on the physical properties of low&#x2010;fat set yoghurt. Int Dairy J 13:909&#x2013;916 (2003). https://doi.org/10.1016/S0958-6946(03)00118-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schorsch C, Jones MG and Norton IT, Thermodynamic incompatibility and microstructure of milk protein/locust bean gum/sucrose systems. Food Hydrocoll 13:89&#x2013;99 (1999). https://doi.org/10.1016/S0268-005X(98)00074-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tolstoguzov V, Phase behaviour of macromolecular components in biological and food systems. Food Nahrung 44:299&#x2013;308 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert A, Rioux L&#x2010;E, St&#x2010;Gelais D and Turgeon SL, Studying stirred yogurt microstructure using optical microscopy: how smoothing temperature and storage time affect microgel size related to syneresis. J Dairy Sci 103:2139&#x2013;2152 (2020). https://doi.org/10.3168/jds.2019-16787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arab M, Yousefi M, Khanniri E, Azari M, Ghasemzadeh&#x2010;Mohammadi V and Mollakhalili&#x2010;Meybodi N, A comprehensive review on yogurt syneresis: effect of processing conditions and added additives. J Food Sci Technol 60:1656&#x2013;1665 (2023). https://doi.org/10.1007/s13197-022-05403-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daba GM, Elnahas MO and Elkhateeb WA, Contributions of exopolysaccharides from lactic acid bacteria as biotechnological tools in food, pharmaceutical, and medical applications. Int J Biol Macromol 173:79&#x2013;89 (2021). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2021.01.110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abarquero D, Renes E, Fresno JM and Tornadijo ME, Study of exopolysaccharides from lactic acid bacteria and their industrial applications: a review. Int J Food Sci Technol 57:16&#x2013;26 (2022). https://doi.org/10.1111/ijfs.15227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xfc;rb&#xfc;z Z, Erkaya&#x2010;Kotan T and &#x15e;eng&#xfc;l M, Evaluation of physicochemical, microbiological, texture and microstructure characteristics of set&#x2010;style yoghurt supplemented with quince seed mucilage powder as a novel natural stabiliser. Int Dairy J 114:104938 (2021). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.idairyj.2020.104938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias&#x2010;Faceto LS and Conti&#x2010;Silva AC, Texture of extruded breakfast cereals: effects of adding milk on the texture properties and on the correlations between instrumental and sensory analyses. J Texture Stud 53:220&#x2013;231 (2022). https://doi.org/10.1111/jtxs.12666.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>