<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41896994</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-1847</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC sports science, medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acute weight cycling and hydration status in elite kickboxers: a repeated-measures field study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13102-026-01669-x</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ceylan</LastName><ForeName>Bayram</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Coaching Education, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Kastamonu University, Kastamonu, 37150, T&#xfc;rkiye. bceylan@kastamonu.edu.tr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ta&#x15f;k&#x131;n</LastName><ForeName>Hasan Basri</ForeName><Initials>HB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Coaching Education, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Kastamonu University, Kastamonu, 37150, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sar&#x131;kaya</LastName><ForeName>U&#x11f;ur</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport, Mehmet Arabac&#x131; School of Physical Education and Sport, Harran University, &#x15e;anl&#x131;urfa, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pekel</LastName><ForeName>Hac&#x131; Ahmet</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Coaching Education, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Gazi University, Ankara, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sab&#x131;rl&#x131;</LastName><ForeName>T&#xfc;rkan Nihan</ForeName><Initials>TN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Recreation, Faculty of Sport Sciences, Eski&#x15f;ehir Technical University, Eski&#x15f;ehir, T&#xfc;rkiye.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101605016</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2052-1847</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Combat sports</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dehydration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RWG</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rehydration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Weight loss</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical approval was obtained from the Kastamonu University Non-Interventional Clinical Trials Ethical Committee (2025-47) and written informed consent was obtained from each participant before the commencement of the study. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41896994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-026-01669-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13102-026-01669-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Barley OR, Chapman DW, Abbiss CR. The current state of weight-cutting in combat sports. Sports. 2019;7(5):123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallar&#xe9;s J, et al. Muscle contraction velocity, strength and power output changes following different degrees of hypohydration in competitive olympic combat sports. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2016;13(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artioli G, et al. Prevalence, magnitude, and methods of rapid weight loss among judo competitors. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42(3):436&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brito CJ, et al. Methods of body-mass reduction by combat sport athletes. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2012;22(2):89&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reale R, Slater G, Burke LM. Weight management practices of Australian Olympic combat sport athletes. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018;13(4):459&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceylan B, Barley OR, Balci SS. Changes in body mass and hydration status in judo athletes before and after a top-level competition: a descriptive case study. Physician Sportsmed. 2023;51(3):228&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kons RL, et al. Methods and magnitudes of rapid weight loss in judo athletes over pre-competition periods. Hum Mov. 2017;18(2):49&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bialowas D, et al. Examining the effects of pre-competition rapid weight loss on hydration status and competition performance in elite judo athletes. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):14756.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceylan B, Balci SS. Dehydration and Rapid Weight Gain Between Weigh-in and Competition in Judo Athletes: The Differences between Women and Men. Res Sports Med, 2023;31(4):462&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceylan B, Baydil B, Aydos L. Weigh-in time affects hydration status and acute weight gain in combat sports: A comparison of judo and wrestling. Revista de Artes Marciales Asi&#xe1;ticas, 2021;16(2):80&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janiszewska K, Przyby&#x142;owicz KE. Pre-competition weight loss models in taekwondo: identification, characteristics and risk of dehydration. Nutrients. 2020;12(9):2793.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jetton AM, et al. Dehydration and acute weight gain in mixed martial arts fighters before competition. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2013;27(5):1322&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Alonso J, et al. Dehydration markedly impairs cardiovascular function in hyperthermic endurance athletes during exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1997;82(4):1229&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheuvront SN, Kenefick RW. Dehydration: Physiology, Assessment, and Performance Effects, in Comprehensive Physiology. 2014;4(1):257&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones LC, et al. Active Dehydration Impairs Upper and Lower Body Anaerobic Muscular Power. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2008;22(2):455&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong LE, Costill DL, Fink WJ. Influence of diuretic-induced dehydration on competitive running performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1985;17(4):456&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cian C, et al. Effects of fluid ingestion on cognitive function after heat stress or exercise-induced dehydration. Int J Psychophysiol. 2001;42(3):243&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirreffs SM, et al. The effects of fluid restriction on hydration status and subjective feelings in man. Br J Nutr. 2004;91(6):951&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dube A, Gouws C, Breukelman G. Effects of hypohydration and fluid balance in athletes&#x2019; cognitive performance: a systematic review. Afr Health Sci. 2022;22(1):367&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zbal AF, Ektirici A, Ceylan B. Weight loss magnitude, prevalence and methods among male and female Olympic-level judo athletes. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabilitation. 2025;17(1):385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews JJ, et al. The magnitude of rapid weight loss and rapid weight gain in combat sport athletes preparing for competition: A systematic review. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2019;29(4):441&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slimani M, et al. Kickboxing review: anthropometric, psychophysiological and activity profiles and injury epidemiology. Biology Sport. 2017;34(2):185&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kordi R, et al. Combat Sports Medicine. Springer Science &amp; Business Media; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Aranda LM, et al. Effects of Different Rapid Weight Loss Strategies and Percentages on Performance-Related Parameters in Combat Sports: An Updated Systematic Review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20(6):5158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barley OR, et al. Acute Dehydration Impairs Endurance Without Modulating Neuromuscular Function. Frontiers in Physiology; 2018;9&#x2013;1562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reale R, Slater G, Burke LM. Acute-Weight-Loss Strategies for Combat Sports and Applications to Olympic Success. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2017;12(2):142&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franchini E, Brito CJ, Artioli GG. Weight loss in combat sports: physiological, psychological and performance effects. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2012;9(1):1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceylan B, et al. Monitoring Hydration Status of Elite Judo Athletes During a Competition Day. Turkish J Sport Exerc. 2020;22(1):150&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pettersson S, Berg CM. Hydration status in elite wrestlers, judokas, boxers, and taekwondo athletes on competition day. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2014;24(3):267&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berkovich B-E, et al. Rapid weight loss in competitive judo and taekwondo athletes: attitudes and practices of coaches and trainers. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2019;29(5):532&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barley OR, Chapman DW, Abbiss CR. Weight loss strategies in combat sports and concerning habits in mixed martial arts. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018;13(7):933&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott JR, Horswill CA, Dick RW. Acute weight gain in collegiate wrestlers following a tournament weigh-in. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1994;26(9):1181&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arif M, et al. Correlation of Percentage Body Fat, Waist Circumference and Waist-to-Hip Ratio with Abdominal Muscle Strength. Healthcare. 2022;10(12):2467.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swartz AM, et al. Evaluation of a foot-to-foot bioelectrical impedance analyser in highly active, moderately active and less active young men. Br J Nutr. 2002;88(2):205&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brewer GJ, et al. Appendicular Body Composition Analysis: Validity of Bioelectrical Impedance Analysis Compared With Dual-Energy X-Ray Absorptiometry in Division I College Athletes. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2019;33(11):2920&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasold KL, et al. Reliability and Validity of Commercially Available Low-Cost Bioelectrical Impedance Analysis. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2019;29(4):406&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kostelnik SB, et al. The validity of urine color as a hydration biomarker within the general adult population and athletes: A systematic review. J Am Coll Nutr. 2021;40(2):172&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casa DJ, Clarkson PM, Roberts WO. American College of Sports Medicine roundtable on hydration and physical activity: consensus statements. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2005;4(3):115&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. The effect size. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences, 1988: 77&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dugonji&#x107; B, Krstulovi&#x107; S, Kuva&#x10d;i&#x107; G. Rapid Weight Loss Practices in Elite Kickboxers. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2019;29(6):583&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong Y, et al. The Practice of Weight Loss in Combat Sports Athletes: A Systematic Review. Nutrients. 2024;16(7):1050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artioli GG, et al. It is Time to Ban Rapid Weight Loss from Combat Sports. Sports Med. 2016;46(11):1579&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall CJ, Lane AM. Effects of rapid weight loss on mood and performance among amateur boxers. Br J Sports Med. 2001;35(6):390&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakicevic N, et al. Weight cycling in combat sports: revisiting 25 years of scientific evidence. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabilitation. 2021;13(1):154.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews JJ, Nicholas C. Extreme rapid weight loss and rapid weight gain observed in UK mixed martial arts athletes preparing for competition. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2017;27(2):122&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reale R, et al. Regain in body mass after weigh-in is linked to success in real life judo competition. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2016;26(6):525&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viveiros L, et al. Pattern of Weight Loss of Young Female and Male Wrestlers. J Strength Conditioning Res. 2015;29(11):3149&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazemi M, Rahman A, De Ciantis M. Weight cycling in adolescent Taekwondo athletes. J Can Chiropr Assoc. 2011;55(4):318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;&#xf6;pik V, et al. Hydration status of Greco-Roman wrestlers in an authentic precompetition situation. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2013;38(6):621&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cannataro R, et al. Acute Effects of Supervised Making Weight on Health Markers, Hormones and Body Composition in Muay Thai Fighters. Sports. 2020;8(10):137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;tangar M, et al. Rapid weight loss among elite-level judo athletes: methods and nutrition in relation to competition performance. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2022;19(1):380&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-El&#xed;as VE, et al. Validity of Hydration Non-Invasive Indices during the Weightcutting and Official Weigh-In for Olympic Combat Sports. PLoS ONE. 2014;9(4):e95336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bueno JCA, et al. Effects and symptoms of dehydration in Brazilian jiu-jitsu athletes. Revista de Artes Marciales Asi&#xe1;ticas, 2023;18(1):1&#x2013;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDermott BP, et al. National athletic trainers&#x2019; association position statement: fluid replacement for the physically active. J Athl Train. 2017;52(9):877&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenefick RW, Cheuvront SN. Physiological adjustments to hypohydration: Impact on thermoregulation. Auton Neurosci. 2016;196:47&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira AAJ, et al. Acute Kidney Injury Associated With Dehydration Protocol Used by Combat Sports Athletes. Translational Sports Med. 2026;2026(1):2946676.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coris EE, Ramirez AM, Van Durme DJ. Heat Illness in Athletes. Sports Med. 2004;34(1):9&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>