<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40065748</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1613-6829</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>17</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Small (Weinheim an der Bergstrasse, Germany)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Small</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nanofibrous Chitin Clusters Constructed via Controllable Crystalline Structure Transition for 3D Functional Materials.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2501328</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2501328</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/smll.202501328</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Intensively studied polymeric particle production technologies often rely on the combination of polymer self-assembly and particle processing techniques. Herein, an elegant crystallization transition-mediated strategy is proposed to confine molecular self-assembly within a limited range, avoiding the need for extra particle processing steps. This approach enables the production of the regenerated nanofibrous chitin clusters woven with the helical nanofibers. By dissolving the &#x3b2;-chitin in an aqueous NaOH solution and adjusting the degree of deacetylation (DD value) to 28.0-41.4%, the chitin chains self-assembly pathway is facilitated to undergo a crystalline transition from &#x3b1;-chitin to hydrated chitosan. This transition diminishes the chitin chains self-assembly tendency and confines the self-assembly to the submicro- and micrometer scales. The morphological parameters of these chitin clusters, including cluster size, nanofiber tentacle density, diameter, and helical pitch, can be tuned by adjusting the DD value. These nanofibrous chitin clusters are successfully employed as building blocks to create 3D structural materials for thermal insulation and functional food applications, demonstrating their potential in constructing advanced materials. It is anticipated that the crystalline structure transition-mediated concept can be applied to other polymeric particle fabrication, opening up a new avenue for designing advanced particles for various applications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Wiley&#x2010;VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Yuxin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry and Molecular Sciences, Hubei Engineering Center of Natural Polymer-based Medical Materials, and Key Laboratory of Biomedical Polymers of Ministry of Education, Wuhan University, Wuhan, 430072, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiang</LastName><ForeName>Jiechun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Institute of NMR and Molecular Sciences, School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Hubei Province for Coal Conversion and New Carbon Materials, Wuhan University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, 430081, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Xueqing</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry and Molecular Sciences, Hubei Engineering Center of Natural Polymer-based Medical Materials, and Key Laboratory of Biomedical Polymers of Ministry of Education, Wuhan University, Wuhan, 430072, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Longting</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Institute of NMR and Molecular Sciences, School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Hubei Province for Coal Conversion and New Carbon Materials, Wuhan University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, 430081, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>Chunyu</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Chemistry and Molecular Sciences, Hubei Engineering Center of Natural Polymer-based Medical Materials, and Key Laboratory of Biomedical Polymers of Ministry of Education, Wuhan University, Wuhan, 430072, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duan</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0782-9925</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Institute of NMR and Molecular Sciences, School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Hubei Province for Coal Conversion and New Carbon Materials, Wuhan University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, 430081, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>22075214</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Small</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101235338</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1613-6810</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chitin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">crystalline structure transition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nanofibrous clusters</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">regeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self&#x2010;assembly</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40065748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202501328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>R. C. Mundargi, S. Srirangarajan, S. A. Agnihotri, S. A. Patil, S. Ravindra, S. B. Setty, T. M. Aminabhavi, J. Controlled Release 2007, 119, 59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Gao, J. M. Karp, R. Langer, N. Joshi, Chem. Mater. 2023, 35, 359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. H. P. Yiu, H. j. Niu, E. Biermans, G. van Tendeloo, M. J. Rosseinsky, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2010, 20, 1599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Akbarian, S. Mahjoub, S. M. Elahi, E. Zabihi, H. Tashakkorian, Colloids Surf. B 2020, 186, 110686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Guo, A. M. Sofias, T. Lammers, J. Xu, Adv. Drug Delivery Rev. 2024, 206, 115188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Tan, R. Zhang, W. Kong, F. Qu, L. Lu, ACS Appl. Bio Mater. 2018, 1, 777.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. I. Osman, Y. Zhang, M. Farghali, A. K. Rashwan, A. S. Eltaweil, E. M. Abd El&#x2010;Monaem, I. M. A. Mohamed, M. M. Badr, I. Ihara, D. W. Rooney, P.&#x2010;S. Yap, Environ. Chem. Lett. 2024, 22, 841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Guzey, D. J. McClements, Adv. Colloid Interface Sci. 2006, 128&#x2013;130, 227.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Li, W. Huang, M. Zhang, Y. Huo, F. Li, L. Song, S. Wu, Q. Yang, X. Li, J. Zhang, L. Yang, J. Hao, L. Kang, J. Nanobiotechnol. 2024, 22, 134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Pulingam, P. Foroozandeh, J.&#x2010;A. Chuah, K. Sudesh, Nanomaterials 2022, 12, 576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. R. Gasilova, G. P. Aleksandrova, I. V. Tyshkunova, Carbohydr. Polym. 2022, 291, 119521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Lepeltier, C. Bourgaux, P. Couvreur, Adv. Drug Delivery Rev. 2014, 71, 86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. S. Saad, R. K. Prud'homme, Nano Today 2016, 11, 212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Malamatari, A. Charisi, S. Malamataris, K. Kachrimanis, I. Nikolakakis, Processes 2020, 8, 788.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Wintzheimer, L. Luthardt, K. L. A. Cao, I. Imaz, D. Maspoch, T. Ogi, A. B&#xfc;ck, D. P. Debecker, M. Faustini, K. Mandel, Adv. Mater. 2023, 35, 2306648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. A. Beach, U. Nayanathara, Y. Gao, C. Zhang, Y. Xiong, Y. Wang, G. K. Such, Chem. Rev. 2024, 124, 5505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Phan, V. Taresco, J. Penelle, B. Couturaud, Biomater. Sci. 2021, 9, 38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Liu, G. Yang, D. Zou, Y. Hui, K. Nigam, A. P. J. Middelberg, C.&#x2010;X. Zhao, Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2019, 59, 4134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. P. Rao, K. E. Geckeler, Prog. Polym. Sci. 2011, 36, 887.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Kolakovic, T. Laaksonen, L. Peltonen, A. Laukkanen, J. Hirvonen, Int. J. Pharm. 2012, 430, 47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. M. Subillaga, S. Heinert, J. Weissbrodt, M. Dragosavac, Food Hydrocolloids 2024, 153, 109953.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Yang, S. Han, H. Zheng, H. Dong, J. Liu, Carbohydr. Polym. 2015, 123, 53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Tao, Y. Zhang, Z. Wu, X. Liao, S. Nie, Carbohydr. Polym. 2019, 214, 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Kugo, S. Nomura, T. Isono, S.&#x2010;i. Sato, M. Fujiwara, T. Satoh, H. Tani, T. Erata, K. Tajima, Carbohydr. Polym. 2024, 332, 121907.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Dinand, M. Vignon, H. Chanzy, L. Heux, Cellulose 2002, 9, 7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Bai, L. Liu, M. Esquivel, B. L. Tardy, S. Huan, X. Niu, S. Liu, G. Yang, Y. Fan, O. J. Rojas, Chem. Rev. 2022, 122, 11604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Focher, P. L. Beltrame, G. T. A. Naggi, Carbohydr. Polym. 1990, 12, 405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Yanat, K. Schro&#xeb;n, Carbohydr. Polym. 2023, 312, 120789.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Jin, T. Liu, E. Lam, A. Moores, Nanoscale Horiz. 2021, 6, 505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Duan, Y. Huang, A. Lu, L. Zhang, Prog. Polym. Sci. 2018, 82, 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Lin, X. Xing, S. Li, X. Wu, Q. Jia, H. Tu, H. Bian, A. Lu, L. Zhang, H. Yang, B. Duan, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2022, 32, 2112685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Liao, Y. Zhou, X. Zhao, B. Hou, J. Zhang, H. Huang, Carbohydr. Polym. 2024, 329, 121773.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. L. Hecht, T. Merkel, A. Schoth, C. Wagner, K. K&#xf6;hler, R. Mu&#xf1;oz&#x2010;Esp&#xed;, K. Landfester, H. P. Schuchmann, Chem. Eng. J. 2013, 229, 206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Duan, X. Zheng, Z. Xia, X. Fan, L. Guo, J. Liu, Y. Wang, Q. Ye, L. Zhang, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2015, 54, 5152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Ogawa, T. Yui, M. Miya, Biosci., Biotechnol., Biochem. 2014, 56, 858.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Cartier, A. Domard, H. Chanzy, Int. J. Biol. Macromol. 1990, 12, 289.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Fittolani, D. Vargova, P. H. Seeberger, Y. Ogawa, M. Delbianco, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2022, 144, 12469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Morozova, P. W. Schmidt, F. S. Bates, T. P. Lodge, Macromolecules 2018, 51, 9413.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Liu, B. Pang, R. Garces, R. Dervisoglu, L. Chen, L. Andreas, K. Zhang, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2018, 57, 16323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Lin, L. Zhang, B. Duan, Mater. Horiz. 2021, 8, 2503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Cai, L. Huang, S. Lv, X. Jiang, Carbohydr. Polym. 2024, 331, 121879.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Liu, Q. Yang, L. Zhang, R. Zhuo, X. Jiang, Carbohydr. Polym. 2016, 137, 600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Zhou, S. Lv, J. Liu, Y. Tan, J. L. Muriel Mundo, L. Bai, O. J. Rojas, D. J. McClements, J. Agric. Food Chem. 2019, 68, 603.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. A. Torlopov, I. N. Vaseneva, V. I. Mikhaylov, I. S. Martakov, P. V. Legki, N. M. Paderin, P. A. Sitnikov, Carbohydr. Polym. 2022, 284, 119162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Hou, G. Tan, A. Wei, S. Gao, H. Zhang, W. Zhang, Y. Liu, R. Zhao, Y. Ma, Food Chem. 2024, 447, 139028.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. V. Tzoumaki, T. Moschakis, E. Scholten, C. G. Biliaderis, Food Funct. 2013, 4, 121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Xiao, C. Chen, B. Wang, Z. Mao, H. Xu, Y. Zhong, L. Zhang, X. Sui, S. Qu, J. Agric. Food Chem. 2018, 66, 12344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhu, S. Huan, L. Bai, A. Ketola, X. Shi, X. Zhang, J. A. Ketoja, O. J. Rojas, ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2020, 12, 11240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Huang, J. Yang, L. Chen, L. Zhang, ACS Sustainable Chem. Eng. 2018, 6, 10552.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>