<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39410369</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>19</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Study of the Influence of Thermoactivated Natural Zeolite on the Hydration of White Cement Mortars.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4798</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma17194798</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>One trend in the development of building materials is the partial or complete replacement of traditional materials that have a high carbon footprint with eco-friendly ecological raw materials and ingredients. In the present work, the influence of replacing cement with 10 wt% thermally activated natural zeolite on the structural and physical-mechanical characteristics of cured mortars based on white Portland cement and river sand was investigated. The phase compositions were determined by wavelength dispersive X-ray fluorescence (WD-XRF) analysis, X-ray powder diffraction (PXRD), diffuse reflectance infrared Fourier transformed spectroscopy (DRIFTS), and scanning electron microscopy (SEM), as well as thermogravimetric analysis simultaneously with differential scanning calorimetry (TG/DTG-DSC). The results show that the incorporation of zeolite increases the amount of pores accessible with mercury intrusion porosimetry by about 40%, but the measured strengths are also higher by over 13%. When these samples were aged in an aqueous environment from day 28 to day 120, the amount of pores decreased by about 10% and the compressive strength increased by nearly 15%, respectively. The microstructural analysis carried out proves that these results are due to hydration with a low content of crystal water and the realization of pozzolanic reactions that last over time. Replacing some of the white cement with thermally activated natural zeolite results in the formation of a greater variety of crystals, including new crystalline CSH and CSAH phases that allow better intergrowth and interlocking. The results of the investigations allow us to present a plausible reaction mechanism of pozzolanic reactions and of the formation of new crystal hydrate phases. This gives grounds to claim that the replacement of part of the cement with zeolite improves the corrosion resistance of the investigated building solutions against aggressive weathering.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stoyanov</LastName><ForeName>Ventseslav</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5788-8141</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Technology and Construction Management, Faculty of Construction, University of Structural Engineering and Architecture "Lyuben Karavelov", 175 Suhodolska Str., 1373 Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Safety Management and Prevention, Faculty of Fire Safety and Civil Protection, Academy of Ministry of Interior, 171 Pirotska Str., 1309 Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Petkova</LastName><ForeName>Vilma</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5280-9280</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Mineralogy and Crystallography "Acad. Ivan Kostov", Bulgarian Academy of Sciences, Acad. G. Bonchev Str., Block 107, 1113 Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mihaylova</LastName><ForeName>Katerina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-3661-691X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Mineralogy and Crystallography "Acad. Ivan Kostov", Bulgarian Academy of Sciences, Acad. G. Bonchev Str., Block 107, 1113 Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shopska</LastName><ForeName>Maya</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9714-2464</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Catalysis, Bulgarian Academy of Sciences, Acad. G. Bonchev Str., Bldg. 11, 1113 Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>BG05M2OP001-1.001-0008</GrantID><Agency>Operational Program "Science and Education for Intelligent Growth", co-financed by the European Union through the European Structural and Investment Funds</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CSH and CSAH phases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cement hydration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cement mortars</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pozzolanic activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">river sand</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">zeolite</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39410369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11478233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17194798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma17194798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chuan L.F. Innovative Cement Additives Quality Improvers in Sustainable Cement and Concrete. Sains Malays. 2015;44:1599&#x2013;1607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbhuiya S., Kanavaris F., Das B.B., Idrees M. Decarbonising Cement and Concrete Production: Strategies, Challenges and Pathways for Sustainable Development. J. Build. Eng. 2024;86:108861. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.108861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.108861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dembovska L., Bajare D., Pundiene I., Vitola L. Effect of Pozzolanic Additives on the Strength Development of High Performance Concrete. Procedia Eng. 2017;172:202&#x2013;210. doi: 10.1016/j.proeng.2017.02.050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.proeng.2017.02.050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Business Council for Sustainable Development . Cement Technology Roadmap 2009: Carbon Emissions Reductions up to 2050. World Business Council for Sustainable Development; Geneva, Switzerland: International Energy Agency; Paris, France: 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juenger M.C.G., Snellings R., Bernal S.A. Supplementary Cementitious Materials: New Sources, Characterization, and Performance Insights. Cem. Concr. Res. 2019;122:257&#x2013;273. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.05.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.05.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapeluszna E., Szudek W., Wolka P., Zieli&#x144;ski A. Implementation of Alternative Mineral Additives in Low-Emission Sustainable Cement Composites. Materials. 2021;14:6423. doi: 10.3390/ma14216423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma14216423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8585175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34771947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadi B., Shekarchi M. Use of Natural Zeolite as a Supplementary Cementitious Material. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2010;32:134&#x2013;141. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2009.10.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2009.10.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snellings R., Suraneni P., Skibsted J. Future and Emerging Supplementary Cementitious Materials. Cem. Concr. Res. 2023;171:107199. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2023.107199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2023.107199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexa-Stratulat S.-M., Olteanu I., Toma A.-M., Pastia C., Banu O.-M., Corbu O.-C., Toma I.-O. The Use of Natural Zeolites in Cement-Based Construction Materials&#x2014;A State of the Art Review. Coatings. 2023;14:18. doi: 10.3390/coatings14010018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/coatings14010018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perraki T., Kontori E., Tsivilis S., Kakali G. The Effect of Zeolite on the Properties and Hydration of Blended Cements. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2010;32:128&#x2013;133. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2009.10.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2009.10.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perraki T., Kakali G., Kontori E. Characterization and Pozzolanic Activity of Thermally Treated Zeolite. J. Therm. Anal. Calorim. 2005;82:109&#x2013;113. doi: 10.1007/s10973-005-0849-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10973-005-0849-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perraki T., Kakali G., Kontoleon F. The Effect of Natural Zeolites on the Early Hydration of Portland Cement. Microporous Mesoporous Mater. 2003;61:205&#x2013;212. doi: 10.1016/S1387-1811(03)00369-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1387-1811(03)00369-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shekarchi M., Ahmadi B., Azarhomayun F., Shafei B., Kioumarsi M. Natural Zeolite as a Supplementary Cementitious Material&#x2014;A Holistic Review of Main Properties and Applications. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;409:133766. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133766.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Test Methods for Sampling and Testing Fly Ash or Natural Pozzolans for Use in Portland-Cement Concrete. ASTM; West Conshohocken, PA, USA: 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massazza F. Pozzolana and Pozzolanic Cements. Lea&#x2019;s Chem. Cem. Concr. 1998;4:471&#x2013;631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opoczky L., Tamas F.D. Multicomponent Composite Cements. In: Ghosh S.N., editor. Advances in Cement Technology: Chemistry, Manufacture and Testing. CRC Press; New Delhi, India: 2002. pp. 559&#x2013;594.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Specification for Coal Fly Ash and Raw or Calcined Natural Pozzolan for Use in Concrete. ASTM; West Conshohocken, PA, USA: 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janotka I., Kraj&#x10d;i L., Dziv&#xe1;k M. Properties and Utilization of Zeolite-Blended Portland Cements. Clays Clay Min. 2003;51:616&#x2013;624. doi: 10.1346/CCMN.2003.0510606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1346/CCMN.2003.0510606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okamura H., Ouchi M. Self-Compacting Concrete. J. Adv. Concr. Technol. 2003;1:5&#x2013;15. doi: 10.3151/jact.1.5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3151/jact.1.5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skarendahl &#xc5;., Billberg P. Report 35: Casting of Self Compacting Concrete-Final Report of RILEM TC 188-CSC. Volume 35. RILEM Publications; Paris, France: 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Concrete S.-C. The European Guidelines for Self-Compacting Concrete. BIBM. 2005;22:563.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petkova V., Stoyanov V., Kostova B., Mihaylova K. Effects of zeolite incorporation and inert fillers on the curing of cement mortars. JCTM. 2024;59:313&#x2013;322. doi: 10.59957/jctm.v59.i2.2024.9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.59957/jctm.v59.i2.2024.9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petkova V., Stoyanov V., Mihaylova K., Kostova B. Impact of Pozzolanic and Inert Powders on the Microstructure and Thermal Chemistry of Cement Mortars. Ceram. Int. 2024 doi: 10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.06.018. in press .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.06.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petkova V., Stoyanov V., Pelovski Y. TG&#x2013;DTG&#x2013;DTA in Studying White Self-Compacting Cement Mortars. J. Therm. Anal. Calorim. 2012;109:797&#x2013;806. doi: 10.1007/s10973-012-2447-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10973-012-2447-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoyanov V., Kostova B., Petkova V., Pelovski Y. Structure of White Cement Mortars with High Content of Marble Powder. J. Therm. Anal. Calorim. 2012;110:405&#x2013;412. doi: 10.1007/s10973-012-2433-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10973-012-2433-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petkova V., Stoyanov V., Kostova B., Kostov-Kytin V., Kalinkin A., Zvereva I., Tzvetanova Y. Crystal-Chemical and Thermal Properties of Decorative Cement Composites. Materials. 2021;14:4793. doi: 10.3390/ma14174793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma14174793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8432547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34500884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggregates for Concrete. Bulgarian Institute for Standardization; Sofia, Bulgaria: 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grifasi N., Ziantoni B., Fino D., Piumetti M. Fundamental Properties and Sustainable Applications of the Natural Zeolite Clinoptilolite. Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res. 2024:1&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1007/s11356-024-33656-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-024-33656-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12696048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38780851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Methods of Testing Cement&#x2014;Part 1: Determination of Strength. Bulgarian Institute for Standardization; Sofia, Bulgaria: 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Methods of Test for Mortar for Masonry&#x2014;Part 3: Determination of Consistence of Fresh Mortar (by Flow Table) Bulgarian Institute for Standardization; Sofia, Bulgaria: 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gates-Rector S., Blanton T. The Powder Diffraction File: A Quality Materials Characterization Database. Powder Diffr. 2019;34:352&#x2013;360. doi: 10.1017/S0885715619000812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0885715619000812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muliawan A., Sali M., Mustakyudin, Lutfi M. XRD and XRF Characterization of White Sand from Sambera Village, East Kalimantan, Indonesia. J. Phys. Conf. Ser. 2019;1242:012029. doi: 10.1088/1742-6596/1242/1/012029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1742-6596/1242/1/012029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafi A.S.M.M., Tasnim U.F., Rahman M.S. Quantification and Qualification of Silica Sand Extracted from Padma River Sand. IOP Conf. Ser. Mater. Sci. Eng. 2018;438:012037. doi: 10.1088/1757-899X/438/1/012037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1757-899X/438/1/012037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burris L.E., Juenger M.C.G. The Effect of Acid Treatment on the Reactivity of Natural Zeolites Used as Supplementary Cementitious Materials. Cem. Concr. Res. 2016;79:185&#x2013;193. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2015.08.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2015.08.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Guo R., Pan T., Fu C., Lin R., Ma Q. Particle Size Effect of Pre-Wet Zeolites on Autogenous Shrinkage and Mechanical Properties of LECC. Dev. Built Environ. 2023;16:100290. doi: 10.1016/j.dibe.2023.100290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dibe.2023.100290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuinukuafe A.A., Mills M.M., Walder B.J., Fritzsching K.J., Jov&#xe9;-Col&#xf3;n C.F., Bullard J.W., Lapeyre J., McEnroe T., Matteo E.N., Rimsza J.M. Natural Carbonation of Portland Cement with Synthetic Zeolite Y as a Supplementary Cementitious Material. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;425:136068. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu D., Wen A., Mu D., Tang A., Jiang L., Yang W. Investigation into Compressive Property, Chloride Ion Permeability, and Pore Fractal Characteristics of the Cement Mortar Incorporated with Zeolite Powder. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;411:134522. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehwailat K.I.A., Ismail M.A.M., Ezreig A.M.A. Ettringite Formation and Stabilization Methods of Sulfate-Bearing Soil: A State-of-the-Art Review. Indian Geotech. J. 2022;52:927&#x2013;941. doi: 10.1007/s40098-022-00619-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40098-022-00619-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pizo&#x144; J., &#x141;a&#x17a;niewska-Piekarczyk B. Microstructure of CEM II/B-S Pastes Modified with Set Accelerating Admixtures. Materials. 2021;14:6300. doi: 10.3390/ma14216300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma14216300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8585294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34771826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiner J., Goetz-Neunhoeffer F., Neubauer J., Volkmann S., Bergold S., Webler R., Jansen D. Advanced Rietveld Refinement and SEM Analysis of Tobermorite in Chemically Diverse Autoclaved Aerated Concrete. Powder Diffr. 2019;34:143&#x2013;150. doi: 10.1017/S0885715619000149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0885715619000149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larkin P. Infrared and Raman Spectroscopy. Elsevier; Amsterdam, The Netherlands: 2011. Instrumentation and Sampling Methods; pp. 27&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khoshhesab Z.M. Reflectance IR Spectroscopy. Infrared Spectrosc. Mater. Sci. Eng. Technol. 2012;11:233&#x2013;244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kr&#xf3;l M., Minkiewicz J., Mozgawa W. IR Spectroscopy Studies of Zeolites in Geopolymeric Materials Derived from Kaolinite. J. Mol. Struct. 2016;1126:200&#x2013;206. doi: 10.1016/j.molstruc.2016.02.027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molstruc.2016.02.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes T.L., Methven C.M., Jones T.G.J., Pelham S.E., Fletcher P., Hall C. Determining Cement Composition by Fourier Transform Infrared Spectroscopy. Adv. Cem. Based Mater. 1995;2:91&#x2013;104. doi: 10.1016/1065-7355(94)00031-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/1065-7355(94)00031-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chukanov N.V., Vigasina M.F. Vibrational (Infrared and Raman) Spectra of Minerals and Related Compounds. Springer International Publishing; Cham, Switzerland: 2020. Springer Mineralogy.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chukanov N.V., Aksenov S.M., Pekov I.V. Infrared Spectroscopy as a Tool for the Analysis of Framework Topology and Extra-Framework Components in Microporous Cancrinite- and Sodalite-Related Aluminosilicates. Spectrochim. Acta Part A Mol. Biomol. Spectrosc. 2023;287:121993. doi: 10.1016/j.saa.2022.121993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.saa.2022.121993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36327807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanienda K.J. Carbonate Phases Rich in Magnesium in the Triassic Limestones of the Eastern Part of the Germanic Basin. Carbonates Evaporites. 2016;31:387&#x2013;405. doi: 10.1007/s13146-016-0297-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13146-016-0297-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theodosoglou E., Koroneos A., Soldatos T., Zorba T., Paraskevopoulos K.M. Comparative fourier transform infrared and x-ray powder diffraction analysis of naturally occurred k-feldspars. Geosociety. 2017;43:2752. doi: 10.12681/bgsg.11681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12681/bgsg.11681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chukanov N.V., Chervonnyi A.D. Infrared Spectroscopy of Minerals and Related Compounds. Springer International Publishing; Cham, Switzerland: 2016. Springer Mineralogy.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belskaya O.B., Danilova I.G., Kazakov M.O., Mironenko R.M., Lavrenov A.V., Likholobov V.A. Infrared Spectroscopy-Materials Science, Engineering and Technology. IntechOpen; London, UK: 2012. FTIR Spectroscopy of Adsorbed Probe Molecules for Analyzing the Surface Properties of Supported Pt (Pd) Catalysts; pp. 149&#x2013;178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma R., Pei J., Miah M.J., Jang J.G. Effect of Sillimanite Sand on the Mechanical Property and Thermal Resistance of Alkali-Activated Slag Mortar. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;370:130654. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.130654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.130654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yal&#xe7;&#x131;nkaya &#xc7;., &#xc7;opuro&#x11f;lu O. Hydration Heat, Strength and Microstructure Characteristics of UHPC Containing Blast Furnace Slag. J. Build. Eng. 2021;34:101915. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2020.101915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Famy C., Brough A.R., Taylor H.F.W. The C-S-H Gel of Portland Cement Mortars: Part I. The Interpretation of Energy-Dispersive X-ray Microanalyses from Scanning Electron Microscopy, with Some Observations on C-S-H, AFm and AFt Phase Compositions. Cem. Concr. Res. 2003;33:1389&#x2013;1398. doi: 10.1016/S0008-8846(03)00064-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0008-8846(03)00064-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>