<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41382199</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2229-5178</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Indian dermatology online journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Indian Dermatol Online J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Relationship Between Activity Level and Skin Moisturizing Function in Older Adults: A Cross-Sectional Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>63</StartPage><EndPage>66</EndPage><MedlinePgn>63-66</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/idoj.idoj_983_24</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Age-related decline in skin moisture affects many older adults and is exacerbated by factors such as sun exposure and lifestyle habits. Recent research has explored the potential of exercise to improve skin moisture; however, the optimal activity levels remain unclear. This study investigated the link between exercise habits and skin moisture to inform clinical preventive strategies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENTS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this cross-sectional study, we investigated the relationship between stratum corneum (SC) hydration and lifestyle habits in older adults using the International Physical Activity Questionnaire (IPAQ) short version and a self-administered questionnaire. Participants were recruited from community spaces and local elderly facilities. Data were collected between September 1 and December 31, 2023. Based on the IPAQ responses, physical activity levels were classified as low, moderate, or high, and SC hydration was measured on the right forearm. Statistical analyses were conducted using t-tests.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 124 participants were included, with a mean age of 84.3 &#xb1; 9.2 years. Among them, 69.4% were female. The participants were belonged to low (57) and moderate/high (67) activity-level groups, with significant differences in SC hydration ( P = 0.001) between the groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LIMITATIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Cross-sectional design, restricted sample, and potential unmeasured confounding may limit interpretation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results suggested a significant difference in horny skin water content between the low-and moderate/high-activity groups, indicating that exercise habits may enhance skin moisturization, possibly via increased skin blood flow, stress reduction, improved sleep, and increased collagen production. Exercise regimens may mitigate age-related decline in skin function, potentially offering a preventive strategy for skin dryness and related conditions in older adults.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Indian Dermatology Online Journal.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oizumi</LastName><ForeName>Ryosuke</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5402-2115</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yuaikai Hospital Education and Training Department, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shibata</LastName><ForeName>Risa</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sonoda University Faculty of Human Health, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Indian Dermatol Online J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101586880</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2229-5178</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41382199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12854578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/idoj.idoj_983_24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01630814-990000000-00601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Proksch E, Brandner JM, Jensen JM. The skin: An indispensable barrier. Exp Dermatol. 2008;17:1063&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19043850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustin M, Kirsten N, K&#xf6;rber A, Wilsmann-Theis D, Itschert G, Staubach-Renz P, et al. Prevalence, predictors and comorbidity of dry skin in the general population. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2019;33:147&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29953684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustin M, Wilsmann-Theis D, K&#xf6;rber A, Kerscher M, Itschert G, Dippel M, et al. Diagnosis and treatment of xerosis cutis-A position paper. J Dtsch Dermatol Ges. 2019;17(Suppl 7):3&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31738016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul C, Maumus-Robert S, Mazereeuw-Hautier J, Guyen CN, Saudez X, Schmitt AM. Prevalence and risk factors for xerosis in the elderly: A cross-sectional epidemiological study in primary care. Dermatology. 2011;223:260&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22104182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith DR, Atkinson R, Tang S, Yamagata Z. A survey of skin disease among patients in an Australian nursing home. J Epidemiol. 2002;12:336&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10616366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12395875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kili&#xe7; A, G&#xfc;l U, Aslan E, Soylu S. Dermatological findings in the senior population of nursing homes in Turkey. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2008;47:93&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17826853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobin DJ. Introduction to skin aging. J Tissue Viabil. 2017;26:37&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27020864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iizaka S. Skin hydration and lifestyle-related factors in community-dwelling older people. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2017;72:121&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28624752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crane JD, MacNeil LG, Lally JS, Ford RJ, Bujak AL, Brar IK, et al. Exercise-stimulated interleukin-15 is controlled by AMPK and regulates skin metabolism and aging. Aging Cell. 2015;14:625&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4531076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25902870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang Q, Wang Y, Liu Y, Zhu D, Xie Y, Zhao J, et al. Prevalence and associated factors of dry skin among older inpatients in hospitals and nursing homes: A multicenter cross-sectional study. Int J Nurs Stud. 2022;135:104358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36152467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>du Plessis J, Stefaniak A, Eloff F, John S, Agner T, Chou TC, et al. International guidelines for the in vivo assessment of skin properties in non-clinical settings: Part 2. Transepidermal water loss and skin hydration. Skin Res Technol. 2013;19:265&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4522909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23331328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oizumi R, Sugimoto Y, Aibara H. The potential of exercise on lifestyle and skin function: Narrative review. JMIR Dermatol. 2024;7:e51962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10979338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38483460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black MA, Green DJ, Cable NT. Exercise prevents age-related decline in nitric-oxide-mediated vasodilator function in cutaneous microvessels. J Physiol. 2008;586:3511&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2538814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18483071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brugler A, Thompson S, Turner S, Ngo B, Rendell M. Skin blood flow abnormalities in diabetic dermopathy. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2011;65:559&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21531041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi E-H, Demerjian M, Crumrine D, Brown BE, Mauro T, Elias PM, et al. Glucocorticoid blockade reverses psychological stress-induced abnormalities in epidermal structure and function. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp. 2006;291:R1657&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16857896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stubbs B, Vancampfort D, Rosenbaum S, Firth J, Cosco T, Veronese N, et al. An examination of the anxiolytic effects of exercise for people with anxiety and stress-related disorders: A meta-analysis. Psychiatry Res. 2017;249:102&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28088704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryosuke O. The impact of exercise on stress: A preliminary study: 2025, V.11, No. 4. HSR [Internet] 2024.  [[Last accessed on 2024 Oct 24]].  Jan. 30. Available from: https://hsr-journal.com/index.php/journal/article/view/950 .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camilion JV, Khanna S, Anasseri S, Laney C, Mayrovitz HN. Physiological, pathological, and circadian factors impacting skin hydration. Cureus. 2022;14:e27666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9440333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36072192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edmondson SR, Thumiger SP, Werther GA, Wraight CJ. Epidermal homeostasis: The role of the growth hormone and insulin-like growth factor systems. Endocr Rev. 2003;24:737&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14671001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornton MJ. Estrogens and aging skin. Dermatoendocrinol. 2013;5:264&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3772914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24194966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>