<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37979026</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-8221</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>175</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Bulletin of experimental biology and medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Bull Exp Biol Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Phytocorrection of Age-Related Changes in the Composition of Blood Plasma, Lymph, and Interstitial Fluid.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>785</StartPage><EndPage>790</EndPage><MedlinePgn>785-790</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10517-023-05947-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>We studied the effect of a new complex phytocomposition on age-related changes in the composition of biological fluids (blood, lymph, and interstitial fluid) in old (22-24-month-old) white Sprague-Dawley rats. A 3-month course of phytocomposition induced an increase in the volumes of interstitial fluid (IF) and plasma and stimulated lymph outflow and diuresis. In the blood and lymph, the clotting time increased, while the viscosity and all lipid indicators decreased. The phytocomposition increased the number of erythrocytes and leukocytes, the levels of immunoglobulins (except IgG) and lymphocyte subpopulations, which contributed to correction and improvement of the immune properties of the blood and lymph. Increased hydration of the tissues of the body and strengthening of the anti-atherogenic and immune properties of the lymph and blood led to recovery of the drainage and detoxification function of the lymphatic system. Due to the presence of bioflavonoids, microelements, and vitamins, the new complex phytocomposition produces a lymphotropic effect by changing the composition of the blood, lymph, and IF and stimulates fluid transport from IF into the vascular bed, thereby promoting natural lymph detoxification and increasing the immune properties of the blood and lymph.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Demchenko</LastName><ForeName>G A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Genetics and Physiology, the Science Committee of the Ministry of Education and Science of the Republic of Kazakhstan, Alma-Ata, Republic of Kazakhstan. georgiidemchenko@mail.ru.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nurmakhanova</LastName><ForeName>B A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Genetics and Physiology, the Science Committee of the Ministry of Education and Science of the Republic of Kazakhstan, Alma-Ata, Republic of Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abdreshov</LastName><ForeName>S N</ForeName><Initials>SN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Genetics and Physiology, the Science Committee of the Ministry of Education and Science of the Republic of Kazakhstan, Alma-Ata, Republic of Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koibasova</LastName><ForeName>L U</ForeName><Initials>LU</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Genetics and Physiology, the Science Committee of the Ministry of Education and Science of the Republic of Kazakhstan, Alma-Ata, Republic of Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhunussova</LastName><ForeName>G S</ForeName><Initials>GS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Genetics and Physiology, the Science Committee of the Ministry of Education and Science of the Republic of Kazakhstan, Alma-Ata, Republic of Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Imankulova</LastName><ForeName>S K</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Abai Kazakh National Pedagogical University, Alma-Ata, Republic of Kazakhstan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Bull Exp Biol Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0372557</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0007-4888</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D045604" MajorTopicYN="Y">Extracellular Fluid</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017207" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats, Sprague-Dawley</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008196" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lymph</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008208" MajorTopicYN="N">Lymphatic System</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010949" MajorTopicYN="N">Plasma</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interstitial fluid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lymph</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">phytocomposition</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37979026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10517-023-05947-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10517-023-05947-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Levin YuM. Breakthrough in Endoecological Medicine: a New Level of Medical Thinking and Effective Therapy. Moscow, 2007. Russian.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borodin YuI. Lymphatic system and ageing. Fundament. Issled. 2011;(5):11-15. Russian.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zolla V, Nizamutdinova IT, Scharf B, Clement CC, Maejima D, Akl T, Nagai T, Luciani P, Leroux JC, Halin C, Stukes S, Tiwari S, Casadevall A, Jacobs WR Jr, Entenberg D, Zawieja DC, Condeelis J, Fooksman DR, Gashev AA, Santambrogio L. Aging-related anatomical and biochemical changes in lymphatic collectors impair lymph transport, fluid homeostasis, and pathogen clearance. Aging Cell. 2015;14(4):582-594. doi: https://doi.org/10.1111/acel.12330</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/acel.12330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25982749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4531072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Concept of the Lymphatic Region in a Preventive Lymphology. Novosibirsk, 2018. Russian.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demchenko GA, Toleukhanov ST, Nurmakhanova BA, Imankulova SK, Boranbayeva G, Abdreshov SN, Makashev EK. Comparative characteristics of the effect of some industrially significant medicinal herbs on the cardiovascular and lymphatic systems of an aging organism. Rep. Nat. Acad. Sci. Rep. Kazakhstan. 2021;2(336):35-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gelashvily OA. Variant of periodization of biologicallysimilar stages of human and rat&#x2019;s ontogenesis. Saratov. Nauch. Med. Zh. 2008;4(4):125-126. Russian.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;mejkal K, Malan&#xed;k M, Zhaparkulova K, Sakipova Z, Ibragimova L, Ibadullaeva G, &#x17d;emli&#x10d;ka M. Kazakh Ziziphora Species as Sources of Bioactive Substances. Molecules. 2016;21(7):826. doi: https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules21070826</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules21070826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27347924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6274025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekbolatova E, Kukula-Koch W, Baj T, Stasiak N, Ibadullayeva G, Koch W, G&#x142;owniak K, Tulemissov S, Sakipova Z, Boylan F. Phenolic composition and antioxidant potential of different organs of Kazakh Crataegus almaatensis Pojark: A comparison with the European Crataegus oxyacantha L. flowers. Open Chemistry. 2018;16(1):415-426. doi: https://doi.org/10.1515/chem-2018-0048</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usenova GS, Sinyavskii YuA. Patent KZ No. 21772. Biological active food additive balsam Vozrozhdenie Plus. Byull. No. 10. Published October 15, 2009. Russian.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fomin AM, Kapitanov EN, Chemeris AN, Koshelev RV, Abrin GV, Pfaf VF, Nikolaev DV, Stroiteleva EM. Patent RU No. 2273452. Method for diagnosing water balance disorders in extracellular fluid of body. Bull. No. 10. Published April 10, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demchenko GA, Tuleukhanov ST, Abdreshov SN, Kaleshov AM, Ossikbayeva SO, Nurmukhanova BA, Zhakina KN. Cellular, biochemical, immunological composition, physical and chemical, rheological parameters of lymph and blood, volume of interstitial fluid, diuresis in young, mature and old animals. News Nat. Acad. Sci. Rep. Kazakhstan. Ser. Biol. Med. 2020;3(339):22-28. doi: https://doi.org/10.32014/2020.2519-1629.19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorchakova O. Increase of the lymph node function as a result of phytostimulation in old age. Arhiv. Euromedica. 2018;8(1):44-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borodin YuI. General principles of organism sanitation due to influence on lymphatic system, lymphatic organs and interstitial tissue. Guide to Clinical Lymphology. Moscow, 2010. P. 13-15. Russian.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobov GI, Pan&#x2019;kova MN, Abdreshov SN. Transport function of the lymph nodes in young and old animals. Uspekhi Gerontologii. 2015;28(4):681-686. Russian.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Ryu D, Wu Y, Gariani K, Wang X, Luan P, D&#x2019;Amico D, Ropelle ER, Lutolf MP, Aebersold R, Schoonjans K, Menzies KJ, Auwerx J. NAD+ repletion improves mitochondrial and stem cell function and enhances life span in mice. Science. 2016;352:1436-1443. doi: https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aaf2693</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aaf2693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27127236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skulachev VP. Mitochondria in the programmed death phenomena; a principle of biology: &#x201c;it is better to die than to be wrong&#x201d;. IUBMB Life. 2000;49(5):365-373. doi: https://doi.org/10.1080/152165400410209</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/152165400410209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10902567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrenko VM. Constitution of lymphatic system. Byull. Sib. Otdel. Ross. Akad. Med. Nauk. 2012;32(2):29-35. Russian.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erofeeva LM, Mnikhovich MV. Changes in the structure and cell composition of human carinal lymph nodes during aging. Bull. Exp. Biol. Med. 2018;165(5):702-706. doi: https://doi.org/10.1007/s10517-018-4246-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10517-018-4246-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30225704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorchakova O, Kolmogorov Y, Gorchakov V, Demchenko G. Interrelation of trace elements and the structural organization of lymph nodes at young and senile age. Arhiv. Euromedica. 2020;10(2):22-25. doi: https://doi.org/10.35630/2199-885X/2020/10/2.6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.35630/2199-885X/2020/10/2.6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>