<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38477197</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2724-7031</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>101</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>La Tunisie medicale</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Tunis Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The assessment of Golden and Red Proportions among a North-African population.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>899</StartPage><EndPage>902</EndPage><MedlinePgn>899-902</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">The constant increase of both esthetic demands and advancement in materials and technologies have led to the development of guidelines to achieve optimal aesthetic results. These tools are useful to predict the teeth proportion and dimensions. Golden and Red proportion are the most described theories.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM">of present study was to evaluate the existence of both Golden and Red proportion in the maxillary anterior teeth among a North-African population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This was an observational study performed at the Fixed Prosthetic department of the dental clinic of Monastir, Tunisia. The study included participants with full intact anterior dentition. Those with diastema or teeth crowding were excluded. For each one, an alginate impression was done. Measures were, including the perceived width and length, have been taken on casts using digital caliper. Width ratios of maxillary lateral incisor to maxillary central incisor and lateral incisor to canine were calculated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The study included 100 Tunisian participants including 97 females and 21 males. The maxillary central incisors were the largest (8.60&#xb1;0.58mm) and the longest (99.71&#xb1;1.14mm). The ratio was 0.89&#xb1;0.09mm. Anterior teeth dimensions were not statistically not different between males and females. Significant differences were observed between calculated ratios with GP and to each other's. (p=0).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Either GP nor RP is applicable amongst the Tunisian Population.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kallala</LastName><ForeName>Rim</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of dental medicine, University of Monastir, Research Laboratory of Occlusodontics and ceramic prostheses LR16ES15, 5000 Monastir, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gassara</LastName><ForeName>Yosra</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of dental medicine, University of Monastir, Research Laboratory of Occlusodontics and ceramic prostheses LR16ES15, 5000 Monastir, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garrach</LastName><ForeName>Behaeddine</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of medicine, University of Monastir, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Touzi</LastName><ForeName>Soumaya</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of dental medicine, University of Monastir, Research Laboratory of Occlusodontics and ceramic prostheses LR16ES15, 5000 Monastir, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harzallah</LastName><ForeName>Belhassen</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of dental medicine, University of Monastir, Research Laboratory of Occlusodontics and ceramic prostheses LR16ES15, 5000 Monastir, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Tunisia</Country><MedlineTA>Tunis Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0413766</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0041-4131</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008437" MajorTopicYN="Y">Maxilla</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003481" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cuspid</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004955" MajorTopicYN="N">Esthetics, Dental</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009811" MajorTopicYN="N">Odontometry</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007180" MajorTopicYN="N">Incisor</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Healthy adult Muslims who practice Ramadan fasting (RF) follow strict religious rules regarding their lifestyle. RF influences several parameters, including nutrition, hydration, and sleep habits, and can potentially reduce physical performance. It seems that RF prevents athletes from training and participating in competitions, and prevents the general community from engaging in physical exercise. This places practicing Muslim athletes at a competitive disadvantage. Therefore, the goal of this guide was to provide practical recommendations, based on expert panel consensus, for healthy athletes and their support staff on how to adopt appropriate behavioral, social, and psychological strategies to cope with the changes and constraints resulting from RF. The recommendations developed in this guide are not limited to prescribing appropriate exercise during the month of Ramadan (ie; schedule, frequency, intensity, duration, type of exercise, and training load), but cover different aspects of lifestyle such as nutrition, hydration, and sleep, and address psychosocial and cognitive aspects related to RF. These recommendations are intended for healthy individuals. Patients with chronic illnesses should refer to their doctor to ensure an eventual safe practice.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38477197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11389697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Londono J, Ghasemi S, Lawand G, Dashti M. Evaluation of the golden proportion in the natural dentition: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Prosthet Dent. 2023;129(5):696&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34489087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldegheishem A, Azam A, Al-Madi E, Abu-Khalaf L, Bani Ali B, Anweigi L. Golden proportion evaluation in maxillary anterior teeth amongst Saudi population in Riyadh. Saudi Dent J. 2019;31(3):322&#x2013;329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6626248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31337935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kallala R, Chaouch MH, Nasr K, Courset T. Step-by-Step Esthetic Rehabilitation with Chairside System. Case Rep Dent. 2021;2021:5558158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8018877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33833880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasanreisoglu U, Berksun S, Aras K, Arslan I. An analysis of maxillary anterior teeth: facial and dental proportions. J Prosthet Dent. 2005;94(6):530&#x2013;538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16316799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alqahtani AS, Habib SR, Ali M, Alshahrani AS, Alotaibi NM, Alahaidib FA. Maxillary anterior teeth dimension and relative width proportion in a Saudi subpopulation. J Taibah Univ Med Sci. 2021;16(2):209&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8046947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33897325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azimi M, Dinparvar M, Teimourian H, Farhadian M. Evaluating Recurring Esthetic Dental Proportion (RED) and Golden Proportion in Natural Dentition. Avicenna J Dent Res. 2016;9(1):e30267</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarek R. Esthetic Dental Proportions and Measurements Comprising a Natural Esthetic Smile: A Literature Review. Saudi J Oral Dent Res. 2021;6(6):270&#x2013;273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagh SA, Mantri SS, Bhasin A. Evaluation of maxillary anterior teeth proportion with Chu&#x2019;s Gauge in a population of Central India: an in vivo study. Med Pharm Rep. 2020;93(1):75&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7051822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32133450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shetty S, Pitti V, Satish Babu C, Surendra Kumar G, Jnanadev K. To evaluate the validity of Recurring Esthetic Dental proportion in natural dentition. J Conserv Dent. 2011;14(3):314&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3198567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22025841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Marzok MI, Majeed KRA, Ibrahim IK. Evaluation of maxillary anterior teeth and their relation to the golden proportion in malaysian population. BMC Oral Health. 2013;13(1):9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3570432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23347800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Von Elm E, Altman DG, Egger M, Pocock SJ, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Vandenbroucke JP. The Strengthening the Reporting of Observational Studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) Statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. Int J Surg. 2014;12(12):1495&#x2013;1499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25046131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva AO, Fabre HSC, Ursi WJS, Hoeppner MG, Do Amaral ALM. Anterior Upper Teeth Golden Proportion Analysis with Millimetric Templates: An Invention Developed at Londrina State University. Int J Dent. 2022;2022:1520812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9744622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36518746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isa ZM, Tawfiq OF, Noor NM, Shamsudheen MI, Rijal OM. Regression methods to investigate the relationship between facial measurements and widths of the maxillary anterior teeth. J Prosthet Dent. 2010;103(3):182&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20188241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcuschamer E, Tsukiyama T, Griffin TJ, Arguello E, Gallucci GO, Magne P. Anatomical crown width/length ratios of worn and unworn maxillary teeth in Asian subjects. Int J Periodontics Restorative Dent. 2011;31(5):495&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21845244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sah SK, Zhang HD, Chang T, Dhungana M, Acharya L, Chen LL, et al. Maxillary anterior teeth dimensions and proportions in a central mainland Chinese population. Chin J Dent Res. 2014;17(2):117&#x2013;124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25531020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolte AP, Kolte RA, Pajnigara NG, Pajnigara NG. A Clinical and Radiographic Assessment of Positional Variations of Gingival Papilla and Its Proportions. Int J Periodontics Restorative Dent. 2016;36(2):213&#x2013;218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26901299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu SJ. Range and mean distribution frequency of individual tooth width of the maxillary anterior dentition. PPAD. 2007;19(4):209&#x2013;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17601327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mavroskoufis F, Ritchie GM. Variation in size and form between left and right maxillary central incisor teeth. J Prost Dent. 1980;43(3):254&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6928193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aziz M, Hossain MZ. Validity of mathematical proportions in maxillary anterior teeth among Bangladeshi population. APOS Trends Orthod. 2017;7(1):41&#x2013;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swelem AA, Al-Rafah EM. Evaluation of &#x201c;Golden Proportion&#x201d; in Saudi individuals with natural smiles. Saudi Dent J. 2019;31(2):277&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6445444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30983840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murthy BV, Ramani N. Evaluation of natural smile: Golden proportion, RED or Golden percentage. J Conserv Dent. 2008;11(1):16&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2813089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20142879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fayyad MA, Jamani KD, Agrabawi J. Geometric and mathematical proportions and their relations to maxillary anterior teeth. J Contemp Dent Pract. 2006;7(5):62&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17091141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amuasi AA, Acheampong AO, Owusu S, Larmie R, Sabbah DK, Buabeng AR. Evaluation of the Golden Proportion in Patients Visiting the Oral Health Directorate of the Komfo Anokye Teaching Hospital, Kumasi. J Biosci Med. 2020;08(08):116&#x2013;126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baghiana G, Peter D, Manju V, Babu AS, Krishnan V. Relevance of Recurring Esthetic Dental (RED) proportion and golden proportion among patients attending a tertiary care center at Kochi, Kerala. J Oral Biol Craniofac Res. 2022;12(6):890&#x2013;893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9582732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36277123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chander NG, Kumar VV, Rangarajan V. Golden proportion assessment between maxillary and mandibular teeth on Indian population. J Adv Prosthodont. 2012;4(2):72&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3381205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22737310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esan TA, Oziegbe OE, Onapokya HO. Facial approximation: evaluation of dental and facial proportions with height. Afr Health Sci. 2012;12(1):63&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3462517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23066422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magne P, Gallucci GO, Belser UC. Anatomic crown width/length ratios of unworn and worn maxillary teeth in white subjects. J Prost Dent. 2003;89(5):453&#x2013;461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12806322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>