<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39132839</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-8652</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>99</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of hematology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Hematol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exercise and training in sickle cell disease: Safety, potential benefits, and recommendations.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1988</StartPage><EndPage>2001</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1988-2001</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ajh.27454</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sickle cell disease (SCD) is a genetic disorder characterized by complex pathophysiological mechanisms leading to vaso-occlusive crisis, chronic pain, chronic hemolytic anemia, and vascular complications, which require considerations for exercise and physical activity. This review aims to elucidate the safety, potential benefits, and recommendations regarding exercise and training in individuals with SCD. SCD patients are characterized by decreased exercise capacity and tolerance. Acute intense exercise may be accompanied by biological changes (acidosis, increased oxidative stress, and dehydration) that could increase the risk of red blood cell sickling and acute clinical complications. However, recent findings suggest that controlled exercise training is safe and well tolerated by SCD patients and could confer benefits in disease management. Regular endurance exercises of submaximal intensity or exercise interventions incorporating resistance training have been shown to improve cardiorespiratory and muscle function in SCD, which may improve quality of life. Recommendations for exercise prescription in SCD should be based on accurate clinical and functional evaluations, taking into account disease phenotype and cardiorespiratory status at rest and in response to exercise. Exercise programs should include gradual progression, incorporating adequate warm-up, cool-down, and hydration strategies. Exercise training represents promising therapeutic strategy in the management of SCD. It is now time to move through the investigation of long-term biological, physiological, and clinical effects of regular physical activity in SCD patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Connes</LastName><ForeName>Philippe</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9232-0268</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratoire Interuniversitaire de Biologie de la Motricit&#xe9; (LIBM) EA7424, Team &#xab;Vascular Biology and Red Blood Cell&#xbb;, Universit&#xe9; Claude Bernard Lyon 1, Universit&#xe9; de Lyon, Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stauffer</LastName><ForeName>Emeric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratoire Interuniversitaire de Biologie de la Motricit&#xe9; (LIBM) EA7424, Team &#xab;Vascular Biology and Red Blood Cell&#xbb;, Universit&#xe9; Claude Bernard Lyon 1, Universit&#xe9; de Lyon, Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Explorations Fonctionnelles Respiratoires, M&#xe9;decine du sport et de l'Activit&#xe9; Physique, Hospices Civils de Lyon, H&#xf4;pital Croix Rousse, Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liem</LastName><ForeName>Robert I</ForeName><Initials>RI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Hematology, Oncology and Stem Cell Transplant, Ann and Robert H Lurie Children's Hospital of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nader</LastName><ForeName>Elie</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratoire Interuniversitaire de Biologie de la Motricit&#xe9; (LIBM) EA7424, Team &#xab;Vascular Biology and Red Blood Cell&#xbb;, Universit&#xe9; Claude Bernard Lyon 1, Universit&#xe9; de Lyon, Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Hematol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7610369</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0361-8609</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000755" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anemia, Sickle Cell</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39132839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajh.27454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Piel FB, Patil AP, Howes RE, et al. Global distribution of the sickle cell gene and geographical confirmation of the malaria hypothesis. Nat Commun. 2010;1:104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adachi K, Asakura T. The solubility of sickle and non&#x2010;sickle hemoglobins in concentrated phosphate buffer. J Biol Chem. 1979;254(10):4079&#x2010;4084.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connes P, Alexy T, Detterich J, Romana M, Hardy&#x2010;Dessources MD, Ballas SK. The role of blood rheology in sickle cell disease. Blood Rev. 2016;30(2):111&#x2010;118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato GJ, Gladwin MT, Steinberg MH. Deconstructing sickle cell disease: reappraisal of the role of hemolysis in the development of clinical subphenotypes. Blood Rev. 2007;21(1):37&#x2010;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nader E, Conran N, Romana M, Connes P. Vasculopathy in sickle cell disease: from red blood cell sickling to vascular dysfunction. Compr Physiol. 2021;11(2):1785&#x2010;1803.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reiter CD, Wang X, Tanus&#x2010;Santos JE, et al. Cell&#x2010;free hemoglobin limits nitric oxide bioavailability in sickle&#x2010;cell disease. Nat Med. 2002;8(12):1383&#x2010;1389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charlot K, Romana M, Moeckesch B, et al. Which side of the balance determines the frequency of vaso&#x2010;occlusive crises in children with sickle cell anemia: blood viscosity or microvascular dysfunction? Blood Cells Mol Dis. 2016;56(1):41&#x2010;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belhassen L, Pelle G, Sediame S, et al. Endothelial dysfunction in patients with sickle cell disease is related to selective impairment of shear stress&#x2010;mediated vasodilation. Blood. 2001;97(6):1584&#x2010;1589.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato GJ, McGowan V, Machado RF, et al. Lactate dehydrogenase as a biomarker of hemolysis&#x2010;associated nitric oxide resistance, priapism, leg ulceration, pulmonary hypertension, and death in patients with sickle cell disease. Blood. 2006;107(6):2279&#x2010;2285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voskou S, Aslan M, Fanis P, Phylactides M, Kleanthous M. Oxidative stress in beta&#x2010;thalassaemia and sickle cell disease. Redox Biol. 2015;6:226&#x2010;239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chirico EN, Pialoux V. Role of oxidative stress in the pathogenesis of sickle cell disease. IUBMB Life. 2012;64(1):72&#x2010;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connes P. Blood rheology and vascular function in sickle cell trait and sickle cell disease: from pathophysiological mechanisms to clinical usefulness. Clin Hemorheol Microcirc. 2024;86(1&#x2013;2):9&#x2010;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hierso R, Waltz X, Mora P, et al. Effects of oxidative stress on red blood cell rheology in sickle cell patients. Br J Haematol. 2014;166(4):601&#x2010;606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belcher JD, Zhang P, Nguyen J, et al. Identification of a Heme activation site on the MD&#x2010;2/TLR4 complex. Front Immunol. 2020;11:1370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conran N, Belcher JD. Inflammation in sickle cell disease. Clin Hemorheol Microcirc. 2018;68(2&#x2013;3):263&#x2010;299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Platt OS, Rosenstock W, Espeland MA. Influence of sickle hemoglobinopathies on growth and development. N Engl J Med. 1984;311(1):7&#x2010;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barden EM, Zemel BS, Kawchak DA, Goran MI, Ohene&#x2010;Frempong K, Stallings VA. Total and resting energy expenditure in children with sickle cell disease. J Pediatr. 2000;136(1):73&#x2010;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borel MJ, Buchowski MS, Turner EA, Goldstein RE, Flakoll PJ. Protein turnover and energy expenditure increase during exogenous nutrient availability in sickle cell disease. Am J Clin Nutr. 1998;68(3):607&#x2010;614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchowski MS, Simmons LA, Chen KY, Flakoll PJ, Mellen BG, Turner EA. Plasma leptin association with body composition and energy expenditure in sickle cell disease. J Am Coll Nutr. 2000;19(2):228&#x2010;236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singhal A, Davies P, Wierenga KJ, Thomas P, Serjeant G. Is there an energy deficiency in homozygous sickle cell disease? Am J Clin Nutr. 1997;66(2):386&#x2010;390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchowski MS, Townsend KM, Williams R, Chen KY. Patterns and energy expenditure of free&#x2010;living physical activity in adolescents with sickle cell anemia. J Pediatr. 2002;140(1):86&#x2010;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charlot K, Moeckesch B, Jumet S, et al. Physical activity level is not a determinant of autonomic nervous system activity and clinical severity in children/adolescents with sickle cell anemia: a pilot study. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2015;62(11):1962&#x2010;1967.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olorunyomi OO, Liem RI, Hsu LL. Motivators and barriers to physical activity among youth with sickle cell disease: brief review. Children (Basel). 2022;9(4):572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connes P, Machado R, Hue O, Reid H. Exercise limitation, exercise testing and exercise recommendations in sickle cell anemia. Clin Hemorheol Microcirc. 2011;49(1&#x2013;4):151&#x2010;163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchese V, Rock K, Harpold A, Salazar A, Williams M, Shipper AG. Physical impairment and function in children and adolescents with sickle cell disease: a systematic review. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2022;103(6):1144&#x2010;1167. e1142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braden DS, Covitz W, Milner PF. Cardiovascular function during rest and exercise in patients with sickle&#x2010;cell anemia and coexisting alpha thalassemia&#x2010;2. Am J Hematol. 1996;52(2):96&#x2010;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callahan LA, Woods KF, Mensah GA, Ramsey LT, Barbeau P, Gutin B. Cardiopulmonary responses to exercise in women with sickle cell anemia. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2002;165(9):1309&#x2010;1316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charlot K, Waltz X, Hedreville M, et al. Impaired oxygen uptake efficiency slope and off&#x2010;transient kinetics of pulmonary oxygen uptake in sickle cell anemia are associated with hemorheological abnormalities. Clin Hemorheol Microcirc. 2015;60(4):413&#x2010;421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith KN, Baynard T, Fischbach PS, et al. Safety of maximal cardiopulmonary exercise testing in individuals with sickle cell disease: a systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2022;56(13):764&#x2010;769.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badawy SM, Payne AB, Rodeghier MJ, Liem RI. Exercise capacity and clinical outcomes in adults followed in the cooperative study of sickle cell disease (CSSCD). Eur J Haematol. 2018;101(4):532&#x2010;541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liem RI, Reddy M, Pelligra SA, et al. Reduced fitness and abnormal cardiopulmonary responses to maximal exercise testing in children and young adults with sickle cell anemia. Physiol Rep. 2015;3(4):e12338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammoudi N, Ceccaldi A, Haymann JP, et al. Altered cardiac reserve is a determinant of exercise intolerance in sickle cell anaemia patients. Eur J Clin Invest. 2022;52(1):e13664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>d'Humieres T, Bouvarel A, Boyer L, et al. Cardiac diastolic maladaptation is associated with the severity of exercise intolerance in sickle cell anemia patients. Sci Rep. 2024;14(1):11095.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anthi A, Machado RF, Jison ML, et al. Hemodynamic and functional assessment of patients with sickle cell disease and pulmonary hypertension. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2007;175(12):1272&#x2010;1279.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liem RI, Nevin MA, Prestridge A, Young LT, Thompson AA. Functional capacity in children and young adults with sickle cell disease undergoing evaluation for cardiopulmonary disease. Am J Hematol. 2009;84(10):645&#x2010;649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogunsile FJ, Stewart KJ, Kanter J, Lanzkron SM. An evaluation of cardiopulmonary endurance and muscular strength in adults living with sickle cell disease. Br J Haematol. 2022;199(4):597&#x2010;602.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delclaux C, Zerah&#x2010;Lancner F, Bachir D, et al. Factors associated with dyspnea in adult patients with sickle cell disease. Chest. 2005;128(5):3336&#x2010;3344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell A, Minniti CP, Nouraie M, et al. Prospective evaluation of haemoglobin oxygen saturation at rest and after exercise in paediatric sickle cell disease patients. Br J Haematol. 2009;147(3):352&#x2010;359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva L, Merces de Jesus G, Bessa Junior J, et al. Exercise capacity and biomarkers among children and adolescents with sickle cell disease. Pediatr Exerc Sci. 2023;35(2):84&#x2010;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waltz X, Romana M, Hardy&#x2010;Dessources MD, et al. Hematological and hemorheological determinants of the six&#x2010;minute walk test performance in children with sickle cell anemia. PLoS One. 2013;8(10):e77830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gouraud E, Connes P, Gauthier&#x2010;Vasserot A, et al. Is skeletal muscle dysfunction a limiting factor of exercise functional capacity in patients with sickle cell disease? J Clin Med. 2021;10(11):2250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halphen I, Elie C, Brousse V, et al. Severe nocturnal and postexercise hypoxia in children and adolescents with sickle cell disease. PLoS One. 2014;9(5):e97462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waltz X, Romana M, Lalanne&#x2010;Mistrih ML, et al. Hematologic and hemorheological determinants of resting and exercise&#x2010;induced hemoglobin oxygen desaturation in children with sickle cell disease. Haematologica. 2013;98(7):1039&#x2010;1044.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McConnell ME, Daniels SR, Lobel J, James FW, Kaplan S. Hemodynamic response to exercise in patients with sickle cell anemia. Pediatr Cardiol. 1989;10(3):141&#x2010;144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grau M, Jerke M, Nader E, et al. Effect of acute exercise on RBC deformability and RBC nitric oxide synthase signalling pathway in young sickle cell anaemia patients. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):11813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liem RI, Onyejekwe K, Olszewski M, et al. The acute phase inflammatory response to maximal exercise testing in children and young adults with sickle cell anaemia. Br J Haematol. 2015;171(5):854&#x2010;861.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balayssac&#x2010;Siransy E, Connes P, Tuo N, et al. Mild haemorheological changes induced by a moderate endurance exercise in patients with sickle cell anaemia. Br J Haematol. 2011;154(3):398&#x2010;407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faes C, Balayssac&#x2010;Siransy E, Connes P, et al. Moderate endurance exercise in patients with sickle cell anaemia: effects on oxidative stress and endothelial activation. Br J Haematol. 2014;164(1):124&#x2010;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das BB, Sobczyk W, Bertolone S, Raj A. Cardiopulmonary stress testing in children with sickle cell disease who are on long&#x2010;term erythrocytapheresis. J Pediatr Hematol Oncol. 2008;30(5):373&#x2010;377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charache S, Bleecker ER, Bross DS. Effects of blood transfusion on exercise capacity in patients with sickle&#x2010;cell anemia. Am J Med. 1983;74(5):757&#x2010;764.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein HG, Winslow RM. Partial red cell exchange transfusion in sickle cell disease. Prog Clin Biol Res. 1982;88:235&#x2010;243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller DM, Winslow RM, Klein HG, Wilson KC, Brown FL, Statham NJ. Improved exercise performance after exchange transfusion in subjects with sickle cell anemia. Blood. 1980;56(6):1127&#x2010;1131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phan V, Hershenson J, Caldarera L, et al. Effect of voxelotor on cardiopulmonary testing in youths with sickle cell anemia in a pilot study. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2023;70(8):e30423.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grau M, Nader E, Jerke M, et al. Impact of a six week training program on Ventilatory efficiency, red blood cell rheological parameters and red blood cell nitric oxide signaling in Young sickle cell anemia patients: a pilot study. J Clin Med. 2019;8(12):2155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gellen B, Messonnier LA, Galacteros F, et al. Moderate&#x2010;intensity endurance&#x2010;exercise training in patients with sickle&#x2010;cell disease without severe chronic complications (EXDRE): an open&#x2010;label randomised controlled trial. Lancet Haematol. 2018;5(11):e554&#x2010;e562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merlet AN, Messonnier LA, Coudy&#x2010;Gandilhon C, et al. Beneficial effects of endurance exercise training on skeletal muscle microvasculature in sickle cell disease patients. Blood. 2019;134(25):2233&#x2010;2241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonelli Rossi DA, De Araujo Junior JA, Luvizutto GJ, et al. Effect of a physical exercise program on the inflammatory response, cardiac functions, functional capacity, and quality of life in patients with sickle cell disease. J Clin Med. 2023;12(12):3952.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almeida CHS, Reis L, Nascimento L, Soares AR, Maioli MCP, Lopes AJ. Therapist&#x2010;oriented home rehabilitation for adults with sickle cell anemia: effects on muscle strength, functional capacity, and quality of life. Hematology. 2021;26(1):612&#x2010;619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noordstar JJ, Hulzebos EHJ, van der Ent CK, Suijker MH, Bartels M. Organized sports activities are safe for children with sickle cell disease: a pilot intervention study. J Pediatr Hematol Oncol. 2023;45(6):e710&#x2010;e715.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liem RI, Akinosun M, Muntz DS, Thompson AA. Feasibility and safety of home exercise training in children with sickle cell anemia. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2017;64(12).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lester LA, Sodt PC, Hutcheon N, Arcilla RA. Cardiac abnormalities in children with sickle cell anemia. Chest. 1990;98(5):1169&#x2010;1174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hankins JS, McCarville MB, Hillenbrand CM, et al. Ventricular diastolic dysfunction in sickle cell anemia is common but not associated with myocardial iron deposition. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2010;55(3):495&#x2010;500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson MC, Kirkham FJ, Redline S, et al. Left ventricular hypertrophy and diastolic dysfunction in children with sickle cell disease are related to asleep and waking oxygen desaturation. Blood. 2010;116(1):16&#x2010;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sachdev V, Machado RF, Shizukuda Y, et al. Diastolic dysfunction is an independent risk factor for death in patients with sickle cell disease. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2007;49(4):472&#x2010;479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musallam KM, Barella S, Origa R, et al. Pretransfusion hemoglobin level and mortality in adults with transfusion&#x2010;dependent beta&#x2010;thalassemia. Blood. 2024;143(10):930&#x2010;932.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coates TD. Higher hemoglobin is better in thalassemia. Blood. 2024;143(10):842&#x2010;844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moheeb H, Wali YA, El&#x2010;Sayed MS. Physical fitness indices and anthropometrics profiles in schoolchildren with sickle cell trait/disease. Am J Hematol. 2007;82(2):91&#x2010;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravelojaona M, Feasson L, Oyono&#x2010;Enguelle S, et al. Evidence for a profound remodeling of skeletal muscle and its microvasculature in sickle cell anemia. Am J Pathol. 2015;185(5):1448&#x2010;1456.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charache S, Terrin ML, Moore RD, et al. Effect of hydroxyurea on the frequency of painful crises in sickle cell anemia. Investigators of the multicenter study of Hydroxyurea in sickle cell anemia. N Engl J Med. 1995;332(20):1317&#x2010;1322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michel CP, Bendahan D, Giannesini B, Vilmen C, Le Fur Y, Messonnier LA. Effects of hydroxyurea on skeletal muscle energetics and force production in a sickle cell disease murine model. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2023;134(2):415&#x2010;425.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troosters T, Gosselink R, Decramer M. Six minute walking distance in healthy elderly subjects. Eur Respir J. 1999;14(2):270&#x2010;274.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becklake MR, Griffiths SB, Mc GM, Goldman HI, Schreve JP. Oxygen dissociation curves in sickle cell anemia and in subjects with the sickle cell trait. J Clin Invest. 1955;34(5):751&#x2010;755.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromberg PA, Jensen WN. Blood oxygen dissociation curves in sickle cell disease. J Lab Clin Med. 1967;70(3):480&#x2010;488.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam YF, Lin AK, Ho C. A phosphorus&#x2010;31 nuclear magnetic resonance investigation of intracellular environment in human normal and sickle cell blood. Blood. 1979;54(1):196&#x2010;209.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>May A, Huehns ER. The concentration dependence of the oxygen affinity of haemoglobin S. Br J Haematol. 1975;30(3):317&#x2010;335.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seakins M, Gibbs WN, Milner PF, Bertles JF. Erythrocyte Hb&#x2010;S concentration. An important factor in the low oxygen affinity of blood in sickle cell anemia. J Clin Invest. 1973;52(2):422&#x2010;432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hines PC, Zen Q, Burney SN, et al. Novel epinephrine and cyclic AMP&#x2010;mediated activation of BCAM/Lu&#x2010;dependent sickle (SS) RBC adhesion. Blood. 2003;101(8):3281&#x2010;3287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Nemer W, Wautier MP, Rahuel C, et al. Endothelial Lu/BCAM glycoproteins are novel ligands for red blood cell alpha4beta1 integrin: role in adhesion of sickle red blood cells to endothelial cells. Blood. 2007;109(8):3544&#x2010;3551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sen CK. Oxidants and antioxidants in exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985). 1995;79(3):675&#x2010;686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treberg JR, Quinlan CL, Brand MD. Evidence for two sites of superoxide production by mitochondrial NADH&#x2010;ubiquinone oxidoreductase (complex I). J Biol Chem. 2011;286(31):27103&#x2010;27110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vina J, Gimeno A, Sastre J, et al. Mechanism of free radical production in exhaustive exercise in humans and rats; role of xanthine oxidase and protection by allopurinol. IUBMB Life. 2000;49(6):539&#x2010;544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong J, Chen P, Wang R, Yu D, Zhang Y, Xiao W. NADPH oxidase: a target for the modulation of the excessive oxidase damage induced by overtraining in rat neutrophils. Int J Biol Sci. 2011;7(6):881&#x2010;891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morozov VI, Tsyplenkov PV, Golberg ND, Kalinski MI. The effects of high&#x2010;intensity exercise on skeletal muscle neutrophil myeloperoxidase in untrained and trained rats. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2006;97(6):716&#x2010;722.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nader E, Skinner S, Romana M, et al. Blood rheology: key parameters, impact on blood flow, role in sickle cell disease and effects of exercise. Front Physiol. 2019;10:1329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waltz X, Hedreville M, Sinnapah S, et al. Delayed beneficial effect of acute exercise on red blood cell aggregate strength in patients with sickle cell anemia. Clin Hemorheol Microcirc. 2012;52(1):15&#x2010;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin C, Pialoux V, Faes C, Charrin E, Skinner S, Connes P. Does physical activity increase or decrease the risk of sickle cell disease complications? Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(4):214&#x2010;218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charrin E, Aufradet E, Douillard A, et al. Oxidative stress is decreased in physically active sickle cell SAD mice. Br J Haematol. 2015;168(5):747&#x2010;756.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charrin E, Dube JJ, Connes P, et al. Moderate exercise training decreases inflammation in transgenic sickle cell mice. Blood Cells Mol Dis. 2018;69:45&#x2010;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faes C, Charrin E, Connes P, Pialoux V, Martin C. Chronic physical activity limits blood rheology alterations in transgenic SAD mice. Am J Hematol. 2015;90(2):E32&#x2010;E33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messonnier LA, Riccetti M, Chatel B, et al. How to implement endurance exercise training in sickle cell disease. Haematologica. 2021;106(5):1476&#x2010;1479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallares JG, Moran&#x2010;Navarro R, Ortega JF, Fernandez&#x2010;Elias VE, Mora&#x2010;Rodriguez R. Validity and reliability of ventilatory and blood lactate thresholds in well&#x2010;trained cyclists. PLoS One. 2016;11(9):e0163389.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stegmann H, Kindermann W, Schnabel A. Lactate kinetics and individual anaerobic threshold. Int J Sports Med. 1981;2(3):160&#x2010;165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wasserman K, McIlroy MB. Detecting the threshold of anaerobic metabolism in cardiac patients during exercise. Am J Cardiol. 1964;14:844&#x2010;852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messonnier LA, Bartolucci P, d'Humieres T, et al. Preventive measures for the critical postexercise period in sickle cell trait and disease. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2021;130(2):485&#x2010;490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anselmi F, Cavigli L, Pagliaro A, et al. The importance of ventilatory thresholds to define aerobic exercise intensity in cardiac patients and healthy subjects. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2021;31(9):1796&#x2010;1808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers J. Applications of cardiopulmonary exercise testing in the management of cardiovascular and pulmonary disease. Int J Sports Med. 2005;26(Suppl 1):S49&#x2010;S55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wanrooij VH, Willeboordse M, Dompeling E, van de Kant KD. Exercise training in children with asthma: a systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48(13):1024&#x2010;1031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamarre Y, Romana M, Waltz X, et al. Hemorheological risk factors of acute chest syndrome and painful vaso&#x2010;occlusive crisis in children with sickle cell disease. Haematologica. 2012;97(11):1641&#x2010;1647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melo HN, Stoots SJ, Pool MA, et al. Physical activity level and performance in the six&#x2010;minute walk test of children and adolescents with sickle cell anemia. Rev Bras Hematol Hemoter. 2017;39(2):133&#x2010;139.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brousse V, Pondarre C, Arnaud C, et al. One&#x2010;fifth of children with sickle cell anemia show exercise&#x2010;induced hemoglobin desaturation: rate of perceived exertion and role of blood rheology. J Clin Med. 2020;9(1):133.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>