<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37788420</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-4095</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35</Volume><Issue>49</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advanced materials (Deerfield Beach, Fla.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Mater</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Engineering In Situ Catalytic Cleaning Membrane Via Prebiotic-Chemistry-Inspired Mineralization.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2306626</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2306626</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/adma.202306626</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Pressure-driven membrane separation promises a sustainable energy-water nexus but is hindered by ubiquitous fouling. Natural systems evolved from prebiotic chemistry offer a glimpse of creative solutions. Herein, a prebiotic-chemistry-inspired aminomalononitrile (AMN)/Mn<sup>2+</sup> -mediated mineralization method is reported for universally engineering a superhydrophilic hierarchical MnO<sub>2</sub> nanocoating to endow hydrophobic polymeric membranes with exceptional catalytic cleaning ability. Green hydrogen peroxide catalytically triggered in-situ cleaning of the mineralized membrane and enabled operando flux recovery to reach 99.8%. The mineralized membrane exhibited a 9-fold higher recovery compared to the unmineralized membrane, which is attributed to active catalytic antifouling coupled with passive hydration antifouling. Electron density differences derived from the precursor interaction during mediated mineralization unveiled an electron-rich bell-like structure with an inner electron-deficient Mn core. This work paves the way to construct multifunctional engineered materials for energy-efficient water treatment as well as for diverse promising applications in catalysis, solar steam generation, biomedicine, and beyond.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 UChicago Argonne, LLC, Operator of Argonne National Laboratory and The Authors. Advanced Materials published by Wiley-VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Xiaobin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MIIT Key Laboratory of Critical Materials Technology for New Energy Conversion and Storage, State Key Laboratory of Urban Water Resource and Environment, School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Harbin Institute of Technology, Harbin, 150001, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Environment, Harbin Institute of Technology, Harbin, 150090, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wen</LastName><ForeName>Yajie</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MIIT Key Laboratory of Critical Materials Technology for New Energy Conversion and Storage, State Key Laboratory of Urban Water Resource and Environment, School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Harbin Institute of Technology, Harbin, 150001, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Yangxue</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MIIT Key Laboratory of Critical Materials Technology for New Energy Conversion and Storage, State Key Laboratory of Urban Water Resource and Environment, School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Harbin Institute of Technology, Harbin, 150001, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Linlin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MIIT Key Laboratory of Critical Materials Technology for New Energy Conversion and Storage, State Key Laboratory of Urban Water Resource and Environment, School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Harbin Institute of Technology, Harbin, 150001, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Chuyang Y</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, the University of Hong Kong, Pokfulam, 999077, Hong Kong.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Environment, Harbin Institute of Technology, Harbin, 150090, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Darling</LastName><ForeName>Seth B</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5461-6965</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chemical Sciences and Engineering Division and Center for Molecular Engineering, Argonne National Laboratory, Lemont, IL, 60439, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Advanced Materials for Energy-Water Systems Energy Frontier Research Center (AMEWS EFRC), Argonne National Laboratory, Lemont, IL, 60439, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shao</LastName><ForeName>Lu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MIIT Key Laboratory of Critical Materials Technology for New Energy Conversion and Storage, State Key Laboratory of Urban Water Resource and Environment, School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Harbin Institute of Technology, Harbin, 150001, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>HITTY-20190033</GrantID><Agency>Heilongjiang Touyan Team</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 2023DX13</GrantID><Agency>Harbin Institute of Technology</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Central Universities of Ministry of Education of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2021M701001</GrantID><Agency>China Postdoctoral Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>LBH-Z21056</GrantID><Agency>Heilongjiang Postdoctoral Fund</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Office of Science</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>BX2021089</GrantID><Agency>National Postdoctoral Program for Innovative Talents</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>JQ2020B001</GrantID><Agency>Science Fund for Distinguished Young Scholars of Heilongjiang Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>22178076</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Energy Frontier Research Centers</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Mater</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9885358</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0935-9648</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antifouling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomimetic mineralization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">catalytic cleaning membrane</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prebiotic chemistry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">water treatment</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37788420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202306626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>a) E. Barry, R. Burns, W. Chen, G. X. De Hoe, J. M. M. De Oca, J. J. De Pablo, J. Dombrowski, J. W. Elam, A. M. Felts, G. Galli, J. Hack, Q. He, X. He, E. Hoenig, A. Iscen, B. Kash, H. H. Kung, N. H. C. Lewis, C. Liu, X. Ma, A. Mane, A. B. F. Martinson, K. L. Mulfort, J. Murphy, K. M&#xf8;lhave, P. Nealey, Y. Qiao, V. Rozyyev, G. C. Schatz, S. J. Sibener, et&#xa0;al., Chem. Rev. 2021, 121, 9450;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) J. Shen, Y. Cai, C. Zhang, W. Wei, C. Chen, L. Liu, K. Yang, Y. Ma, Y. Wang, C.-C. Tseng, J.-H. Fu, X. Dong, J. Li, X.-X. Zhang, L.-J. Li, J. Jiang, I. Pinnau, V. Tung, Y. Han, Nat. Mater. 2022, 21, 1183;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) Y. Wen, R. Dai, X. Li, X. Zhang, X. Cao, Z. Wu, S. Lin, C. Y. Tang, Z. Wang, Sci. Adv. 2022, 8, eabm4149;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>d) D. Lu, Z. Zhou, Z. Wang, D. T. Ho, G. Sheng, L. Chen, Y. Zhao, X. Li, L. Cao, U. Schwingenschl&#xf6;gl, J. Ma, Z. Lai, Adv. Mater. 2022, 34, 2109718;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>e) X. Wang, Q. Lyu, T. Tong, K. Sun, L.-C. Lin, C. Y. Tang, F. Yang, M. D. Guiver, X. Quan, Y. Dong, Nat. Commun. 2022, 13, 266;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>f) X. Yang, A. B. Martinson, J. W. Elam, L. Shao, S. B. Darling, Matter 2021, 4, 3515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) B. Van Der Bruggen, Nat. Rev. Chem. 2021, 5, 217;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) R. Ou, H. Zhang, V. X. Truong, L. Zhang, H. M. Hegab, L. Han, J. Hou, X. Zhang, A. Deletic, L. Jiang, G. P. Simon, H. Wang, Nat. Sustain. 2020, 3, 1052;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) C. Z. Liang, M. Askari, L. T. S. Choong, T.-S. Chung, Nat. Ccommun. 2021, 12, 2338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S. B. Darling, J. Appl. Phys. 2018, 124, 030901;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) R. Zhang, Y. Liu, M. He, Y. Su, X. Zhao, M. Elimelech, Z. Jiang, Chem. Soc. Rev. 2016, 45, 5888;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) P. J. J. Alvarez, C. K. Chan, M. Elimelech, N. J. Halas, D. Villagr&#xe1;n, Nat. Nanotechnol. 2018, 13, 634;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>d) X. Yang, P. Sun, H. Zhang, Z. Xia, R. Z. Waldman, A. U. Mane, J. W. Elam, L. Shao, S. B. Darling, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2020, 30, 1910062;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>e) Y. Wen, X. Yang, Y. Li, L. Yan, Y. Zhao, L. Shao, Sep. Purif. Technol. 2023, 320, 124225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Y. Liu, Y. Su, J. Guan, J. Cao, R. Zhang, M. He, K. Gao, L. Zhou, Z. Jiang, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2018, 28, 1706545;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) Y. Cai, D. Chen, N. Li, Q. Xu, H. Li, J. He, J. Lu, Adv. Mater. 2020, 32, 2001265;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) S. Lotfi, K. Fischer, A. Schulze, A. I. Sch&#xe4;fer, Nat. Nanotechnol. 2022, 17, 417;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>d) Y. Zhao, Y. Gu, B. Liu, Y. Yan, C. Shan, J. Guo, S. Zhang, C. D. Vecitis, G. Gao, Nature 2022, 608, 69;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>e) H. Zhang, A. U. Mane, X. Yang, Z. Xia, E. F. Barry, J. Luo, Y. Wan, J. W. Elam, S. B. Darling, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2020, 30, 2002847;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>f) A. Xie, J. Cui, J. Yang, Y. Chen, J. Lang, C. Li, Y. Yan, J. Dai, Appl Catal B 2020, 264, 118548;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>g) H. Zhang, Y. Wan, J. Luo, S. B. Darling, ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2021, 13, 14844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) S. L. Miller, Science 1953, 117, 528;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) J. L. Bada, A. Lazcano, Science 2003, 300, 745;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) S. Pulletikurti, M. Yadav, G. Springsteen, R. Krishnamurthy, Nat. Chem. 2022, 14, 1142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L.-B. Mao, H.-L. Gao, H.-B. Yao, L. Liu, H. C&#xf6;lfen, G. Liu, S.-M. Chen, S.-K. Li, Y.-X. Yan, Y.-Y. Liu, S.-H. Yu, Science 2016, 354, 107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Thissen, A. Koegler, M. Salwiczek, C. D. Easton, Y. Qu, T. Lithgow, R. A. Evans, NPG Asia Mater 2015, 7, e225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. B. D. Cassie, S. Baxter, Trans. Faraday Soc. 1944, 40, 546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Wang, H. Jia, T. Zheng, Y. Dai, C. Zhang, X. Guo, T. Wang, L. Zhu, Appl Catal B 2020, 272, 119030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) D. K. Owens, R. C. Wendt, J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 1969, 13, 1741;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) D. H. Kaelble, J. Adhes. 1970, 2, 66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) Z. Xue, S. Wang, L. Lin, L. Chen, M. Liu, L. Feng, L. Jiang, Adv. Mater. 2011, 23, 4270;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) L. Yan, X. Yang, Y. Li, R. Song, Y. Lin, Q. Huang, L. Shao, J. Membr. Sci. 2023, 679, 121705;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) L. Yan, X. Yang, H. Zeng, Y. Zhao, Y. Li, X. He, J. Ma, L. Shao, J. Membr. Sci. 2023, 668, 121243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) R. Wang, X. Zhao, N. Jia, L. Cheng, L. Liu, C. Gao, ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2020, 12, 10000;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) H.-C. Yang, Y. Xie, H. Chan, B. Narayanan, L. Chen, R. Z. Waldman, S. K. R. S. Sankaranarayanan, J. W. Elam, S. B. Darling, ACS Nano 2018, 12, 8678;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>c) D. Dong, Y. Zhu, W. Fang, M. Ji, A. Wang, S. Gao, H. Lin, R. Huang, J. Jin, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2022, 2113247;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>d) W. Yang, M. Pan, J. Zhang, L. Zhang, F. Lin, X. Liu, C. Huang, X.-Z. Chen, J. Wang, B. Yan, H. Zeng, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2022, 32, 2109989;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>e) Y. Zhu, J. Wang, F. Zhang, S. Gao, A. Wang, W. Fang, J. Jin, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2018, 28, 1804121;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>f) A. Xie, J. Cui, J. Yang, Y. Chen, J. Dai, J. Lang, C. Li, Y. Yan, J. Mater. Chem. A 2019, 7, 8491;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>g) L. Zhang, L. Cheng, H. Wu, T. Yoshioka, H. Matsuyama, J. Mater. Chem. A 2018, 6, 24641;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>h) R. Wang, X. Zhao, Y. Lan, L. Liu, C. Gao, J. Membr. Sci. 2020, 615, 118566;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>i) L. Zhang, Y. Lin, L. Cheng, Z. Yang, H. Matsuyama, J. Membr. Sci. 2019, 582, 48;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>j) X. Zhao, L. Cheng, N. Jia, R. Wang, L. Liu, C. Gao, J. Membr. Sci. 2020, 600, 117857;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>k) L. Yan, X. Yang, Y. Zhao, Y. Wu, R. Motlhaletsi Moutloali, B. B. Mamba, P. Sorokin, L. Shao, Sep. Purif. Technol. 2022, 285, 120383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>a) M. J. Frisch, G. W. Trucks, H. B. Schlegel, G. E. Scuseria, M. A. Robb, J. R. Cheeseman, G. Scalmani, V. Barone, B. Mennucci, G. A. Petersson, H. Nakatsuji, M. Caricato, X. Li, H. P. Hratchian, A. F. Izmaylov, J. Bloino, G. Zheng, J. L. Sonnenberg, M. Hada, M. Ehara, K. Toyota, R. Fukuda, J. Hasegawa, M. Ishida, T. Nakajima, Y. Honda, O. Kitao, H. Nakai, T. Vreven, J. A. Montgomery Jr, et&#xa0;al., Gaussian 09&#xa0;W, Revision A, Gaussian Inc., Wallingford, CT, 2009;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>b) C. Lee, W. Yang, R. G. Parr, Phys. Rev. B 1988, 37, 785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Lu, F. Chen, J. Comput. Chem. 2012, 33, 580.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>