<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39856339</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mechanism and CO<sub>2</sub> emissions analysis of multi-solid-waste synergistic red mud-based composite cementitious materials under orthogonal tests.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3097</StartPage><MedlinePgn>3097</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">3097</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-87772-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The large stockpile and low utilization rate of red mud (RM) have caused an urgent need for large quantities of RM to be eliminated. In this study, multi-solid-waste synergistic RM-based composite cementitious materials (MS-RMCM) were prepared using RM as the primary material, combined with fly ash, silica fume, and quicklime. Orthogonal tests were conducted to investigate the effects of cementitious components on the mechanical properties. The effect mechanisms were discussed by SEM-EDS results. The results revealed that: (1) Range analysis indicated that the factors influencing the 28 d compressive strength ranked as follows: quicklime (C)&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;silica fume (B)&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;fly ash (A). The optimal combination was determined to be A<sub>2</sub>B<sub>3</sub>C<sub>4</sub>, achieving a maximum compressive strength of 25.13&#xa0;MPa with 53% RM. (2) Variance analysis revealed that F (fly ash)&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.961&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;F<sub>0.01</sub>, F(silica fume)&#x2009;=&#x2009;17.778&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;F<sub>0.01</sub>, and F(quicklime)&#x2009;=&#x2009;61.921&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;F<sub>0.01</sub>, indicating that fly ash had no significant effect on the 28 d compressive strength, while silica fume had a significant effect, and quicklime had a highly significant effect. (3) Microscopic analysis showed that the strength improvement contributed by fly ash and silica fume was mainly attributed to their good potential pozzolanic activity and microaggregate filling effect. Quicklime enhanced the compactness by generating more hydration products after activating fly ash, silica fume and RM. (4) Life cycle assessment calculations indicated that the carbon emissions of MS-RMCM were 273.01&#xa0;kg/t, with a unit compressive strength carbon emission coefficient of 10.86&#xa0;kg/MPa, indicating the significant advantages of MS-RMCM in reducing CO<sub>2</sub> emissions in the construction industry.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Lili</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Guiyang Institute of Information Science and Technology, Guiyang, 550025, Guizhou, China. Lilycheng1231@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Daiyu</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil Engineering, Guizhou University, Guiyang, 550025, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Qiwan</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Guiyang Institute of Information Science and Technology, Guiyang, 550025, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Lingling</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil Engineering, Guizhou University, Guiyang, 550025, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Ninggui</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil Engineering, Guizhou University, Guiyang, 550025, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zeyuan</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil Engineering, Guizhou University, Guiyang, 550025, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>[2024]276</GrantID><Agency>Natural Science Research Program of Guizhou Education Department</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>12362011</GrantID><Agency>Foundation for Innovative Research Groups of the National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Carbon emissions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mechanical strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multi-solid-waste</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Red mud</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">synergistic mechanism</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39856339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11759942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-87772-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-87772-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ren, C. D. et al. Performance study and effect mechanism of red mud manufactured sand foam concrete using a single-factor experiment. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>458</b>, 139629 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.139629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arroyo, F., Luna-Galiano, Y., Leiva, C., Vilches, L. F. &amp; Fern&#xe1;ndez-Pereira, C. Environmental risks and mechanical evaluation of recycling red mud in bricks. <i>Environ. Res.</i><b>186</b>, 109537 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envres.2020.109537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32315825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimipour, A., Jahangir, H. &amp; Eidgahee, D. R. A thorough study on the effect of red mud, granite, limestone and marble slurry powder on the strengths of steel fibres-reinforced self-consolidation concrete: Experimental and numerical prediction. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>44</b>, 103398 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, Y. F. et al. Effects of red mud on workability and mechanical properties of autoclaved aerated concrete (AAC). <i>J. Build. Eng.</i>10.1016/j.jobe.2022.105238 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.105238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu, J. et al. Performance and microstructure of red-mud-blended concrete under different aqueous environments. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>447</b>, 137988 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao, X. S. et al. In-depth insight into the cementitious synergistic effect of steel slag and red mud on the properties of composite cementitious materials. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>52</b>, 104449 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan, Z. H., Cheng, L., Lu, Y. N. &amp; Yang, N. R. Hydration products of alkali-activated slag&#x2013;red mud cementitious material. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>32</b>, 357&#x2013;362 (2002).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0008-8846(01)00683-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An, Y. X. et al. An efficient and clean utilization technique for red mud based on fluidized bed carbon monoxide reduction. <i>Adv. Powder Technol.</i><b>33</b>, 103828 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apt.2022.103828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, N. et al. Effects of low- and high-calcium fly ash on the water resistance of magnesium oxysulfate cement. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>230</b>, 116951 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.116951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, B. et al. Simultaneous removal of SO<sub>2</sub> and NO using a novel method with red mud as absorbent combined with O<sub>3</sub> oxidation. <i>J. Hazard. Mater.</i><b>392</b>, 122270 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2020.122270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32086090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gon&#xe7;alves, N. P. F., Olhero, S. M., Labrincha, J. A. &amp; Novais, R. M. 3D-printed red mud/metakaolin-based geopolymers as water pollutant sorbents of methylene blue. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>383</b>, 135315 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.135315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, C. Experimental study on preparation and application of high strength cold bonded lightweight aggregates based on two-step transition utilization of red mud together with multi-source solid wastes. 10.27272/d.cnki.gshdu.2023.007120 (In Chinese) (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, B., Zhang, Y. M. &amp; Bao, S. X. Mechanical activation to improve activity of vanadium tailing from stone coal. <i>Metal Mine.</i><b>2</b>, 188&#x2013;192 (2017) (<b>(In Chinese)</b>).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, C. C. &amp; Li, G. Z. Study on light porous unsintered building material. <i>Adv. Mater. Res.</i><b>549</b>, 144&#x2013;148. 10.4028/www.scientific.net/AMR.532-533.144 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4028/www.scientific.net/AMR.532-533.144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanagaraj, B., Anand, N., Samuvel Raj, R. &amp; Lubloy, E. Performance evaluation on engineering properties of sodium silicate binder as a precursor material for the development of cement-free concrete. <i>Dev. Built Env.</i><b>12</b>, 100092 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dibe.2022.100092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanagaraj, B., Anand, N., Samuvel Raj, R. &amp; Lubloy, E. Performance evaluation of sodium silicate waste as a replacement for conventional sand in geopolymer concrete. <i>J. Clean. Product.</i><b>375</b>, 134172 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.134172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, S. C., Zhang, G. L., Zhao, T. J., Wang, H. T. &amp; Jin, Z. Q. Effect of activation mode of Bayer red mud on properties of cement-based materials. <i>Concrete</i><b>6</b>, 29&#x2013;32 (2013) (<b>(In Chinese)</b>).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue, S. G. et al. Research progress of red mud in gelling materials and road applications. <i>Chin. J. Nonferrous Metals.</i><b>33</b>, 3421&#x2013;3439 (2023) (<b>(In Chinese)</b>).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanagaraj, B. et al. Investigation of physical, chemical, mechanical, and microstructural properties of cement-less concrete&#x2014;state-of-the-art review. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>365</b>, 130020 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.130020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, J. X., Li, Z. Y., Zhang, M. L., Wang, S. Q. &amp; Hai, R. Mechanical properties and polymerization mechanism of red mud polymer cement. <i>J. Build. Mater.</i><b>25</b>, 178&#x2013;183 (2022) (<b>(In Chinese)</b>).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geng, J. J. et al. Comparison of red mud and coal gangue blended geopolymers synthesized through thermal activation and mechanical grinding preactivation. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>153</b>, 185&#x2013;192 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.07.045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bao, S. X., Qin, L., Zhang, Y. M., Luo, Y. P. &amp; Huang, X. L. A combined calcination method for activating mixed shale residue and red mud for preparation of geopolymer. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>297</b>, 123789 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, Y. Y., Wang, X. C., Zhou, B., Xu, X. J. &amp; Chen, L. Systematic assessment of a multi&#x2013;solid waste cementitious material: Feasibility and environmental impact. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>428</b>, 136323 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. et al. Preparation, characterization and application of red mud, fly ash and desulfurized gypsum based eco-friendly road base materials. <i>J. Clean. Product.</i><b>284</b>, 124777 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.124777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, Z. T. et al. Solidification/stabilization of chromium slag in red mud-based geopolymer. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>316</b>, 125813 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.125813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, R. Q. et al. Study on the design method of multi-component industrial solid waste low carbon cementitious material with cement as the activator. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater.</i><b>21</b>, e03478 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirthiga, R. &amp; Elavenil, S. Potential utilization of sugarcane bagasse ash in cementitious composites for developing inorganic binder. <i>Ain Shams Eng. J.</i><b>14</b>, 102560 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asej.2023.102560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding, Z. Y., Cheng, Y., Jin, L., Wang, W. T. &amp; Yan, S. Y. Study on the strength characteristics and micro-mechanism of modified solidified red mud. <i>J. Front. Mater.</i><b>11</b>, 1461198 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmats.2024.1461198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, G.L., Cui, W.W., Yang, Z., Zhao, R.Y., Dong, X.Q. Research on basic engineering properties of lkali-activated red mud solidified by slag and silica fume. J. Taiyuan Univ. Technol. 1&#x2013;11; http://kns.cnki.net/kcms/detail/14.1220.N.20231221.1114.002.html. (In Chinese) (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, C. H., Yue, X. T., Jiao, C. B., Zhao, Y. L. &amp; Zhang, X. B. Preparation and properties of red mud based cementitious materials. <i>Bull. Chin. Silic. Soc.</i><b>39</b>, 3574&#x2013;3581 (2020) (<b>(In Chinese)</b>).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, M. H. et al. Size distribution of pores and their geometric analysis in red mud-based autoclaved aerated concrete (AAC) using regression neural network and elastic mechanics. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>359</b>, 129420 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of machinery industry of the people&#x2019;s republic of China. JB-T7510&#x2013;1994 "Process parameter optimization method orthogonal test method" (Chinese standard) (1994).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, C. W. et al. Hydration mechanism and orthogonal optimisation of mix proportion for steel slag-slag-based clinker-free prefabricated concrete. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>228</b>, 117036 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Que, L. L., Zhu, J. L., Wang, F. &amp; Li, Z. R. Mechanical properties of polyethylene fiber reinforced red mud-alkali slag composite materials. <i>J. Compos. Mater.</i><b>39</b>, 5367&#x2013;5374 (2022) (<b>(In Chinese)</b>).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, A. et al. Mechanical properties and microscopic mechanism of basalt fiber-reinforced red mud concrete. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>416</b>, 135155 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, S. N. et al. Strength performance and enhancement mechanism of silty sands stabilized with cement, red mud, and phosphogypsum. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>73</b>, 106762 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duxson, P. et al. Geopolymer technology: the current state of the art. <i>J. Mater. Sci.</i><b>42</b>, 2917&#x2013;2933. 10.1007/s10853-006-0637-z (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10853-006-0637-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, Z. Q. &amp; Guo, J. Y. Study on mechanical properties and microscopic mechanism of lime treated soil. <i>Rock Soil Mech.</i><b>3</b>, 11&#x2013;23 (1991) (<b>(In Chinese)</b>).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu, X. L. et al. Heat release characteristics of lime and time-dependent rheological behaviors of lime-activated fly ash pastes. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater.</i><b>16</b>, e01043 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, X., Fan, X. L. &amp; Yang, C. L. Investigation on physical properties, strength and phase evolution of binary cementitious materials made of CFBC ash and lime. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>265</b>, 120302 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanagaraj, B., Anand, N., Samuvel Raj, R. &amp; Lubloy, E. Techno-socio-economic aspects of portland cement, geopolymer, and limestone calcined clay cement (LC3) composite systems: A-State-of-Art-Review. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>398</b>, 132484 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X. J. et al. Quantification of CO<sub>2</sub> emission from the preparation and utilization of solid waste-based sulphoaluminate cementitious materials. <i>J. Clean. Product.</i><b>376</b>, 134054 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.134054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, W. et al. GB/T 51366&#x2013;2019 &#x201c;Calculation Standards of Building Carbon Emissions&#x201d; (Chinese standard) (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin, B. Research on low carbon concrete ratio based on low cement dosage. 10.27398/d.cnki.gxalu.2024.000280. (In Chinese) (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, C.X. Quantitative analysis of carbon emission of 3D printing building structure based on life cycle assessment. 10.27461/d.cnki.gzjdx.2021.002813. (In Chinese) (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Y. X. et al. Preparation of environmental-friendly cementitious material from red mud and waste glass sludge by mechanical activation. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>423</b>, 135861 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, J. M. et al. Upcycling use of red mud-based solid waste in engineered cementitious composites: Properties, activation mechanism, and life-cycle assessment. <i>J. Clean. Product.</i><b>447</b>, 141504 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.141504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, C. et al. Collaborative recycling of red mud and FGD-gypsum into multi-shell cold bonded lightweight aggregates: Synergistic effect, structure design and application in sustainable concrete. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>379</b>, 131134 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.131134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>