<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39895476</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1439-7641</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Chemphyschem : a European journal of chemical physics and physical chemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Chemphyschem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Charge Transfer Effect on Relaxation Mechanism in Hydrated Pyrrole-Water Systems Following N-2s Ionization.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e202400962</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e202400962</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cphc.202400962</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study investigates the relaxation mechanisms of pyrrole and pyrrole-water clusters (C<sub>4</sub>H<sub>5</sub>N-(H<sub>2</sub>O)<sub>n</sub>, where <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"> <mml:semantics><mml:mrow><mml:mi>n</mml:mi> <mml:mo>=</mml:mo> <mml:mn>0</mml:mn> <mml:mo>-</mml:mo> <mml:mn>3</mml:mn></mml:mrow> <mml:annotation>${n = 0 - 3}$</mml:annotation> </mml:semantics> </mml:math> ) following N-2s ionization of pyrrole. Using various theoretical methods, we focus on the influence of water molecules and charge transfer on these non-radiative relaxation pathways. Our simulations included pyrrole solvated in 494 explicit water molecules equilibrated at 300&#x2005;K and also employed a polarizable continuum model (PCM) to make the system more realistic and gain additional insights. In hydrated environments, the hydrogen bonding network between pyrrole and surrounding water molecules facilitates enhanced non-radiative relaxation pathways following inner valence ionization. Since these are hydrogen bonding systems, we have explored the possibility of proton transfer, which could occur in conjunction with other electronic decay processes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Wiley-VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Ravi</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Academy of Scientific and Innovative Research (AcSIR), Ghaziabad, 201002, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical and Materials Chemistry Division, CSIR-National Chemical Laboratory, Dr. Homi Bhabha Road, Pune, 411008, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhattacharjee</LastName><ForeName>Kankana</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Ashoka University, Sonipat, Haryana, 131029, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghosh</LastName><ForeName>Aryya</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Ashoka University, Sonipat, Haryana, 131029, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vaval</LastName><ForeName>Nayana</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5107-1875</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Academy of Scientific and Innovative Research (AcSIR), Ghaziabad, 201002, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical and Materials Chemistry Division, CSIR-National Chemical Laboratory, Dr. Homi Bhabha Road, Pune, 411008, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>SRG/2022/001115</GrantID><Agency>National Supercomputing Mission, Government of India at Indian Institute of Science, Education and Research (IISER), Pune, India. A.G.</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Chemphyschem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100954211</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1439-4235</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ab&#x2005;initio-calculations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">auger decay</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">charge transfer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">proton transfer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pyrrole</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39895476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cphc.202400962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>S. D. Stoychev, A. I. Kuleff, L. S. Cederbaum, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2011, 133, 6817.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Ren, E. Wang, A. D. Skitnevskaya, A. B. Trofimov, K. Gokhberg, A. Dorn, Nat. Phys. 2018, 14, 1062.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Alizadeh, T. M. Orlando, L. Sanche, Annu. Rev. Phys. Chem. 2015, 66, 379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Erk, D. Rolles, L. Foucar, B. Rudek, S. W. Epp, M. Cryle, C. Bostedt, S. Schorb, J. Bozek, A. Rouzee, A. Hundertmark, T. Marchenko, M. Simon, F. Filsinger, L. Christensen, S. De, S. Trippel, J. K&#xfc;pper, H. Stapelfeldt, S. Wada, K. Ueda, M. Swiggers, M. Messerschmidt, C. D. Schr&#xf6;ter, R. Moshammer, I. Schlichting, J. Ullrich, A. Rudenko, Phys. Rev. Lett. 2013, 110, 053003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Erk, R. Boll, S. Trippel, D. Anielski, L. Foucar, B. Rudek, S. W. Epp, R. Coffee, S. Carron, S. Schorb, K. R. Ferguson, M. Swiggers, J. D. Bozek, M. Simon, T. Marchenko, J. K&#xfc;pper, I. Schlichting, J. Ullrich, C. Bostedt, D. Rolles, A. Rudenko, Science 2014, 345, 288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. I. Kuleff, L. S. Cederbaum, Chem. Phys. 2007, 338, 320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Rudenko, Y. H. Jiang, M. Kurka, K. U. K&#xfc;hnel, L. Foucar, O. Herrwerth, M. Lezius, M. F. Kling, C. D. Schr&#xf6;ter, R. Moshammer, J. Ullrich, J. Phys. B At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 2010, 43, 194004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Zhou, S. Jia, X. Hu, E. Wang, X. Xue, Y. Wu, J. Wang, A. Dorn, X. Ren, Phys. Rev. Lett. 2023, 130, 233001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Slav&#xed;&#x10d;ek, B. Winter, L. S. Cederbaum, N. V. Kryzhevoi, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2014, 136, 18170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Richter, D. Hollas, C.-M. Saak, M. F&#xf6;rstel, T. Miteva, M. Mucke, O. Bj&#xf6;rneholm, N. Sisourat, P. Slav&#xed;&#x10d;ek, U. Hergenhahn, Nat. Commun. 2018, 9, 4988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. S. Cederbaum, J. Zobeley, F. Tarantelli, Phys. Rev. Lett. 1997, 79, 4778.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Jahnke, U. Hergenhahn, B. Winter, R. D&#xf6;rner, U. Fr&#xfc;hling, P. V. Demekhin, K. Gokhberg, L. S. Cederbaum, A. Ehresmann, A. Knie, A. Dreuw, Chem. Rev. 2020, 120, 11295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Jahnke, J. Phys. B: At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 2015, 48, 082001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Jahnke, A. Czasch, M. S. Sch&#xf6;ffler, S. Sch&#xf6;ssler, A. Knapp, M. K&#xe4;sz, J. Titze, C. Wimmer, K. Kreidi, R. E. Grisenti, A. Staudte, O. Jagutzki, U. Hergenhahn, H. Schmidt-B&#xf6;cking, R. D&#xf6;rner, Phys. Rev. Lett. 2004, 93, 163401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Marburger, O. Kugeler, U. Hergenhahn, T. M&#xf6;ller, Phys. Rev. Lett. 2003, 90, 203401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Zobeley, R. Santra, L. S. Cederbaum, J. Chem. Phys. 2001, 115, 5076.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>E. Fasshauer, M. F&#xf6;rstel, T. Arion, U. Hergenhahn, Chem. Phys. 2017, 482, 226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. F&#xf6;rstel, M. Mucke, T. Arion, A. M. Bradshaw, U. Hergenhahn, Phys. Rev. Lett. 2011, 106, 033402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Yan, P. Zhang, X. Ma, S. Xu, B. Li, X. L. Zhu, W. T. Feng, S. F. Zhang, D. M. Zhao, R. Zhang, D. Guo, H. P. Liu, Phys. Rev. A 2013, 88, 042712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. T. Walsh, S. Garneau-Tsodikova, A. R. Howard-Jones, Nat. Prod. Rep. 2006, 23, 517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. T. Ulijasz, G. Cornilescu, C. C. Cornilescu, J. Zhang, M. Rivera, J. L. Markley, R. D. Vierstra, Nature 2010, 463, 250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. N. R. Ashfold, B. Cronin, A. L. Devine, R. N. Dixon, M. G. D. Nix, Science 2006, 312, 1637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y.-S. Yen, Y.-C. Hsu, J. T. Lin, C.-W. Chang, C.-P. Hsu, D.-J. Yin, J. Phys. Chem. C 2008, 112, 12557.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. M. Marques, J. Biol. Inorg. Chem. 2024, 29, 641&#x2013;683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Liu, F. Wu, Nanoscale Adv. 2023, 5, 3606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. H. Borges, B. E. Nagay, R. C. Costa, J. ao Gabriel S Souza, M. T. Mathew, V. A. B. ao, Adv. Colloid Interface Sci. 2023, 314, 102860.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Sood, K. Singh, H. Mudila, P. Lokhande, L. Singh, D. Kumar, A. Kumar, N. M. Mubarak, M. H. Dehghani, Heliyon 2024, 10, e33643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. K. Zborowski, J. Poater, ACS Omega 2021, 6, 24693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Sapunar, A. Ponzi, S. Chaiwongwattana, M. Mali&#x161;, A. Prlj, P. Decleva, N. Do&#x161;li&#x107;, Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2015, 17, 19012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O. M. Kirkby, M. A. Parkes, S. P. Neville, G. A. Worth, H. H. Fielding, Chem. Phys. Lett. 2017, 683, 179.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. D. Skitnevskaya, K. Gokhberg, A. B. Trofimov, E. K. Grigoricheva, A. I. Kuleff, L. S. Cederbaum, J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2023, 14, 1418.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Johny, C. A. Schouder, A. Al-Refaie, L. He, J. Wiese, H. Stapelfeldt, S. Trippel, J. K&#xfc;pper, Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2024, 26, 13118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Slavicek, B. Winter, L. S. Cederbaum, N. V. Kryzhevoi, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2014, 136, 18170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Ghosh, S. Pal, N. Vaval, J. Chem. Phys. 2013, 139, 064112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>I. Unger, R. Seidel, S. Th&#xfc;rmer, M. N. Pohl, E. F. Aziz, L. S. Cederbaum, E. Muchov&#xe1;, P. Slav&#xed;&#x10d;ek, B. Winter, N. V. Kryzhevoi, Nat. Chem. 2017, 9, 708&#x2013;714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. D. Becke, J. Chem. Phys. 1993, 98, 5648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Lee, W. Yang, R. G. Parr, Phys. Rev. B 1988, 37, 785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. J. Stephens, F. J. Devlin, C. F. Chabalowski, M. J. Frisch, J. Phys. Chem. 1994, 98, 11623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Krishnan, J. S. Binkley, R. Seeger, J. A. Pople, J. Chem. Phys. 1980, 72, 650.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Werner, P. J. Knowles, J. Chem. Phys. 1985, 82, 5053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Andersson, P. &#xc5;. Malmqvist, B. O. Roos, A. J. Sadlej, K. Wolinski, J. Phys. Chem. 1990, 94, 5483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K. Andersson, P. &#xc5;. Malmqvist, B. O. Roos, J. Chem. Phys. 1992, 96, 1218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Aquilante, J. Autschbach, R. K. Carlson, L. F. Chibotaru, M. G. Delcey, L. De Vico, I. Fdez Galv&#xe9;n, N. Ferr&#xe9;, L. M. Frutos, L. Gagliardi, M. Garavelli, A. Giussani, C. E. Hoyer, G. Li Manni, H. Lischka, D. Ma, P. &#xc5;. Malmqvist, T. M&#xfc;ller, A. Nenov, M. Olivucci, T. B. Pedersen, D. Peng, F. Plasser, B. Pritchard, M. Reiher, I. Rivalta, I. Schapiro, J. Segarra-Mart&#xed;, M. Stenrup, D. G. Truhlar, L. Ungur, A. Valentini, S. Vancoillie, V. Veryazov, V. P. Vysotskiy, O. Weingart, F. Zapata, R. Lindh, J. Comput. Chem. 2016, 37, 506.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Xiong, S. Izadi, A. V. Onufriev, J. Chem. Theory Comput. 2023, 19, 377.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Case, H. Aktulga, K. Belfon, I. Ben-Shalom, J. Berryman, S. Brozell, D. Cerutti, T.&#x2005;C. III, G. Cisneros, V. Cruzeiro, T. Darden, N. Forouzesh, M. Ghazimirsaeed, G. Giamba&#x15f;u, T. Giese, M. Gilson, H. Gohlke, A. Goetz, J. Harris, Z. Huang, S. Izadi, S. Izmailov, K. Kasavajhala, M. Kaymak, A. Kovalenko, T. Kurtzman, T. Lee, P. Li, Z. Li, C. Lin, J. Liu, T. Luchko, R. Luo, M. Machado, M. Manathunga, K. Merz, Y. Miao, O. Mikhailovskii, G. Monard, H. Nguyen, K. O'Hearn, A. Onufriev, F. Pan, S. Pantano, A. Rahnamoun, D. Roe, A. Roitberg, C. Sagui, S. Schott-Verdugo, A. Shajan, J. Shen, C. Simmerling, N. Skrynnikov, J. Smith, J. Swails, R. Walker, J. Wang, J. Wang, X. Wu, Y. Wu, Y. Xiong, Y. Xue, D. York, C. Zhao, Q. Zhu,, P. Kollman, Amber 2024, University of California: SanFrancisco 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Averbukh, I. B. M&#xfc;ller, L. S. Cederbaum, Phys. Rev. Lett. 2004, 93, 263002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M.&#x2005;J. Frisch, G.&#x2005;W. Trucks, H.&#x2005;B. Schlegel, G.&#x2005;E. Scuseria, M.&#x2005;A. Robb, J.&#x2005;R. Cheeseman, G. Scalmani, V. Barone, B. Mennucci, G.&#x2005;A. Petersson, H. Nakatsuji, M. Caricato, X. Li, H.&#x2005;P. Hratchian, A.&#x2005;F. Izmaylov, J. Bloino, G. Zheng, J.&#x2005;L. Sonnenberg, M. Hada, M. Ehara, K. Toyota, R. Fukuda, J. Hasegawa, M. Ishida, T. Nakajima, Y. Honda, O. Kitao, H. Nakai, T. Vreven, J. Montgomery, J.&#x2005;A., J.&#x2005;E. Peralta, F. Ogliaro, M. Bearpark, J.&#x2005;J. Heyd, E. Brothers, K.&#x2005;N. Kudin, V.&#x2005;N. Staroverov, R. Kobayashi, J. Norm, K. Raghavachari, A. Rendell, J.&#x2005;C. Burant, S.&#x2005;S. Iyengar, J. Tomasi, M. Cossi, N. Rega, J.&#x2005;M. Millam, M. Klene, J.&#x2005;E. Knox, J.&#x2005;B. Cross, V. Bakken, C. Adamo, J. Jaramillo, R. Gomperts, R.&#x2005;E. Stratmann, O. Yazyev, A.&#x2005;J. Austin, R. Cammi, C. Pomelli, J.&#x2005;W. Ochterski, R.&#x2005;L. Martin, K. Morokuma, V.&#x2005;G. Zakrzewski, G.&#x2005;A. Voth, P. Salvador, J.&#x2005;J. Dannenberg, S. Dapprich, A.&#x2005;D. Daniels, O. Farkas, J.&#x2005;B. Foresman, J.&#x2005;V. Ortiz, J. Cioslowski, D.&#x2005;J. Fox, Gaussian-09 Gaussian Inc., Wallingford CT 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. A. Kendall, T. H. Dunning, R. J. Harrison, J. Chem. Phys. 1992, 96, 6796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. J. Bartlett, M. Musia&#x142;, Rev. Mod. Phys. 2007, 79, 291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. I. Lyakh, M. Musia&#x142;, V. F. Lotrich, R. J. Bartlett, Chem. Rev. 2012, 112, 182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Nooijen, R. J. Bartlett, J. Chem. Phys. 1995, 102, 3629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Kumar, A. Ghosh, N. Vaval, J. Chem. Theory Comput. 2022, 18, 807.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Kumar, N. Vaval, ChemPhysChem 2023, 24, e202200340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Kumar, A. Ghosh, N. Vaval, J. Chem. Phys. 2024, 160, 214302.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>