<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41272713</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1479-5876</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of translational medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Transl Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Feeding intelligence: comparative evaluation of ChatGPT and clinical guidelines for nutritional management in head and neck cancer.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1437</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1437</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1437</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12967-025-07477-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Artificial intelligence (AI) tools such as ChatGPT are increasingly applied in digital health and patient education, yet their alignment with established clinical guidelines for cancer-related nutritional management remains unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to evaluate the concordance, functional characteristics, patient accessibility, and innovation of ChatGPT-generated nutritional recommendations compared with clinical guidelines from the Chinese Society of Clinical Oncology (CSCO), Chinese Nutrition Society (CNS), and European Society for Clinical Nutrition and Metabolism (ESPEN).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We analyzed ChatGPT responses across six key nutrition-related issues&#x2014;anorexia/cachexia, dysphagia, oral mucositis, unintentional weight loss, gastrointestinal intolerance, and nutritional monitoring&#x2014;and compared them with guideline recommendations. Expert evaluation (<i>n</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;5), readability metrics, semantic similarity (TF-IDF), and patient-centered assessments were conducted to compare personalization, innovation, clinical feasibility, evidence-based support, population applicability, clarity, and self-management guidance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">ChatGPT recommendations aligned with at least one guideline in 50.0&#x2013;64.3% of cases, highest for dysphagia (64.3%), and included general strategies such as small frequent meals, texture modification, hydration, and high-protein/high-calorie intake. ChatGPT-specific suggestions (8.3&#x2013;18.2%) focused on lifestyle and behavioral interventions, including mindful eating, music therapy, and wearable diet trackers. Expert ratings indicated higher personalization (4.3/5) and innovation (4.6/5) for ChatGPT, whereas guidelines scored higher for clinical feasibility (4.7/5), evidence-based support (4.9/5), and population applicability (4.8/5). Between-group differences were statistically significant for clinical feasibility, evidence-based support, and applicability (all <i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01; 95% CI for mean differences: 0.62&#x2013;1.12), whereas personalization showed no significant difference (<i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.063). ChatGPT exhibited superior patient-centered performance in clarity (4.5 vs. 3.2, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.004, 95% CI: 0.47&#x2013;2.13) and self-management guidance (4.6 vs. 3.0, <i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.002, 95% CI: 0.65&#x2013;2.05) and demonstrated more concise, readable content (Flesch&#x2013;Kincaid grade 12.9&#x2013;14.2) compared with guidelines (17.9&#x2013;20.5). Semantic analysis revealed moderate overlap with CSCO (&#x2248;&#x2009;0.63) and CNS (&#x2248;&#x2009;0.59), and lower similarity with ESPEN (&#x2248;&#x2009;0.47), highlighting ChatGPT&#x2019;s use of patient-friendly language. Topic modeling identified three clusters: patient support and accessibility (ChatGPT), technical nutrition therapy (ESPEN/CSCO), and nutritional assessment and monitoring (CNS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">ChatGPT provides personalized, innovative, and patient-accessible nutritional guidance for cancer-related malnutrition, complementing traditional clinical guidelines. While guidelines remain essential for evidence-based decision-making, AI tools may enhance patient education, engagement, and self-management in digital health applications.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1186/s12967-025-07477-0.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Shasha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9987-0801</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Head and Neck Oncology, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Zunyi Medical University, Zunyi, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Kai</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Abdominal Oncology, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Zunyi Medical University, Zunyi, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Mingna</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Head and Neck Oncology, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Zunyi Medical University, Zunyi, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Dahai</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Zunyi Medical University, Zunyi, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Xiaotong</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Zunyi Medical University, Zunyi, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Peijie</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Zunyi Medical University, Zunyi, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Head and Neck Oncology, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Zunyi Medical University, Zunyi, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Sijia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Head and Neck Oncology, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Zunyi Medical University, Zunyi, Guizhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gou</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoxia</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3842-4007</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Head and Neck Oncology, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Zunyi Medical University, Zunyi, Guizhou, China. gouxx2020@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No. 006 [2023]</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Project of the Guizhou Anti-Cancer Association</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>EXZL-GX-028</GrantID><Agency>Beijing Huakang Charity Foundation Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>ZSKH-HZ-2025-124</GrantID><Agency>Zunyi Science and Technology Bureau</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>ZSKH-HZ-2025-147</GrantID><Agency>Zunyi Science and Technology Bureau</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Transl Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101190741</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1479-5876</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AI-assisted guidance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ChatGPT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nutrition management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patient education</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethical approval: Not applicable. This study did not involve real patients or the collection of identifiable clinical data. The &#x201c;patient panel&#x201d; was composed of simulated participants recruited from research affiliates to approximate patient perspectives. As such, formal ethics committee approval was not required. The evaluation was conducted in accordance with institutional ethical standards. We acknowledge, however, that simulated participants may not fully capture the lived experiences of cancer survivors, and future studies should incorporate ethically approved recruitment of real patients to enhance representativeness and validity. Originality and publication status: This manuscript is original, has not been published previously, and is not under consideration for publication elsewhere in any language. AI/Internet tool statement: All recommendations generated by ChatGPT in this study were used solely for research and comparative purposes and were not applied in clinical decision-making. AI outputs do not constitute medical guidance. Any clinical implementation of AI-generated recommendations should occur under expert supervision and in accordance with local regulations. Consent to participate / Consent for publication: Not applicable. Conflict of interest: The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41272713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12754952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-025-07477-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12967-025-07477-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Jin S, Wang Y, Zhang Z, Jia H, Li D, Lu Q. Predict nutrition-related adverse outcomes in head and neck cancer patients undergoing radiotherapy: A systematic review. Radiother Oncol. 2024;197:110339. 10.1016/j.radonc.2024.110339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.radonc.2024.110339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38795812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varkey P, Tang WR, Tan NC. Nutrition in head and neck cancer patients. Semin Plast Surg. 2010;24:325&#x2013;30. 10.1055/s-0030-1263074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0030-1263074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3324234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22550454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter M, Kellett J, Toohey K, D&#x2019;Cunha NM, Isbel S, Naumovski N. Toxicities caused by head and neck cancer treatments and their influence on the development of malnutrition: review of the literature. Eur J Investig Health Psychol Educ. 2020;10:935&#x2013;49. 10.3390/ejihpe10040066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ejihpe10040066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8314324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34542427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anghel R, B&#xee;lteanu L, Folea AR, Marinescu &#x218;A, Pisoschi AM, Alexandrescu MF, Dumachi AI, Gale&#x219; LN, Trif&#x103;nescu OG, Zgur&#x103; AF, et al. Assessing the impact of nutritional status on the quality of life in head and neck cancer patients-the need for comprehensive digital tools. Cancers (Basel). 2025;17. 10.3390/cancers17071128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11987966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40227666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes M, Ferreira PMV, Almeida A, Corn&#xe9;lio JS, Arruda TJ, Mafra A, Nunes MHS, Salera RB, Nogueira RF, Sclauser JMB, et al. Dysphagia, nutritional status, and quality of life in patients with head and neck cancer undergoing radiotherapy alone or combined with chemotherapy: an observational study. BMC Cancer. 2025;25:416. 10.1186/s12885-025-13695-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12885-025-13695-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11887319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40055649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muthanandam S, Muthu J. Understanding cachexia in head and neck cancer. Asia Pac J Oncol Nurs. 2021;8:527&#x2013;38. 10.4103/apjon.apjon-2145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/apjon.apjon-2145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8420913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34527782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chera BS, Eisbruch A, Murphy BA, Ridge JA, Gavin P, Reeve BB, Bruner DW, Movsas B. Recommended patient-reported core set of symptoms to measure in head and neck cancer treatment trials. J Natl Cancer Inst. 2014;106. 10.1093/jnci/dju127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4192043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25006189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levonyak NS, Hodges MP, Haaf N, Brown TJ, Hardy S, Mhoon V, Kainthla R, Beg MS, Kazmi SM. Importance of addressing malnutrition in cancer and implementation of a quality improvement project in a Gastrointestinal cancer clinic. Nutr Clin Pract. 2022;37:215&#x2013;23. 10.1002/ncp.10753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ncp.10753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34339072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lygizos V, Haidopoulos D, Vlachos DE, Varthaliti A, Fanaki M, Daskalakis G, Thomakos N, Pergialiotis V. Immunonutrition in ERAS protocol for patients with gynecologic cancer: a narrative review of the literature. Life (Basel). 2025;15. 10.3390/life15030487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11943961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40141831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muscaritoli M, Arends J, Bachmann P, Baracos V, Barthelemy N, Bertz H, Bozzetti F, H&#xfc;tterer E, Isenring E, Kaasa S, et al. ESPEN practical guideline: clinical nutrition in cancer. Clin Nutr. 2021;40:2898&#x2013;913. 10.1016/j.clnu.2021.02.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2021.02.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33946039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Expert consensus on the nutritional therapy for patients with malignancies. Chin Clin Oncol. 2013;2:24. 10.3978/j.issn.2304-3865.2012.12.04.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3978/j.issn.2304-3865.2012.12.04</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25841680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denlinger CS, Ligibel JA, Are M, Baker KS, Demark-Wahnefried W, Dizon D, Friedman DL, Goldman M, Jones L, King A, et al. Survivorship: nutrition and weight management, version 2.2014. Clinical practice guidelines in oncology. J Natl Compr Canc Netw. 2014;12:1396&#x2013;406. 10.6004/jnccn.2014.0137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.6004/jnccn.2014.0137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4465236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25313179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergerot CD, Bergerot PG, Philip EJ, Ferrari R, Peixoto RM, Crane TE, Schmitz KH, Soto-Perez-de-Celis E. Enhancing cancer supportive care: integrating psychosocial Support, Nutrition, and physical activity using telehealth solutions. JCO Glob Oncol. 2024;10:e2400333. 10.1200/go-24-00333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/go-24-00333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11583352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39509661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondrup J, Allison SP, Elia M, Vellas B, Plauth M. ESPEN guidelines for nutrition screening 2002. Clin Nutr. 2003;22:415&#x2013;21. 10.1016/s0261-5614(03)00098-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0261-5614(03)00098-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12880610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Liu X, Ji W, Zhao Y, He Y, Liu Y, Li Q, Shi H, Cui J. The PG-SGA outperforms the NRS 2002 for nutritional risk screening in cancer patients: a retrospective study from China. Front Nutr. 2023;10:1272420. 10.3389/fnut.2023.1272420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2023.1272420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10702952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38075213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinovic D, Tokic D, Puizina Mladinic E, Usljebrka M, Kadic S, Lesin A, Vilovic M, Lupi-Ferandin S, Ercegovic S, Kumric M, et al. Nutritional management of patients with head and neck cancer-a comprehensive review. Nutrients. 2023;15. 10.3390/nu15081864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10144914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37111081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holdoway A, Page F, Bauer J, Dervan N, Maier AB. Individualised nutritional care for disease-related malnutrition: improving outcomes by focusing on what matters to patients. Nutrients. 2022;14. 10.3390/nu14173534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9460401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36079795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theodore Armand TP, Nfor KA, Kim JI, Kim HC. Applications of artificial Intelligence, machine learning, and deep learning in nutrition: a systematic review. Nutrients. 2024;16. 10.3390/nu16071073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11013624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38613106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papastratis I, Konstantinidis D, Daras P, Dimitropoulos K. AI nutrition recommendation using a deep generative model and ChatGPT. Sci Rep. 2024;14:14620. 10.1038/s41598-024-65438-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-65438-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11199627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38918477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varayil JE, Bielinski SJ, Mundi MS, Bonnes SL, Salonen BR, Hurt RT. Artificial intelligence in clinical nutrition: bridging data analytics and nutritional care. Curr Nutr Rep. 2025;14:91. 10.1007/s13668-025-00680-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13668-025-00680-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40608213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassem H, Beevi AA, Basheer S, Lutfi G, Cheikh Ismail L, Papandreou D. Investigation and assessment of AI&#x2019;s role in nutrition-an updated narrative review of the evidence. Nutrients. 2025;17. 10.3390/nu17010190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11723148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39796624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai CY, Cheng PY, Deng JH, Jaw FS, Yii SC. ChatGPT v4 outperforming v3.5 on cancer treatment recommendations in quality, clinical guideline, and expert opinion concordance. Digit Health. 2024;10:20552076241269538. 10.1177/20552076241269538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20552076241269538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11325467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39148811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alami K, Willemse E, Quiriny M, Lipski S, Laurent C, Donquier V, Digonnet A. Evaluation of ChatGPT-4&#x2019;s performance in therapeutic Decision-Making during multidisciplinary oncology meetings for head and neck squamous cell carcinoma. Cureus. 2024;16:e68808. 10.7759/cureus.68808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.68808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11456411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39376890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maity S, MJ Saikia. Large Language models in healthcare and medical applications: a review. Bioeng (Basel). 2025;12. 10.3390/bioengineering12060631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12189880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40564447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kianian R, Sun D, Rojas-Carabali W, Agrawal R, Tsui E. Large Language models May help patients understand Peer-Reviewed scientific articles about ophthalmology: development and usability study. J Med Internet Res. 2024;26:e59843. 10.2196/59843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/59843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11707445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39719077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou HJ, Deng LJ, Wang T, Chen JX, Jiang SZ, Yang L, Liu F, Weng MH, Hu JW, Tan JY. Clinical practice guidelines for the nutritional risk screening and assessment of cancer patients: a systematic quality appraisal using the AGREE II instrument. Support Care Cancer. 2021;29:2885&#x2013;93. 10.1007/s00520-021-06094-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-021-06094-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33638747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ponzo V, Rosato R, Scigliano MC, Onida M, Cossai S, De Vecchi M, Devecchi A, Goitre I, Favaro E, Merlo FD, et al. Comparison of the accuracy, completeness, reproducibility, and consistency of different AI chatbots in providing nutritional advice: an exploratory study. J Clin Med. 2024;13. 10.3390/jcm13247810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11677083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39768733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin MJ, Hsieh LC, Chen CK. Evaluating ChatGPT&#x2019;s concordance with clinical guidelines of M&#xe9;ni&#xe8;re&#x2019;s disease in Chinese. Diagnostics (Basel). 2025;15. 10.3390/diagnostics15162006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12385325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40870857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandya S, Bresler TE, Wilson T, Htway Z, Fujita M. Decoding the NCCN guidelines with AI: A comparative evaluation of ChatGPT-4.0 and Llama 2 in the management of thyroid carcinoma. Am Surg. 2025;91:94&#x2013;8. 10.1177/00031348241269430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00031348241269430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39136578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucas HC, Upperman JS, Robinson JR. A systematic review of large Language models and their implications in medical education. Med Educ. 2024;58:1276&#x2013;85. 10.1111/medu.15402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/medu.15402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38639098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirk D, van Eijnatten E, Camps G. Comparison of answers between ChatGPT and human dieticians to common nutrition questions. J Nutr Metab. 2023;2023:5548684. 10.1155/2023/5548684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2023/5548684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10645493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38025546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atwal K. Artificial intelligence in clinical nutrition and dietetics: A brief overview of current evidence. Nutr Clin Pract. 2024;39:736&#x2013;42. 10.1002/ncp.11150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ncp.11150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38591653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sguanci M, Palomares SM, Cangelosi G, Petrelli F, Sandri E, Ferrara G, Mancin S. Artificial intelligence in the management of malnutrition in cancer patients: A systematic review. Adv Nutr. 2025;16:100438. 10.1016/j.advnut.2025.100438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.advnut.2025.100438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12281439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40334987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traylor DO, Kern KV, Anderson EE, Henderson R. Beyond the screen: the impact of generative artificial intelligence (AI) on patient learning and the patient-Physician relationship. Cureus. 2025;17:e76825doi. 10.7759/cureus.76825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.76825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11787409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39897260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekbolatova M, Mayer J, Ong CW, Toma M. Transformative potential of AI in healthcare: definitions, applications, and navigating the ethical landscape and public perspectives. Healthc (Basel). 2024;12. 10.3390/healthcare12020125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10815906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38255014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J, Wang C, Liu S. Utility of ChatGPT in clinical practice. J Med Internet Res. 2023;25:e48568. 10.2196/48568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/48568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10365580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37379067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Z, Liu J, Fan Y, Lu S, Xu D, Yang Y, Wang H, Mao J, Tseng HC, Chang TH, Chen Y. Ability of ChatGPT to replace Doctors in patient education: Cross-Sectional comparative analysis of inflammatory bowel disease. J Med Internet Res. 2025;27:e62857. 10.2196/62857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/62857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11997527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40163853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aydin S, Karabacak M, Vlachos V, Margetis K. Large Language models in patient education: a scoping review of applications in medicine. Front Med (Lausanne). 2024;11:1477898. 10.3389/fmed.2024.1477898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2024.1477898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11554522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39534227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paasche-Orlow MK, Taylor HA, Brancati FL. Readability standards for informed-consent forms as compared with actual readability. N Engl J Med. 2003;348:721&#x2013;6. 10.1056/NEJMsa021212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMsa021212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12594317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wasir AS, Volgman AS, Jolly M. Assessing readability and comprehension of web-based patient education materials by American heart association (AHA) and cardiosmart online platform by American college of cardiology (ACC): how useful are these websites for patient understanding? Am Heart J Plus. 2023;32:100308. 10.1016/j.ahjo.2023.100308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ahjo.2023.100308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10946022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38510202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okuhara T, Furukawa E, Okada H, Yokota R, Kiuchi T. Readability of written information for patients across 30 years: A systematic review of systematic reviews. Patient Educ Couns. 2025;135:108656. 10.1016/j.pec.2025.108656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pec.2025.108656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40068244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bader M, Zheng L, Rao D, Shiyanbola O, Myers L, Davis T, O&#x2019;Leary C, McKee M, Wolf M, Assaf AR. Towards a more patient-centered clinical trial process: A systematic review of interventions incorporating health literacy best practices. Contemp Clin Trials. 2022;116:106733. 10.1016/j.cct.2022.106733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cct.2022.106733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9196949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35301134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gencer A. Readability analysis of chatgpt&#x2019;s responses on lung cancer. Sci Rep. 2024;14:17234. 10.1038/s41598-024-67293-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-67293-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11282056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39060365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onder CE, Koc G, Gokbulut P, Taskaldiran I, Kuskonmaz SM. Evaluation of the reliability and readability of ChatGPT-4 responses regarding hypothyroidism during pregnancy. Sci Rep. 2024;14:243. 10.1038/s41598-023-50884-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-50884-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10761760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38167988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golan R, Ripps SJ, Reddy R, Loloi J, Bernstein AP, Connelly ZM, Golan NS, Ramasamy R. ChatGPT&#x2019;s ability to assess quality and readability of online medical information: evidence from a Cross-Sectional study. Cureus. 2023;15:e42214. 10.7759/cureus.42214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.42214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10362474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37484787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brali&#x107; N, Mijatovi&#x107; A, Maru&#x161;i&#x107; A, Buljan I. Conclusiveness, readability and textual characteristics of plain Language summaries from medical and non-medical organizations: a cross-sectional study. Sci Rep. 2024;14:6016. 10.1038/s41598-024-56727-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-56727-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10933350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38472285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picton B, Andalib S, Spina A, Camp B, Solomon SS, Liang J, Chen PM, Chen JW, Hsu FP, Oh MY. Assessing AI simplification of medical texts: readability and content fidelity. Int J Med Inf. 2025;195:105743. 10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2024.105743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2024.105743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39667051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gondode P, Duggal S, Garg N, Lohakare P, Jakhar J, Bharti S, Dewangan S. Comparative analysis of Accuracy, Readability, Sentiment, and actionability: artificial intelligence chatbots (ChatGPT and Google Gemini) versus traditional patient information leaflets for local anesthesia in eye surgery. Br Ir Orthopt J. 2024;20:183&#x2013;92. 10.22599/bioj.377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22599/bioj.377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11342839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39183761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma L, Chen R, Ge W, Rogers P, Lyn-Cook B, Hong H, Tong W, Wu N, Zou W. AI-powered topic modeling: comparing LDA and BERTopic in analyzing opioid-related cardiovascular risks in women. Exp Biol Med (Maywood). 2025;250:10389. 10.3389/ebm.2025.10389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/ebm.2025.10389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11906279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40093658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ponzo V, Goitre I, Favaro E, Merlo FD, Mancino MV, Riso S, Bo S. Is ChatGPT an effective tool for providing dietary advice? Nutrients. 2024;16. 10.3390/nu16040469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10892804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38398794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee VV, van der Lubbe SCC, Goh LH, Valderas JM. Harnessing ChatGPT for thematic analysis: are we ready? J Med Internet Res. 2024;26:e54974. 10.2196/54974.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/54974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11179012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38819896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatziisaak D, Burri P, Sparn M, Hahnloser D, Steffen T, Bischofberger S. Concordance of ChatGPT artificial intelligence decision-making in colorectal cancer multidisciplinary meetings: retrospective study. BJS Open. 2025;9. 10.1093/bjsopen/zraf040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12056934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40331891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tun HM, Rahman HA, Naing L, Malik OA. Trust in artificial Intelligence-Based clinical decision support systems among health care workers: systematic review. J Med Internet Res. 2025;27:e69678. 10.2196/69678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/69678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12440830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40772775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elhaddad M, Hamam S. AI-Driven clinical decision support systems: an ongoing pursuit of potential. Cureus. 2024;16:e57728. 10.7759/cureus.57728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.57728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11073764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38711724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>