<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38351381</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1755-4349</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature chemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Chem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A charge-neutral organic cage selectively binds strongly hydrated sulfate anions in water.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>335</StartPage><EndPage>342</EndPage><MedlinePgn>335-342</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41557-024-01457-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In biological systems, enzymes and transport proteins can bind anions in aqueous media solely by forming hydrogen bonds with charge-neutral motifs. Reproducing this functionality in synthetic systems presents challenges and incurs high costs, particularly when targeting strongly hydrated anions such as sulfate. Here we report a [2.2.2]urea cryptand (cage), synthesized in one pot, that selectively binds sulfate in a mixture of dimethyl sulfoxide and water and in water with affinities in the micromolar to millimolar range. The neutral cage bearing six urea groups donates 12 strong hydrogen bonds to encapsulate a sulfate anion, showing favourable enthalpy even in pure water. Sulfate binding can be further enhanced by using micelles to provide a low-polarity microenvironment. The cage finds utility in analysing divalent anions in water and beverage samples or in removing sulfate. The work demonstrates the achievability of robust and selective anion binding in water with minimal synthetic efforts, by using neutral NH hydrogen bonds akin to those found in biology.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Limited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jing</LastName><ForeName>Liuyang</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-4461-9111</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fujian Provincial Key Laboratory of Innovative Drug Target Research, School of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Xiamen University, Xiamen, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deplazes</LastName><ForeName>Evelyne</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2052-5536</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Molecular Biosciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Queensland, Australia. e.deplazes@uq.edu.au.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clegg</LastName><ForeName>Jack K</ForeName><Initials>JK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7140-5596</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Molecular Biosciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7715-8784</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fujian Provincial Key Laboratory of Innovative Drug Target Research, School of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Xiamen University, Xiamen, China. xin.wu@xmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Molecular Biosciences, The University of Queensland, St Lucia, Queensland, Australia. xin.wu@xmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MOE Key Laboratory of Spectrochemical Analysis and Instrumentation, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Xiamen University, Xiamen, China. xin.wu@xmu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>DE220101000</GrantID><Agency>Department of Education and Training | Australian Research Council (ARC)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>LE170100144</GrantID><Agency>Department of Education and Training | Australian Research Council (ARC)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>21820102006</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>92356308</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China (National Science Foundation of China)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Chem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101499734</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1755-4330</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38351381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41557-024-01457-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41557-024-01457-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wu, X., Gilchrist, A. M. &amp; Gale, P. A. Prospects and challenges in anion recognition and transport. Chem 6, 1296&#x2013;1309 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNaughton, D. A. et al. New insights and discoveries in anion receptor chemistry. Chem 9, 3045&#x2013;3112 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langton, M. J., Serpell, C. J. &amp; Beer, P. D. Anion recognition in water: recent advances from a supramolecular and macromolecular perspective. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 55, 1974&#x2013;1987 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcus, Y. Ions in Solution and their Solvation 107&#x2013;155 (Wiley, 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luecke, H. &amp; Quiocho, F. A. High specificity of a phosphate transport protein determined by hydrogen bonds. Nature 347, 402&#x2013;406 (1990).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2215649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pflugrath, J. W. &amp; Quiocho, F. A. Sulphate sequestered in the sulphate-binding protein of Salmonella typhimurium is bound solely by hydrogen bonds. Nature 314, 257&#x2013;260 (1985).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3885043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jentsch, T. J. &amp; Pusch, M. CLC chloride channels and transporters: structure, function, physiology, and disease. Physiol. Rev. 98, 1493&#x2013;1590 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29845874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foyle, E., Mason, T., Coote, M., Izgorodina, E. &amp; White, N. Robust organic cages prepared using hydrazone condensation display sulfate/hydrogenphosphate selectivity in water. Preprint at ChemRxiv https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2021-qqhs8 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, H. et al. Highly selective fluorescent recognition of sulfate in water by two rigid tetrakisimidazolium macrocycles with peripheral chains. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 135, 14908&#x2013;14911 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24011256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Custelcean, R., Bosano, J., Bonnesen, P. V., Kertesz, V. &amp; Hay, B. P. Computer-aided design of a sulfate-encapsulating receptor. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 48, 4025&#x2013;4029 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiala, T., Sleziakova, K., Marsalek, K., Salvadori, K. &amp; Sindelar, V. Thermodynamics of halide binding to a neutral bambusuril in water and organic solvents. J. Org. Chem. 83, 1903&#x2013;1912 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29372640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lisbjerg, M., Nielsen, B. E., Milhoj, B. O., Sauer, S. P. A. &amp; Pittelkow, M. Anion binding by biotin[6]uril in water. Org. Biomol. Chem. 13, 369&#x2013;373 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25407665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borissov, A. et al. Anion recognition in water by charge-neutral halogen and chalcogen bonding foldamer receptors. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 141, 4119&#x2013;4129 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30730716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sommer, F., Marcus, Y. &amp; Kubik, S. Effects of solvent properties on the anion binding of neutral water-soluble bis(cyclopeptides) in water and aqueous solvent mixtures. ACS Omega 2, 3669&#x2013;3680 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31457681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6641638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubik, S. Anion recognition in aqueous media by cyclopeptides and other synthetic receptors. Acc. Chem. Res. 50, 2870&#x2013;2878 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29125287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, L., Hartley, A., Turner, P., Elmes, R. B. P. &amp; Jolliffe, K. A. Macrocyclic squaramides: anion receptors with high sulfate binding affinity and selectivity in aqueous media. Chem. Sci. 7, 4563&#x2013;4572 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30155103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6014085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin, L. et al. Receptors for sulfate that function across a wide pH range in mixed aqueous&#x2013;DMSO media. Chem. Commun. 55, 12312&#x2013;12315 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, H. et al. A hexapodal capsule for the recognition of anions. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 143, 3874&#x2013;3880 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33656878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., Zhao, W., Chen, C.-H. &amp; Flood, A. H. Chloride capture using a C&#x2013;H hydrogen-bonding cage. Science 365, 159&#x2013;161 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31123106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tromans, R. A. et al. A biomimetic receptor for glucose. Nat. Chem. 11, 52&#x2013;56 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30420776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, S. K. et al. Bipyrrole-strapped calix[4]pyrroles: strong anion receptors that extract the sulfate anion. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 136, 15079&#x2013;15085 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25254498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang, S. O., Llinares, J. M., Day, V. W. &amp; Bowman-James, K. Cryptand-like anion receptors. Chem. Soc. Rev. 39, 3980&#x2013;4003 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20820597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dietrich, B., Lehn, J. M. &amp; Sauvage, J. P. Les cryptates. Tetrahedron Lett. 10, 2889&#x2013;2892 (1969).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park, C. H. &amp; Simmons, H. E. Macrobicyclic amines. III. Encapsulation of halide ions by in,in-1,(k&#x2009;+&#x2009;2)-diazabicyclo[k.l.m.]alkane ammonium ions. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 90, 2431&#x2013;2432 (1968).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehn, J. M., Sonveaux, E. &amp; Willard, A. K. Molecular recognition. Anion cryptates of a macrobicyclic receptor molecule for linear triatomic species. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 100, 4914&#x2013;4916 (1978).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mont&#xe0;-Gonz&#xe1;lez, G., Sancen&#xf3;n, F., Mart&#xed;nez-M&#xe1;&#xf1;ez, R. &amp; Mart&#xed;-Centelles, V. Purely covalent molecular cages and containers for guest encapsulation. Chem. Rev. 122, 13636&#x2013;13708 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35867555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9413269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H. et al. Quantitative self-assembly of a purely organic three-dimensional catenane in water. Nat. Chem. 7, 1003&#x2013;1008 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26587716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mastalerz, M. et al. Transformation of a [4+6] salicylbisimine cage to chemically robust amide cages. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 58, 8819&#x2013;8823 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollstein, S. et al. Dynamic covalent self-assembly of chloride- and ion-pair-templated cryptates. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 61, e202201831 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busschaert, N. et al. Tripodal transmembrane transporters for bicarbonate. Chem. Commun. 46, 6252&#x2013;6254 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valkenier, H., Dias, C. M., Butts, C. P. &amp; Davis, A. P. A folding decalin tetra-urea for transmembrane anion transport. Tetrahedron 73, 4955&#x2013;4962 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryantsev, V. S. &amp; Hay, B. P. De novo structure-based design of bisurea hosts for tetrahedral oxoanion guests. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 128, 2035&#x2013;2042 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16464105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia, C. et al. Highly efficient extraction of sulfate ions with a tripodal hexaurea receptor. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 50, 486&#x2013;490 (2011).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Custelcean, R., Moyer, B. A. &amp; Hay, B. P. A coordinatively saturated sulfate encapsulated in a metal&#x2013;organic framework functionalized with urea hydrogen-bonding groups. Chem. Commun. 2005, 5971&#x2013;5973 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, X., Wang, P., Lewis, W., Jiang, Y.-B. &amp; Gale, P. A. Measuring anion binding at biomembrane interfaces. Nat. Commun. 13, 4623 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35941124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9359984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shinde, S. et al. Urea-based imprinted polymer hosts with switchable anion preference. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 142, 11404&#x2013;11416 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32425049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7467678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua, Y., Liu, Y., Chen, C.-H. &amp; Flood, A. H. Hydrophobic collapse of foldamer capsules drives picomolar-level chloride binding in aqueous acetonitrile solutions. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 135, 14401&#x2013;14412 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24028552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks, S. J., Gale, P. A. &amp; Light, M. E. Carboxylate complexation by 1,1&#x2032;-(1,2-phenylene)bis(3-phenylurea) in solution and the solid state. Chem. Commun. 2005, 4696&#x2013;4698 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eiberweiser, A., Nazet, A., Hefter, G. &amp; Buchner, R. Ion hydration and association in aqueous potassium phosphate solutions. J. Phy. Chem. B 119, 5270&#x2013;5281 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, S.-Q., Zhao, W. &amp; Wu, B. Separation of sulfate anion from aqueous solution governed by recognition chemistry: a minireview. Front. Chem. 10, 905563 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35572111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9099046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moyer, B. A. et al. A case for molecular recognition in nuclear separations: sulfate separation from nuclear wastes. Inorg. Chem. 52, 3473&#x2013;3490 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23134587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKeown, D. A., Muller, I. S. &amp; Pegg, I. L. Iodine valence and local environments in borosilicate waste glasses using X-ray absorption spectroscopy. J. Nucl. Mater. 456, 182&#x2013;191 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pegg, I. L. Behavior of technetium in nuclear waste vitrification processes. J. Radioanal. Nucl. Chem. 305, 287&#x2013;292 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26224991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4514641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keymeulen, F. et al. Fluoride binding in water with the use of micellar nanodevices based on salophen complexes. Org. Biomol. Chem. 13, 2437&#x2013;2443 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25553919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatulian, S. A. Effect of lipid phase transition on the binding of anions to dimyristoylphosphatidylcholine liposomes. Biochim. Biophys. Acta 736, 189&#x2013;195 (1983).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6652082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hlawacek, G., Ahmad, I., Smithers, M. A. &amp; Kooij, E. S. To see or not to see: imaging surfactant coated nano-particles using HIM and SEM. Ultramicroscopy 135, 89&#x2013;94 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23948627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gou, F. et al. One-pot cyclization to large peptidomimetic macrocycles by in situ-generated &#x3b2;-turn-enforced folding. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 145, 9530&#x2013;9539 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37037798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzioumis, N., Cullen, D., Jolliffe, K. &amp; White, N. G. Selective removal of sulfate from water by precipitation with a rigid bis-amidinium compound. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 62, e202218360 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, K.-J., Moon, D., Lah, M. S. &amp; Jeong, K.-S. Indole-based macrocycles as a class of receptors for anions. Angew. Chem. Int. Ed. 44, 7926&#x2013;7929 (2005).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havel, V., Yawer, M. A. &amp; Sindelar, V. Real-time analysis of multiple anion mixtures in aqueous media using a single receptor. Chem. Commun. 51, 4666&#x2013;4669 (2015).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>