<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39258363</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-2494</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>47</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of cosmetic science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Cosmet Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Application of the upcycling trend using ultrafiltrate of water from the production of collagen from fish skin in hair care cosmetics.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>190</StartPage><EndPage>204</EndPage><MedlinePgn>190-204</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ics.13015</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The aim of the research problem of the article was to try to popularize the upcycling trend in the production of sustainable cosmetics and to confirm their effectiveness. The development of recycled raw materials is a new discovery in the chemical industry. Manufacturers emphasize the production of more environmentally friendly raw materials. Conscious consumers choose cosmetics whose production is based on sustainable development. Instead of throwing away waste from various industries, let us use it to produce active substances used in hair cosmetics. The production of the collagen series was created in accordance with the principles of upcycling, which involves obtaining collagen water, which is waste generated during the production of supplements. The main goal of the work was to learn cosmetic recipes for styling, washing and conditioning hair based on collagen waste, as well as to compare the results of people using the product in question. The aim of the study was also to demonstrate the effectiveness of the treatment in preventing split ends and hair breakage, usually caused by mechanical stress (brushing), as well as to confirm the effectiveness of other tests. The article presents procedures and parameters confirming the effectiveness of treatment with the tested hair products. The following tests were carried out: hair thickness and density, colour uniformity, shine factor and scalp hydration. All parameters numerically confirmed the beneficial effects of products containing collagen water used in hair care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Society of Cosmetic Scientists and Societe Francaise de Cosmetologie.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Igielska-Kalwat</LastName><ForeName>Joanna</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7017-7392</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Cosmetology, University of Education and Therapy, Poznan, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Symbiosis Laboratory, Poznan, Poznan, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kilian-Pi&#x119;ta</LastName><ForeName>Ewa</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Symbiosis Laboratory, Poznan, Poznan, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Siedlecki</LastName><ForeName>Maciej</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Civil Engineering and Transport, Institute of Combustion Engines and Powertains, Poznan, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Cosmet Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8007161</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0142-5463</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9007-34-5</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003094">Collagen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006203">Hair Preparations</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003358">Cosmetics</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003094" MajorTopicYN="Y">Collagen</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006203" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hair Preparations</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="Y">Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005399" MajorTopicYN="N">Fishes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012867" MajorTopicYN="Y">Skin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006197" MajorTopicYN="N">Hair</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003358" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cosmetics</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="fre"><AbstractText>L'objectif Synth&#xe8;se: de l'article &#xe9;tait de vulgariser la tendance de l'upcycling dans la production de cosm&#xe9;tiques durables et de confirmer leur efficacit&#xe9;. Le&#xa0;d&#xe9;veloppement de mati&#xe8;res premi&#xe8;res recycl&#xe9;es est une nouvelle d&#xe9;couverte dans l'industrie chimique. Les fabricants mettent l'accent sur la production de mati&#xe8;res premi&#xe8;res plus respectueuses de l'environnement. Les consommateurs responsables vont choisir des cosm&#xe9;tiques dont la production s'appuie sur des principes de d&#xe9;veloppement durable. Les d&#xe9;chets provenant de diverses industries peuvent servir &#xe0; la fabrication de substances actives utilis&#xe9;es dans les produits de soins des cheveux. La fabrication de produits &#xe0; base de collag&#xe8;ne reposait sur le principe de l'upcycling, qui consistait &#xe0; obtenir de l'eau de collag&#xe8;ne issue des d&#xe9;chets g&#xe9;n&#xe9;r&#xe9;s lors de la production de compl&#xe9;ments alimentaires. Le but principal &#xe9;tait d'apprendre des recettes de cosm&#xe9;tiques pour le coiffage, le lavage et le soin des cheveux &#xe0; partir de d&#xe9;chets de collag&#xe8;ne, et de comparer les r&#xe9;sultats avec des personnes utilisant le produit en question. L'objectif de l'&#xe9;tude &#xe9;tait de d&#xe9;montrer l'efficacit&#xe9; des soins dans la pr&#xe9;vention des fourches et de la casse, g&#xe9;n&#xe9;ralement caus&#xe9;s par un stress m&#xe9;canique tel que le brossage, et de confirmer l'efficacit&#xe9; d'autres tests. L'article pr&#xe9;sente les proc&#xe9;dures et param&#xe8;tres confirmant l'efficacit&#xe9; du traitement avec les soins capillaires test&#xe9;s. Les tests suivant ont &#xe9;t&#xe9; men&#xe9;s : &#xe9;paisseur et densit&#xe9; des cheveux, uniformit&#xe9; de la couleur, brillance et hydratation du cuir chevelu. Les chiffres ont parl&#xe9; et tous les param&#xe8;tres ont confirm&#xe9; les effets b&#xe9;n&#xe9;fiques des produits contenant de l'eau de collag&#xe8;ne dans les soins capillaires.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Society of Cosmetic Scientists and Societe Francaise de Cosmetologie.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biodegradability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">collagen</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cosmetics formulations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">respect the nature</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sustainable cosmetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">upcycling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">water less</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">zero waste</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39258363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ics.13015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Cetin M, Sevik H. Measuring the impact of selected plants on indoor CO2 concentrations. Pol J Environ Stud. 2016;3:973&#x2013;979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sevik H, Cetin M. Effects of water stress on seed germination for select landscape plants. Pol J Environ Stud. 2015;24:689&#x2013;693.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cetin M. Sustainability of urban coastal area management: a case study on Cide. Front Sustain. 2016;35:527&#x2013;533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dermik I, Mavi K. Effect of salt and osmotic stresses on the germination of pepper seeds of different maturation stages. Braz Arch Biol Technol. 2008;51:897&#x2013;902.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pratap V, Sharma YK. Impact of osmotic stress on seed germination and seedling growth in black germ (Phaseolus mungo). J Environ Biol. 2010;31:721&#x2013;725.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karaca E, Kusuran A. The evaluation of water&#x2010;wise landscape of certain plants which were used on Cankiri landscape arrangements. Turk J Med Sci. 2012;5:19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Servininc I, Kuscu K, Cetin M, YigitI N, Savaci G, Sevik H. Relationship between enzyme activity (urease&#x2010;catalase) and nutrient element in soil use. Pol J Environ Stud. 2018;5:2107&#x2013;2112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright SL, Kelly FJ. Plastic and human health: a micro issue? Environ Sci Technol. 2017;51:6634&#x2013;6647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>George A, Sanjay MR, Srisuk R, Parameswaranpillai J, Siengchin S. A comprehensive review on chemical properties and applications of biopolymers and their composites. Int J Biol Macromol. 2020;154:329&#x2013;338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalia S, Av&#xe9;rous L. Biopolymers: biomedical and environmental applications. Hoboken, NJ, USA: Wiley; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain S, Tote D, Kolte G, Jajoo S, Tote S. Effect of moist dressing, collagen sheet dressing and epidermal growth factor in healing of chronic wounds. Int Surg J. 2017;4:2594&#x2013;2599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahul VG, Nair PD. Biomaterials and designs supporting cartilage regeneration. In: Sethuraman S, Krishnan UM, Subramanian A, editors. Biomaterials and nanotechnology for tissue engineering. Boca Raton, FL, USA: CRC Press; 2016. p. 93&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitkowski P, Szaferski W. Production of emulsion in tank mixer with sieve bottom. Chem Eng Res Des. 2016;109:618&#x2013;627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Igielska&#x2010;Kalwat J, Kilian&#x2010;Pi&#x119;ta E, Poloczanska&#x2010;Godek S. The use of natural collagen obtained from fish waste in HairStyling and care. Polymers. 2022;14:749&#x2013;761.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The cosmetics act of 4.10.2018. Pol J Laws 2018, 11, 2227. https://www.cosmeticscare.eu/en/legal&#x2010;provisions/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang K, Kang TW, Lee SD, Park YM, Kim HO, Kim SY. Thechanging patterns of hair density and thickness in SouthKorean women with hair loss: clinical office&#x2010;based photo&#x2010;trichogram analysis. Int J Dermatol. 2009;48:14&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leerunyakul K, Suchonwanit P. Evaluation of hair density and hair diameter in the adult Thai population using quantitative trichoscopic analysis. Biomed Res Int. 2020;2020:247&#x2013;268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMullen R, Jachowicz J. Thermal degradation of hair. I. Effect of curling irons. J Cosmet Sci. 2002;49:223&#x2013;244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song S&#x2010;H, Park H&#x2010;S, Jeon J, Son SK, Kang N&#x2010;G. Hair pores caused by surfactants via the cell membrane complex and a prevention strategy through the use of cuticle sealing. Cosmetics. 2023;10:161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wortmann F. Analyzing the laser&#x2010;light reflection form hair fibers. II. Deriving a measure of hair luster. J Cosmet Sci. 2004;55:81&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Igielska&#x2010;Kalwat J, Kilian&#x2010;Pi&#x119;ta E. The use of Dalmatian Tansy and auxiliary substances as natural substitutes in the treatmentof dermatosis. SSRG. 2021;8:1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kharin A, Varghese B, Verhagen R, Uzunbajakava N. Optical properties of the medulla and the cortex of human scalp hair. J Biomed Opt. 2009;14:24035.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robbins CR, editor. Chemical and physical behavior of human hair. 5th ed. Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: Springer; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hrdy D. Quantitative hair form variation in seven populations. Am J Phys Anthropol. 1973;39:7&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richena M, Rezende CA. Effect of photodamage on the outermost cuticle layer of human hair. J Photochem Photobiol B Biol. 2015;153:296&#x2013;304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMullen RL, Zhang G, Gillece T. Quantifying hair shape and hair damage induced during reshaping of hair. J Cosmet Sci. 2015;66:379&#x2013;409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding CR. The stratum corneum: structure and function in health and disease. Dermatol Ther. 2004;17:6&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudnicka L, Olszewska M, Rakowska A, Slowinska M. Trichoscopy update. J Dermatol Case Rep. 2011;5:82&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagase S, Shibuichi S, Ando K, Kariya E, Satoh N. Influence of internal structures of hair fiber on hair appearance. I. LiDhtscatterind from the porouss tructure of the medulla of human hair. J Cosmet Sci. 2002;53:89&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mannari T, Toda K, Hirayama T, Nakashima R, Hosokawa H, Ohnishi H. A novel concept &#x201c;hair medulla care&#x201d;&#x2014;unveiling hair medulla structure can change the appearance of gray hair. Yokohama, Japan: IFSCC; 2020. p. 93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hessefort Y, Holland BT, Cloud RW. True porosity measurement of hair: a new way to study hair damage mechanisms. J Cosmet Sci. 2008;59:303&#x2013;315.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheehy EJ, Cunniffe GM, O'Brien FJ. Collagen&#x2010;based biomaterials for tissue regeneration and repair. In: Barbosa MA, Martins MCL, editors. Peptides and proteins as biomaterials for tissue regeneration and repair. Sawston, UK: Woodhead Publishing; 2018. p. 127&#x2013;150. ISBN 978&#x2010;0&#x2010;08&#x2010;100803&#x2010;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeng WM. Preparation of biomaterials using fish collagen and seaweed alginate to promote in&#xa0;vivo cell growth and Prolifertion activity. PhD Thesis, Ipoh, Malaysia: Universiti Tunku Abdul Rahman; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada S, Yamamoto K, Ikeda T, Yanagiguchi K, Hayashi Y. Potency of fish collagen as a scaffold for regenerative medicine. Bio Med Res Int. 2014;2014:302932.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savoji H, Godau B, Hassani MS, Akbari M. Skin tissue substitutes and biomaterial risk assessment and testing. Front Bioeng Biotechnol. 2018;6:86 [CrossRef].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Rosso JQ, Levin J. The clinical relevance of maintaining the functional integrity of the stratum corneum in both healthy and disease&#x2010;affected skin. J Clin Aesthet Dermatol. 2011;4:22&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes DF, Lu Y, Starborg T, Kadler KE. Collagen fibril assembly and function. Curr Top Dev Biol. 2018;130:107&#x2013;142.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>