<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37925388</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-7339</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Supportive care in cancer : official journal of the Multinational Association of Supportive Care in Cancer</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Support Care Cancer</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The role of dermocosmetics in the management of cancer-related skin toxicities: international expert consensus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>672</StartPage><MedlinePgn>672</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">672</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00520-023-08116-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Skin toxicities are very common in patients undergoing cancer treatment and have been found to occur with all types of cancer therapeutic interventions (cytotoxic chemotherapy, targeted therapies, immunotherapy, and radiotherapy). Further, skin toxicities can lead to interruption or even discontinuation of anticancer treatment in some patients, translating to suboptimal outcomes. Dermocosmetics (or cosmeceuticals)-defined as skincare solutions incorporating dermatologically active ingredients (beyond vehicle effects) that directly improve symptoms of various skin conditions-are increasingly being used in cancer care to prevent and manage skin toxicities. The active ingredients in these products have a measurable biological action in skin; they typically improve skin integrity (barrier function/hydration and other factors) while relieving skin symptoms. The Association Francophone des Soins Oncologiques de Support (AFSOS) and Multinational Association of Supportive Care in Cancer (MASCC) partnered to select a multidisciplinary group of healthcare professionals involved in the management of patients with cancer and skin toxicities. The group reviewed existing literature and created a summary of recommendations for managing these toxicities through online meetings and communication. In this publication, the group (1) reviews new skin toxicities seen with oncology drugs and (2) evaluates the role of dermocosmetics in improving patient outcomes and minimizing cancer treatment interruptions. We provide general recommendations for initiation and selection of skin care in all oncology patients as well as recommendations for what factors should be considered when using dermocosmetics in specific types of skin toxicities.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dreno</LastName><ForeName>Brigitte</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nantes Universit&#xe9;, INSERM, CNRS, Immunology and New Concepts in Immunotherapy, INCIT, UMR 1302/EMR6001. F-44000, Nantes, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khosrotehrani</LastName><ForeName>Kiarash</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Experimental Dermatology Group, University of Queensland Diamantina Institute, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Barros Silva</LastName><ForeName>Giselle</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Hospital Alemao Oswaldo Cruz, Sao Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wolf</LastName><ForeName>Julie Ryan</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Dermatology and Radiation Oncology, School of Medicine and Dentistry, University of Rochester Medical Center, Rochester, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kerob</LastName><ForeName>Delphine</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>La Roche Posay International, Levallois, France. delphine.kerob@loreal.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trombetta</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of the Radiologic Sciences, Allegheny Health Network, Drexel University College of Medicine, Pittsburgh, PA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Atenguena</LastName><ForeName>Etienne</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, University of Yaound&#xe9; I, Yaound&#xe9; Hospital General, Yaound&#xe9;, Cameroon.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dielenseger</LastName><ForeName>Pascale</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research and Education for Paramedic Professionals Nursing Coordinator, Gustave Roussy, Villejuif, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>&#xc9;cole Des Sciences du Cancer, Universit&#xe9; Paris Sud (XI), Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Association Fran&#xe7;aise Des Infirmi&#xe8;res de Cancerologie (AFIC), Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pan</LastName><ForeName>Meng</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Rui Jin Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scotte</LastName><ForeName>Florian</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Patient Pathway Division, Gustave Roussy, Villejuif, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Multinational Association of Supportive Care in Cancer (MASCC), Aurora, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krakowski</LastName><ForeName>Ivan</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Oncologist, Bordeaux, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Association Francophone Des Soins Oncologiques de Support (AFSOS), B&#xe8;gles, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lacouture</LastName><ForeName>Mario</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dermatology Service, Department of Medicine, Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P30 CA008748</GrantID><Acronym>CA</Acronym><Agency>NCI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016446">Consensus Statement</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Support Care Cancer</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9302957</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0941-4355</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Support Care Cancer. 2025 Oct 16;33(11):954. doi: 10.1007/s00520-025-09982-w.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">41099779</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012871" MajorTopicYN="Y">Skin Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009369" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012867" MajorTopicYN="N">Skin</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007167" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunotherapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anticancer therapeutics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cancer management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cosmeceuticals</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dermocosmetics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oncodermatology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Skin toxicity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Pr. Dreno has served as consultant/speaker/received honoraria from La Roche Posay, Pierre Fabre, and Galderma; Dr. Khosrotehrani has served as investigator or consultant to La Roche Posay, Novartis, Sanofi, and Eli Lilly; Dr. De Barros Silva has served as investigator or consultant to La Roche Posay, Bio Brazilian Information Oncology, Janssen, and Merck; Dr. Wolf has served as investigator or consultant to La Roche Posay, VisualDx (dba Logical Images), Argentum Medical, and Pfizer; Dr. Kerob is an employee of La Roche-Posay, a L&#x2019;Oreal company; Dr. Trombetta has nothing to declare; Dr. Atenguena has served as consultant to La Roche Posay and Merck; Ms. Dielenseger has served as consultant to La Roche Posay, Pfizer, Glaxo SmithKline, Astra Zeneca, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Mundi Pharma, and Servier; Dr. Pan has nothing to declare; Dr. Scotte and Dr Krakowski have no conflicts of interest to declare; Dr. Lacouture has a consultant role with Johnson and Johnson, Novocure, Janssen, Novartis, Deciphera, Kintara, RBC/La Roche Posay, Tmunity, Repare, Kinnate, Trifecta, Genentech, Loxo, Seattle Genetics, Lutris, OnQuality, Roche, Oncoderm, and Apricity. Dr. Lacouture also receives research funding from Lutris, Paxman, Novocure, OQL, Novartis, and AZ and is funded in part through the NIH/NCI Cancer Center Support Grant P30 CA008748.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37925388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10625513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-023-08116-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00520-023-08116-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lacouture ME, Choi J, Ho A et al (2021) Us cutaneous oncodermatology management (uscom): a practical algorithm. J Drugs Dermatol 20:3s-s19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36849/JDD.6229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34491030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deutsch A, Leboeuf NR, Lacouture ME et al (2020) Dermatologic adverse events of systemic anticancer therapies: cytotoxic chemotherapy, targeted therapy, and immunotherapy. Am Soc Clin Oncol Educ Book 40:485&#x2013;500</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/EDBK_289911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32421446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensadoun RJ, Humbert P, Krutman J et al (2013) Daily baseline skin care in the prevention, treatment, and supportive care of skin toxicity in oncology patients: recommendations from a multinational expert panel. Cancer Manag Res 5:401&#x2013;408</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CMAR.S52256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3862511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24353440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacouture M, Sibaud V (2018) Toxic side effects of targeted therapies and immunotherapies affecting the skin, oral mucosa, hair, and nails. Am J Clin Dermatol 19:31&#x2013;39</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40257-018-0384-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6244569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30374901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Lim J, Park JS et al (2018) The impact of skin problems on the quality of life in patients treated with anticancer agents: a cross-sectional study. Cancer Res Treat 50:1186&#x2013;1193</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4143/crt.2017.435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6192901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29237254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behroozian T, Fatima S, Finkelstein S et al (2022) Current quality of life assessment tools may not fully address dermatological adverse events from anti-cancer therapies. Support Care Cancer 30:9681&#x2013;9685</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36274078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byun HJ, Lee HJ, Yang JI et al (2012) Daily skin care habits and the risk of skin eruptions and symptoms in cancer patients. Ann Oncol 23:1992&#x2013;1998</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mds141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22700992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boone SL, Rademaker A, Liu D et al (2007) Impact and management of skin toxicity associated with anti-epidermal growth factor receptor therapy: survey results. Oncology 72:152&#x2013;159</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000112795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18160805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacouture ME (2009) The growing importance of skin toxicity in egfr inhibitor therapy. Oncology (Williston Park) 23(194):6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19323302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang V, Anadkat M (2011) Dermatologic manifestations of cytotoxic therapy. Dermatol Ther 24:401&#x2013;410</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1529-8019.2011.01432.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21910798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreno B, Amici JM, Demessant-Flavigny AL et al (2021) The impact of acne, atopic dermatitis, skin toxicities and scars on quality of life and the importance of a holistic treatment approach. Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol 14:623&#x2013;632</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CCID.S315846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8213955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34163201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceglio W, Rebeis MM, Santana MF et al (2022) Cutaneous adverse events to systemic antineoplastic therapies: a retrospective study in a public oncologic hospital. An Bras Dermatol 97:14&#x2013;21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.abd.2021.05.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8799855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34844792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreno B, Bensadoun RJ, Humbert P et al (2013) Algorithm for dermocosmetic use in the management of cutaneous side-effects associated with targeted therapy in oncology. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 27:1071&#x2013;1080</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.12082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3883088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23368717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girnita A, Lorentzen H, Kauppi S et al (2021) Supplement individual article: skincare for cancer patients in scandinavia. J Drugs Dermatol 20:ss4-s14</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34898158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arditi C, Eicher M, Colomer-Lahiguera S et al (2022) Patients&#x2019; experiences with cancer care in switzerland: results of a multicentre cross-sectional survey. Eur J Cancer Care (Engl) 31:e13705</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9787424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36130722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daste A, Chakiba C, Domblides C et al (2016) Targeted therapy and elderly people: a review. Eur J Cancer 69:199&#x2013;215</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejca.2016.10.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27855351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bang AS, Anadkat MJ, Choi JN et al (2022) Oncodermatology: advancing the science and care of cancer patients and survivors. Am J Clin Dermatol 23:587&#x2013;589</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40257-022-00705-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10569770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35788536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrios DM, Phillips GS, Freites-Martinez A et al (2020) Outpatient dermatology consultations for oncology patients with acute dermatologic adverse events impact anticancer therapy interruption: a retrospective study. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 34:1340&#x2013;1347</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.16159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7302962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31856311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen ST, Molina GE, Lo JA et al (2020) Dermatology consultation reduces interruption of oncologic management among hospitalized patients with immune-related adverse events: a retrospective cohort study. J Am Acad Dermatol 82:994&#x2013;996</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2019.09.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31560981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araviiskaia E, Dreno B (2016) The role of topical dermocosmetics in acne vulgaris. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 30:926&#x2013;935</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.13579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26916232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren Z, Zhu K, Kang H et al (2015) Randomized controlled trial of the prophylactic effect of urea-based cream on sorafenib-associated hand-foot skin reactions in patients with advanced hepatocellular carcinoma. J Clin Oncol 33:894&#x2013;900</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2013.52.9651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25667293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spada F, Harrison IP, Barnes TM et al (2021) A daily regimen of a ceramide-dominant moisturizing cream and cleanser restores the skin permeability barrier in adults with moderate eczema: a randomized trial. Dermatol Ther 34:e14970</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dth.14970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8459234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33984185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clabbers JMK, Boers-Doets CB, Gelderblom H et al (2016) Xerosis and pruritus as major egfri-associated adverse events. Support Care Cancer 24:513&#x2013;521</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4689742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26111953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galimont-Collen AF, Vos LE, Lavrijsen AP et al (2007) Classification and management of skin, hair, nail and mucosal side-effects of epidermal growth factor receptor (egfr) inhibitors. Eur J Cancer 43:845&#x2013;851</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejca.2006.11.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17289377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valentine J, Belum VR, Duran J et al (2015) Incidence and risk of xerosis with targeted anticancer therapies. J Am Acad Dermatol 72:656&#x2013;667</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2014.12.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25637330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wohlrab J, Bangemann N, Kleine-Tebbe A et al (2014) Barrier protective use of skin care to prevent chemotherapy-induced cutaneous symptoms and to maintain quality of life in patients with breast cancer. Breast Cancer (Dove Med Press) 6:115&#x2013;122</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4126578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25114589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fluhr JW, Miteva M, Primavera G et al (2007) Functional assessment of a skin care system in patients on chemotherapy. Skin Pharmacol Physiol 20:253&#x2013;259</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000104423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17587889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wohlrab J, Luftner D, Johne A, Camara O, Dominik S, Runnebaum I (2011) The advantage of a proactive, barrier-protective, supportive skin care in patients with brest cancer on chemotherapy. Oncology 34:62</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roe E, Garcia Muret MP, Marcuello E et al (2006) Description and management of cutaneous side effects during cetuximab or erlotinib treatments: a prospective study of 30 patients. J Am Acad Dermatol 55:429&#x2013;437</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2006.04.062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16908348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekiguchi K, Sumi M, Saito A et al (2023) The effectiveness of moisturizer on acute radiation-induced dermatitis in breast cancer patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Breast Cancer 30:2&#x2013;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12282-022-01403-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36258148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yahiro C, Takai T, Nakatani S et al (2022) Skin rash associated with combined cytotoxic chemotherapy and immunotherapy for cancer: a retrospective single-center case series. J Dermatol 50:357&#x2013;363</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1346-8138.16614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36258256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ocvirk J, Cencelj S (2010) Management of cutaneous side-effects of cetuximab therapy in patients with metastatic colorectal cancer. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 24:453&#x2013;459</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-3083.2009.03446.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19793151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bierbrier R, Lam M, Pehr K (2022) A systematic review of oral retinoids for treatment of acneiform eruptions induced by epidermal growth factor receptor inhibitors. Dermatol Ther 35:e15412</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dth.15412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35220635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacouture ME, Sibaud V, Gerber PA et al (2021) Prevention and management of dermatological toxicities related to anticancer agents: Esmo clinical practice guidelines(&#x2606;). Ann Oncol 32:157&#x2013;170</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annonc.2020.11.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33248228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dummer R, Rinderknecht J, Goldinger SM (2012) Ultraviolet a and photosensitivity during vemurafenib therapy. N Engl J Med 366:480&#x2013;481</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMc1113752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22296092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mittal S, Khunger N, Kataria SP (2022) Nail changes with chemotherapeutic agents and targeted therapies. Indian Dermatol Online J 13:13&#x2013;22</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/idoj.IDOJ_801_20</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8809183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35198463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandy JGP, Franco PIG, Li RK (2022) Prophylactic strategies for hand-foot syndrome/skin reaction associated with systemic cancer treatment: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Support Care Cancer 30:8655&#x2013;8666</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35655045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan B, Ciardiello F, Lacouture ME et al (2015) Regorafenib-associated hand-foot skin reaction: practical advice on diagnosis, prevention, and management. Ann Oncol 26:2017&#x2013;2026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdv244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4576906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26034039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan TC, Tsou PH, Tam KW et al (2022) Effect of urea cream on hand-foot syndrome in patients receiving chemotherapy: a meta-analysis. Cancer Nurs 45:378&#x2013;386</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NCC.0000000000001008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34483284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee WJ, Lee JL, Chang SE et al (2009) Cutaneous adverse effects in patients treated with the multitargeted kinase inhibitors sorafenib and sunitinib. Br J Dermatol 161:1045&#x2013;1051</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2133.2009.09290.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19558553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacouture ME, Sibaud V, Anadkat MJ et al (2021) Dermatologic adverse events associated with selective fibroblast growth factor receptor inhibitors: overview, prevention, and management guidelines. Oncologist 26:e316&#x2013;e326</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/onco.13552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7873330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33021006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hijal T, Sauder MB, Andriessen A, Claveau J, Lynde CW (2021) Canadian skin management in oncology group (casmo) algorithm for the prevention and management of acute radiation dermatitis. Skin Ther Lett. 1&#x2013;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger A, Regueiro C, Hijal T et al (2018) Interest of supportive and barrier protective skin care products in the daily prevention and treatment of cutaneous toxicity during radiotherapy for breast cancer. Breast Cancer (Auckl) 12:1178223417752772</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1178223417752772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5802618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29434476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolf JR HA (2023) Radiation dermatitis. Up to Date Wolters Kluwer</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leventhal J, Young MR (2017) Radiation dermatitis: recognition, prevention, and management. Oncology (Williston Park) 31(885&#x2013;7):94&#x2013;99</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29297172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolderston A, Lloyd NS, Wong RK et al (2006) The prevention and management of acute skin reactions related to radiation therapy: a systematic review and practice guideline. Support Care Cancer 14:802&#x2013;817</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16758176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sauder M, Addona M, Andriessen A et al (2020) The role of skin care in oncology patients. Skin Therapy Lett Oct (Suppl):1&#x2013;12</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trombetta M, Julian TB, Valakh V et al (2010) Reduction in radiation-induced morbidity by use of an intercurrent boost in the management of early-stage breast cancer. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys 77:1303&#x2013;1308</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrobp.2009.06.056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20044218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardefeldt PJ, Edirimanne S, Eslick GD (2012) Deodorant use and the risk of skin toxicity in patients undergoing radiation therapy for breast cancer: a meta-analysis. Radiother Oncol 105:378&#x2013;379</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.radonc.2012.08.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22995589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo AM-SRR, Ketosugbo K et al (2022) Oral minoxidil for the treatment of late alopecia in cancer survivors. J Clin Oncol 40:12022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2022.40.16_suppl.12022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39097564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng HC, Chen HH (2023) Platelet-rich plasma in the treatment of alopecia areata after covid-19 vaccination. Clin Case Rep 11:e7342</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ccr3.7342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10182003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37192849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iamsumang W, Leerunyakul K, Suchonwanit P (2020) Finasteride and its potential for the treatment of female pattern hair loss: evidence to date. Drug Des Devel Ther 14:951&#x2013;959</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/DDDT.S240615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7060023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32184564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacouture ME, Mitchell EP, Piperdi B et al (2010) Skin toxicity evaluation protocol with panitumumab (stepp), a phase ii, open-label, randomized trial evaluating the impact of a pre-emptive skin treatment regimen on skin toxicities and quality of life in patients with metastatic colorectal cancer. J Clin Oncol 28:1351&#x2013;1357</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2008.21.7828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20142600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luftner D, Dell&#x2019;Acqua V, Selle F et al (2018) Evaluation of supportive and barrier-protective skin care products in the daily prevention and treatment of cutaneous toxicity during systemic chemotherapy. Onco Targets Ther 11:5865&#x2013;5872</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/OTT.S155438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6149940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30271169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rades D, Zwaan I, Cacicedo J et al (2022) Impact of a mobile application (reminder app) on acute toxicity during radiotherapy of head-and-neck cancer - results of a randomized phase iii trial (rarest-02). BMC Cancer 22:989</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12885-022-10088-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9482290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36115962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vendrely V, Mayor-Ibarguren A, Stennevin A et al (2022) An emollient plus balm is useful for the management of xerosis in patients treated for cancer: a real-world, prospective, observational, multicenter study. Dermatol Ther (Heidelb) 12:683&#x2013;699</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13555-022-00685-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8941027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35107817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luu M, Lai SE, Patel J et al (2007) Photosensitive rash due to the epidermal growth factor receptor inhibitor erlotinib. Photodermatol Photoimmunol Photomed 23:42&#x2013;45</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0781.2007.00273.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17254038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>