<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39683738</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1420-3049</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>23</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Molecules (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Molecules</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Research Progress and Outlook of Molecular Dynamics Simulation on Carbon Dioxide Applied for Methane Exploitation from Hydrates.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5579</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/molecules29235579</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Research progress of carbon dioxide applied for methane exploitation from hydrates is summarized, with a focus on advances in molecular dynamics simulations and their application in understanding the mechanism of carbon dioxide replacement for hydrate exploitation. The potential of carbon dioxide in enhancing energy recovery efficiency and promoting carbon capture and storage is emphasized. An overview is provided of the advancements made in utilizing carbon dioxide for methane hydrate exploitation, highlighting its significance. Subsequently, the theoretical foundations and techniques of molecular dynamics simulations are delved into, encompassing key elements such as statistical ensembles, molecular force fields, and numerical solution methods. Through simulations, various characterization parameters including mean square displacement, radial distribution functions, coordination numbers, angular order parameters, and hydrogen bonds are computed and analyzed, which are crucial for understanding the dynamic changes in hydrate structures and the replacement process. Thorough research and analysis have been conducted on the two possible and widely debated mechanisms involved in the replacement of methane hydrates by carbon dioxide, with a particular emphasis on guest molecular replacement and hydrate reconfiguration. These processes encompass the intricate interactions between carbon dioxide molecules and the cage-like structure of hydrates, as well as the rearrangement and stabilization of hydrate structures. Several key issues surrounding the application of carbon dioxide for methane hydrate exploitation are identified, including the influence of thermodynamic conditions, the selection of auxiliary gases, and other potential factors such as geological conditions and fluid properties. Addressing these issues is crucial for optimizing the extraction process and enhancing economic and environmental benefits. A theoretical foundation and technical reference for the application of carbon dioxide in methane hydrate exploitation are provided, while future research directions and priorities are also outlined.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Qiannan</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2313-3768</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Energy and Power Engineering, Guangdong University of Petrochemical Technology, Maoming 525000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Chenglong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exploration and Development Research Institute, Daqing Oilfield Co., Ltd., Daqing 163712, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peng</LastName><ForeName>Boyang</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Geological Research Institute of No. 4 Oil Production Plant, Daqing Oilfield Co., Ltd., Daqing 163511, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Huimin</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hainan Branch CNOOC (China) Co., Ltd., Haikou 570311, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Tao</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Energy and Power Engineering, Guangdong University of Petrochemical Technology, Maoming 525000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Energy and Power Engineering, Guangdong University of Petrochemical Technology, Maoming 525000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Kun</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Energy and Power Engineering, Guangdong University of Petrochemical Technology, Maoming 525000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Zhijing</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Energy and Power Engineering, Guangdong University of Petrochemical Technology, Maoming 525000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No.2023010</GrantID><Agency>Maoming Municipal Science and Technology Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>GDUPT2023</GrantID><Agency>International Training Program for Outstanding Young Scientific Research Talents, Guangdong, China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Molecules</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100964009</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1420-3049</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">carbon dioxide replacement method</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">methane exploitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">molecular dynamics simulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">natural gas hydrate</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Authors Chenglong Li and Boyang Peng are employed by the Daqing Oilfield Co. Ltd., Author Huimin Tang is employed by the Hainan Branch CNOOC (China) Co., Ltd. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39683738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11643654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules29235579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">molecules29235579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ebinuma T. Method for Dumping and Disposing of Carbon Dioxide Gas and Apparatus Therefor. 5,261,490. U.S. Patent. 1993 November 16;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohgaki K., Takano K., Sangawa H., Matsubara T., Nakano S. Methane exploitation by carbon dioxide from gas hydrates&#x2014;Phase equilibria for CO&#x2082;-CH&#x2084; mixed hydrate system. J. Chem. Eng. Jpn. 1996;29:478&#x2013;483. doi: 10.1252/jcej.29.478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1252/jcej.29.478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoderbek D., Boswell R. Ignik Sikumi#1, gas hydrate test well, successfully installed on the Alaska North Slope. Nat. Gas Oil. 2011;11:1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schicks J.M., Spangenberg E., Giese R., Steinhauer B., Klump J., Luzi M. New approaches for the production of hydrocarbons from hydrate-bearing sediments. Energies. 2011;4:151&#x2013;172. doi: 10.3390/en4010151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en4010151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sloan E.D., Koh C.A. Estimation techniques for phase equilibria of natural gas hydrates; Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Natural Gas Hydrates; Salt Lake City, UT, USA. 18&#x2013;22 July 1999; New York, NY, USA: Francis Group; 2008. pp. 320&#x2013;523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janicki G., Schl&#xfc;ter S., Hennig T., Lyko H., Deerberg G. Simulation of methane recovery from gas hydrates combined with storing carbon dioxide as hydrates. J. Geol. Res. 2011;2011:462156. doi: 10.1155/2011/462156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2011/462156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svandal A., Kuznetsova T., Kvamme B. Thermodynamic properties and phase transitions in the H2O/CO2/CH4 system. Fluid Phase Equilib. 2006;246:177&#x2013;184. doi: 10.1016/j.fluid.2006.06.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fluid.2006.06.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchida T., Ikeda I.Y., Takeya S., Kamata Y., Ohmura R., Nagao J. Kinetics and stability of CH4&#x2013;CO2 mixed gas hydrates during formation and long-term storage. ChemPhysChem. 2005;6:646&#x2013;654. doi: 10.1002/cphc.200400364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cphc.200400364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15881580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akihiro H. Phase equilibrium and comparison of formation speeds of CH4 and CO2 hydrate below the ice point; Proceedings of the Fifth International Conference on Gas Hydrates; Trondheim, Norway. 13&#x2013;16 June 2005; pp. 126&#x2013;128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ota M., Morohashi K., Abe Y., Watanabe M., Smith R.L., Inomata H. Replacement of CH4 in the hydrate by use of liquid CO2. Energy Convers. Manag. 2005;46:1680&#x2013;1691. doi: 10.1016/j.enconman.2004.10.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2004.10.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon J.H., Yoon T., Kawamura T., Yoshitaka Y., Yamamoto Y. Transformation of Methane Hydrate to Carbon Dioxide Hydrate: In Situ Raman Spectroscopic Observations. J. Phys. Chem. A. 2004;108:5057&#x2013;5059. doi: 10.1021/jp049683l.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp049683l</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ota M., Abe Y., Watanabe M., Smith R.L., Inomata H. Methane recovery from methane hydrate using pressurized CO2. Fluid Phase Equilib. 2005;228:553&#x2013;559.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yezdimer E.M., Cummings P.T., Chialvo A.A. Determination of the Gibbs free energy of gas replacement in SI clathrate hydrates by molecular simulation. J. Phys. Chem. A. 2002;106:7982&#x2013;7987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel N. In situ methane hydrate dissociation with carbon dioxide sequestration: Current knowledge and issues. J. Pet. Sci. Eng. 2006;51:169&#x2013;184. doi: 10.1016/j.petrol.2006.01.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2006.01.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z.Z., Guo X.Q., Chen G.J., Wang J.B., Yang L.Y., Wang T. Experimental kinetic studies on methane replacement from methane hydrate formed in SDS system by using pressurized CO2. J. Chem. Ind. Eng. 2007;58:1197&#x2013;1202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park Y., Kim D., Lee J., Huh D., Park K., Lee J. Sequestering carbon dioxide into complex structures of naturally occurring gas hydrates. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA. 2006;103:12690&#x2013;12694. doi: 10.1073/pnas.0602251103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.0602251103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1568911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16908854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey J.S., Solms N. Hydrate stability and methane recovery from gas hydrate through CH4&#x2013;CO2 replacement in different mass transfer scenarios. Energies. 2019;12:2309. doi: 10.3390/en12122309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en12122309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y.F., Wang Y.F., Zhong J.R., Li W.Z., Li R., Cao B.J. Gas hydrate exploitation using CO2/H2 mixture gas by semi-continuous injection-production mode. Appl. Energy. 2019;240:215&#x2013;225. doi: 10.1016/j.apenergy.2019.01.209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2019.01.209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y.L., Xu C.G., Yu Y.S. Methane recovery from natural gas hydrate with simulated IGCC syngas. Energy. 2017;120:192&#x2013;198. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2016.12.129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2016.12.129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y.F., Wang Y.F., Zhong J.R., Li W.Z., Li R., Cao B.J. Natural gas hydrate exploitation by CO2/H2 continuous Injection-Production mode. Appl. Energy. 2018;226:10&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1016/j.apenergy.2018.05.098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apenergy.2018.05.098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M., Wang X., Deng C., Liu B., Sun C., Chen G., El-Halwagi M.M. Computer Aided Chemical Engineering. Elsevier; Amsterdam, The Netherlands: 2019. Process modeling and energy efficiency analysis of natural gas hydrate production by CH4-CO2/H2 replacement coupling steam methane reforming; pp. 131&#x2013;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alder B.J., Wainwright T.E. Phase transition for a hard sphere system. J. Chem. Phys. 1957;27:1208&#x2013;1209. doi: 10.1063/1.1743957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.1743957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman A. Correlations in motion of atoms in liquid argon. Phys. Rev. 1964;136:A405. doi: 10.1103/PhysRev.136.A405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRev.136.A405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verlet L. Computer experiments on classical fluids. I. Thermodynamical properties of Lennard-Jones molecules. Phys. Rev. 1967;159:98. doi: 10.1103/PhysRev.159.98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRev.159.98</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haile J.M. Molecular Dynamics Simulation: Elementary Methods. OAI; New York, NY, USA: 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frenkel D., Smit B. Understanding Molecular Simulation: From Algorithms to Applications. Academic Press; Cambridge, MA, USA: 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen M.P., Tildesley D.J. Computer Simulation of Liquids. Oxford University Press; Oxford, UK: 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuckerman M.E. Statistical Mechanics: Theory and Molecular Simulation. Oxford University Press; Oxford, UK: 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandler D. Introduction to Modern Statistical Mechanics. Oxford University Press; Oxford, UK: 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorgensen W.L., Ghahremanpour M.M., Saar A., Tirado-Rives J. OPLS/2020 Force Field for Unsaturated Hydrocarbons, Alcohols, and Ethers. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2024;128:250&#x2013;262. doi: 10.1021/acs.jpcb.3c06602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcb.3c06602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38127719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun H., Ren P., Fried J.R. Condensed-phased optimized molecular potential for atomistic simulation studies. Comput. Theor. Polym. Sci. 1998;8:229. doi: 10.1016/S1089-3156(98)00042-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1089-3156(98)00042-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karplus M. Chemistry at Harvard Macromolecular Mechanics (CHARMM): A Computational Approach to Biomolecular Systems. J. Comput. Chem. 1983;4:1&#x2013;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiner P.K., Kollman P.A. AMBER: Assisted model building with energy refinement A general program for modeling molecules their interactions. J. Comput. Chem. 1981;2:287&#x2013;303. doi: 10.1002/jcc.540020311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcc.540020311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dauber-Osguthorpe L., Osguthorpe D.R. Consistent valence force field for organic molecules: 1. The hydrocarbons. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 1988;110:7750&#x2013;7759.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berendsen H.J.C., Grigera J.R., Straatsma T.P. The missing term in effective pair potentials. Physica A. 1987;131:109&#x2013;122. doi: 10.1021/j100308a038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/j100308a038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson D.M., Weare J.H. A new water potential for simulating liquid water and ice. J. Chem. Phys. 1984;81:5675&#x2013;5684.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vega C., de Pablo J.J. Modeling water and ice: The TIP4P/Ice potential. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2009;113:8864&#x2013;8873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abascal J.L.F., Vega C. Globular protein folding in water: A comparison of two water models. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2005;109:15646&#x2013;15654.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris J.G., Yung K.H. Force Fields for Molecular Dynamics Simulations of Carbon Dioxide. J. Chem. Phys. 2001;115:10238&#x2013;10245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone A.J. A new force field for carbon dioxide. Mol. Phys. 1998;94:953&#x2013;962.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorgensen W.L., Tirado-Rives J. The OPLS [optimized potentials for liquid simulations] potential functions for proteins, energy minimizations for crystals of cyclic peptides and crambin. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 1988;110:1657&#x2013;1666. doi: 10.1021/ja00214a001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ja00214a001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27557051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jorgensen W.L., Madura J.D., Swenson C.J. Optimized intermolecular potential functions for liquid hydrocarbons. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 1984;106:6638&#x2013;6646. doi: 10.1021/ja00334a030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ja00334a030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B., Siepmann J.I. A New Force Field for Methane. J. Phys. Chem. A. 2001;105:5274&#x2013;5285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman A. Correlations in the motion of atomic systems. Phys. Rev. Lett. 1964;12:34&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swope W.C., Anderson H.C., Berens P.H., Wilson K.R. Computer simulation of liquids. Rev. Mod. Phys. 1982;53:681&#x2013;740.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrew R.L. Molecular Modeling: Principle and Practice. Springer; Berlin/Heidelberg, Germany: 1996. pp. 357&#x2013;359.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stillinger F.H., Weber T.A. Computer simulation of local order in condensed phases of silicon. Phys. Rev. B. 1985;31:5262&#x2013;5271. doi: 10.1103/PhysRevB.31.5262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevB.31.5262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9936488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marshall W.L., Haymet A.D.J. The structure of water in the hydration shells of some ions. J. Chem. Soc. Faraday Trans. 1985;81:1633&#x2013;1642.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vatamanu J., Kusalik P.G. The Growth of Structure I Methane Hydrate from Molecular Dynamics Simulations. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2006;128:15588&#x2013;15589. doi: 10.1021/ja066515t.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ja066515t</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17147358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Zhao L., Deng S., Nie X., Du Z. Molecular dynamics simulation on carbon dioxide hydrate formation. Energy Procedia. 2019;158:4648&#x2013;4654. doi: 10.1016/j.egypro.2019.01.741.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egypro.2019.01.741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sircar S., Deb S. Kinetics of methane release from hydrates by CO2 exchange. Fuel. 2006;85:2458&#x2013;2464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai X., Koh C.G. Kinetics of CO2-induced methane release from methane hydrate. Int. J. Greenh. Gas Control. 2009;3:213&#x2013;219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horvat K., Kerkar P., Jones K., Mahajan D. Kinetics of the formation and dissociation of gas hydrates from CO2-CH4 mixtures. Energies. 2012;5:2248&#x2013;2262. doi: 10.3390/en5072248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en5072248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung Y.T., Chen L.J., Chen Y.P., Lin S.T. In situ methane recovery carbon dioxide sequestration in methane hydrates: A molecular dynamics simulation study. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2011;115:15295&#x2013;15302. doi: 10.1021/jp2088675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp2088675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22091947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K., Qin G. Mechanistic and kinetic study of CO2-CH4 exchange process in methane hydrates using molecular dynamics simulation; Proceedings of the SPE Europec Featured at 81st EAGE Conference and Exhibition; London, UK. 3&#x2013;6 June 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi Y., Ota M., Zhang H. Molecular dynamics simulation of replacement of CH4 in hydrate with CO2. Energy Convers. Manag. 2011;52:2682&#x2013;2687. doi: 10.1016/j.enconman.2011.01.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2011.01.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang S., Liang D., Wu N., Yi L., Hu G. Molecular mechanisms of gas diffusion in CO2 hydrates. J. Phys. Chem. C. 2016;120:16298&#x2013;16304. doi: 10.1021/acs.jpcc.6b03111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.6b03111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi L., Liang D., Zhou X. Molecular dynamics simulation of CO2 displacement of CH4 hydrate in NaCl solution. J. Eng. Thermophys. 2016;37:1383&#x2013;1387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwai Y., Nakamura H., Hirata M. Molecular dynamics simulation of replacement of methane hydrate with carbon dioxide. Mol. Simul. 2012;38:481&#x2013;490. doi: 10.1080/08927022.2011.647817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08927022.2011.647817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai D., Zhang X., Chen G., Wang W. Replacement mechanism of methane hydrate with carbon dioxide from microsecond molecular dynamics simulations. Energy Environ. Sci. 2012;5:7033&#x2013;7041. doi: 10.1039/c2ee21189k.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/c2ee21189k</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uddin M., Coombe D. Kinetics of CH4 and CO2 hydrate dissociation and gas bubble evolution via MD simulation. J. Phys. Chem. A. 2014;118:1971&#x2013;1988. doi: 10.1021/jp410789j.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp410789j</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24571292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu G., Tian L., Chen D., Niu M., Ji H. CO2 and CH4 hydrates: Replacement or cogrowth? J. Phys. Chem. C. 2019;123:13401&#x2013;13409. doi: 10.1021/acs.jpcc.9b00579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcc.9b00579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Xu Y., Khan N., Zhu C., Gao Y. Effects of the Surfactant, Polymer, and Crude Oil Properties on the Formation and Stabilization of Oil-Based Foam Liquid Films: Insights from the Microscale. J. Mol. Liq. 2022;373:121194. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2022.121194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2022.121194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pess&#xf4;a Filho P.A., Weidmann A.B., Franco LF M., Sum A.K. Dissociation Temperature of Gas Hydrates through Isenthalpic&#x2013;Isobaric Molecular Dynamics Simulations. J. Chem. Phys. 2024;161:174505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39484910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cladek B.R., Everett S.M., McDonnell M.T., Kizzire D.G., Tucker M.G., Keffer D.J., Rawn C.J. Local structure analysis of low-temperature neutron pair distribution function coupled with molecular dynamics simulations of CH4 and CO2 hydrates from 2 to 210 K. Fuel. 2021;299:120908. doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2021.120908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2021.120908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo P., Song Y.L., Liu H., Zhang W.B., Zhao J.F. Molecular dynamic simulation study on replacement of methane hydrates with carbon dioxide under different temperatures, pressures, and concentrations of ethylene glycol. ACS Omega. 2024;5:13936&#x2013;13950. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.3c09630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.3c09630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11064176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38708202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gajanayake S., Gamage R.P., Wanniarachchige P., Zhang D. Quantification of CO2 replacement in methane gas hydrates: A molecular dynamics perspective. J. Nat. Gas.Sci. Eng. 2022;98:104396. doi: 10.1016/j.jngse.2021.104396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2021.104396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng L., Li Y., Cui J., Wu Q., Liu B., Ning F., Chen G. Molecular simulation study on carbon dioxide replacement in methane hydrate near the freezing point. Gas Sci. Eng. 2024;122:205220. doi: 10.1016/j.jgsce.2024.205220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jgsce.2024.205220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Yan Y., Xu J., Li S., Chen G., Zhang J. Replacement micro-mechanism of CH4 hydrate by nitrogen/CO2 mixture revealed by ab initio studies. Comput. Mater. Sci. 2016;123:106&#x2013;110. doi: 10.1016/j.commatsci.2016.06.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.commatsci.2016.06.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Yan Y., Liu H., Xu J., Zhang J., Chen G. Understanding effect of structure and stability on transformation of CH4 hydrate to CO2 hydrate. Chem. Phys. Lett. 2016;648:75&#x2013;80. doi: 10.1016/j.cplett.2016.02.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cplett.2016.02.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsui H., Jia J., Tsuji T., Liang Y., Masuda Y. Microsecond simulation study on the replacement of methane in methane hydrate by carbon dioxide, nitrogen, and carbon dioxide&#x2013;nitrogen mixtures. Fuel. 2020;263:116640. doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2019.116640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2019.116640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song W., Sun X., Zhou G., Huang W., Lu G., Wu C. Molecular dynamics simulation study of nitrogen/CO2 displacement process of methane hydrate. ChemistrySelect. 2020;5:13936&#x2013;13950. doi: 10.1002/slct.202003845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/slct.202003845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D., Chen L., Liu G., Xiao J., Li B., Yu W. Comparison between the replacements of CH4 in natural gas hydrate with CO2 and NH3. Energy Rep. 2021;7:3639&#x2013;3646. doi: 10.1016/j.egyr.2021.04.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.egyr.2021.04.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palodkar A.V., Dongre H.J., Thakre N., Jana A.K. Microsecond molecular dynamics of methane&#x2013;carbon dioxide swapping in pure and saline water environment. Sci. Rep. 2022;12:2634. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-06583-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-06583-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8850547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35173234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Huang T., Shan T., Yuan Q., Yin S., Li J., Zhang P. Molecular dynamics study of the influence of water molecular phase state on the replacement of CO2&#x2013;CH4 hydrate in porous media. J. Mol. Liq. 2023;391:123401. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2023.123401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2023.123401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>