<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41366222</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Research on PFC3D meso-parameters prediction model and strength simulation of backfill based on hemical-mechanical coupling.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>43376</StartPage><MedlinePgn>43376</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">43376</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-28620-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study develops and validates a meso-parameter prediction model for backfill materials in PFC3D, enabling efficient numerical construction under varying curing ages and mix ratios. A quantitative correlation was established between hydration degree of the backfill and macroscopic mechanical properties, facilitating prediction of performance evolution. Using the parallel bonded contact model, the effective modulus [Formula: see text]<sup>*</sup> was found to exhibit a linear relationship with the macroscopic elastic modulus E, while the stiffness ratio [Formula: see text] <sub>n</sub>/[Formula: see text] <sub>s</sub> demonstrated a strong correlation with Poisson's ratio v. Compressive strength &#x3c3; was shown to depend on both [Formula: see text] <sub>n</sub>/[Formula: see text] <sub>s</sub> and the bonding parameter &#x3c3;<sub>n</sub>/&#x3c3;<sub>s</sub>. Based on these relationships, a coupled chemo-mechanical prediction framework was developed to integrate hydration, mechanical response, and meso-scale input parameters. Validation against uniaxial and biaxial simulations demonstrated good agreement with laboratory tests, with mean errors below 8.5% for strength and 10% for deformation. Simulated failure modes closely reproduced experimental observations, confirming model reliability. Application to real stope conditions further demonstrated its capability to evaluate backfill strength. This work provides a mechanistic foundation for efficient and accurate parameter determination, supporting predictive modeling of cemented backfill systems.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Safety Engineering, University of Science and Technology Beijing, Beijing, 100083, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of High Efficient Mining and Safety of Metal, Ministry of Education, University of Science and Technology Beijing, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Chen</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Safety Engineering, University of Science and Technology Beijing, Beijing, 100083, China. 761251200@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CINF Engineering Co., Ltd., Changsha, 410001, China. 761251200@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Defeng</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Safety Engineering, University of Science and Technology Beijing, Beijing, 100083, China. wangdefengvip@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiao</LastName><ForeName>Jiang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Safety Engineering, University of Science and Technology Beijing, Beijing, 100083, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of High Efficient Mining and Safety of Metal, Ministry of Education, University of Science and Technology Beijing, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Aixiang</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Resources and Safety Engineering, University of Science and Technology Beijing, Beijing, 100083, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of High Efficient Mining and Safety of Metal, Ministry of Education, University of Science and Technology Beijing, Beijing, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>(2024ZD1003805)</GrantID><Agency>Major National Science and Technology Project for Deep Earth</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>(2024ZD1003805)</GrantID><Agency>Major National Science and Technology Project for Deep Earth</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>FRF-BD-25-054</GrantID><Agency>Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52574134&#x202c;</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Backfill</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Failure mode</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mechanical properties</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Meso-parameters</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Numerical simulation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41366222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12690136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-28620-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-28620-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wu, A. X. et al. New development and prospect of key technology in underground mining of metal mines. <i>Metal Mine.</i><b>10</b>, 1&#x2013;13 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, A. X. et al. Effect of initial backfill temperature on the deformation behavior of early age cemented paste backfill that contains sodium silicate. <i>Adv. Mater. Sci. Eng.</i><b>2016</b>, 1&#x2013;10 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghirian, A. &amp; Fall, M. Coupled thermo-hydro-mechanical&#x2013;chemical behaviour of cemented paste backfill in column experiments Part II: Mechanical, chemical and microstructural processes and characteristics. <i>Eng. Geol.</i><b>170</b>, 11&#x2013;23 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enggeo.2013.12.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, A. X. &amp; Wang, H. J. <i>Theory and technology of metal mineral paste backfill</i> (Science Press, 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, H. Q. et al. Strength and microstructural evolution of alkali-activated slag-based cemented paste backfill: Coupled effects of activator composition and temperature. <i>Powder Technol.</i><b>401</b>, 117322 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.powtec.2022.117322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, K. et al. Synergistic deformation in a combination of cemented paste backfill and rocks. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>317</b>, 125943 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.125943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, L. H. et al. Effect of mixing time on hydration kinetics and mechanical property of cemented paste backfill. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>247</b>, 118516 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin, S. H. et al. Optimization of the effect and formulation of different coarse aggregates on performance of the paste backfill condensation. <i>Chinese J. Eng.</i><b>42</b>(07), 829&#x2013;837 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, S. &amp; Song, W. D. Effect of filling interval time on the mechanical strength and ultrasonic properties of cemented coarse tailing backfill. <i>Int. J. Miner. Process.</i><b>166</b>, 62&#x2013;68 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.minpro.2017.07.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, W. C. &amp; Fall, M. Sulphate effect on the early age strength and self-desiccation of cemented paste backfill. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>106</b>, 296&#x2013;304 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.12.124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou, C. et al. Bi-axial loading experiments on interactions between cemented backfill and pillar. <i>Metal Mine.</i><b>511</b>, 24&#x2013;28 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiu, Z. G. et al. Experimental study on the triaxial mechanical behaviors of the Cemented Paste Backfill: Effect of curing time, drainage conditions and curing temperature. <i>J. Environ. Manage.</i><b>301</b>, 113828 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2021.113828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34583283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J., Fu, J. X. &amp; Song, W. D. Mechanical properties and microstructure of layered cemented paste backfill under triaxial cyclic loading and unloading. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>257</b>, 119540 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, L. L., Zhang, Q. L. &amp; Feng, R. Numerical simulation of backfill strength based on optimization results of stope structural parameters. <i>Gold Sci. Technol..</i><b>29</b>(3), 421&#x2013;432 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, W. B., Liu, B. &amp; Wu, W. L. Strength and deformation behaviors of cemented tailings backfill under triaxial compression. <i>J. China Univ. Min. Technol.</i><b>27</b>(12), 3531&#x2013;3543 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, J., Jin, A. B. &amp; Chen, S. J. Study on synergistic effect of blasting effect and backfill stability in post-filling stope. <i>Metal Mine.</i><b>543</b>, 8&#x2013;17 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, R. F., Zeng, F. T. &amp; Li, L. Stability analyses of side-exposed backfill considering mine depth and extraction of adjacent stope. <i>Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci.</i><b>142</b>, 104735 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2021.104735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, S. H., Liu, J. &amp; Zhao, P. F. Numerical simulation of upward layered backfill method and optimization of backfill strength in Tonglushan Mine. <i>Min. Technol.</i><b>22</b>(2), 167&#x2013;170 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, H. Y. et al. Study on the microfabric evolution law of quartz sandstone under biaxial compression. <i>China Mining Magazine.</i><b>29</b>(9), 160&#x2013;167 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, J. et al. Numerical analysis of the failure process of soil&#x2013;rock mixtures through computed tomography and PFC3D models. <i>Int. J. Coal Sci. Technol.</i><b>5</b>(2), 126&#x2013;141 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40789-018-0194-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Z., Zhou, N. &amp; Zhang, J. X. Random gravel model and particle flow based numerical biaxial test of solid backfill materials. <i>Int. J. Min. Sci. Technol.</i><b>23</b>(04), 463&#x2013;467 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmst.2013.07.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, Z. Y., Konietzky, H. &amp; Herbst, M. Three-dimensional particle model based numerical simulation on multi-level compressive cyclic loading of concrete. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>220</b>, 661&#x2013;677 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.07.260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, X. P. et al. Simulation research on granite compression test based on particle discrete element model. <i>Rock Soil Mech.</i><b>35</b>(S1), 99&#x2013;105 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong, X. M., Lu, Z. C. &amp; Zhang, C. Y. Recent development on understanding cement hydration mechanism and effects of chemical admixtures on cement hydration. <i>J Chinese Ceramic Soc.</i><b>45</b>(02), 274&#x2013;281 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schindler, A. K., Folliard, K. J. Influence of supplementary cementing materials on the heat of hydration of concrete, Advances in Cement and Concrete IX Conference Copper Mountain Conference Resort in Colorado. 10&#x2013;14 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu, D., Fall, M. &amp; Cai, S. J. Numerical modelling of thermally and hydraulically coupled processes in hydrating cemented tailings backfill columns. <i>Int. J. Min. Reclam. Environ.</i><b>28</b>(3), 173&#x2013;199 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17480930.2013.809194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. et al. Correlative mechanism of hydraulic-mechanical property in cemented paste backfill. <i>J. Wuhan Univ. Technol(Materials Science Edition)</i><b>32</b>(3), 579&#x2013;585 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11595-017-1637-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schutter, G. D. Hydration and temperature development of concrete made with blast-furnace slag cement. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>29</b>(1), 143&#x2013;149 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0008-8846(98)00229-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schindler, A. K. Effect of temperature on hydration of cementitious materials. <i>ACI Mater. J.</i><b>101</b>, 72&#x2013;81 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills, R. H. Factors influencing cessation of hydration in water cured cement pastes, Highway Research Board Special. <i>Report.</i><b>90</b>, 406&#x2013;424 (1966).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein, K. &amp; Simon, D. Effect of specimen composition on the strength development in cemented paste backfill. <i>Can. Geotech. J.</i><b>43</b>(3), 310&#x2013;324 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/t06-005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smilauer, V. &amp; Bittnar, Z. Microstructure-based micromechanical prediction of elastic properties in hydrating cement paste. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>36</b>(9), 1708&#x2013;1718 (2006).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2006.05.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galaa, A. M. et al. Characterizing stiffness development in hydrating mine backfill using ultrasonic wave measurements. <i>Can. Geotech. J.</i><b>48</b>(8), 1174&#x2013;1187 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/t11-026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou, C. et al. The effects of temperature and binder content on the behavior of frozen cemented tailings backfill at early ages. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>239</b>, 117752 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. et al. Damage constitutive model of cemented tailing paste under initial temperature effect. <i>Chinese J. Eng.</i><b>39</b>(01), 31&#x2013;38 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z. &amp; Rao, Q. H. Quantitative determination of PFC3D microscopic parameters. <i>J. Central South Univ.</i><b>28</b>, 911&#x2013;925 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11771-021-4653-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, H. T. &amp; Cheng, X. H. Discrete element analysis for size effects of coarse-grained soils. <i>Rock Soil Mech.</i><b>30</b>(S1), 287&#x2013;292 (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potyondy, D. O. &amp; Cundall, P. A. A bonded-particle model for rock. <i>Int. J. Rock Mech. Min. Sci.</i><b>41</b>, 1329&#x2013;1364 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrmms.2004.09.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, L. &amp; Qiao, D. P. Experimenta study on strength parameters of cement filling with classified tailings. <i>Gold</i><b>37</b>(04), 30&#x2013;32 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao, K. et al. Research on mechanical properties and damage law of tantalum-niobium ore cemented tailings backfill. <i>J. Mining &amp; Saf. Eng.</i><b>36</b>(2), 413&#x2013;419 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi. C. Numerical Simulation Technology and Application with Particle Flow Code (PFC5.0), Beijing: China Construction Industry Press. (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng, A. P. et al. Crack propagation and convergence mode of cemented backfill under uniaxial compression. <i>J. China Univ. Min. Technol.</i><b>50</b>(1), 50&#x2013;59 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin, A. B. et al. Mechanical properties of filling materials containing composite phase change materials. <i>J. Central South University (Science and Technology)</i><b>52</b>(09), 3153&#x2013;3163 (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y. T. Acoustic emission and fractal characteristics of cemented tailing backfill in different age under uniaxial compression, Wuhan university of science and technology. (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang. G.F. Research on mechanical characteristics and strength design of cemented paste backfill under lateral-restraint, University of Science and Technology Beijing. (2022).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>