<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40600097</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Case Report and Review of Literature on Spinning-Induced Rhabdomyolysis Among First-Time Female Spinners.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e85199</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e85199</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e85199</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.85199</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Spinning is an indoor static cycling training program, and spinning-induced rhabdomyolysis (SIR)&#xa0;is a type of exercise-induced rhabdomyolysis causing systemic and local complications.&#xa0;In this case report, we would like to address its relevance to young women, especially first-time or unfit spinners, and the precautions that should be taken. A 24-year-old woman presented with bilateral thigh pain and dark brown-colored urine after a 45-minute first-time spinning session. She had a creatinine phosphokinase level of 108,166 U/L and myoglobinuria. She was diagnosed with SIR, treated with adequate hydration and urine alkalinization, and was discharged without any complications.&#xa0;Even though the reports are quite limited and focused mainly on the treatment, in view of the high incidence noted in a particular group of people, we recommend&#xa0;public awareness and&#xa0;low-intensity&#xa0;training for all young women engaging in their first indoor cycling session to prevent SIR.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, George et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>George</LastName><ForeName>James C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopaedics, Believers Church Medical College, Thiruvalla, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopaedics, Aster Hospital, Sharjah, ARE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Valsalan</LastName><ForeName>Brijesh</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopaedics, Aster Hospital, Sharjah, ARE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhaskaran</LastName><ForeName>Ramesh</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine, Aster Hospital, Sharjah, ARE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cycling</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise-induced muscle damage</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rhabdomyolysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spinning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">women&#x2019;s health</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. Aster DM Healthcare issued approval IEC/2025/01/216. All procedures followed were in accordance with the ethical standards of the responsible committee on human experimentation (institutional and national) and with the Helsinki Declaration of 1975, as revised in 2008. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40600097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12212886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.85199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rhabdomyolysis: An evaluation of 475 hospitalized patients. Melli G, Chaudhry V, Cornblath DR. Medicine (Baltimore) 2005;84:377&#x2013;385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16267412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The syndrome of rhabdomyolysis: Pathophysiology and diagnosis. Giannoglou GD, Chatzizisis YS, Misirli G. Eur J Intern Med. 2007;18:90&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17338959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comments on point: Counterpoint: Estrogen and sex do/do not influence post-exercise indexes of muscle damage, inflammation, and repair. Pizza FX, Clark BC, De Meersman RE, et al. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2009;106:1016&#x2013;1020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19244554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acute exertional rhabdomyolysis. Line RL, Rust GS. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7625324/ Am Fam Physician. 1995;52:502&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7625324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exercise-induced upper extremity rhabdomyolysis and myoglobinuria in shipboard military personnel. Brown JA, Elliott MJ, Sray WA. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/7816216/ Mil Med. 1994;159:473&#x2013;475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7816216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serum and urinary markers of skeletal muscle tissue damage after weight lifting exercise. Paul GL, DeLany JP, Snook JT, Seifert JG, Kirby TE. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1989;58:786&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2737198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical characteristics and outcomes of exertional rhabdomyolysis after indoor spinning: A systematic review. Masuda Y, Wam R, Paik B, Ngoh C, Choong AM, Ng JJ. Phys Sportsmed. 2023;51:294&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35254210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical characteristics of spinning-induced rhabdomyolysis and other causes of rhabdomyolysis: A comparative study. Shroff K, Gunasegaren M, Norbu K, Omar E. Singapore Med J. 2022;63:567&#x2013;571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9728312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34581545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spinning-induced rhabdomyolysis: Eleven case reports and review of the literature. Kim D, Ko EJ, Cho H, et al. Electrolyte Blood Press. 2015;13:58&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4737663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26848305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spinning: An arising cause of rhabdomyolysis in young females. Kim YH, Ham YR, Na KR, Lee KW, Choi DE. Intern Med J. 2016;46:1062&#x2013;1068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27346188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemiological analysis of factors influencing an episode of exertional rhabdomyolysis in high school students. Lin H, Chie W, Lien H. Am J Sports Med. 2006;34:481&#x2013;486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16260462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Exercise and fluid replacement. Convertino VA, Armstrong LE, Coyle EF, Mack GW, Sawka MN, Senay LC Jr, Sherman WM. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1996;28:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9303999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The hydrating effects of hypertonic, isotonic and hypotonic sports drinks and waters on central hydration during continuous exercise: A systematic meta-analysis and perspective. Rowlands DS, Kopetschny BH, Badenhorst CE. Sports Med. 2022;52:349&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8803723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34716905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>When exercise goes awry: Exertional rhabdomyolysis. Hamer R. South Med J. 1997;90:548&#x2013;551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9160079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical outcomes of hospitalised individuals with spin-induced exertional rhabdomyolysis. Lim SY, Chong CJ, Liu Z, Kan JY. Ann Acad Med Singap. 2023;52:356&#x2013;363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38904501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>