<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41835663</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Assessing Risk of Nephrolithiasis in Urology Residents: Are We Practicing What We Preach?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e103483</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e103483</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e103483</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.103483</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Purpose Nephrolithiasis is a common urological condition that is treated by urologists. Urologists counsel patients on the importance of adequate hydration to decrease the risk of nephrolithiasis as well as the avoidance of specific diets that can contribute to the condition. To date, the risk of urology resident physicians developing nephrolithiasis during their residency has not been studied. This study aimed to investigate nephrolithiasis in urology residents and factors that may contribute to their potential protection or increased susceptibility to this pathology. Based on self-reported water intake, most respondents reported fluid consumption below commonly cited hydration targets, though guideline awareness and adherence were not directly assessed.&#xa0;Previous studies have examined residents' satisfaction with their programs, but none have investigated the occurrence of kidney stones among residents. Materials and methods Through a nationally distributed survey of current urology residents, this pilot study aimed to address these questions by examining variables such as caffeine consumption, PGY year, family history of kidney stones, personal history of kidney stones, and life satisfaction. Results The results indicated that as urology residents' PGY level increased, their water intake decreased. In addition, life satisfaction increased as PGY increased. Conclusion Future research on this topic will aim to expand the study cohort to include attending physicians at a later stage in their careers to compare attitudes and actions that may contribute to the occurrence of nephrolithiasis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Maine et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maine</LastName><ForeName>Hope</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, University of Louisville School of Medicine, Louisville, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sheth</LastName><ForeName>Aashka</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, University of Louisville School of Medicine, Louisville, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ziegler</LastName><ForeName>Craig</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Graduate Medical Education Research, University of Louisville School of Medicine, Louisville, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Kellen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, University of Louisville Hospital, Louisville, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">kidney stones</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nephrolithiasis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nephrolithiasis risk factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">residency</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Informed consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. The University of Louisville Institutional Review Board issued approval 24.0589. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41835663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12988828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.103483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kidney stones: treatment and prevention. Fontenelle LF, Sarti TD. https://www.aafp.org/pubs/afp/issues/2019/0415/p490.html. Am Fam Physician. 2019;99:490&#x2013;496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30990297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidney stones. Khan SR, Pearle MS, Robertson WG, et al. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2016;2:16008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5685519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27188687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nutrition and kidney stone disease. Siener R. Nutrients. 2021;13:1917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8229448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34204863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medical management of kidney stones: AUA guideline. Pearle MS, Goldfarb DS, Assimos DG, et al. J Urol. 2014;192:316&#x2013;324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24857648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hydration for health hypothesis: a narrative review of supporting evidence. Perrier ET, Armstrong LE, Bottin JH, et al. Eur J Nutr. 2021;60:1167&#x2013;1180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7987589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32632658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidney stone prevention. Peerapen P, Thongboonkerd V. Adv Nutr. 2023;14:555&#x2013;569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10201681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36906146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urolithiasis risk: a comparison between healthcare providers and the general population. Chen MH, Weng SF, Hsu CC, et al. BMC Health Serv Res. 2016;16:273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4949927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27430323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The exposome for kidney stones. Goldfarb DS. Urolithiasis. 2016;44:3&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4726479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26615595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An assessment of residency wellness programming in urology training programs. Pavuluri H, Malik R, Seideman CA. Urology. 2022;165:113&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35276201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resident burnout and well-being in otolaryngology and other surgical specialties: strategies for change. Shah HP, Salehi PP, Ihnat J, et al. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2023;168:165&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35133919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stressful life events and risk of symptomatic kidney stones. Najem GR, Seebode JJ, Samady AJ, Feuerman M, Friedman L. Int J Epidemiol. 1997;26:1017&#x2013;1023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9363523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association between sleep quality and urolithiasis among general population in Western China: a cross-sectional study. Wang S, Zhou X, Qiu S, et al. BMC Public Health. 2022;22:1787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9490950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36127664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nojaba L, Guzman N. In: StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2023. Nephrolithiasis (Kidney Stones) (Archived)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Development of the perceived stress questionnaire: a new tool for psychosomatic research. Levenstein S, Prantera C, Varvo V, Scribano ML, Berto E, Luzi C, Andreoli A. J Psychosom Res. 1993;37:19&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8421257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The role of fluid intake in the prevention of kidney stone disease: a systematic review over the last two decades. Gamage KN, Jamnadass E, Sulaiman SK, Pietropaolo A, Aboumarzouk O, Somani BK. Turk J Urol. 2020;46:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7731957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32525478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tea and coffee consumption and pathophysiology related to kidney stone formation: a systematic review. Barghouthy Y, Corrales M, Doizi S, Somani BK, Traxer O. World J Urol. 2021;39:2417&#x2013;2426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33052484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The association between caffeine intake and risk of kidney stones: a population-based study. Geng J, Qiu Y, Kang Z, et al. Front Nutr. 2022;9:935820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9589282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36299992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caffeine in kidney stone disease: risk or benefit? Peerapen P, Thongboonkerd V. Adv Nutr. 2018;9:419&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6054181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30032225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Integrated vascular surgery resident satisfaction. Dansey K, Wooster M, Shames M. Ann Vasc Surg. 2015;29:1581&#x2013;1588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26315796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>It depends on your perspective: resident satisfaction with operative experience. Perone JA, Fankhauser GT, Adhikari D, Mehta HB, Woods MB, Tyler DS, Brown KM. Am J Surg. 2017;213:253&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6681826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27776758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resident satisfaction with the pediatric surgery training program. Altokhais T, Al Rajhi M, Bawazir O, Almogbel GT, Aljunaydil AI, Alshehri A. BMC Med Educ. 2020;20:375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7576832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33081768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etiopathogenic factors of urolithiasis. Wagner CA. https://www.aeurologia.com/EN/Y2021/V74/I1/16#2. Arch Esp Urol. 2021;74:16&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33459618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Genetic determinants of urolithiasis. Monico CG, Milliner DS. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2011;8:151&#x2013;162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3901084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22183508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diet quality in medical trainees: a cross-sectional assessment comparing medical students and primary care residents using the Rapid Eating Assessment for Participants-shortened version. Khandalavala B, Emig S, Yousef M, Geske J. BMC Nutr. 2024;10:106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11271206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39054563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health behaviors of medical students decline towards residency: how could we maintain and enhance these behaviors throughout their training. Wilf-Miron R, Kagan I, Saban M. Isr J Health Policy Res. 2021;10:13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8054363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33866965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>