<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40018636</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2753-4294</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMJ public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMJ Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Randomised trial of Mentored 'Planning to be Active+Family' [MPBA+F] for Appalachian youth at risk for diabetes: virtual delivery protocol.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e000798</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e000798</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e000798</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1136/bmjph-2023-000798</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Obesity (OB) in children remains a national epidemic. This trial targets children suffering from overweight (OW) and OB living in rural Appalachia. Rural Appalachia is fraught with unhealthy behaviours, high rates of OB, pre-diabetes and type 2 diabetes among children. Diabetes prevalence in Appalachia is nearly double that of other regions. The prevalence of Appalachian children suffering from OB and extreme obesity (EO) increases the severity of diabetes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS AND ANALYSIS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We will conduct a stratified randomised-controlled trial to evaluate <i>Mentored Planning to be Active+Family (MPBA+F</i>) among seventh grade children with OW/OB/EO from rural Appalachian counties. Based on the Social Cognitive Theory, <i>MPBA+F</i> curriculum is a self-regulation approach to physical activity (PA) developed at The Ohio State University and successfully tested for feasibility in rural Appalachian middle schools. <i>MPBA+F</i> (a) incorporates active skill-building activities; (b) reinforces self-regulating activities; (c) engages in individual and group PA; (d) builds the link between PA, hydration and physical health and (e) actively supports weekly PA goals. Weekly skills are incorporated into reinforcement assignments verified at the beginning the following week. The primary outcome is the average daily minutes of moderate-vigorous PA. We will stratify by sex assigned at birth and conduct intent-to-treat analysis. We use descriptive statistics to summarise cohort and group (<i>MPBA+F</i>&#x2009;or comparison) baseline characteristics and examine variable distributions. Bivariate tests examine the balance of baseline characteristics by intervention groups. Mixed-effects linear modelling will be our more primary regression strategy. A potential problem is loss of curricular integrity. Our process assessment, structured mentor training and Instructor's Guide reduce this concern. Another concern may be the lack of reliable broadband access. Participating counties exceed 75% broadband access. Those who lose internet access may have materials mailed to their home or accessed on the study website.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="ETHICS AND DISSEMINATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study was reviewed and approved by the American Diabetes Association Grants Review Committee (Grant number 11-22-ICTSN-30), the host institution's Social and Behavioral Human Subjects Review Committee (Protocol 2022B0149) and is registered on ClinicalTrials.gov (Protocol NCT05758441). All data that can be shared without compromising human subject protections will be shared to an approved open data repository within six months of publication or 18 months of the conclusion of the funding period (November 2025) if the study remains unpublished. Dissemination to families and stakeholders is by project newsletters. Public presentation of findings will be shared at the Annual Appalachian Translational Research Network and local health department meetings.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION NUMBER" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">NCT05758441.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; Author(s) (or their employer(s)) 2024. Re-use permitted under CC BY-NC. Published by BMJ.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Laureen H</ForeName><Initials>LH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8460-0617</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Petosa</LastName><ForeName>Rick L</ForeName><Initials>RL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Alai</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shankle</LastName><ForeName>Shawnice</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phosri</LastName><ForeName>Yoottapichai</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05758441</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMJ Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918697578906676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2753-4294</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Body Mass Index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Community Health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Public Health</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40018636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11816420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjph-2023-000798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">bmjph-2023-000798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Singh GK, Kogan MD, Slifkin RT. Widening Disparities In Infant Mortality And Life Expectancy Between Appalachia And The Rest Of The United States, 1990&#x2013;2013. Health Aff (Millwood) 2017;36:1423&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1377/hlthaff.2016.1571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1377/hlthaff.2016.1571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28784735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ickes MJ, M. Slagle K. Targeting Obesity in Rural and Appalachian Children and Families: A Systematic Review of Prevention and Treatment Interventions. ujph. 2013;1:51&#x2013;64. doi: 10.13189/ujph.2013.010303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13189/ujph.2013.010303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore JB, Brinkley J, Crawford TW, et al. Association of the built environment with physical activity and adiposity in rural and urban youth. Prev Med. 2013;56:145&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.ypmed.2012.11.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ypmed.2012.11.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4761410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23219761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffith BN, Lovett GD, Pyle DN, et al. Self-rated health in rural Appalachia: health perceptions are incongruent with health status and health behaviors. BMC Public Health. 2011;11:229. doi: 10.1186/1471-2458-11-229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-11-229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3087683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21489282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swanson M, Schoenberg NE, Erwin H, et al. Perspectives on physical activity and exercise among Appalachian youth. J Phys Act Health. 2013;10:42&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1123/jpah.10.1.42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/jpah.10.1.42</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4445838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22397810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Council on Rural Health and Human Services . Mortality and Life Expectancy in Rural America: Connecting the Health and Human Service Safety Nets to Improve Health Outcomes over the Life Course. Rockville, MD: National Advisory Committee on Rural Health and Human Services; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moy E, Garcia MC, Bastian B, et al. Leading Causes of Death in Nonmetropolitan and Metropolitan Areas- United States, 1999-2014. MMWR Surveill Summ . 2017;66:1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.15585/mmwr.ss6601a1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15585/mmwr.ss6601a1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5829895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28081058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beverly EA, Ritholz MD, Cook K, et al. Diabetes in Appalachia: providers&#x2019; perspectives. Prim Health Care Res Dev . 2020;21:e11. :e11. doi: 10.1017/S1463423620000134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1463423620000134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7232122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32404218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meit M, Knudson A, Gilbert T, et al. The 2014 Update of the Rural-Urban Chartbook. Grand Forks, ND: Rural Health Reform Policy Research Center; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hortz B, Petosa R. Impact of the 'Planning to be Active' Leisure Time Physical Exercise Program on Rural High School Students. J Adolesc Health. 2006;39:530&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1016/j.jadohealth.2006.03.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jadohealth.2006.03.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16982388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith LH, Petosa RL, Shoben A. Peer mentor versus teacher delivery of a physical activity program on the effects of BMI and daily activity: protocol of a school-based group randomized controlled trial in Appalachia. BMC Public Health. 2018;18:633. doi: 10.1186/s12889-018-5537-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-018-5537-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5956615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29769106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petosa RL, Smith LH. Intervention Construct Validity of Planning to Be Active among Adolescents Living in Appalachia. Am J Health Educ. 2022;53:127&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1080/19325037.2022.2048752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19325037.2022.2048752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention  . Defining Childhood Weight Status: BMI for Children and Teens. 2024. https://www.cdc.gov/obesity/childhood/defining/html Available.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly AS, Barlow SE, Rao G, et al. Severe obesity in children and adolescents: identification, associated health risks, and treatment approaches: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2013;128:1689&#x2013;712. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0b013e3182a5cfb3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0b013e3182a5cfb3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24016455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felix J, Stark R, Teuner C, et al. Health related quality of life associated with extreme obesity in adolescents &#x2013; results from the baseline evaluation of the YES-study. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2020;18:58. doi: 10.1186/s12955-020-01309-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12955-020-01309-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7059717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32138734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karcher MJ. The Cross-Age Mentoring Program (CAMP)for Children with Adolescent Mentors: Mentor Training Guide. San Antonio, TX: Developmental Press; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leary JM, Lilly CL, Dino G, et al. Parental influences on 7-9 year olds&#x2019; physical activity: a conceptual model. Prev Med. 2013;56:341&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1016/j.ypmed.2013.02.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ypmed.2013.02.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4888866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23438761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith LH, Petosa RL, Sexton C, et al. Evaluating the Effectiveness of 'Mentoring to Be Active' for Rural Appalachian Middle School Youth on Physical Activity and Dietary Sugar Consumption during 'out of School Time. Mentor Tutoring: Partn in Learn. 2021;30:24&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1080/13611267.2022.2030184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13611267.2022.2030184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith LH. Piloting the use of teen mentors to promote a healthy diet and physical activity among children in Appalachia. J Spec Pediatr Nurs. 2011;16:16&#x2013;26. doi: 10.1111/j.1744-6155.2010.00264.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1744-6155.2010.00264.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21294832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith LH, Holloman C. Comparing the effects of teen mentors to adult teachers on child lifestyle behaviors and health outcomes in Appalachia. J Sch Nurs. 2013;29:386&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1177/1059840512472708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1059840512472708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5106027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23307890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith LH. Cross-age peer mentoring approach to impact the health outcomes of children and families. J Spec Pediatr Nurs. 2011;16:220&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1111/j.1744-6155.2011.00286.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1744-6155.2011.00286.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21702883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Actigraph Support . What&#x2019;s the Difference among the Cut Points Available in Actilife?Actigraph Support. 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanita Corporation of America . Tanita Corporation of America. Body Composition Analyzer Dc-430u Instruction Manual. Arlington Heights, Ill; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lubans DR, Hesketh K, Cliff DP, et al. A systematic review of the validity and reliability of sedentary behaviour measures used with children and adolescents. Obes Rev. 2011;12:781&#x2013;99. doi: 10.1111/j.1467-789X.2011.00896.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-789X.2011.00896.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21676153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rich C, Griffiths LJ, Dezateux C. Seasonal variation in accelerometer-determined sedentary behaviour and physical activity in children: a review. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2012;9:49. doi: 10.1186/1479-5868-9-49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1479-5868-9-49</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3511197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22546178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barreira TV, Staiano AE, Katzmarzyk PT. Validity assessment of a portable bioimpedance scale to estimate body fat percentage in white and African-American children and adolescents. Pediatr Obes. 2013;8:e29&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1111/j.2047-6310.2012.00122.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.2047-6310.2012.00122.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3602331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23239610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabiri LS, Hernandez DC, Mitchell K. Reliability, Validity, and Diagnostic Value of a Pediatric Bioelectrical Impedance Analysis Scale. Child Obes. 2015;11:650&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1089/chi.2014.0156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/chi.2014.0156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26332367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PROMIS Health Organization  Physical activity-a brief guide to the promis physical activity instruments. 2017. http://www.healthmeasures.net/ Available.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tucker CA, Bevans KB, Becker BD, et al. Development of the PROMIS Pediatric Physical Activity Item Banks. Phys Ther. 2020;100:1393&#x2013;410. doi: 10.1093/ptj/pzaa074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ptj/pzaa074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7439224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32313952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PROMIS Health Organization  Global health-a brief guide to the promis global health instruments. 2017. www.healthmeasures.net Available.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PROMIS Health Organization  PROMIS parent proxy scale v 1.0 - global health 7. 2016. https://www.healthmeasures.net/ Available.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altman DG. Comparability of Randomised Groups. Statistician. 1985;34:125. doi: 10.2307/2987510.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/2987510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senn SJ. Covariate imbalance and random allocation in clinical trials. Stat Med. 1989;8:467&#x2013;75. doi: 10.1002/sim.4780080410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.4780080410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2727470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. 2nd. Hillsdale, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates Publishers; 1988. edn.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cro S, Morris TP, Kenward MG, et al. Sensitivity analysis for clinical trials with missing continuous outcome data using controlled multiple imputation: A practical guide. Stat Med. 2020;39:2815&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1002/sim.8569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.8569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32419182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White IR, Royston P, Wood AM. Multiple imputation using chained equations: Issues and guidance for practice. Stat Med. 2011;30:377&#x2013;99. doi: 10.1002/sim.4067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.4067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21225900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin DB. Inference and missing data. Biometrika. 1976;63:581&#x2013;92. doi: 10.1093/biomet/63.3.581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/biomet/63.3.581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Little RJA. A Class of Pattern-Mixture Models for Normal Incomplete Data. Biometrika. 1994;81:471. doi: 10.2307/2337120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/2337120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>