<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40552059</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2673-5059</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>6</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in global women's health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Glob Womens Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Uncovering the hidden implications of water scarcity for maternal health: a photovoice study in rural Malawi (Thyolo district).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1588219</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1588219</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1588219</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fgwh.2025.1588219</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Access to clean water is essential for health, but in rural Malawi, water scarcity significantly threatens the health of postpartum women and their babies. Water is critical not only for hydration but also for hygiene, preventing infections, and promoting overall health, particularly during the postpartum period. Despite women's central role in water management within their households, they are seldom included in discussions about water access and management at the community level or within formal governance structures, where decisions are often made without their input. As climate change exacerbates water scarcity, addressing these challenges becomes increasingly urgent for maternal and child health.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="GOAL &amp; METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study aimed to create space for postpartum women to document and share their experiences with water scarcity and its implications through participatory photography. Eight women from rural communities in Thyolo District, Southern Malawi, were trained in photography and ethics. They captured images reflecting the challenges they faced with water access and maternal health. Through gallery walks and group discussions, photovoice allowed women to share the stories behind their images, providing deeper insight into the emotional, social and health implications of water insecurity. A phenomenological analysis was conducted to interpret the photographs and narratives.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The women's photographs and stories highlighted the multifaceted impact of water scarcity on health. They depicted not only the physical toll of water collection but also the emotional stress and heightened risk of infection due to inadequate sanitation. Through photovoice, the women conveyed a powerful narrative of vulnerability, resilience and frustration, revealing issues that are often invisible in traditional health research.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Photovoice proved to be an effective tool for amplifying the voices of marginalized postpartum women, enabling them to highlight the urgent need for clean water access. This approach not only raised awareness of water-related health issues but also provided valuable insights into the lived realities of women in rural Malawi. As climate change continues to intensify water scarcity, these findings underscore the need for sustainable, community-driven solutions. The study offers a model for inclusive research on global health challenges, particularly in vulnerable communities.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Pittalis, Kogoya, Ja&#xe9;n Osuna and Kambala.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pittalis</LastName><ForeName>Chiara</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Global Surgery, School of Population Health, RCSI University of Medicine and Health Sciences, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kogoya</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public and Environmental Health Sciences Department, School of Science and Technology, Malawi University of Business and Applied Sciences, Blantyre, Malawi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ja&#xe9;n Osuna</LastName><ForeName>Antonio</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Global Surgery, School of Population Health, RCSI University of Medicine and Health Sciences, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kambala</LastName><ForeName>Christabel</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Public and Environmental Health Sciences Department, School of Science and Technology, Malawi University of Business and Applied Sciences, Blantyre, Malawi.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Glob Womens Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101776281</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2673-5059</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Africa</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clean water</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">climate change</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">community-based participatory research</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">photovoice</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">public health</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40552059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12183164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fgwh.2025.1588219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Global Progress Report on Water, Sanitation and Hygiene in Health Care Facilities: Fundamentals First. Geneva: World Health Organization; (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Government of Malawi. Revised National Water Policy. Lilongwe: Ministry of Water and Sanitation, Government of Malawi;  (2022). Available at:
https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.water.gov.mw/index.php/ar/downloads/policy-documents&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1737386611697838&amp;usg=AOvVaw3sWskfiKNHBPTG_XqguYW9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hay RE, Phiri MAR. Situation Analysis of Disaster Risk Management Programmes and Practices in Malawi (2008). Available at:
https://www4.unfccc.int/sites/napparties/Malawi/Shared Documents/Disaster SA Malawi Final Volume 1 20081105.pdf (Accessed January 20, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng JJ, Schuster-Wallace CJ, Watt S, Newbold BK, Mente A. An ecological quantification of the relationships between water, sanitation and infant, child, and maternal mortality. Environ Heal A Glob Access Sci Source. (2012) 11(1):1&#x2013;8. 10.1186/1476-069X-11-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1476-069X-11-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3293047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22280473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benova L, Cumming O, Campbell OMR. Systematic review and meta-analysis: association between water and sanitation environment and maternal mortality. Trop Med Int Health. (2014) 19(4):368&#x2013;87. 10.1111/tmi.12275</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tmi.12275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24506558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhutta ZA, Das JK, Walker N, Rizvi A, Campbell H, Rudan I, et al. Interventions to address deaths from childhood pneumonia and diarrhoea equitably: what works and at what cost? Lancet. (2013) 381(9875):1417&#x2013;29. 10.1016/S0140-6736(13)60648-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(13)60648-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23582723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The SURG-Water project. Available at:
https://surgwater.ie/
(Accessed May 4, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster RC, Butler MS, Wutich A, Miller JD, Young SL. If there is no water, we cannot feed our children&#x201d;: the far-reaching consequences of water insecurity on infant feeding practices and infant health across 16 low- and middle-income countries. Am J Hum Biol. (2020) 32(1):e23357. 10.1002/ajhb.23357</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajhb.23357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7537364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31868269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watt S, Chamberlain J. Water, climate change, and maternal and newborn health. Curr Opin Environ Sustain. (2011) 3(6):491&#x2013;6. 10.1016/j.cosust.2011.10.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cosust.2011.10.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bisung E, Elliott SJ. Psychosocial impacts of the lack of access to water and sanitation in low- and middle-income countries: a scoping review. J Water Health. (2017) 15(1):17&#x2013;30. 10.2166/wh.2016.158</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/wh.2016.158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28151436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins SM, Mbullo Owuor P, Miller JD, Boateng GO, Wekesa P, Onono M, et al. I know how stressful it is to lack water!&#x201d; exploring the lived experiences of household water insecurity among pregnant and postpartum women in western Kenya. Glob Public Health. (2019) 14(5):649&#x2013;62. 10.1080/17441692.2018.1521861</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17441692.2018.1521861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6414268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30231793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terefe B, Jembere MM, Assimamaw NT. Access to drinking safe water and its associated factors among households in East Africa: a mixed effect analysis using 12 East African countries recent national health survey. J Heal Popul Nutr. (2024) 43(1):1&#x2013;10. 10.1186/s41043-024-00562-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41043-024-00562-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11127454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38790067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engel S, Iskandarani M, Useche MdP. Improved Water Supply in the Ghanaian Volta Basin: Who Uses It and Who Participates in Community Decision-Making? EPTD Discuss Pap (2005); Available at:
https://ideas.repec.org/p/fpr/eptddp/129.html
(Accessed January 20, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demberere T, Chidziya T, Ncozana T, Manyeruke N. Knowledge and practices regarding water, sanitation and hygiene (WASH) among mothers of under-fives in Mawabeni, Umzingwane district of Zimbabwe. Phys Chem Earth, Parts A/B/C. (2016) 92:119&#x2013;24. 10.1016/j.pce.2015.09.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pce.2015.09.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kioko KJ, Obiri JF. Household attitudes and knowledge on drinking water enhance water hazards in peri-urban communities in Western Kenya. J&#xe0;mb&#xe1; J Disaster Risk Stud. (2012) 4(1):1&#x2013;5. 10.4102/jamba.v4i1.49</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4102/jamba.v4i1.49</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bitew BD, Gete YK, Biks GA, Adafrie TT. Knowledge, attitude, and practice of mothers/caregivers on household water treatment methods in Northwest Ethiopia: a community-based cross-sectional study. Am J Trop Med Hyg. (2017) 97(3):914. 10.4269/ajtmh.16-0860</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4269/ajtmh.16-0860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5590582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28722624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsekleves E, Braga MF, Abonge C, Santana M, Pickup R, Anchang KY, et al. Community engagement in water, sanitation and hygiene in sub-Saharan Africa: does it WASH? J Water, Sanit Hyg Dev. (2022) 12(2):143&#x2013;56. 10.2166/washdev.2022.136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/washdev.2022.136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Burris MA. Photovoice: concept, methodology, and use for participatory needs assessment. Health Educ Behav. (1997) 24(3):369&#x2013;87. 10.1177/109019819702400309</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/109019819702400309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9158980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fantini E. Picturing waters: a review of photovoice and similar participatory visual research on water governance. WIRES Water. (2017) 4(5):e1226. 10.1002/wat2.1226</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wat2.1226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5586199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28944054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musoke D, Ssemugabo C, Ndejjo R, Ekirapa-Kiracho E, George AS. Reflecting strategic and conforming gendered experiences of community health workers using photovoice in rural Wakiso district, Uganda. Hum Resour Health. (2018) 16(1):1&#x2013;9. 10.1186/s12960-018-0306-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12960-018-0306-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6104020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30134905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson J. Picturing gendered water spaces: a textual approach to water in rural Sierra Leone. Agenda. (2011) 25(2):43&#x2013;53. 10.1080/10130950.2011.575996</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10130950.2011.575996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Natural Resources and Climate Change. State of Malawi Climate in 2022. Blantyre: Department of Climate Change and Meteorological Services, Government of Malawi;  (2022). Available at:
https://www.metmalawi.gov.mw/documents/5/stateofmalawiclimate22.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of Disaster Management Affairs. Malawi Hazards and Vulnerability Atlas. Lilongwe: Department of Disaster Management Affairs, Government of Malawi; (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Homeland Security Department of Disaster Management Affairs. Comprehensive Baseline Assessment of Disaster Risk Management in Malawi. Lilongwe: Government of Malawi;  (2018). Available at:
https://drmims.sadc.int/sites/default/files/document/2020-03/2018_DRM Revised report Dec%2C 2018.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Government of Malawi. Malawi 2015 Floods Post Disaster Needs Assessment Report. Lilongwe: Government of Malawi;  (2015). Available at:
https://www.gfdrr.org/sites/default/files/publication/pda-2015-malawi.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Statistics Office. Malawi Poverty Report 2020. Zomba: Government of Malawi; (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Bank. Malawi Total Population. Available at:
https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/SP.POP.TOTL?end=2023&amp;locations=MW&amp;start=2013
(Accessed May 5, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman IM, Kanjanawong S. Using photography to cross generational, linguistic, and cultural barriers to develop useful survey instruments. Health Promot Pract. (2005) 6(1):53&#x2013;6. 10.1177/1524839903259307</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1524839903259307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15574528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liebenberg L. Thinking critically about photovoice: achieving empowerment and social change. Int J Qual Methods. (2018) 17(1):1609406918757631. 10.1177/1609406918757631</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1609406918757631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Israel BA, Schulz AJ, Parker EA, Becker AB. Review of community-based research: assessing partnership approaches to improve public health. Annu Rev Public Health. (1998) 19:173&#x2013;202. 10.1146/annurev.publhealth.19.1.173</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.publhealth.19.1.173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9611617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coemans S, Raymakers AL, Vandenabeele J, Hannes K. Evaluating the extent to which social researchers apply feminist and empowerment frameworks in photovoice studies with female participants: a literature review. Qual Soc Work. (2017) 18(1):37&#x2013;59. 10.1177/1473325017699263</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1473325017699263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minkler M. Ethical challenges for the &#x201c;outside&#x201d; researcher in community-based participatory research. Health Educ Behav. (2004) 31(6):684&#x2013;97. 10.1177/1090198104269566</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1090198104269566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15539542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans-Agnew RA, Rosemberg MAS. Questioning photovoice research: whose voice? Qual Health Res. (2016) 26(8):1019&#x2013;30. 10.1177/1049732315624223</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732315624223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26786953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Statistical Office. 2018 Malawi Population and Housing Census Main Report. Blantyre: Government of Malawi; (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutton-Brown CA. Photovoice: a methodological guide. Photogr Cult. (2014) 7(2):169&#x2013;85. 10.2752/175145214X13999922103165</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2752/175145214X13999922103165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PhotoVoice. PhotoVoice Statement of Ethical Practice (2023). Available at:
https://photovoice.org/soep/
(Accessed January 20, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussey W. Slivers of the journey: the use of photovoice and storytelling to examine female to male transsexuals&#x2019; experience of health care access. J Homosex. (2006) 51(1):129&#x2013;58. 10.1300/J082v51n01_07</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1300/J082v51n01_07</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16893829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mooney R, Bhui K. Analysing multimodal data that have been collected using photovoice as a research method. BMJ Open. (2023) 13(4):e068289. 10.1136/bmjopen-2022-068289</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2022-068289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10111907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37068902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell C. &#x201c;The girl should just clean up the mess&#x201d;: on studying audiences in understanding the meaningful engagement of young people in policy-making. Int J Qual Methods. (2017) 16(1):1609406917703501. 10.1177/1609406917703501</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1609406917703501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geere JAL, Hunter PR, Jagals P. Domestic water carrying and its implications for health: a review and mixed methods pilot study in Limpopo province, South Africa. Environ Heal A Glob Access Sci Source. (2010) 9(1):1&#x2013;13. 10.1186/1476-069X-9-52</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1476-069X-9-52</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2939590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20796292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gjerde JL, Rortveit G, Muleta M, Adefris M, Blystad A. Living with pelvic organ prolapse: voices of women from amhara region, Ethiopia. Int Urogynecol J. (2017) 28(3):361&#x2013;6. 10.1007/s00192-016-3077-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-016-3077-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5331107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27475794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomberge VMJ, Shrestha A, Meierhofer R, Inauen J. Understanding safe water-carrying practices during pregnancy and postpartum: a mixed-methods study in Nepal. Appl Psychol Health Well Being. (2022) 14(2):691&#x2013;711. 10.1111/aphw.12325</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aphw.12325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9300039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34862740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Postnatal Care for Mothers and Newborns: Highilights from the WHO 2013 Guidelines. Geneva: World Health Organization; (2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boone C, Glick P, Sahn DE. Household water supply choice and time allocated to water collection: evidence from Madagascar. J Dev Stud. (2011) 47(12):1826&#x2013;50. 10.1080/00220388.2011.579394</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00220388.2011.579394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robb KA, Habiyakare C, Kateera F, Nkurunziza T, Dusabe L, Kubwimana M, et al. Variability of water, sanitation, and hygiene conditions and the potential infection risk following cesarean delivery in rural Rwanda. J Water Health. (2020) 18(5):741&#x2013;52. 10.2166/wh.2020.220</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2166/wh.2020.220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33095197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lusambili A, Nakstad B. Awareness and interventions to reduce dehydration in pregnant, postpartum women, and newborns in rural Kenya. African J Prim Heal Care Fam Med. (2023) 15(1):3991. 10.4102/phcfm.v15i1.3991</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4102/phcfm.v15i1.3991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10244926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37265162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimutai JJ, Lund C, Moturi WN, Shewangizaw S, Feyasa M, Hanlon C. Evidence on the links between water insecurity, inadequate sanitation and mental health: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. (2023) 18(5):e0286146. 10.1371/journal.pone.0286146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0286146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10212143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37228056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham JP, Hirai M, Kim SS. An analysis of water collection labor among women and children in 24 Sub-Saharan African countries. PLoS One. (2016) 11(6):e0155981. 10.1371/journal.pone.0155981</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0155981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4889070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27248494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pindani M, Chilinda I, Botha J, Chorwe-Sungani G. Exploring community support on safe motherhood: a case of Lilongwe district, Malawi. Afr J Prim Heal Care Fam Med. (2021) 13(1):1&#x2013;7. 10.4102/phcfm.v13i1.2907</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4102/phcfm.v13i1.2907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8424708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34342479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akpabio EM, Mwathunga E, Rowan JS. Understanding the challenges governing Malawi&#x2019;s water, sanitation and hygiene sector. Int J Water Resour Dev. (2022) 38(3):426&#x2013;46. 10.1080/07900627.2021.1897947</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07900627.2021.1897947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obrist B, Pfeiffer C, Henley R. Multi-layered social resilience: a new approach in mitigation research. Prog Dev Stud. (2010) 10(4):283&#x2013;93. 10.1177/146499340901000402</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/146499340901000402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson JA. Intersectionality and water: how social relations intersect with ecological difference. Gender, Place Cult. (2016) 23(9):1286&#x2013;301. 10.1080/0966369X.2016.1160038</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0966369X.2016.1160038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>UNICEF/WHO. Joint Monitoring Programme for Water Supply Sanitation and Hygiene. Progress on Household Drinking Water, Sanitation and Hygiene 2000&#x2013;2022: Special Focus on Gender (2023). Available at:
https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/progress-on-household-drinking-water-sanitation-and-hygiene-2000-2022-special-focus-on-gender#:&#x223c;:text=The 2023 WHO%2FUNICEF JMP, Gender Inequalities in WASH Services (Accessed January 20, 2025).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>