<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39238226</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1520-6033</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>41</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Season>Jan-Feb</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biotechnology progress</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biotechnol Prog</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A new method to immobilize urease in silk fibroin membrane by unidirectional nanopore dehydration.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e3502</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e3502</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/btpr.3502</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The immobilization of free enzymes is crucial for enhancing their stability in different environments, enabling reusability, and expanding their applications. However, the development of a straightforward immobilization method that offers stability, high efficiency, biocompatibility, and modifiability remains a significant challenge. Silk fibroin (SF) is a good carrier for immobilized enzymes and drugs. Here, we employed urease as a model enzyme and utilized our developed technology called unidirectional nanopore dehydration (UND) to efficiently dehydrate a regenerated SF solution containing urease in a single step, resulting in the preparation of a highly functionalized SF membrane immobilizing urease (UI-SFM). The preparation process of UI-SFM is based on an all-water system, which is mild, green and able to efficiently and stably immobilize urease in the membranes, maintaining 92.7% and 82.8% relative enzyme activity after 30&#x2009;days of storage in dry and hydrated states, respectively. Additionally, we performed additional post-treatments, including stretching and cross-linking with polyethylene glycol diglycidyl ether (PEGDE), to obtain two more robust immobilized urease membranes (UI-SFMs and UI-SFMc). The thermal and storage stability of these two membranes were significantly improved, and the recovery ratio of enzyme activity reached more than 90%. After 10 repetitions of the enzymatic reaction, the activity recovery of UI-SFMs and UI-SFMc remained at 92% and 88%, respectively. The results suggest that both UND-based and post-treatment-developed membranes exhibit excellent urease immobilization capabilities. Furthermore, the enzyme immobilization method offers a straightforward and versatile approach for efficient and stable enzyme immobilization, while its flexible modifiability caters to diverse application requirements.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 American Institute of Chemical Engineers.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Meng</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Silk Biotechnology Laboratory, School of Biology and Basic Medical Sciences, National Engineering Laboratory for Modern Silk, Soochow University, Suzhou, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Hai-Yan</ForeName><Initials>HY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Stomatology Department, The People's Hospital of Suzhou New District, Suzhou, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Qing</ForeName><Initials>YQ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7670-386X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Silk Biotechnology Laboratory, School of Biology and Basic Medical Sciences, National Engineering Laboratory for Modern Silk, Soochow University, Suzhou, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>CARS-18-ZJ0502</GrantID><Agency>Earmarked Fund for China Agriculture Research System</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>SKJYD2021059</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Development of Suzhou Science and Technology Bureau</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>SKYD2022091</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Development of Suzhou Science and Technology Bureau</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>SGY2020E02</GrantID><Agency>Science and Innovation Project funded by The People's Hospital of Suzhou New District</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>JDYY2023127</GrantID><Agency>Medical Education Collaborative Innovation Fund of Jiangsu University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Priority Academic Program Development of Jiangsu Higher Education Institutions</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Biotechnol Prog</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8506292</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1520-6033</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 3.5.1.5</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014510">Urease</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9007-76-5</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005349">Fibroins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004800">Enzymes, Immobilized</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008567">Membranes, Artificial</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014510" MajorTopicYN="Y">Urease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005349" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fibroins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004800" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enzymes, Immobilized</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058608" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nanopores</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008567" MajorTopicYN="N">Membranes, Artificial</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cross&#x2010;linking</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immobilized enzyme</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">silk fibroin membrane</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stretching</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">unidirectional nanopore dehydration</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39238226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/btpr.3502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Ashkan Z, Hemmati R, Homaei A, Dinari A, Jamlidoost M, Tashakor A. Immobilization of enzymes on nanoinorganic support materials: an update. Int J Biol Macromol. 2021;168:708&#x2010;721. doi:10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2020.11.127</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang X, Liu Y, Wen K, Jiang W, Li Q. Immobilized enzymes in inorganic hybrid nanoflowers for biocatalytic and biosensing applications. J Mater Chem B. 2021;9(37):7597&#x2010;7607. doi:10.1039/d1tb01476e</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li P, Chen Q, Wang TC, et al. Hierarchically engineered mesoporous metal&#x2010;organic frameworks toward cell&#x2010;free immobilized enzyme systems. Chem. 2018;4(5):1022&#x2010;1034. doi:10.1016/j.chempr.2018.03.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oke MA, Ojo SA, Fasiku SA, Adebayo EA. Nanotechnology and enzyme immobilization: a review. Nanotechnology. 2023;34(38):10. doi:10.1088/1361&#x2010;6528/acda35</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei X, Luo Z, Qiao L. Putting precision and elegance in enzyme immobilization with bio&#x2010;orthogonal chemistry. Chem Soc Rev. 2022;51(16):7281&#x2010;7304. doi:10.1039/d1cs01004b</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilal M, Asgher M, Cheng H, Yan Y, Iqbal HMN. Multi&#x2010;point enzyme immobilization, surface chemistry, and novel platforms: a paradigm shift in biocatalyst design. Crit Rev Biotechnol. 2019;39(2):202&#x2010;219. doi:10.1080/07388551.2018.1531822</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva MVC, Rangel ABS, Rosa CMR, Assis GP, Aguiar LG, Freitas L. Development of a magnetically stabilized fluidized bed bioreactor for enzymatic synthesis of 2&#x2010;ethylhexyl oleate. Bioprocess Biosyst Eng. 2023;46(11):1665&#x2010;1676. doi:10.1007/s00449&#x2010;023&#x2010;02928&#x2010;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu DM, Dong C. Recent advances in nano&#x2010;carrier immobilized enzymes and their applications. Process Biochem. 2020;92:464&#x2010;475. doi:10.1016/j.procbio.2020.02.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sass AC, J&#xf6;rdening HJ. Immobilization of &#x3b2;&#x2010;galactosidase from Aspergillus oryzae on electrospun gelatin nanofiber mats for the production of Galactooligosaccharides. Appl Biochem Biotechnol. 2020;191(3):1155&#x2010;1170. doi:10.1007/s12010&#x2010;020&#x2010;03252&#x2010;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilal M, Singh AK, Iqbal HMN, Zdarta J, Chrobok A, Jesionowski T. Enzyme&#x2010;linked carbon nanotubes as biocatalytic tools to degrade and mitigate environmental pollutants. Environ Res. 2024;241:117579. doi:10.1016/j.envres.2023.117579</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed NS, Hsu CY, Mahmoud ZH, Sayadi H, Kianfar E. A graphene oxide/polyaniline nanocomposite biosensor: synthesis, characterization, and electrochemical detection of bilirubin. RSC Adv. 2023;13(51):36280&#x2010;36292. doi:10.1039/d3ra06815c</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y, Xu Y, Liu S, et al. Recent advances in enzyme immobilization based on novel porous framework materials and its applications in biosensing. Coord Chem Rev. 2022;459:214414. doi:10.1016/j.ccr.2022.214414</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang HY, Zhang Y, Zhang M, Zhang YQ. Functional modification of silk fibroin from silkworms and its application to medical biomaterials: a review. Int J Biol Macromol. 2024;259(Pt 1):129099. doi:10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2023.129099</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakadia BM, Qaed Ahmed AA, Lamboni L, et al. Engineering homologous platelet&#x2010;rich plasma, platelet&#x2010;rich plasma&#x2010;derived exosomes, and mesenchymal stem cell&#x2010;derived exosomes&#x2010;based dual&#x2010;crosslinked hydrogels as bioactive diabetic wound dressings. Bioact Mater. 2023;28:74&#x2010;94. doi:10.1016/j.bioactmat.2023.05.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian XQ, Wang HY, Jing FY, Zhang YQ, Xu X, Shu Y. A novel immobilization method of urease in silk fibroin scaffolds by annealing at constant temperature and humidity. Macromol Mater Eng. 2023;308(7):1&#x2010;11. doi:10.1002/mame.202200700</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv S. Silk fibroin&#x2010;based materials for catalyst immobilization. Molecules. 2020;25(21):4929. doi:10.3390/molecules25214929</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demura M, Asakura T. Immobilization of glucose oxidase with Bombyx mori silk fibroin by only stretching treatment and its application to glucose sensor. Biotechnol Bioeng. 1989;33(5):598&#x2010;603. doi:10.1002/bit.260330513</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao M, Lv S. Self&#x2010;assembled regenerated silk fibroin microsphere&#x2010;embedded Fe3O4 magnetic nanoparticles for immobilization of zymolyase. ACS Omega. 2019;4(25):21612&#x2010;21619. doi:10.1021/acsomega.9b03491</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen H, Wang P, Han X, et al. GOx/Hb cascade oxidized crosslinking of silk fibroin for tissue&#x2010;responsive wound repair. Gels. 2022;8(1):56. doi:10.3390/gels8010056</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ai M, Guo C, Wang L, et al. Modulating surface charge of dexamethasone non&#x2010;spherical microcrystals for improved inner ear delivery. Colloids Surf B Biointerfaces. 2021;204:111806. doi:10.1016/j.colsurfb.2021.111806</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao F, Zhang J, Wang J, et al. Silk fibroin&#x2010;coated PLGA dimpled microspheres for retarded release of simvastatin. Colloids Surf B Biointerfaces. 2017;158:112&#x2010;118. doi:10.1016/j.colsurfb.2017.06.038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Wang HY, Zhang YQ. Unidirectional dehydration via nanopore constructs a silk metamaterial dominated by type II &#x3b2;&#x2010;turn structure with unusual stretching behavior and tunable mechanical properties. ACS Biomater Sci Eng. 2023;9:2741&#x2010;2754. doi:10.1021/acsbiomaterials.2c00729</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Weng YJ, Zhang YQ. Accelerated desalting and purification of silk fibroin in a CaCl2&#x2010;EtOH&#x2010;H2O ternary system by excess isopropanol extraction. J Chem Technol Biotechnol. 2021;96(5):1176&#x2010;1186. doi:10.1002/jctb.6629</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang YQ, Zhang M, Dong X, et al. A functional polymer membrane/hydrogel membrane based on unidirectional nanopore dehydration, preparation method and device. PRC Patent. 2022. CN114702704A, 2022&#x2010;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon BM, Choi MJ, Sultan MT, et al. Novel fabrication method of the peritoneal dialysis filter using silk fibroin with urease fixation system. J Biomed Mater Res B Appl Biomater. 2017;105(7):2136&#x2010;2144. doi:10.1002/jbm.b.33751</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui Y, Zhang F, Chen G. A stretchable and transparent electrode based on pegylated silk fibroin for in vivo dual&#x2010;modal neural&#x2010;vascular activity probing. Adv Mater. 2021;33(34):e2100221. doi:10.1002/adma.202100221</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>