<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40949278</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-1343</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>35</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS omega</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Omega</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Construction of the Clay Inhibition System for Water-Sensitive Reservoirs and Mechanism Study on CO<sub>2</sub>&#x2011;Assisted Synergistic Oil Recovery.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>40402</StartPage><EndPage>40415</EndPage><MedlinePgn>40402-40415</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsomega.5c05748</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Aiming at the problems of high clay mineral content in strong water-sensitive reservoirs and easy hydration expansion caused by foreign fluids, a clay inhibitor (silyl quaternary ammonium salt DSC) was prepared using 2-(dimethylamino)-ethyl methacrylate and (3-chloropropyl)-trimethoxysilane as raw materials. This is the first report on the synergistic application of silyl quaternary ammonium salt (DSC) and CO<sub>2</sub> for enhanced oil recovery in strongly water-sensitive reservoirs, realizing the dual effects of clay stabilization and CO<sub>2</sub> seepage enhancement. It is demonstrated that the synergy of DSC/CO<sub>2</sub> increases the oil recovery rate by 47.29% compared to traditional water flooding, with a 0.35 PV delay in gas channeling. The DSC system, composed of DSC, ethylene glycol, inorganic salt, and nonionic surfactant, stabilizes pore structures through synergistic charge neutralization, hydrogen bond inhibition, and electric double-layer compression, with an antiswelling rate of 93.92% and dissolution rate of 5.32%. The study on the synergistic effect of the DSC system and CO<sub>2</sub> found that the CO<sub>2</sub> diffusion coefficient in DSC-saturated cores increased to 9.226 &#xd7; 10<sup>-9</sup> m<sup>2</sup>/s (16 times higher than that in formation water-saturated cores), the initiation pressure gradient was reduced by 2 orders of magnitude compared with simulated water flooding, and the antiswelling rate decreased by only 13.72% after multiple rounds of flushing in an acidic environment. It was confirmed that DSC reconstructed the pore surface energy through silyl bonding, significantly improving the CO<sub>2</sub> seepage capacity. Nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) proved from a microscopic perspective that the synergy of DSC and CO<sub>2</sub> increased the recovery rate of the remaining oil in small pores by 25.08%. Macroscopic oil displacement experiments further showed that the total recovery rate of DSC system flooding + gas-liquid alternating flooding reached 62.85%. The proposed technical model of "dual-effect stable flow-synergistic oil recovery-delayed gas channeling" provides a solution with both technical feasibility and economic rationality for the development of low-permeability water-sensitive reservoirs and CO<sub>2</sub> geological storage. Future research will focus on formula optimization and adaptability studies for reservoirs with different clay compositions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Miaoxin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-3023-7581</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for EOR Technology (Ministry of Education), Northeast Petroleum University, Daqing 163318, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">117792</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Jingchun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for EOR Technology (Ministry of Education), Northeast Petroleum University, Daqing 163318, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">117792</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cai</LastName><ForeName>Liyuan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7402-8458</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for EOR Technology (Ministry of Education), Northeast Petroleum University, Daqing 163318, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">117792</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for EOR Technology (Ministry of Education), Northeast Petroleum University, Daqing 163318, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">117792</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for EOR Technology (Ministry of Education), Northeast Petroleum University, Daqing 163318, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">117792</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hou</LastName><ForeName>Yangyang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for EOR Technology (Ministry of Education), Northeast Petroleum University, Daqing 163318, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">117792</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fang</LastName><ForeName>Shi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for EOR Technology (Ministry of Education), Northeast Petroleum University, Daqing 163318, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">117792</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Chunlong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Daqing Yongzhu Petroleum Technology Development Co Ltd., Daqing 163000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Omega</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101691658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-1343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40949278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12423810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.5c05748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>International Energy Agency . World Energy Outlook 2024; International Energy Agency: Paris, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change . Climate Change 2023: Mitigation of Climate Change; Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change: Geneva, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations Environment Programme . Emissions Gap Report 2024; United Nations Environment Programme: Nairobi, 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu T., Tian H., Zhu H., Cai J.. China actively promotes CO2 capture, utilization and storage research to achieve carbon peak and carbon neutrality. Adv. Geo-Energy Res. 2022;6:1&#x2013;3. doi: 10.46690/ager.2022.01.01.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46690/ager.2022.01.01</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Guo C., Du C., Chen X., Jia L., Guo X.. et al. Carbon peak and carbon neutrality in China: Goals, implementation path, and prospects. China Geol. 2021;4:1&#x2013;27. doi: 10.31035/cg2021083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31035/cg2021083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Y., Nie F., Zhang B., Liu T., Hong Y.. The three-dimensional heterogeneous simulation study of CO2 flooding in low-permeability reservoirs. Processes. 2024;12:1843. doi: 10.3390/pr12091843.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pr12091843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paidin, W. R. ; Mwangi, P. ; Rao, D. N. . Economic evaluation within the scope of the field development and application of the gas-assisted gravity drainage GAGD process in an actual northern louisiana field. In SPE Hydrocarbon Economics and Evaluation Symposium, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Zhang B., Yang Y., Liu B., Shen L.. Storage ratio of CO2 miscible flooding in chang 8 reservoir of H block in ordos basin under different injection methods. Front. Energy Res. 2022;10:848324. doi: 10.3389/fenrg.2022.848324.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fenrg.2022.848324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grekov D. I., Robinet J.-C., Grambow B.. Adsorption of methane and carbon dioxide by water-saturated clay minerals and clay rocks. Appl. Clay Sci. 2023;232:106806. doi: 10.1016/j.clay.2022.106806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clay.2022.106806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao C., Jia J., Fan W., Chen S., Hu T., Wang X.. et al. Optimization of CO2 flooding under dual goals of oil recovery and CO2 storage: Numerical case studies of the first-ever CCUS pilot in changqing oilfield. Geoenergy Sci. Eng. 2024;240:213063. doi: 10.1016/j.geoen.2024.213063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geoen.2024.213063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu R., Wei B., Li S., Zhang Y., Luo Q.. Enhanced oil recovery in complex reservoirs: Challenges and methods. Adv. Geo-Energy Res. 2023;10:208&#x2013;212. doi: 10.46690/ager.2023.12.07.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46690/ager.2023.12.07</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Zhang K., Cheng N., Xing Z., Wang S., Wang B.. et al. Optimization and Evaluation of Stabilizers for Tight Water-Sensitive Conglomerate Reservoirs. ACS Omega. 2022;7:5921&#x2013;5928. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.1c06140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.1c06140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8867474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35224352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murtaza M., Kamal M. S., Mahmoud M.. Application of a novel and sustainable silicate solution as an alternative to sodium silicate for clay swelling inhibition. ACS Omega. 2020;5:17405&#x2013;17415. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.0c01777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.0c01777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7377079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32715225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macha S.. Diffusion control in thin clay films: Tailoring layered clay film structures through control of aqueous electrolyte. Appl. Clay Sci. 1999;15:153&#x2013;172. doi: 10.1016/S0169-1317(99)00022-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0169-1317(99)00022-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang R., Yang L., Qin N., Tu R., Zhou J., Ye Z.. The swelled clay shrinkage property and inhibition of microcosmic migration in pores of quaternary ammonium salt cationic polymer. Polym. Adv. Technol. 2015;26:1544&#x2013;1550. doi: 10.1002/pat.3579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pat.3579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L., Zhang H., Peng X., Wang P., Zhao N., Chu S.. et al. Water-sensitive damage mechanism and the injection water source optimization of low permeability sandy conglomerate reservoirs. Pet. Explor. Dev. 2019;46:1218&#x2013;1230. doi: 10.1016/S1876-3804(19)60275-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1876-3804(19)60275-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alazigha D. P., Indraratna B., Vinod J. S., Heitor A.. Mechanisms of stabilization of expansive soil with lignosulfonate admixture. Transp. Geotech. 2018;14:81&#x2013;92. doi: 10.1016/j.trgeo.2017.11.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trgeo.2017.11.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C., Lv K., Gong J., Wang Z., Huang X., Sun J.. et al. Synthesis of a hydrophobic quaternary ammonium salt as a shale inhibitor for water-based drilling fluids and determination of the inhibition mechanism. J. Mol. Liq. 2022;362:119474. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2022.119474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2022.119474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou L., Fan X., He Y., Gou S., Bi Q., Chen J.. et al. Enhanced the permeability of water invasion sandstone by effectively inhibiting the swelling and dispersion of montmorillonite. J. Mol. Liq. 2023;372:121196. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2022.121196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2022.121196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahmoud, T. N. ; Rao, D. N. . Mechanisms and performance demonstration of the gas-assisted gravity-drainage process using visual models. In SPE Annual Technical Conference and Exhibition, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X., Sun J., Jin J., Lv K., Li H., Rong K.. et al. Use of silicone quaternary ammonium salt for hydrophobic surface modification to inhibit shale hydration and mechanism study. J. Mol. Liq. 2021;341:117369. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2021.117369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2021.117369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu R., Wang S., Guo P., Hukuang H., Yuan N.. Multi-scale investigation of CO2-WAG injection mechanisms in water-sensitive tight oil reservoirs. Arabian J. Sci. Eng. 2025;50:10327&#x2013;10344. doi: 10.1007/s13369-024-09836-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13369-024-09836-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi Y., Xie J., Guo X., Wu T., Cheng D., Sun L.. et al. Experimental study of co2 drive/throughput in medium and deep thick oil in Xinjiang oilfield. Pet. Reservoir Eval. Dev. 2024;14:76&#x2013;82. doi: 10.13809/j.cnki.cn32-1825/te.2024.01.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13809/j.cnki.cn32-1825/te.2024.01.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murtaza M., Kamal M. S., Hussain S. M. S., Mahmoud M., Syed N. A.. Quaternary ammonium gemini surfactants having different spacer length as clay swelling inhibitors: Mechanism and performance evaluation. J. Mol. Liq. 2020;308:113054. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2020.113054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2020.113054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan R. A., Kalam S., Norrman K., Kamal M. S., Mahmoud M., Abdulraheem A.. Ionic liquids as clay swelling inhibitors: Adsorption study. Energy Fuels. 2022;36:3596&#x2013;3605. doi: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.2c00088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.2c00088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu S., Zou C., Ma D., Zhai X., Yu H., Yu Z.. Reservoir property changes during CO2&#x2013;brine flow-through experiments in tight sandstone: Implications for CO2 enhanced oil recovery in the Triassic Chang 7 Member tight sandstone, Ordos Basin, China. J. Asian Earth Sci. 2019;179:200&#x2013;210. doi: 10.1016/j.jseaes.2019.05.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jseaes.2019.05.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murtaza M., Ahmed Khan R., Kamal M. S., Hussain S. M. S., Mahmoud M.. Poly&#xad;(oxyethylene)-amidoamine based gemini cationic surfactants with hydrophilic spacers as clay stabilizers. Energy Fuels. 2020;34:10619&#x2013;10630. doi: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.0c01010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.0c01010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan L., Lu X., Zheng Y., Zhang G., Cheng Z.. Synthesis and performance of D230 polyether ammonium salts mixed with cationic gemini surfactant as clay stabilizer for water injection reservoirs. Arabian J. Sci. Eng. 2022;47:11793&#x2013;11805. doi: 10.1007/s13369-022-06561-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13369-022-06561-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong X., Shi Y., Huang D., Yang D.. Quantification of preferential and mutual mass transfer of gases-light oil systems at high pressures and elevated temperatures by dynamic volume analysis. Int. J. Heat Mass Transfer. 2022;195:123188. doi: 10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2022.123188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2022.123188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X., Qi Z., Yan W., Yuan Y., Tian J., Qin T.. Functions of capillary pressure and dissolution in the CO2-flooding process in low-permeability reservoirs. J. Pet. Explor. Prod. Technol. 2020;10:1881&#x2013;1890. doi: 10.1007/s13202-020-00853-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13202-020-00853-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong J., Yan R., Zhang H., Feng Y., Li N., Liu X.. A decomposition method of nuclear magnetic resonance T2 spectrum for identifying fluid properties. Pet. Explor. Dev. 2020;47:740&#x2013;752. doi: 10.1016/S1876-3804(20)60089-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1876-3804(20)60089-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui G., Zhang L., Tan C., Ren S., Zhuang Y., Enechukwu C.. Injection of supercritical CO 2 for geothermal exploitation from sandstone and carbonate reservoirs: CO 2 &#x2013; water&#x2013;rock interactions and their effects. J. CO2 Util. 2017;20:113&#x2013;128. doi: 10.1016/j.jcou.2017.05.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcou.2017.05.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L., Ren Y., Yao R., Yang H.. [NVim]&#xad;br and poly&#xad;([NVim]&#xad;br-co-AM): Synthesis and effects on inhibiting clay swelling and dispersion and the mechanisms. Macromol. Chem. Phys. 2024;225:2400141. doi: 10.1002/macp.202400141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/macp.202400141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H., Pu X.. Structure and inhibition properties of a new amine-terminated hyperbranched oligomer shale inhibitor. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 2019;136:47573. doi: 10.1002/app.47573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/app.47573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S., Huang D., Xu Z., Bai Y., Xie G., Li X.. et al. Synthesis and mechanism analysis of a non-toxic amine-based clay mineral surface hydration intercalation inhibitor. J. Mol. Liq. 2024;399:124362. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2024.124362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2024.124362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beg M., Haider M. B., Thakur N. K., Husein M., Sharma S., Kumar R.. Clay-water interaction inhibition using amine and glycol-based deep eutectic solvents for efficient drilling of shale formations. J. Mol. Liq. 2021;340:117134. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2021.117134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2021.117134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang G., Du H., Jiang S.. Synergistic inhibition effect of organic salt and polyamine on water-sensitive shale swelling and dispersion. J. Energy Resour. Technol. 2019;141:082901. doi: 10.1115/1.4042528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.4042528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murtaza M., Kamal M. S., Hussain S. M. S., Mahmoud M.. Clay swelling inhibition using novel cationic gemini surfactants with different spacers. J. Surfactants Deterg. 2020;23:963&#x2013;972. doi: 10.1002/jsde.12420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jsde.12420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balaban R. D. C., Vidal E. L. F., Borges M. R.. Design of experiments to evaluate clay swelling inhibition by different combinations of organic compounds and inorganic salts for application in water base drilling fluids. Appl. Clay Sci. 2015;105&#x2013;106:124&#x2013;130. doi: 10.1016/j.clay.2014.12.029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clay.2014.12.029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao S., Lin H., Peng X., Zhao X., Wang G.. Preparation and performance evaluation of quaternary ammonium cationic clay stabilizer for oilfield use. J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. 2023;2610:01205C7. doi: 10.1088/1742-6596/2610/1/012057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1742-6596/2610/1/012057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siyao H., Mingbiao X., Peng X., Yu Z., Xinying W.. Composite hydration process of clay minerals simulating mineral clay components and influence mechanism of cations. Energies. 2022;15:7550. doi: 10.3390/en15207550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en15207550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rezk M. G., Foroozesh J.. Phase behavior and fluid interactions of a CO2-light oil system at high pressures and temperatures. Heliyon. 2019;5:e02057. doi: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2019.e02057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2019.e02057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6664036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31384679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia W., Wang Y.-B., Wu J.-T., Zhang T., Gong L., Zhu C.-Y.. Microscopic mechanism study on gas&#x2013;crude-oil interactions during the CO2 flooding process in water-bearing reservoirs. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2025;26:6402. doi: 10.3390/ijms26136402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms26136402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12250298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40650179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basilio E., Addassi M., Al-Juaied M., Hassanizadeh S. M., Hoteit H.. Improved pressure decay method for measuring CO2-water diffusion coefficient without convection interference. Adv. Water Resour. 2024;183:104608. doi: 10.1016/j.advwatres.2023.104608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.advwatres.2023.104608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalam S., Abu-Khamsin S. A., Patil S., Hussain S. M. S., Mahmoud M., Kamal M. S.. et al. Static adsorption of a novel cationic gemini surfactant: A mineralogical study. Geoenergy Sci. Eng. 2023;225:211661. doi: 10.1016/j.geoen.2023.211661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geoen.2023.211661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clegg F., Breen C., Khairuddin. Synergistic and Competitive Aspects of the Adsorption of Poly&#xad;(ethylene glycol) and Poly&#xad;(vinyl alcohol) onto Na-Bentonite. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2014;118:13268&#x2013;13278. doi: 10.1021/jp507772t.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp507772t</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25348503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Earnden L., Van Der Zalm J., Chen A., Marangoni A. G., Van Lier R., Pensini E.. Comparative study of corrosion inhibition by three anionic surfactants in an acidic environment. J. Surfactants Deterg. 2022;25:399&#x2013;411. doi: 10.1002/jsde.12568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jsde.12568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J., Duan H., Jiang R.. Synergistic corrosion inhibition effect of quinoline quaternary ammonium salt and gemini surfactant in H2S and CO2 saturated brine solution. Corros. Sci. 2015;91:108&#x2013;119. doi: 10.1016/j.corsci.2014.11.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.corsci.2014.11.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin Y., Cui Z., Zhang X., Song J., Zhang X., Chen Y.. et al. Effects of Clay Content on Non-Linear Seepage Behaviors in the Sand&#x2013;Clay Porous Media Based on Low-Field Nuclear Magnetic Resonance. Water. 2024;16:883. doi: 10.3390/w16060883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/w16060883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang D.-C., Xie G., Peng N.-Y., Zou J.-G., Xu Y., Deng M.-Y., Du W. C., Xiao Y. R., Huang J. J., Luo P. Y.. Synergistic inhibition of polyethylene glycol and potassium chloride in water-based drilling fluids. Pet. Sci. 2021;18:827. doi: 10.1007/s12182-020-00543-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12182-020-00543-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan W.. Water-sensitive characterization and its controlling factors in clastic reservoir: A case study of jurassic ahe formation in northern tectonic zone of kuqa depression. Pet. Res. 2020;5:77&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1016/j.ptlrs.2019.07.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptlrs.2019.07.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang F.. Sensitivity evaluation and stimulation optimization of ultralow permeability sandstone reservoir. ACS Omega. 2023;8:37176&#x2013;37185. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.3c04767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.3c04767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10569001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37841149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>