<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39999755</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1095-8630</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>377</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of environmental management</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Environ Manage</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A study of benthic habitat classification schemes in the northern equatorial Pacific based on a Gaussian mixture model.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>124638</StartPage><MedlinePgn>124638</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.124638</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0301-4797(25)00614-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Due to the complexity and extreme environment of the deep sea, related research is limited by the level of detection technology, and the overall understanding of this topic is limited. At present, the increasing number of disturbances in the deep sea, such as those caused by deep-sea mining, necessitates the urgent formulation of scientifically informed deep-sea environmental management decisions. In response to this challenge, a data-driven, large-scale, and probability-based benthic habitat classification scheme is proposed for the northern equatorial Pacific. The dominant environmental factors were identified as topographic features (depth and slope), nutrients (particulate organic carbon flux entering the seabed and phosphate), and water mass properties (dissolved oxygen and pH), and the importance assessment indicated that nutrient played a dominant role, followed by water mass properties, with topographic features having a relatively minor influence. The multiple classification evaluation parameters determined 5 clusters of benthic habitats in the northern equatorial Pacific using the Gaussian mixture model (GMM). Furthermore, this paper provides the first discussion of ecotones at the edges of habitats and suggests that ecotones are more cost effective for environmental management. In conclusion, the benthic habitat classification scheme could provide a consistent unit for habitat mapping and representative assessment of marine protected area network design, as well as a scientific basis for the protection and management of the international seabed area.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Du</LastName><ForeName>Ranran</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Marine Mineral Resources, Ministry of Natural Resources, Guangzhou Marine Geological Survey, Guangzhou, 511458, China; National Engineering Research Center for Gas Hydrate Exploration and Development, Guangzhou, 511458, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Yong</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Marine Mineral Resources, Ministry of Natural Resources, Guangzhou Marine Geological Survey, Guangzhou, 511458, China; National Engineering Research Center for Gas Hydrate Exploration and Development, Guangzhou, 511458, China; Southern Marine Science and Engineering Guangdong Laboratory (Guangzhou), Guangzhou, 511458, China; Institute of Geology, Chinese Academy of Geological Sciences, Beijing, 100037, China. Electronic address: yong0913029@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Yikai</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Tropical Oceanography (LTO), South China Sea Institute of Oceanology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Guangzhou, 510000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Dongsheng</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Marine Ecosystem Dynamics, Second Institute of Oceanography, Ministry of Natural Resources, Hangzhou, 310012, China; School of Oceanography, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, 200240, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xia</LastName><ForeName>Ruixue</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ministry of Education Key Laboratory for Earth System Modeling, Institute for Global Change Studies, Department of Earth System Science, Tsinghua University, Beijing, 100084, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Miao</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Marine Mineral Resources, Ministry of Natural Resources, Guangzhou Marine Geological Survey, Guangzhou, 511458, China; National Engineering Research Center for Gas Hydrate Exploration and Development, Guangzhou, 511458, China. Electronic address: yumiao104@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Gaowen</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Marine Mineral Resources, Ministry of Natural Resources, Guangzhou Marine Geological Survey, Guangzhou, 511458, China; National Engineering Research Center for Gas Hydrate Exploration and Development, Guangzhou, 511458, China; Institute of Geology, Chinese Academy of Geological Sciences, Beijing, 100037, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hong</LastName><ForeName>Shuang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Marine Mineral Resources, Ministry of Natural Resources, Guangzhou Marine Geological Survey, Guangzhou, 511458, China; National Engineering Research Center for Gas Hydrate Exploration and Development, Guangzhou, 511458, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Shengxiong</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Marine Mineral Resources, Ministry of Natural Resources, Guangzhou Marine Geological Survey, Guangzhou, 511458, China; National Engineering Research Center for Gas Hydrate Exploration and Development, Guangzhou, 511458, China; Institute of Geology, Chinese Academy of Geological Sciences, Beijing, 100037, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Environ Manage</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0401664</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0301-4797</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017753" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ecosystem</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010140" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Pacific Ocean</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004784" MajorTopicYN="N">Environmental Monitoring</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deep-sea ecotone (DSE)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dominant environmental factors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gaussian mixture model (GMM)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Habitat classification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39999755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.124638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0301-4797(25)00614-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>