<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39867048</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Stay in the Game: Comprehensive Approaches to Decrease the Risk of Sports Injuries.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e76461</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e76461</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e76461</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.76461</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Recurrent sports injuries present complex challenges that extend beyond the playing field, impacting athletes' physical well-being, mental resilience, and financial stability. This review outlines a comprehensive framework designed to prevent and manage these setbacks, empowering athletes to achieve sustained performance and recovery. This multidimensional issue requires an integrative approach encompassing physical rehabilitation, psychological resilience, and nutritional strategies. Physically, injury prevention relies on tailored rehabilitation programs that address athletes' specific injury histories and sport-related demands. Techniques such as biomechanical assessments and neuromuscular training correct faulty movement patterns, while workload monitoring ensures a balance between training and recovery. Strength and conditioning programs have demonstrated success in reducing injury rates and enhancing musculoskeletal resilience. Psychologically, reinjury anxiety and mental disengagement are key barriers to recovery and performance. Interventions such as goal setting, mindfulness, and cognitive restructuring rebuild confidence and foster readiness to return to play. Addressing psychological well-being is as critical as physical health in promoting sustained performance. Nutrition is equally pivotal, with balanced macronutrient intake supporting energy and tissue repair and micronutrients (magnesium, manganese, vitamin D, selenium, zinc, coenzyme Q10, etc.) bolstering bone health. Anti-inflammatory nutrients and proper hydration reduce muscle strain and aid recovery, while personalized dietary strategies meet the specific demands of individual sports. By integrating these physical, psychological, and nutritional dimensions, this framework empowers athletes, coaches, and medical teams to minimize injury recurrence and enhance long-term performance, ensuring athletes remain competitive and resilient in their sporting pursuits.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024, Forelli et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Forelli</LastName><ForeName>Florian</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Rehabilitation, Orthosport Center, Domont, FRA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedic Surgery, Clinic of Domont, Domont, FRA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moiroux-Sahraoui</LastName><ForeName>Ayrton</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Rehabilitation, Orthosport Center, Domont, FRA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedic Surgery, Clinic of Domont, Domont, FRA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nielsen-Le Roux</LastName><ForeName>Mathias</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedic Surgery, Clinic of Domont, Domont, FRA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miraglia</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Therapy, Miraglia Private Clinic, Trieste, ITA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gaspar</LastName><ForeName>Maxime</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation, Centre National du Football (CNF) Clairefontaine, Clairefontaine-en-Yvelines, FRA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stergiou</LastName><ForeName>Maria</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Medicine, Universidad Europea de Madrid (UEM) Real Madrid, Madrid, ESP.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bjerregaard</LastName><ForeName>Andreas</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, DNK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mazeas</LastName><ForeName>Jean</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Rehabilitation, Orthosport Center, Domont, FRA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedic Surgery, Clinic of Domont, Domont, FRA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Douryang</LastName><ForeName>Maurice</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy and Physical Medicine, University of Dschang, Dschang, CMR.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomechanical assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">injury prevention strategies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutrition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychological resilience</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sports injuries</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39867048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11769697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.76461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Comparison of hamstring strain injury rates between male and female intercollegiate soccer athletes. Cross KM, Gurka KK, Saliba S, Conaway M, Hertel J. Am J Sports Med. 2013;41:742&#x2013;748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23408592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fear of re-injury: a hindrance for returning to sports after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. Kvist J, Ek A, Sporrstedt K, Good L. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2005;13:393&#x2013;397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15703963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Return to sport following anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis of the state of play. Ardern CL, Webster KE, Taylor NF, Feller JA. Br J Sports Med. 2011;45:596&#x2013;606.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21398310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An integrated model of response to sport injury: psychological and sociological dynamics. Wiese-bjornstal DM, Smith AM, Shaffer SM, Morrey MA. J Appl Sport Psychol. 1998;10:46&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of a sports specific balance training programme on the incidence of ankle sprains in basketball. Cumps E, Verhagen E, Meeusen R. https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC3786242/ J Sports Sci Med. 2007;6:212&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3786242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk factors for sports injuries&#x2014;a methodological approach. Bahr R, Holme I. Br J Sports Med. 2003;37:384&#x2013;392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1751357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14514527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Symptoms of common mental disorders in professional football (soccer) across five European countries. Gouttebarge V, Backx FJ, Aoki H, Kerkhoffs GM. https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC4657424/ J Sports Sci Med. 2015;14:811&#x2013;818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4657424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26664278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluating the level of injury in English professional football using a risk based assessment process. Drawer S, Fuller CW. Br J Sports Med. 2002;36:446&#x2013;451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1724558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12453840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sports, joint injury, and posttraumatic osteoarthritis. Buckwalter JA. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2003;33:578&#x2013;588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14620787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Infographic. Pain or injury? Why differentiation matters in exercise and sports medicine. Hoegh M, Stanton T, George S, Lyng KD, Vistrup S, Rathleff MS. Br J Sports Med. 2022;56:299&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34531187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serious sports-related injury in England and Wales from 2012-2017: a study protocol. Davies MA, Lawrence T, Edwards A, Lecky F, McKay CD, Stokes KA, Williams S. Inj Epidemiol. 2020;7:14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7184700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32336291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinjury anxiety and return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a cluster analysis and prospective study among 162 athletes. Caumeil B, Laboute E, Verhaeghe E, P&#xe9;rez S, D&#xe9;camps G. Am J Sports Med. 2024;52:1189&#x2013;1198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38520139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Does perceived injustice correlate with pain intensity and disability in orthopaedic trauma patients? van Leeuwen WF, van der Vliet QM, Janssen SJ, Heng M, Ring D, Vranceanu AM. Injury. 2016;47:1212&#x2013;1216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26994517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mental and psychosocial health among current and former professional footballers. Gouttebarge V, Frings-Dresen MH, Sluiter JK. Occup Med (Lond) 2015;65:190&#x2013;196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25638208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psychological consequences of athletic injury among high-level competitors. Leddy MH, Lambert MJ, Ogles BM. Res Q Exerc Sport. 1994;65:347&#x2013;354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7886284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Injury in professional basketball players and medical support. Kim SG, Nozawa M. Juntendo Med J. 2018;64:444&#x2013;449.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of physical inactivity on major non-communicable diseases worldwide: an analysis of burden of disease and life expectancy. Lee IM, Shiroma EJ, Lobelo F, Puska P, Blair SN, Katzmarzyk PT. Lancet. 2012;380:219&#x2013;229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3645500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22818936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health benefits of physical activity: the evidence. Warburton DE, Nicol CW, Bredin SS. CMAJ. 2006;174:801&#x2013;809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1402378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16534088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Psychological predictors of injuries in circus artists: an exploratory study. Shrier I, Hall&#xe9; M. Br J Sports Med. 2011;45:433&#x2013;436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21047839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Previous injury as a risk factor for injury in elite football: a prospective study over two consecutive seasons. H&#xe4;gglund M, Wald&#xe9;n M, Ekstrand J. Br J Sports Med. 2006;40:767&#x2013;772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2564391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16855067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effective prevention of sports injuries: a model integrating efficacy, efficiency, compliance and risk-taking behaviour. Van Tiggelen D, Wickes S, Stevens V, Roosen P, Witvrouw E. Br J Sports Med. 2008;42:648&#x2013;652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18400875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calf muscle strain injuries in elite Australian football players: a descriptive epidemiological evaluation. Green B, Lin M, Schache AG, et al. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2020;30:174&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31494970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Intrinsic risk factors of non-contact quadriceps and hamstring strains in soccer: a prospective study of 100 professional players. Fousekis K, Tsepis E, Poulmedis P, Athanasopoulos S, Vagenas G. Br J Sports Med. 2011;45:709&#x2013;714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21119022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Methodological approaches and rationale for training to prevent anterior cruciate ligament injuries in female athletes. Myer GD, Ford KR, Hewett TE. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2004;14:275&#x2013;285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15387801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strength training as superior, dose-dependent and safe prevention of acute and overuse sports injuries: a systematic review, qualitative analysis and meta-analysis. Lauersen JB, Andersen TE, Andersen LB. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52:1557&#x2013;1563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30131332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Progressing rehabilitation after injury: consider the 'control-chaos continuum'. Taberner M, Allen T, Cohen DD. Br J Sports Med. 2019;53:1132&#x2013;1136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6818668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30737202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Complex systems approach for sports injuries: moving from risk factor identification to injury pattern recognition-narrative review and new concept. Bittencourt NF, Meeuwisse WH, Mendon&#xe7;a LD, Nettel-Aguirre A, Ocarino JM, Fonseca ST. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:1309&#x2013;1314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27445362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The training-injury prevention paradox: should athletes be training smarter and harder? Gabbett TJ. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:273&#x2013;280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4789704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26758673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anterior pelvic tilt increases hamstring strain and is a key factor to target for injury prevention and rehabilitation. Mendiguchia J, Garrues MA, Schilders E, Myer GD, Dalmau-Pastor M. Knee Surg Sports Traumatol Arthrosc. 2024;32:573&#x2013;582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38391038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevention of overhead shoulder injuries in throwing athletes: a systematic review. Moiroux-Sahraoui A, Mazeas J, Delgado N, et al. Diagnostics (Basel) 2024;14:2415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11545345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39518380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparative electromyographic activity of hamstrings during sprinting versus strengthening exercises: implications for injury prevention. Moiroux-Sahraoui A, Mazeas J, Bener EA, Bouzekraoui Alaoui I, Douryang M, Forelli F. Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11378697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39247046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Relationship between force-velocity characteristics and sprint performance in elite sprinters: a pilot study. Moiroux-Sahraoui A, Mazeas J, Jhingoor JM, Douryang M, Bouzerkraoui Alaoui I, Forelli F. Cureus. 2024;16:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11365460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39221303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Incidence and determinants of lower extremity running injuries in long distance runners: a systematic review. van Gent RN, Siem D, van Middelkoop M, van Os AG, Bierma-Zeinstra SM, Koes BW. Br J Sports Med. 2007;41:469&#x2013;480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2465455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17473005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>431 BO54 - is decceleration the key element in vertical jump performance to return to sport after anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction? Forelli F, Branis Nekhouf M, Vandebrouck A, Duffiet P, Ratte L, Hewett TE, Rambaud AJ. Br J Sports Med. 2024;58:0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Predict anterior cruciate ligament injury in elite male soccer players? Focus on the five factors maximum model. Forelli F, Traulle M, Bechaud N, et al. Int J Physiother. 2021;8:211&#x2013;216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Determination of predictive isokinetic indicators for return to sport at 6 months after ACL surgery with semitendinous and gracilis tendons. Oertwig R, Linard M, Traulle M, Vandebrouck A, Duffiet P, Ratte L, Forelli F. Int J Phys Ther Rehabil. 2019;5:1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The psychosocial aspects of a return to sport following serious injury: a review of the literature from a self-determination perspective. Podlog L, Eklund RC. Psychol Sport Exerc. 2007;8:535&#x2013;566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anterior cruciate ligament injuries in female athletes: part 2, a meta-analysis of neuromuscular interventions aimed at injury prevention. Hewett TE, Ford KR, Myer GD. Am J Sports Med. 2006;34:490&#x2013;498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16382007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>How much is too much? (Part 1) International Olympic Committee consensus statement on load in sport and risk of injury. Soligard T, Schwellnus M, Alonso JM, et al. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:1030&#x2013;1041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27535990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemiology of injury complaints in elite sprinting athletes in athletics (track and field) Edouard P, Caumeil B, Giroux C, et al. Appl Sci. 2023;13:8105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Injury rehabilitation: a goal-setting intervention study. Evans L, Hardy L. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2002;73:310&#x2013;319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12230338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of mindfulness-based interventions in high school and college athletes for reducing stress and injury, and improving quality of life. Petterson H, Olson BL. J Sport Rehabil. 2017;26:578&#x2013;587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27632857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chronic lack of sleep is associated with increased sports injuries in adolescent athletes. Milewski MD, Skaggs DL, Bishop GA, Pace JL, Ibrahim DA, Wren TA, Barzdukas A. J Pediatr Orthop. 2014;34:129&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25028798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sleep and performance in professional athletes. Cook JD, Charest J. Curr Sleep Med Rep. 2023;9:56&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9843114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36683842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regulation of muscle glycogen repletion, muscle protein synthesis and repair following exercise. Ivy JL. https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC3905295/ J Sports Sci Med. 2004;3:131&#x2013;138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3905295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24482590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acute effects of carbohydrate supplementation on intermittent sports performance. Baker LB, Rollo I, Stein KW, Jeukendrup AE. Nutrients. 2015;7:5733&#x2013;5763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4517026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26184303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The influence of omega-3 fatty acids on skeletal muscle protein turnover in health, disuse, and disease. McGlory C, Calder PC, Nunes EA. Front Nutr. 2019;6:144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6742725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31555658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calcium and vitamin d supplementation decreases incidence of stress fractures in female navy recruits. Lappe J, Cullen D, Haynatzki G, Recker R, Ahlf R, Thompson K. J Bone Miner Res. 2008;23:741&#x2013;749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18433305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessment of vitamin D concentration in non-supplemented professional athletes and healthy adults during the winter months in the UK: implications for skeletal muscle function. Close GL, Russell J, Cobley JN, et al. J Sports Sci. 2013;31:344&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23083379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids augment the muscle protein anabolic response to hyperinsulinaemia-hyperaminoacidaemia in healthy young and middle-aged men and women. Smith GI, Atherton P, Reeds DN, Mohammed BS, Rankin D, Rennie MJ, Mittendorfer B. Clin Sci (Lond) 2011;121:267&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3499967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21501117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>