<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41093308</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2733-7545</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physical activity and nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Phys Act Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of small variations in hydration status due to 12-hour fasting on lower limb muscle function in middle-aged adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>33</StartPage><EndPage>39</EndPage><MedlinePgn>33-39</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.20463/pan.2025.0023</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Evidence on the effects of low-grade dehydration on muscle function in non-athletic middle-aged adults is scarce and inconclusive. The objective was to assess the effect of small variations in hydration status due to 12-hour overnight fasting on right-leg muscle function in middle-aged adults.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Single-group before-and-after study in volunteers aged 35-65 years. Participants were assessed at two time points: after 12 hours of absolute fasting and after breakfast and drinking 1.5 L of water. Body composition and hydration status were assessed by bioelectrical impedance analysis (BIA) and muscle function by an isokinetic test.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Fifty-nine volunteers (47 years, 81.4% women) were recruited. Under fasting conditions, total body water, intracellular water (ICW), and extracellular water were positively correlated with knee flexion and extension strength, work, and power in men and women. The ICW to fat-free mass ratio and phase angle were positively correlated with flexion and extension strength and work in women but not men. Flexion strength and work improved significantly after water intake in women but not men. No changes in muscle function were observed in individuals younger than 45 years. In those aged 45 years or older, significant differences were observed for flexion strength (58.7 vs 61.8 N, p = 0.004), work (269.0 vs 284.0 J, p = 0.003) and power (39.5 vs 41.3 W, p = 0.018).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Hydration status appears to have a role in muscle function, especially with increasing age. More studies, however, are required to better understand the influence of hydration on muscle function and the underlying mechanisms.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Serra-Prat</LastName><ForeName>Mateu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit, Consorci Sanitari del Maresme, Matar&#xf3;, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centro de Investigaci&#xf3;n Biom&#xe9;dica en Red de Enfermedades Hep&#xe1;ticas y Digestivas (CIBEREHD), Instituto de Salud Carlos III, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lorenzo</LastName><ForeName>Isabel</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Information Management Unit, Consorci Sanitari del Maresme, Matar&#xf3;, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mart&#xed;nez</LastName><ForeName>Jessica</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dietetics and Nutritional Unit, Consorci Sanitari del Maresme, Matar&#xf3;, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Palomera</LastName><ForeName>Elisabet</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit, Consorci Sanitari del Maresme, Matar&#xf3;, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cuquet</LastName><ForeName>Marta</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Unit, Consorci Sanitari del Maresme, Matar&#xf3;, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferrer</LastName><ForeName>Pau</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tecnocampus Fundation, Matar&#xf3;, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pleguezuelos</LastName><ForeName>Eulogio</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation Department, Hospital of Matar&#xf3;, Consorci Sanitari del Maresme, Matar&#xf3;, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>PI19/00500</GrantID><Agency>Spanish Ministry of Health-Instituto de Salud Carlos III</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>PIR22/00327</GrantID><Agency>Spanish Ministry of Health-Instituto de Salud Carlos III</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>European Union</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Phys Act Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101770644</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2733-7545</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bioimpedance analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dehydration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">isokinetic test</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle function</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle strength</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41093308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12530993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20463/pan.2025.0023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">pan.2025.0023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>J&#xe9;quier E, Constant F. Water as an essential nutrient: the physiological basis of hydration. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2010;64:115&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19724292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burg MB, Ferraris JD, Dmitrieva NI. Cellular response to hyperosmotic stresses. Physiol Rev. 2007;87:1441&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17928589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck AM, Seemer J, Knudsen AW, Munk T. Narrative Review of Low-Intake Dehydration in Older Adults. Nutrients. 2021;13(9):3142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8470893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34579019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edmonds CJ, Foglia E, Booth P, Fu CHY, Gardner M. Dehydration in older people: A systematic review of the effects of dehydration on health outcomes, healthcare costs and cognitive performance. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2021;95:104380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33636649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasegawa Y, Kato K, Ogai K, Konya C, Minematsu T. Need for a consensus definition of chronic dehydration: A scoping review. Drug Discov Ther; 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38658358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva AM, Matias CN, Santos DA, Rocha PM, Minderico CS, Sardinha LB. Increases in intracellular water explain strength and power improvements over a season. Int J Sports Med. 2014;35:1101&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25009970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campa F, Piras A, Raffi M, Trof&#xe8; A, Perazzolo M, Mascherini G, Toselli S. The Effects of Dehydration on Metabolic and Neuromuscular Functionality During Cycling. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17:1161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7068562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32059577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlton A, Orr RM. The effects of fluid loss on physical performance: A critical review. J Sport Health Sci. 2015;4:357&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray B. Hydration and Physical Performance. J Am Coll Nutr. 2007;26:542S&#x2013;8S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17921463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada Y, Matsuda K, Bj&#xf6;rkman MP, Kimura M. Application of segmental bioelectrical impedance spectroscopy to the assessment of skeletal muscle cell mass in elderly men. Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2014;14:129&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24450571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada Y, Yoshida T, Yokoyama K, Watanabe Y, Miyake M, Yamagata E, Yamada M, Kimura M, Kyoto-Kameoka Study The Extracellular to Intracellular Water Ratio in Upper Legs is Negatively Associated With Skeletal Muscle Strength and Gait Speed in Older People. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2017;72:293&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27422438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taniguchi M, Yamada Y, Fukumoto Y, Sawano S, Minami S, Ikezoe T, Watanabe Y, Kimura M, Ichihashi N. Increase in echo intensity and extracellular-to-intracellular water ratio is independently associated with muscle weakness in elderly women. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117:2001&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28755131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serra-Prat M, Lorenzo I, Palomera E, Ram&#xed;rez S, Y&#xe9;benes JC. Total Body Water and Intracellular Water Relationships with Muscle Strength, Frailty and Functional Performance in an Elderly Population. J Nutr Health Aging. 2019;23:96&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12280413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30569076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serra-Prat M, Lorenzo I, Papiol M, Palomera E, Bartolom&#xe9; M, Pleguezuelos E, Burdoy E. Intracellular water content in lean mass as an indicator of muscle quality in an older obese population. J Clin Med. 2020;9:1580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7290582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32455974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo JI, Choi H, Song SY, Park KS, Lee DH, Ha YC. Relationship between water intake and skeletal muscle mass in elderly Koreans: A nationwide population-based study. Nutrition. 2018;53:38&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29655775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serra-Prat M, Lorenzo I, Cabr&#xe9; M, Mart&#xed;nez J, Palomera E, Ferrer P, Burdoy E, Pleguezuelos E. Relationship between lower-limb bioelectrical impedance indicators of hydration status and muscle function in aged population. A cross-sectional study. J Fam Med. 2023;10:1327.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward L.C. Bioelectrical impedance analysis for body composition assessment: reflections on accuracy, clinical utility, and standardisation. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2019;73:194&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30297760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Nelson DR, Zhao Y, Cui Z, Johnston JA. Relationship between muscle mass and muscle strength, and the impact of comorbidities: a population-based, cross-sectional study of older adults in the United States. BMC Geriatr. 2013;13:74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3765109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23865675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norman K, Stobaus N, Pirlich M, Bosy-Westphal A. Bioelectrical phase angle and impedance vector analysis - clinical relevance and applicability of impedance parameters. Clin Nutr. 2012;31:854&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22698802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Torres O, Rodr&#xed;guez-Longobardo C, Escribano-Tabernero R, Fern&#xe1;ndez-El&#xed;as VE. Hydration, Hyperthermia, Glycogen, and Recovery: Crucial Factors in Exercise Performance-A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Nutrients. 2023;15:4442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10610078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37892517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botek M, Krej&#x10d;&#xed; J, McKune A, Valenta M, Sl&#xe1;de&#x10d;kov&#xe1; B. Hydrogen Rich Water Consumption Positively Affects Muscle Performance, Lactate Response, and Alleviates Delayed Onset of Muscle Soreness After Resistance Training. J Strength Cond Res. 2022;36:2792&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Blasio F, de Blasio F, Miracco Berlingieri G, Bianco A, La Greca M, Franssen FM, Scalfi L. Evaluation of body composition in COPD patients using multifrequency bioelectrical impedance analysis. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2016;11:2419&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5053371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27757027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Blasio F, Di Gregorio A, de Blasio F, Bianco A, Bellofiore B, Scalfi L. Malnutrition and sarcopenia assessment in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease according to international diagnostic criteria, and evaluation of raw BIA variables. Respir Med. 2018;134:1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29413494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mamoto T, Fujiwara H, Toyama Y, Hirata K, Yoshikawa J, Fujimoto S. Relationship between exercise performance and water distribution measured by new bioelectrical impedance analysis in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Clin. Physiol. Funct. Imaging. 2003;23:230&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12914563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conley KE, Amara CE, Jubrias SA, Marcinek DJ. Mitochondrial function, fbre types and ageing: new insights from human muscle in vivo. Exp Physiol. 2007;92:333&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17170059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>