<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37012522</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-9932</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>AAPS PharmSciTech</Title><ISOAbbreviation>AAPS PharmSciTech</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Structural Changes in Liposomal Vesicles in Association with Sodium Taurodeoxycholate.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>95</StartPage><MedlinePgn>95</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1208/s12249-023-02550-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Liposomes composed of soy lecithin (SL) have been studied widely for drug delivery applications. The stability and elasticity of liposomal vesicles are improved by incorporating additives, including edge activators. In this study, we report the effect of sodium taurodeoxycholate (STDC, a bile salt) upon the microstructural characteristics of SL vesicles. Liposomes, prepared by the thin film hydration method, were characterized by dynamic light scattering (DLS), small-angle neutron scattering (SANS), electron microscopy, and rheological techniques. We noticed a reduction in the size of vesicles with the incremental addition of STDC. Initial changes in the size of spherical vesicles were ascribed to the edge-activating action of STDC (0.05 to 0.17&#xa0;&#xb5;M). At higher concentrations (0.23 to 0.27&#xa0;&#xb5;M), these vesicles transformed into cylindrical structures. Morphological transitions at higher STDC concentrations would have occurred due to its hydrophobic interaction with SL molecules in the bilayer. This was ascertained from nuclear magnetic resonance observations. Whereas shape transitions underscored the deformability of vesicles in the presence of STDC, the consistency of bilayer thickness ruled out any dissociative effect. It was interesting to notice that SL-STDC mixed structures could survive high thermal stress, electrolyte addition, and dilution.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to American Association of Pharmaceutical Scientists.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kumar</LastName><ForeName>Deepak</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics, National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research (NIPER), Raebareli, Lucknow, 226002, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suna</LastName><ForeName>Abhishek</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics, National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research (NIPER), Raebareli, Lucknow, 226002, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ray</LastName><ForeName>Debes</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5564-2973</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Solid State Physical Division, Bhabha Atomic Research Centre, Mumbai, 400085, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aswal</LastName><ForeName>Vinod K</ForeName><Initials>VK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2020-9026</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Solid State Physical Division, Bhabha Atomic Research Centre, Mumbai, 400085, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bahadur</LastName><ForeName>Pratap</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Veer Narmad South Gujarat University, Surat, Gujarat, 395007, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tiwari</LastName><ForeName>Sanjay</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7898-7974</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics, National Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research (NIPER), Raebareli, Lucknow, 226002, India. tiwarisanju@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>AAPS PharmSciTech</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100960111</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1530-9932</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008081">Liposomes</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>516-50-7</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013657">Taurodeoxycholic Acid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008823">Micelles</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011108">Polymers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Liposomes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013657" MajorTopicYN="Y">Taurodeoxycholic Acid</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016503" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Delivery Systems</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008823" MajorTopicYN="N">Micelles</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053838" MajorTopicYN="N">Scattering, Small Angle</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011108" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bile salt</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">edge activator</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">elasticity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">liposomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mixed vesicles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">soy lecithin</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37012522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1208/s12249-023-02550-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1208/s12249-023-02550-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rehman AU, Omran Z, Anton H, Mely Y, Akram S, Vandamme TF, et al. Development of doxorubicin hydrochloride loaded pH-sensitive liposomes: investigation on the impact of chemical nature of lipids and liposome composition on pH-sensitivity. Eur J Pharm Biopharm. 2018;133:331&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30414990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejpb.2018.11.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu B, Ma Q, Zhang J, Liu R, Yue Z, Xu C, et al. Preparation and characterization of bupivacaine multivesicular liposome: a QbD study about the effects of formulation and process on critical quality attributes. Int J Pharm. 2021;598:120335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33545281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2021.120335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guimaraes D, Cavaco-Paulo A, Nogueira E. Design of liposomes as drug delivery system for therapeutic applications. Int J Pharm. 2021;601:120571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33812967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2021.120571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Xiao J, Hu X, Liu Q, Zheng Y, Kang Z, et al. Liquid core nanoparticle with high deformability enables efficient penetration across biological barriers. Adv Healthc Mater. 2023;12:2201889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Goins B, Zhang L, Bao A. Novel multifunctional theranostic liposome drug delivery system: construction, characterization, and multimodality MR, near-infrared fluorescent, and nuclear imaging. Bioconjug Chem. 2012;23:1322&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22577859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3435449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/bc300175d</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celia C, Cristiano MC, Froiio F, Di Francesco M, d&#x2019;Avanzo N, Di Marzio L, et al. Nanoliposomes as multidrug carrier of gemcitabine/paclitaxel for the effective treatment of metastatic breast cancer disease: a comparison with gemzar and taxol. Adv Therap. 2021;4:2000121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adtp.202000121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu S, Zhang P, Heing-Becker I, Zhang J, Tang P, Bej R, et al. Dual tumor-and subcellular-targeted photodynamic therapy using glucose-functionalized MoS<sub>2</sub> nanoflakes for multidrug-resistant tumor ablation. Biomaterials. 2022;290:121844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crommelin DJA, Van Hoogevest P, Storm G. The role of liposomes in clinical nanomedicine development. What now? Now what? J Control Release. 2020;318:256&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szabova J, Misik O, Havlikova M, Lizal F, Mravec F. Influence of liposomes composition on their stability during the nebulization process by vibrating mesh nebulizer. Colloids Surf B Biointerfaces. 2021;204: 111793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33932888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfb.2021.111793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awad NS, Paul V, Mahmoud MS, Al Sawaftah NM, Kawak PS, Al Sayah MH, et al. Effect of pegylation and targeting moieties on the ultrasound-mediated drug release from liposomes. ACS Biomater Sci Eng. 2020;6:48&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33463192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsbiomaterials.8b01301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudhakar K, Mishra V, Jain S, Rompicherla NC, Malviya N, Tambuwala MM. Development and evaluation of the effect of ethanol and surfactant in vesicular carriers on lamivudine permeation through the skin. Int J Pharm. 2021;610:121226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34710540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2021.121226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barone A, Cristiano MC, Cilurzo F, Locatelli M, Iannotta D, Di Marzio L, et al. Ammoniumglycyrrhizate skin delivery from ultradeformable liposomes: a novel use as anti-inflammatory agent in topical drug delivery. Colloids Surf B Biointerfaces. 2020;193: 111152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32535351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfb.2020.111152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang X, Mao G, Ng KYS. Mechanical properties and stability measurement of cholesterol-containing liposome on mica by atomic force microscopy. J Colloid Interface Sci. 2004;278:53&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15313637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2004.05.042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trilli J, Caramazza L, Paolicelli P, Casadei MA, Liberti M, Apollonio F, et al. The impact of bilayer rigidity on the release from magnetoliposomes vesicles controlled by PEMFs. Pharmaceutics.2021;13:1712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benne N, Leboux RJT, Glandrup M, van Duijn J, Lozano Vigario F, Neustrup MA, et al. Atomic force microscopy measurements of anionic liposomes reveal the effect of liposomal rigidity on antigen-specific regulatory T cell responses. J Control Release. 2020;318:246&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31812539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jconrel.2019.12.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mouritsen OG, Jorgensen K. Dynamical order and disorder in lipid bilayers. Chem Phys Lipids. 1994;73:3&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8001184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0009-3084(94)90171-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim E-B, Haam S, Lee S-W. Sphingomyelin-based liposomes with different cholesterol contents andpolydopamine coating as a controlled delivery system. Colloids Surf A Physicochem Eng Asp. 2021;618:126447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2021.126447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui M, Wu W, Hovgaard L, Lu Y, Chen D, Qi J. Liposomes containing cholesterol analogues of botanical origin as drug delivery systems to enhance the oral absorption of insulin. Int J Pharm. 2015;489:277&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25957702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2015.05.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding WX, Qi XR, Li P, Maitani Y, Nagai T. Cholesteryl hemisuccinate as a membrane stabilizer in dipalmitoylphosphatidylcholine liposomes containing saikosaponin-d. Int J Pharm. 2005;300:38&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15978754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2005.05.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van den Bergh BA, Wertz PW, Junginger HE, Bouwstra JA. Elasticity of vesicles assessed by electronspin resonance, electron microscopy and extrusion measurements. Int J Pharm. 2001;217:13&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11292538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0378-5173(01)00576-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Wang X. Effect of vesicle-to-micelle transition on the interactions of phospholipid/sodium cholate mixed systems with curcumin in aqueous solution. J Phy Chem B. 2016;120:7392&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcb.6b02492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathod S, Joshi A, Ray D, Aswal VK, Verma G, Bahadur P, et al. Changes in aggregation properties of TPGS micelles in the presence of sodium cholate. Colloids Surf A Physicochem Eng Asp. 2021;610:125938.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2020.125938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niu M, Lu Y, Hovgaard L, Guan P, Tan Y, Lian R, et al. Hypoglycemic activity and oral bioavailability of insulin-loaded liposomes containing bile salts in rats: the effect of cholate type, particle size and administered dose. Eur J Pharm Biopharm. 2012;81:265&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22369880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejpb.2012.02.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kafle A, Akamatsu M, Bhadani A, Sakai K, Kaise C, Kaneko T, et al. Phase behavior of the bilayers containing hydrogenated soy lecithin and &#x3b2;-sitosteryl sulfate. Langmuir. 2020;36:6025&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32393038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.0c00472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Lei B, Wang Y, Xu S, Liu H. Dual-sensitive on&#x2013;off switch in liposome bilayer for controllable drug release. Langmuir. 2019;35:5213&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30883134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.8b04094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Touti R, Noun M, Guimberteau F, Lecomte S, Faure C. What is the fate of multi-lamellar liposomes of controlled size, charge and elasticity in artificial and animal skin? Eur J Pharm Biopharm. 2020;151:18&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32275955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejpb.2020.03.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lichtenberg D, Ahyayauch H, Goni FM. The mechanism of detergent solubilization of lipid bilayers. Biophys J. 2013;105:289&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23870250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3714928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bpj.2013.06.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee EH, Kim A, Oh Y-K, Kim C-K. Effect of edge activators on the formation and transfection efficiency of ultradeformable liposomes. Biomaterials. 2005;26:205&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15207467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biomaterials.2004.02.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Shen L, Zhang K, Guo T, Zhao J, Li N, et al. Enhanced antioxidation via encapsulation of isooctyl p-methoxycinnamate with sodium deoxycholate-mediated liposome endocytosis. Int J Pharm. 2015;496:392&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26453790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2015.10.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohapatra M, Mishra AK. Effect of submicellar concentrations of conjugated and unconjugated bile salts on the lipid bilayer membrane. Langmuir. 2011;27:13461&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21973323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la203028s</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathod S, Arya S, Shukla R, Ray D, Aswal VK, Bahadur P, et al. Investigations on the role of edge activator upon structural transitions in span vesicles. Colloids Surfaces A Physicochem Eng Asp. 2021;627:127246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2021.127246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debye P, Anacker EW. Micelle shape from dissymmetry measurements. J Phys Chem. 1951;55:644&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agrawal NR, Omarova M, Burni F, John VT, Raghavan SR. Spontaneous formation of stable vesicles and vesicle gels in polar organic solvents. Langmuir. 2021;37:7955&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34169719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.1c00628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L, Tucker IG, Ostergaard J. Effects of bile salts on propranolol distribution into liposomes studied by capillary electrophoresis. J Pharm Biomed Anal. 2011;56:553&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21784594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpba.2011.06.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prameela G, Kumar BP, Reddy RR, Pan A, Subramanian J, Kumar S, et al. Vesicle to micelle transition in the ternary mixture of L121/SDS/D<sub>2</sub>O: NMR, EPR and SANS studies. Phys Chem Chem Phys. 2017;19:31747&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29167857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C7CP06796H</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celino M. Biomembrane solubilization mechanism by Triton X-100: a computational study of the three stage model. 2017;19:29780&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Q, Wu S, Gong N, Li X, Dou J, Mu M, Yu X, Yu J, Liang P. Liposomes loading sodium chloride as effective thermo-seeds for microwave ablation of hepatocellular carcinoma. Nanoscale. 2017;9:11068&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28741635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C7NR02955A</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin Y, Liang X, An Y, Dai Z. Microwave-triggered smart drug release from liposomes co-encapsulating doxorubicin and salt for local combined hyperthermia and chemotherapy of cancer. Bioconjug Chem. 2016;27:2931&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27998076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.bioconjchem.6b00603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobrzynska I. Association equilibria of divalent ions on the surface of liposomes formed from phosphatidylcholine. Eur Phys J E. 2019;42:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1140/epje/i2019-11762-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotynska J, Figaszewski ZA. Binding of trivalent metal ions (Al<sup>3+</sup>, In<sup>3+</sup>, La<sup>3+</sup>) with phosphatidylcholine liposomal membranes investigated by microelectrophoresis. Eur Phys J E. 2018;41:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1140/epje/i2018-11679-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiwari S, Singh K, Marangoni DG, Bahadur P. Amphiphilic star block copolymer micelles in saline as effective vehicle for quercetin solubilization. J Mol Liq. 2022;345:118259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2021.118259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patidar P, Bahadur A, Prasad K, Tiwari S, Aswal VK, Bahadur P. Synthesis, self-assembly and micellization characteristics of choline alkanoate ionic liquids in association with a star block copolymer. Colloids Surf A Physicochem Eng Asp. 2018;555:691&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2018.08.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore EW, Celic L, Ostrow JD. Interactions between ionized calcium and sodium taurocholate: bile salts are important buffers for prevention of calcium-containing gallstones. Gastroenterology. 1982;83:1079&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7117791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0016-5085(82)80077-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Pena C, Arroyo-Maya IJ, McClements DJ. Interaction of a bile salt (sodium taurocholate) with cationic (&#x3b5;-polylysine) and anionic (pectin) biopolymers under simulated gastrointestinal conditions. Food Hydrocoll. 2019;87:352&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodhyd.2018.08.029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gou J, Chao Y, Liang Y, Zhang N, He H, Yin T, et al. Humid heat autoclaving of hybrid nanoparticles achieved by decreased nanoparticle concentration and improved nanoparticle stability using medium chain triglycerides as a modifier. Pharm Res. 2016;33:2140&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27251415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11095-016-1952-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yalcinkaya H, Feoktystov A, Gradzielski M. Formation of well-defined vesicles by styrene addition to a nonionic surfactant and their polymerization leading to viscous hybrid systems. Langmuir. 2018;34:9184&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30010346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.8b01377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Liu L, Xia S, Muhoza B, Cai J, Zhang X, et al. Sodium carboxymethyl cellulose modulates the stability of cinnamaldehyde-loaded liposomes at high ionic strength. Food Hydrocoll. 2019;93:10&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodhyd.2019.02.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng C-Y, Wang T-Y, Tung S-H. Biological hydrogels formed by swollen multilamellar liposomes. Langmuir. 2015;31:13312&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26574777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.5b03267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>