<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40519387</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Atypical Femoral Fracture in Patients With Metastatic Bone Tumors: An Analysis Based on the Japanese Adverse Drug Event Reaction Database (JADER).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e84126</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e84126</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e84126</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.84126</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Objective Denosumab (DEN)-related atypical femoral fracture (AFF) is a&#xa0;rare entity, and hence not feasible to examine with a single institution-based study. In light of this, we performed a retrospective analysis of the clinical characteristics of patients with metastatic bone tumors treated with DEN and developed AFF. Methods The Japanese Adverse Drug Event Report (JADER) database (2023.8 public version) from the second quarter of 2004 to the second quarter of 2023 was used to investigate the backgrounds of patients with metastatic bone tumors who developed AFF while receiving DEN. The time of AFF onset was defined as the number of days from the start of treatment to the onset of AFF. We also aimed to identify drugs associated with the development of AFF. Cut-off values for signal detection were &#x3c7;2 &#x2265;4 and number of reports &#x2265;3. Results The JADER database contained 2,012 cases of metastatic bone tumors for which DEN was the suspect drug or administered concomitantly with the suspect drug. Of these cases, 106 (5.3%) had AFF, with 91 (85.8%) being women and 61 (57.5%)&#xa0;patients receiving drugs for osteoporosis. The duration from administration to the onset of AFF by DEN was known in 36 cases, and the median value was 926 [interquartile range (IQR): 534-1,552] days. Furthermore, among the drugs suspected of involvement other than DEN, a signal was detected for ZOL, with a reporting odds ratio (OR) of 6.93 and a 95% confidence interval (CI) of 4.39-10.93. Conclusions In JADER, AFF in patients with metastatic bone tumors receiving DEN was more common in women and patients receiving osteoporosis drugs, and the time of onset of AFF was approximately 2.5 years.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Aimono et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aimono</LastName><ForeName>Yuka</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, Hitachi General Hospital, Hitachi, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sunaga</LastName><ForeName>Tomiko</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Epidemiology, Division of Applied Pharmaceutical Education and Research, Hoshi University, Tokyo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yonezawa</LastName><ForeName>Ryo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hospital Pharmaceutics, School of Pharmacy, Showa Medical University, Tokyo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsuboya</LastName><ForeName>Ayako</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hospital Pharmaceutics, Showa University Northern Yokohama Hospital, Yokohama, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kogo</LastName><ForeName>Mari</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pharmacotherapeutics, Department of Clinical Pharmacy, Showa Medical University School of Pharmacy, Tokyo, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsuge</LastName><ForeName>Shinjiro</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, Hitachi, Ltd. Hitachi General Hospital, Hitachi, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tamura</LastName><ForeName>Akihiro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, Hitachi General Hospital, Hitachi, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Itoh</LastName><ForeName>Ako</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Breast and Thyroid Surgery, Hitachi, Ltd. Hitachi General Hospital, Hitachi, JPN.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adverse events</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">atypical femoral fracture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bisphosphonates</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bone-modifying agents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">denosumab</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">japanese adverse drug event report (jader) database</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-term efficacy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metastatic bone tumors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reporting odds ratio</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">zoledronic acid hydrate</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: Consent for treatment and open access publication was obtained or waived by all participants in this study. The Research Ethics Committee of Corporate Hospital Group, Hitachi, Ltd. issued approval 2021-55. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40519387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12165732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.84126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Long-term efficacy and safety of zoledronic acid compared with pamidronate disodium in the treatment of skeletal complications in patients with advanced multiple myeloma or breast carcinoma: a randomized, double-blind, multicenter, comparative trial. Rosen LS, Gordon D, Kaminski M, et al. Cancer. 2003;98:1735&#x2013;1744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14534891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denosumab compared with zoledronic acid for the treatment of bone metastases in patients with advanced breast cancer: a randomized, double-blind study. Stopeck AT, Lipton A, Body JJ, et al. J Clin Oncol. 2010;28:5132&#x2013;5139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21060033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Severely suppressed bone turnover: a potential complication of alendronate therapy. Odvina CV, Zerwekh JE, Rao DS, Maalouf N, Gottschalk FA, Pak CY. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2005;90:1294&#x2013;1301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15598694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atypical subtrochanteric and diaphyseal femoral fractures: report of a task force of the American Society for Bone and Mineral Research. Shane E, Burr D, Ebeling PR, et al. J Bone Miner Res. 2010;25:2267&#x2013;2294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20842676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atypical femoral fractures mimicking metastatic lesions in 2 patients taking denosumab. Austin DC, Torchia MT, Klare CM, Cantu RV. Acta Orthop. 2017;88:351&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5434608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28077015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impending atypical femoral fracture in a patient of breast cancer with bone metastases receiving long-term denosumab. Sugihara T, Koizumi M, Hayakawa K, Ito Y, Sata N. Clin Nucl Med. 2018;43:365&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29517548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Managing osteoporosis in patients on long-term bisphosphonate treatment: report of a Task Force of the American Society for Bone and Mineral Research. Adler RA, El-Hajj Fuleihan G, Bauer DC, et al. J Bone Miner Res. 2016;31:16&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4906542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26350171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atypical femoral fractures related to bisphosphonate treatment: issues and controversies related to their surgical management. Koh A, Guerado E, Giannoudis PV. Bone Joint J. 2017;99-B:295&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28249967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Increasing occurrence of atypical femoral fractures associated with bisphosphonate use. Meier RP, Perneger TV, Stern R, Rizzoli R, Peter RE. Arch Intern Med. 2012;172:930&#x2013;936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22732749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Use of proportional reporting ratios (PRRs) for signal generation from spontaneous adverse drug reaction reports. Evans SJ, Waller PC, Davis S. Pharmacoepidemiol Drug Saf. 2001;10:483&#x2013;486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11828828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osteoporosis Committee of the Japanese Orthopaedic Association. Vol. 97. Tokyo, Japan: Japanese Orthopaedic Association; 2023. Osteoporosis Committee of the Japanese Orthopaedic Association Results of the Survey of Registered Cases of Atypical Femur Fractures (AFFs) in 2021 Report of the Project Research Project of the Japanese Orthopaedic Association; pp. 285&#x2013;287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited: RANMARK&#xae; subcutaneous injection 120 mg specific use results survey on long-term use.  [
May;
2025 
]. 2020. http://www.medicalcommunity.jp/sites/default/files/di/manufacturing_sales_survey/RMK9PX06.pdf http://www.medicalcommunity.jp/sites/default/files/di/manufacturing_sales_survey/RMK9PX06.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FDA Adverse Event Reporting System (FAERS) Public Dashboard.  [
May;
2025 
]. 2024. https://fis.fda.gov/sense/app/95239e26-e0be-42d9-a960-9a5f7f1c25ee/sheet/6b5a135f-f451-45be-893d-20aaee34e28e/state/analysis https://fis.fda.gov/sense/app/95239e26-e0be-42d9-a960-9a5f7f1c25ee/sheet/6b5a135f-f451-45be-893d-20aaee34e28e/state/analysis</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Design and baseline characteristics of a prospective cohort study for determinants of osteoporotic fracture in community-dwelling elderly Japanese men: the Fujiwara-kyo osteoporosis risk in men (FORMEN) study. Iki M, Fujita Y, Tamaki J, et al. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2009;10:165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2811107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20030855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burden of bisphosphonate-associated femoral fractures. Shkolnikova J, Flynn J, Choong P. ANZ J Surg. 2013;83:175&#x2013;181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23216704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atypical subtrochanteric and diaphyseal femoral fractures: second report of a task force of the American Society for Bone and Mineral Research. Shane E, Burr D, Abrahamsen B, et al. J Bone Miner Res. 2014;29:1&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23712442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk of atypical femoral fracture during and after bisphosphonate use. Schilcher J, Koeppen V, Aspenberg P, Micha&#xeb;lsson K. Acta Orthop. 2015;86:100&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4366670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25582459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Incidence of atypical nontraumatic diaphyseal fractures of the femur. Dell RM, Adams AL, Greene DF, et al. J Bone Miner Res. 2012;27:2544&#x2013;2550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22836783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atypical femur fractures among breast cancer and multiple myeloma patients receiving intravenous bisphosphonate therapy. Chang ST, Tenforde AS, Grimsrud CD, et al. Bone. 2012;51:524&#x2013;527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22634175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atypical femoral fracture in patients with bone metastasis receiving denosumab therapy: a retrospective study and systematic review. Takahashi M, Ozaki Y, Kizawa R, et al. BMC Cancer. 2019;19:980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6805596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31640606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atypical subtrochanteric femoral fractures in patients with skeletal malignant involvement treated with intravenous bisphosphonates. Puhaindran ME, Farooki A, Steensma MR, Hameed M, Healey JH, Boland PJ. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2011;93:1235&#x2013;1242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21776577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bench to bedside: elucidation of the OPG-RANK-RANKL pathway and the development of denosumab. Lacey DL, Boyle WJ, Simonet WS, et al. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2012;11:401&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22543469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy and safety of 12-weekly versus 4-weekly zoledronic acid for prolonged treatment of patients with bone metastases from breast cancer (ZOOM): a phase 3, open-label, randomised, non-inferiority trial. Amadori D, Aglietta M, Alessi B, et al. Lancet Oncol. 2013;14:663&#x2013;670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23684411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of longer-interval vs standard dosing of zoledronic acid on skeletal events in patients with bone metastases: a randomized clinical trial. Himelstein AL, Foster JC, Khatcheressian JL, et al. JAMA. 2017;317:48&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5321662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28030702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atypical femoral fractures from bisphosphonate in cancer patients - review. Lockwood M, Banderudrappagari R, Suva LJ, Makhoul I. J Bone Oncol. 2019;18:100259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6722257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31497503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FDA: safety update for osteoporosis drugs, bisphosphonate, and atypical fractures.  [
May;
2025 
]. 2019. https://www.fda.gov/drugs/drug-safety-and-availability/fda-drug-safety-communication-safety-update-osteoporosis-drugs-bisphosphonates-and-atypical https://www.fda.gov/drugs/drug-safety-and-availability/fda-drug-safety-communication-safety-update-osteoporosis-drugs-bisphosphonates-and-atypical</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Incidence of atypical femoral fractures in the treatment of bone metastasis: an alert report. Kaku T, Oh Y, Sato S, et al. J Bone Oncol. 2020;23:100301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7334371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32642421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Retrospective review of atypical femoral fracture in metastatic bone disease patients receiving denosumab therapy. Yang SP, Kim TW, Boland PJ, Farooki A. Oncologist. 2017;22:438&#x2013;444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5388375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28275116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>