<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39727603</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2310-2861</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Gels (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Gels</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Thermal Degradation Study of Hydrogel Nanocomposites Based on Polyacrylamide and Nanosilica Used for Conformance Control and Water Shutoff.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">846</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/gels10120846</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The application of nanocomposites based on polyacrylamide hydrogels as well as silica nanoparticles in various tasks related to the petroleum industry has been rapidly developing in the last 10-15 years. Analysis of the literature has shown that the introduction of nanoparticles into hydrogels significantly increases their structural and mechanical characteristics and improves their thermal stability. Nanocomposites based on hydrogels are used in different technological processes of oil production: for conformance control, water shutoff in production wells, and well killing with loss circulation control. In all these processes, hydrogels crosslinked with different crosslinkers are used, with the addition of different amounts of nanoparticles. The highest nanoparticle content, from 5 to 9 wt%, was observed in hydrogels for well killing. This is explained by the fact that the volumes of injection of block packs are counted only in tens of cubic meters, and for the sake of trouble-free workover, it is very important to preserve the structural and mechanical properties of block packs during the entire repair of the well. For water shutoff, the volumes of nanocomposite injection, depending on the well design, are from 50 to 150 m<sup>3</sup>. For conformance control, it is required to inject from one to several thousand cubic meters of hydrogel with nanoparticles. Naturally, for such operations, service companies try to select compositions with the minimum required nanoparticle content, which would ensure injection efficiency but at the same time would not lose economic attractiveness. The aim of the present work is to develop formulations of nanocomposites with increased structural and mechanical characteristics based on hydrogels made of partially hydrolyzed polyacrylamide crosslinked with resorcinol and paraform, with the addition of commercially available nanosilica, as well as to study their thermal degradation, which is necessary to predict the lifetime of gel shields in reservoir conditions. Hydrogels with additives of pyrogenic (HCSIL200, HCSIL300, RX380) and hydrated (white carbon black grades: 'BS-50', 'BS-120 NU', 'BS-120 U') nanosilica have been studied. The best samples in terms of their structural and mechanical properties have been established: nanocomposites with HCSIL200, HCSIL300, and BS-120 NU. The addition of hydrophilic nanosilica HCSIL200 in the amount of 0.4 wt% to a hydrogel consisting of partially hydrolyzed polyacrylamide (1%), resorcinol (0.04%), and paraform (0.09%) increased its elastic modulus by almost two times and its USS by almost three times. The thermal degradation of hydrogels was studied at 140 &#xb0;C, and the experimental time was converted to the exposure time at 80 &#xb0;C using Van't Hoff's rule. It was found that the nanocomposite with HCSIL200 retains its properties at a satisfactory level for 19 months. Filtration studies on water-saturated fractured reservoir models showed that the residual resistance factor and selectivity of the effect of nanocomposites with HCSIL200 on fractures are very high (226.4 and 91.6 for fracture with an opening of 0.05 cm and 11.0 for porous medium with a permeability of 332.3 mD). The selectivity of the isolating action on fractured intervals of the porous formation was noted.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Telin</LastName><ForeName>Aleksey</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ufa Scientific and Technical Center, LLC., 450078 Ufa, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Safarov</LastName><ForeName>Farit</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6590-2951</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ufa Scientific and Technical Center, LLC., 450078 Ufa, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ufa Institute of Chemistry, Ufa Federal Research Center, Russian Academy of Sciences, 450054 Ufa, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yakubov</LastName><ForeName>Ravil</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Mining and Petroleum, Ufa State Petroleum Technological University, 450064 Ufa, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gusarova</LastName><ForeName>Ekaterina</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-9203-6175</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interdisciplinary Research Laboratory of Oilfield Chemistry, Ufa University of Science and Technology, 450008 Ufa, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pavlik</LastName><ForeName>Artem</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-9342-0859</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Mining and Petroleum, Ufa State Petroleum Technological University, 450064 Ufa, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lenchenkova</LastName><ForeName>Lyubov</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Mining and Petroleum, Ufa State Petroleum Technological University, 450064 Ufa, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dokichev</LastName><ForeName>Vladimir</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ufa Institute of Chemistry, Ufa Federal Research Center, Russian Academy of Sciences, 450054 Ufa, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>The project "Development of acid treatment technology with in-situ deviation in order to equalize the inflow profile in carbonate reservoirs" of the strategic project "New technological solutions in fuel and energy complex" FSBEI HE "USPTU" Priority 2030.</GrantID><Agency>The Ministry of Education and Science of the Russian Federation</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Gels</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101696925</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2310-2861</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">conformance control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">filtration studies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydrogels</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nanoparticles</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rheological studies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thermodestruction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">water shutoff</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>A.T. and F.S. was employed by the company Ufa Scientific and Technical Center, LLC. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39727603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11675931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/gels10120846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">gels10120846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Seright R., Brattekas B. Water shutoff and conformance improvement: An introduction. Pet. Sci. 2021;18:450&#x2013;478. doi: 10.1007/s12182-021-00546-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12182-021-00546-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Telin A., Lenchenkova L., Yakubov R., Poteshkina K., Krisanova P., Filatov A., Stefantsev A. Application of hydrogels and hydrocarbon-based gels in oil production processes and well drilling. Gels. 2023;9:609. doi: 10.3390/gels9080609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/gels9080609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10454059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37623064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang P.W., Gruetzmacher G.D., Meltz C.N., Totino R.A. Enhanced Hydrocarbon Recovery by Permeability Modification with Phenolic Gels. 4,708,974A. U.S. Patent. 1987 November 24;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia H., Pu W.-F., Zhao J.-Z., Liao R. Experimental Investigation of the Novel Phenol&#x2212;Formaldehyde Crosslinking HPAM Gel System: Based on the Secondary Crosslinking Method of Organic Crosslinkers and Its Gelation Performance Study after Flowing Through Porous Media. Energy Fuels. 2011;25:727&#x2013;736. doi: 10.1021/ef101334y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ef101334y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui C., Zhou Z., He Z. Enhance Oil Recovery in Low Permeability Reservoirs: Optimization and Evaluation of Ultra-High Molecular Weight HPAM Phenolic weak gel system. J. Pet. Sci. Eng. 2020;195:107908. doi: 10.1016/j.petrol.2020.107908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2020.107908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Muntasheri G.A., Hussein I.A., Nasr-El-Din H.A., Amin M.B. Viscoelastic Properties of a High Temperature Crosslinked Water Shut-Off Polymeric Gel. J. Pet. Sci. Eng. 2007;55:56&#x2013;66. doi: 10.1016/j.petrol.2006.04.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2006.04.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H., Ge J., Li L., Zhang G., Li Z., Wang W., Liu M. New Insights and Experimental Investigation of High-Temperature Gel Reinforced by Nano-SiO2. Gels. 2022;8:362. doi: 10.3390/gels8060362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/gels8060362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9223159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35735706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong C., Wei F., Li W., Liu P., Wu Y., Dai M., Chen J. Mechanism of Polyacrylamide Hydrogel Instability on High-Temperature Conditions. ACS Omega. 2018;3:10716&#x2013;10724. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.8b01205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.8b01205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6645078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31459189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Z., Haruna M., Gao H., Nourafkan E., Wen D. Rheological Properties of Partially Hydrolyzed Polyacrylamide Seeded by Nanoparticles. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2017;56:3456&#x2013;3463. doi: 10.1021/acs.iecr.6b05036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.iecr.6b05036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu P., Shang Z., Yao M., Li X. Mechanistic Insight into Improving Strength and Stability of Hydrogels via Nano-Silica. J. Mol. Liq. 2022;357:119094. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2022.119094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2022.119094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zareie C., Bahramian A.R., Sefti M.V., Salehi M.B. Network-Gel Strength Relationship and Performance Improvement of Polyacrylamide Hydrogel Using Nano-Silica; with Regards to Application in Oil Wells Conditions. J. Mol. Liq. 2019;278:512&#x2013;520. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2019.01.089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2019.01.089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia H., Yang X. Environmental and Strength-enhanced Nanosilica-based Composite Gel for Well Temporary Plugging in High-temperature Reservoirs. Asia-Pac. J. Chem. Eng. 2019;14:e2270. doi: 10.1002/apj.2270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/apj.2270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia H., Xie D.-S., Kang Z. Secondary Surface Modified Laponite-Based Nanocomposite Hydrogel for Gas Shutoff in Wellbore. J. Pet. Sci. Eng. 2020;191:107116. doi: 10.1016/j.petrol.2020.107116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2020.107116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azimi Dijvejin Z., Ghaffarkhah A., Sadeghnejad S., Vafaie Sefti M. Effect of Silica Nanoparticle Size on the Mechanical Strength and Wellbore Plugging Performance of SPAM/Chromium (III) Acetate Nanocomposite Gels. Polym. J. 2019;51:693&#x2013;707. doi: 10.1038/s41428-019-0178-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41428-019-0178-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samaryk V., Varvarenko S., Nosova N., Fihurka N., Musyanovych A., Landfester K., Popadyuk N., Voronov S. Optical properties of hydrogels filled with dispersed nanoparticles. Chem. Chem. Technol. 2017;11:449&#x2013;453. doi: 10.23939/chcht11.04.449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23939/chcht11.04.449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samaryk V., Voronov A., Tarnavchyk I., Kohut A., Nosova N., Varvarenko S., Voronov S. A versatile approach to develop porous hydrogels with a regular pore distribution and investigation of their physicomechanical properties. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 2009;114:2204&#x2013;2212. doi: 10.1002/app.30426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/app.30426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui X., Wang C., Huang W., Zhang S., Chen H., Wu B., Qin D., Zheng X. Multiple Hydrogen Bonding-Assisted High-Strength Hydrogel of Silica/Polyacrylamide Nanocomposite Crosslinked with Polyethylenimine. ACS Omega. 2023;8:39401&#x2013;39407. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.3c05025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.3c05025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10600902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37901508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun D., Yang Y., Liu Y., Wu Z., Zhang H. Strengthening the Hydrogel for Lost Circulation Control through In Situ Self-Assembled Nanocomposite Networks. Energy Fuels. 2023;37:4320&#x2013;4330. doi: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.2c04071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.2c04071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao J., Song T., Wang X., Zhu Y., Wang S., Zhao M., Miao Y., Zhang J. Studies on the Rheological Properties of Amphiphilic Nanosilica and a Partially Hydrolyzed Polyacrylamide Hybrid for Enhanced Oil Recovery. Chem. Eng. Sci. 2019;206:146&#x2013;155. doi: 10.1016/j.ces.2019.05.034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ces.2019.05.034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morozov P.G., Galimov I.M., Cherepanova N.A., Gerasimov A.N. A Method for Developing an Inhomogeneous Reservoir. RU2256785C1. Russian Patent. 2005 July 20;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terziyan T.V., Safronov A.P., Belous Y.G. Interaction of aerosil nanoparticles with a grid of polyacrylamide, polyacrylic and polymethacrylic acid hydrogels. High Mol. Weight Compd. Ser. A. 2015;57:176&#x2013;184. doi: 10.7868/S2308112015020169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7868/S2308112015020169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tongwa P., Nygaard R., Bai B. Evaluation of a Nanocomposite Hydrogel for Water Shut-off in Enhanced Oil Recovery Applications: Design, Synthesis, and Characterization. J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 2013;128:787&#x2013;794. doi: 10.1002/app.38258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/app.38258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du J., Wang Q., Liu P., Xiong G., Chen P., Chen X., Liu J. Nanocomposite Gels for Water Shut-off and Temporary Plugging in the Petroleum Industry: A Review. Pet. Sci. Technol. 2023;41:2204&#x2013;2239. doi: 10.1080/10916466.2022.2108839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10916466.2022.2108839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia H., Niu C.-C., Yang X.-Y. Improved Understanding Nanocomposite Gel Working Mechanisms: From Laboratory Investigation to Wellbore Plugging Application. J. Pet. Sci. Eng. 2020;191:107214. doi: 10.1016/j.petrol.2020.107214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2020.107214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia H., Kang Z., Li S., Ge J., Feng D. Thermal degradation behavior of seawater based temporary plugging gel crosslinked by polyethyleneimine for fluid loss control in gas well: Kinetics study and degradation prediction. J. Disper. Sci. Technol. 2021;42:1299&#x2013;1310. doi: 10.1080/01932691.2020.1740727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01932691.2020.1740727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safarov F.E., Gusarova E.I., Karazeev D.V., Arslanov I.R., Telin A.G., Dokichev V.A. Synthesis of Polyacrylamide Gels for Restricting the Water Inflow in Development of Oil Fields. Russ. J. Appl. Chem. 2018;91:872&#x2013;876. doi: 10.1134/S107042721805018X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1134/S107042721805018X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safarov F.E., Karazeev D.V., Vezhnin S.A., Ratner A.A., Koptyaeva E.I., Khasanova G.I., Telin A.G. Development of compositions for equalizing the injectivity profile of injection wells in low-permeability high-temperature reservoirs with a complex structure of pore space. Oil. Gas. Innov. 2017;4:40&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas A. Essentials of Polymer Flooding Technique. John Wiley &amp; Sons; Hoboken, NJ, USA: 2019. 336p</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gospodarev D.A., Tkachev D.V., Gulevich V.V., Antuseva A.V., Lymar I.V., Khodkov E.N. Improvement of flow-diverting technology for enhanced oil recovery using gel systems with prolonged action. Equip. Technol. Oil Gas Complex. 2021;2:55&#x2013;61. doi: 10.33285/1999-6934-2021-2(122)-55-61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33285/1999-6934-2021-2(122)-55-61</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altunina L.K., Kuvshinov V.A. Improved Oil Recovery of High-Viscosity Oil Pools with Physicochemical Methods and Thermal-Steam Treatments. Oil Gas Sci. Technol. 2008;1:37&#x2013;48. doi: 10.2516/ogst:2007075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2516/ogst:2007075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oil Method of Determining the Coefficient of Displacement of Oil by Water in the Laboratory. Minnefteprom; Moscow, Russia: 1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meshalkin V., Akhmetov A., Lenchenkova L., Nzioka A., Politov A., Strizhnev V., Telin A., Fakhreeva A. Application of Renewable Natural Materials for Gas and Water Shutoff Processes in Oil Wells. Energies. 2022;15:9216. doi: 10.3390/en15239216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en15239216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>