<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39040929</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-861X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The usefulness of total body protein mass models for adolescent athletes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1439208</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1439208</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1439208</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fnut.2024.1439208</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The present study aimed to assess the utility of a less laborious technique for estimating total body protein (TBPro) in young athletes, using a multicomponent model as the criterion method. A total of 88 (49 boys and 39 girls) adolescent athletes (age: 15.2&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.5&#x2009;years; body mass index: 21.2&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.7&#x2009;kg/m<sup>2</sup>) participated. A 6-compartment model was used as the reference method (TBPro<sub>Reference</sub>) involving air displacement plethysmography for body volume, dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) for bone mineral content, and deuterium dilution for total body water (TBW). Alternatively, DXA TBPro models were used as TBPro&#x2009;=&#x2009;lean-soft mass (LSM) - HF<sub>FFM</sub> &#xd7; fat-free mass (FFM) - Ms. - G, where LSM and FFM were assessed using DXA, HF<sub>FFM</sub> is the hydration fraction of the FFM using measured TBW or assumed TBW (adult fraction of 0.732; Lohman's constants or mean observed HF<sub>FFM</sub>), Ms. is soft tissue minerals (Ms&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.0129 &#xd7; HF<sub>FFM</sub> &#xd7; FFM), and G is glycogen calculated as 0.044 &#xd7; (LSM - HF<sub>FFM</sub> &#xd7; FFM - Ms). The maturation level was determined by self-assessment. TBPro obtained from DXA using the assumed HF<sub>FFM</sub> explained 73% to 77% of the variance compared to TBPro<sub>Reference.</sub> Meanwhile, using the mean values of measured HF<sub>FFM</sub>, the DXA model explained 53 and 36% for boys and girls, respectively. Larger bias (8.6% for boys and 25.8% for girls) and limits of agreement were found for the DXA model using measured HF<sub>FFM</sub> (boys for 66.9% and girls for 70%) compared to an assumed HF<sub>FFM</sub> (bias ranged from 1.5% to 22.5% and limits of agreement ranged from 31.3% to 35.3%). Less complex and demanding TBPro DXA models with the assumed HF<sub>FFM</sub> are valid alternatives for assessing this relevant FFM component in groups of adolescent athletes but are less accurate for individual results. Though future studies should be conducted to test the usefulness of these models in longitudinal and experimental designs, their potential to provide an estimation of protein mass after exercise and diet interventions in young athletes is anticipated.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Silva, Campa and Sardinha.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silva</LastName><ForeName>Analiza M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Health Laboratory, CIPER, Faculdade Motricidade Humana, Universidade de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campa</LastName><ForeName>Francesco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Padua, Padua, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sardinha</LastName><ForeName>Lu&#xed;s B</ForeName><Initials>LB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Health Laboratory, CIPER, Faculdade Motricidade Humana, Universidade de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101642264</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-861X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DXA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adolescent athletes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body composition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multicomponent models</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">total body protein</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest. The author(s) declared that they were an editorial board member of Frontiers, at the time of submission. This had no impact on the peer review process and the final decision.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39040929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11262245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2024.1439208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Heshka S, Wang J, Heymsfield SB. Total body protein mass: validation of total body potassium prediction model in children and adolescents. J Nutr. (2006) 136:1032&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1093/jn/136.4.1032, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jn/136.4.1032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16549470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva AM. Structural and functional body components in athletic health and performance phenotypes. Eur J Clin Nutr. (2019) 73:215&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1038/s41430-018-0321-9, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41430-018-0321-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30287933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartman JW, Moore DR, Phillips SM. Resistance training reduces whole-body protein turnover and improves net protein retention in untrained young males. Appl Nutr Metab. (2006) 31:557&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1139/h06-031, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/h06-031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17111010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xe4;ger R, Kerksick CM, Campbell BI, Cribb PJ, Wells SD, Skwiat TM, et al. International Society of Sports Nutrition Position Stand: protein and exercise. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2017) 14:20. doi: 10.1186/s12970-017-0177-8, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-017-0177-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5477153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28642676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick CM, Arent S, Schoenfeld BJ, Stout JR, Campbell B, Wilborn CD, et al. International society of sports nutrition position stand: nutrient timing. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. (2017) 14:33. doi: 10.1186/s12970-017-0189-4, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12970-017-0189-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5596471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28919842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohn SH, Parr RM. Nuclear-based techniques for the in vivo study of human body composition. Report of an advisory Group of the International Atomic Energy Agency. <i>Clin. Phys. Physiol. Meas. An off. J. Hosp. Phys. Assoc. Dtsch. Gesellschaft fur Medizinische Phys</i>. Eur Fed Organ Med Phys. (1985) 6:275&#x2013;301. doi: 10.1088/0143-0815/6/4/001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/0143-0815/6/4/001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3907934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siri WE. Body composition from fluid spaces and density: analysis of methods. 1961. Nutrition. (1993) 9:480&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8286893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brozek J, Grande F, Anderson JT, Keys A. DENSITOMETRIC analysis of body composition: revision of some quantitative assumptions. Ann N Y Acad Sci. (1963) 110:113&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1111/j.1749-6632.1963.tb17079.x, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1749-6632.1963.tb17079.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14062375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fields DA, Goran MI, McCrory MA. Body-composition assessment via air-displacement plethysmography in adults and children: a review. Am J Clin Nutr. (2002) 75:453&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1093/ajcn/75.3.453, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/75.3.453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11864850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells JC, Fuller NJ, Dewit O, Fewtrell MS, Elia M, Cole TJ. Four-component model of body composition in children: density and hydration of fat-free mass and comparison with simpler models. Am J Clin Nutr. (1999) 69:904&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1093/ajcn/69.5.904, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/69.5.904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10232629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymsfield SB, Ebbeling CB, Zheng J, Pietrobelli A, Strauss BJ, Silva AM, et al. Multi-component molecular-level body composition reference methods: evolving concepts and future directions. Obes Rev. (2015) 16:282&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1111/obr.12261, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.12261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4464774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25645009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Pi-Sunyer FX, Kotler DP, Wielopolski L, Withers RT, Pierson RNJ, et al. Multicomponent methods: evaluation of new and traditional soft tissue mineral models by in vivo neutron activation analysis. Am J Clin Nutr. (2002) 76:968&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1093/ajcn/76.5.968, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/76.5.968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12399267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuller NJ, Wells JC, Elia M. Evaluation of a model for total body protein mass based on dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry: comparison with a reference four-component model. Br J Nutr. (2001) 86:45&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1079/bjn2001387, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1079/bjn2001387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11432764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietrobelli A, Formica C, Wang Z, Heymsfield SB. Dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry body composition model: review of physical concepts. Am J Phys. (1996) 271:E941&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.1996.271.6.E941</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.1996.271.6.E941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8997211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoeller D. Hydrometry. In: SB Heymsfield, TG Lohman, Z Wang, S Going, editors. The human body composition. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; (2005). p. 35&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Deurenberg P, Wang W, Pietrobelli A, Baumgartner RN, Heymsfield SB. Hydration of fat-free body mass: new physiological modeling approach. Am J Phys. (1999a) 276:E995&#x2013;E1003. doi: 10.1152/ajpendo.1999.276.6.E995, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.1999.276.6.E995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10362610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lohman T. Assessment of body composition in children. Pediatr Exerc Sci. (1989) 1:19&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1123/pes.1.1.19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1123/pes.1.1.19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36696627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos DA, Matias CN, Rocha PM, Minderico CS, Allison DB, Sardinha LB, et al. Association of basketball season with body composition in elite junior players. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. (2014) 54:162&#x2013;73. PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24509987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuller NJ, Jebb SA, Laskey MA, Coward WA, Elia M. Four-component model for the assessment of body composition in humans: comparison with alternative methods, and evaluation of the density and hydration of fat-free mass. Clin Sci. (1992) 82:687&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1042/cs0820687, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/cs0820687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1320550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanner JM. Growth at adolescence; with a general consideration of the effects of hereditary and environmental factors upon growth and maturation from birth to maturity. 2nd ed. Oxford: Blackwell Scientific Publications; (1962).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross WD, Marfell-Jones MJ. Kinanthropometry. In: JD MacDougall, HA Wenger, HJ Green, editors. Phsysiological testing of the high-performance athlete. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics Publishers; (1991). p. 224&#x2013;305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Bois D, Bois D. A formula to estimate the approximate surface area if height and weight be known. Nutrition. (1989) 5:303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2520314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva AM, Santos DA, Matias CN, Minderico CS, Schoeller DA, Sardinha LB. Total energy expenditure assessment in elite junior basketball players: a validation study using doubly labeled water. J Strength Cond Res. (2013) 27:1920&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31827361eb, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JSC.0b013e31827361eb</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22990574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prosser SJ, Scrimgeour CM. High-precision determination of 2H/1H in H2 and H2O by continuous-flow isotope ratio mass spectrometry. Anal Chem. (1995) 67:1992&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1021/ac00109a014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ac00109a014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Shen W, Whithers RT, Heymsfield SB. Multicomponent molecular level models of body composition analysis. In: SB Heymsfield, TG Lohman, Z Wang, S Going, editors. The human body composition. Champaign, IL: Human Kinetics; (2005). p. 163&#x2013;176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Deurenberg P, Wang W, Pietrobelli A, Baumgartner RN, Heymsfield SB. Hydration of fat-free body mass: review and critique of a classic body-composition constant. Am J Clin Nutr. (1999b) 69:833&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1093/ajcn/69.5.833, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/69.5.833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10232621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bland JM, Altman DG, Warner DS. Agreed statistics: measurement method comparison. Anesthesiology. (2012) 116:182&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1097/ALN.0b013e31823d7784</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ALN.0b013e31823d7784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22129533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva AM, Minderico CS, Teixeira PJ, Pietrobelli A, Sardinha LB. Body fat measurement in adolescent athletes: multicompartment molecular model comparison. Eur J Clin Nutr. (2006) 60:955&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1038/sj.ejcn.1602405, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ejcn.1602405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16523205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells JCK, Williams JE, Chomtho S, Darch T, Grijalva-Eternod C, Kennedy K, et al. Pediatric reference data for lean tissue properties: density and hydration from age 5 to 20 y. Am J Clin Nutr. (2010) 91:610&#x2013;8. doi: 10.3945/ajcn.2009.28428, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.2009.28428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20089731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borovnicar DJ, Stroud DB, Wahlqvist ML, Strauss BJ. A neutron activation analysis facility for in vivo measurement of nitrogen and chlorine in children. Australas Phys Eng Sci Med. (1996) 19:252&#x2013;63. PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9060212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jebb SA, Goldberg GR, Jennings G, Elia M. Dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry measurements of body composition: effects of depth and tissue thickness, including comparisons with direct analysis. Clin Sci. (1995) 88:319&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1042/cs0880319, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/cs0880319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7736701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laskey MA. Dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry and body composition. Nutrition. (1996) 12:45&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1016/0899-9007(95)00017-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0899-9007(95)00017-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8838836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roubenoff R, Kehayias JJ, Dawson-Hughes B, Heymsfield SB. Use of dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry in body-composition studies: not yet a &#x201c;gold standard.&#x201d;. Am J Clin Nutr. (1993) 58:589&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1093/ajcn/58.5.589</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/58.5.589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8237861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbes GB. Human body composition: Growth, aging, nutrition, and activity. New York: Springer-Verlag; (1987).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyons-Reid J, Kenealy T, Albert BB, Ward KA, Harvey N, Godfrey KM, et al. Cross-calibration of two dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry devices for the measurement of body composition in young children. Sci Rep. (2022) 12:13862. doi: 10.1038/s41598-022-17711-0, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-17711-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9381538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35974044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SS, Lim S, Kim H, Kim KM. Comparison of two DXA systems, Hologic horizon W and GE lunar prodigy, for assessing body composition in healthy Korean adults. Endocrinol Metab. (2021) 36:1219&#x2013;31. doi: 10.3803/EnM.2021.1274, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3803/EnM.2021.1274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8743584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34911173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francisco R, Jesus F, Nunes CL, Cioffi I, Alvim M, Mendonca GV, et al. Athletes with different habitual fluid intakes differ in hydration status but not in body water compartments. Scand J Med Sci Sports. (2023) 33:1072&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1111/sms.14355</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36951582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Faria ER, Franceschini S, Peluzio MCG, Sant&#x2019;Ana LFR, Priore SE. Methodological and ethical aspects of the sexual maturation assessment in adolescents. Rev Paul Pediatr. (2013) 31:398&#x2013;405. doi: 10.1590/S0103-05822013000300019, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0103-05822013000300019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4182982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24142325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>