<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40897370</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-445X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Experimental physiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Exp Physiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Water and wisdom: Hydration as a defence against dementia.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/EP093168</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Byfield</LastName><ForeName>David C</ForeName><Initials>DC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0898-5337</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurovascular Research Laboratory, Faculty of Life Sciences and Education, University of South Wales, Pontypridd, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bailey</LastName><ForeName>Damian M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0498-7095</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurovascular Research Laboratory, Faculty of Life Sciences and Education, University of South Wales, Pontypridd, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bexorg, Inc., New Haven, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016421">Editorial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Exp Physiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9002940</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0958-0670</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40897370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP093168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Adan, A. (2012). Cognitive performance and dehydration. Journal of the American College of Nutrition, 31(2), 71&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aslan Kirazoglu, D., Heybeli, C., Atc&#x131;yurt, K., Yigitalp, V., Smith, L., Veronese, N., Rahmati, M., &amp; Soysal, P. (2024). The relationship between dehydration and etiologic subtypes of major neurocognitive disorder in older patients. European Geriatric Medicine, 15(4), 1159&#x2013;1168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai, W., Chen, P., Cai, H., Zhang, Q., Su, Z., Cheung, T., Jackson, T., Sha, S., &amp; Xiang, Y.&#x2010;T. (2022). Worldwide prevalence of mild cognitive impairment among community dwellers aged 50 years and older: A meta&#x2010;analysis and systematic review of epidemiology studies. Age and Ageing, 51, afac173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey, D. M., Bain, A. R., Hoiland, R. L., Barak, O. F., Drvis, I., Hirtz, C., Lehmann, S., Marchi, N., Janigro, D., MacLeod, D. B., Ainslie, P. N., &amp; Dujic, Z. (2022). Hypoxemia increases blood&#x2010;brain barrier permeability during extreme apnea in humans. Journal of Cerebral Blood Flow and Metabolism, 42(6), 1120&#x2013;1135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunn, D. K., &amp; Hooper, L. (2019). Signs and Symptoms of Low&#x2010;Intake Dehydration Do Not Work in Older Care Home Residents&#x2010;DRIE Diagnostic Accuracy Study. Journal of the American Medical Directors Association, 20(8), 963&#x2013;970.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dmitrieva, N. I., Boehm, M., Yancey, P. H., &amp; Enh&#xf6;rning, S. (2024). Long&#x2010;term health outcomes associated with hydration status. Nature Reviews Nephrology, 20(5), 275&#x2013;294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faraco, G., Wijasa, T. S., Park, L., Moore, J., Anrather, J., &amp; Iadecola, C. (2014). Water deprivation induces neurovascular and cognitive dysfunction through vasopressin&#x2010;induced oxidative stress. Journal of Cerebral Blood Flow and Metabolism, 34(5), 852&#x2013;860.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2019 Dementia Forecasting Collaborators. (2022). Estimation of the global prevalence of dementia in 2019 and forecasted prevalence in 2050: An analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2019. Lancet Public Health, 7(2), e105&#x2013;e125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins, S., Baillie, L., Moorley, C., &amp; Nolan, F. (2023). Person&#x2010;centred oral hydration care for older people with dementia admitted to acute hospital wards: Empirical research qualitative. Journal of Clinical Nursing, 32(19&#x2010;20), 7467&#x2013;7482.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper, L., Abdelhamid, A., Attreed, N. J., Campbell, W. W., Channell, A. M., Chassagne, P., Culp, K. R., Fletcher, S. J., Fortes, M. B., Fuller, N., Gaspar, P. M., Gilbert, D. J., Heathcote, A. C., Kafri, M. W., Kajii, F., Lindner, G., Mack, G. W., Mentes, J. C., Merlani, P., &#x2026; Hunter, P. (2015). Clinical symptoms, signs and tests for identification of impending and current water&#x2010;loss dehydration in older people. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews (Online), 2015(7), CD009647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper, L., Bunn, D., Jimoh, F. O., &amp; Fairweather&#x2010;Tait, S. J. (2014). Water&#x2010;loss dehydration and aging. Mechanisms of Ageing and Development, 136&#x2010;137, 50&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hooper, L., Bunn, D. K., Downing, A., Jimoh, F. O., Groves, J., Free, C., Cowap, V., Potter, J. F., Hunter, P. R., &amp; Shepstone, L. (2016). Which frail older people are dehydrated? The UK DRIE study. Journals of Gerontology&#x2010;Series A, Biological Sciences and Medical Sciences, 71(10), 1341&#x2013;1347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iadecola, C. (2013). The pathobiology of vascular dementia. Neuron, 80(4), 844&#x2013;866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iliff, J. J., Wang, M., Liao, Y., Plogg, B. A., Peng, W., Gundersen, G. A., Benveniste, H., Vates, G. E., Deane, R., Goldman, S. A., Nagelhus, E. A., &amp; Nedergaard, M. (2012). A paravascular pathway facilitates CSF flow through the brain parenchyma and the clearance of interstitial solutes, including amyloid &#x3b2;. Science Translational Medicine, 4, 147ra111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacoby, N. (2020). Electrolyte disorders and the nervous system. Continuum (Minneapolis, Minn), 26(3), 632&#x2013;658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kylkilahti, T. M., Berends, E., Ramos, M., Shanbhag, N. C., T&#xf6;ger, J., Markenroth Bloch, K., &amp; Lundgaard, I. (2021). Achieving brain clearance and preventing neurodegenerative diseases &#x2013; A glymphatic perspective. Journal of Cerebral Blood Flow and Metabolism, 41(9), 2137&#x2013;2149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, S., Xiao, X., &amp; Zhang, X. (2023). Hydration status in older adults: Current knowledge and future challenges. Nutrients, 15(11), 2609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livingston, G., Huntley, J., Liu, K. Y., Costafreda, S. G., Selb&#xe6;k, G., Alladi, S., Ames, D., Banerjee, S., Burns, A., Brayne, C., Fox, N. C., Ferri, C. P., Gitlin, L. N., Howard, R., Kales, H. C., Kivim&#xe4;ki, M., Larson, E. B., Nakasujja, N., Rockwood, K., &#x2026; Mukadam, N. (2024). Dementia prevention, intervention, and care: 2024 report of the Lancet standing Commission. Lancet, 404(10452), 572&#x2013;628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masento, N. A., Golightly, M., Field, D. T., Butler, L. T., &amp; van Reekum, C. M. (2014). Effects of hydration status on cognitive performance and mood. British Journal of Nutrition, 111(10), 1841&#x2013;1852.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishi, S. K., Babio, N., Paz&#x2010;Graniel, I., Serra&#x2010;Majem, L., Vioque, J., Fit&#xf3;, M., Corella, D., Pint&#xf3;, X., Bueno&#x2010;Cavanillas, A., Tur, J. A., Diez&#x2010;Ricote, L., Martinez, J. A., G&#xf3;mez&#x2010;Mart&#xed;nez, C., Gonz&#xe1;lez&#x2010;Botella, A., Casta&#xf1;er, O., Alvarez&#x2010;Sala, A., Montesdeoca&#x2010;Mendoza, C., Fanlo&#x2010;Maresma, M., Cano&#x2010;Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez, N., &#x2026; Salas&#x2010;Salvad&#xf3;, J. (2023). Water intake, hydration status and 2&#x2010;year changes in cognitive performance: A prospective cohort study. BioMed Central Medicine [Electronic Resource], 21(1), 82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogoh, S., &amp; Ainslie, P. N. (2009). Cerebral blood flow during exercise: Mechanisms of regulation. Journal of Applied Physiology (1985), 107(5), 1370&#x2013;1380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parkinson, E., Hooper, L., Fynn, J., Wilsher, S. H., Oladosu, T., Poland, F., Roberts, S., Van Hout, E. &amp;, &amp; Bunn, D. (2023). Low&#x2010;intake dehydration prevalence in non&#x2010;hospitalised older adults: Systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Clinical Nutrition, 42(8), 1510&#x2013;1520.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry, B. G., Bear, T. L. K., Lucas, S. J. E., &amp; M&#xfc;ndel, T. (2016). Mild dehydration modifies the cerebrovascular response to the cold pressor test. Experimental Physiology, 101(1), 135&#x2013;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poe, J., Sriram, S., Mehkri, Y., &amp; Lucke&#x2010;Wold, B. (2024). Electrolyte imbalance and neurologic injury. Central Nervous System Neurological Disorder Drug Targets, 23(7), 841&#x2013;851.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popkin, B. M., D'Anci, K. E., &amp; Rosenberg, I. H. (2010). Water, hydration, and health. Nutrition Reviews, 68(8), 439&#x2013;458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pross, N. (2017). Effects of dehydration on brain functioning: A life&#x2010;span perspective. Annals of Nutrition &amp; Metabolism, 70(Suppl. 1), 30&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajeev, V., Chai, Y. L., Poh, L., Selvaraji, S., Fann, D. Y., Jo, D.&#x2010;G., De Silva, T. M., Drummond, G. R., Sobey, C. G., Arumugam, T. V., Chen, C. P. &amp;, &amp; Lai, M. K. P. (2023). Chronic cerebral hypoperfusion: A critical feature in unravelling the etiology of vascular cognitive impairment. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 11(1), 93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salari, N., Lotfi, F., Abdolmaleki, A., Heidarian, P., Rasoulpoor, S., Fazeli, J., Najafi, H., &amp; Mohammadi, M. (2025). The global prevalence of mild cognitive impairment in geriatric population with emphasis on influential factors: A systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. BioMed Central Geriatrics, 25(1), 313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stookey, J. D. (2005). High prevalence of plasma hypertonicity among community&#x2010;dwelling older adults: Results from NHANES III. Journal of the American Dietetic Association, 105(8), 1231&#x2013;1239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trangmar, S. J., Chiesa, S. T., Llodio, I., Garcia, B., Kalsi, K. K., Secher, N. H., &amp; Gonz&#xe1;lez&#x2010;Alonso, J. (2015). Dehydration accelerates reductions in cerebral blood flow during prolonged exercise in the heat without compromising brain metabolism. American Journal of Physiology&#x2010;Heart and Circulatory Physiology, 309(9), H1598&#x2013;H1607.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson, K., &amp; Dewing, J. (2020). Strategies to prevent dehydration in older people with dementia: A literature review. Nursing Older People, 32(1), 27&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittbrodt, M. T., &amp; Millard&#x2010;Stafford, M. (2018). Dehydration impairs cognitive performance: A meta&#x2010;analysis. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 50(11), 2360&#x2013;2368.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>