<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41078806</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-1343</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>39</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS omega</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Omega</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Molecular Dynamics Simulation Study of Polyvinylpyrrolidone as a Kinetic Inhibitor for Natural Gas Hydrates under Ultradeepwater Conditions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>45792</StartPage><EndPage>45800</EndPage><MedlinePgn>45792-45800</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsomega.5c06271</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The rapid advancement of ultradeepwater oil and gas exploration has led to the secondary formation of natural gas hydrates under low temperatures and high pressures typical of these environments. Inhibiting secondary hydrate formation is essential for ensuring the safety and efficiency of ultradeepwater drilling operations. This study extends prior molecular dynamics work by elucidating the inhibition mechanism of polyvinylpyrrolidone during the nucleation and formation of natural gas hydrates through molecular dynamics simulations, providing new insights into molecular-level interactions under ultradeepwater conditions. The simulations analyzed the dynamic trajectories of hydrate nucleation, formation, and structural and dynamic properties, including the radial distribution function, coordination number, mean square displacement, diffusion coefficients, hydrogen bonding interactions, interaction energies, and axial concentration distributions. The results indicate that polyvinylpyrrolidone increases methane molecule aggregation, decreases methane solubility in water, and restricts water molecule movement, reducing the likelihood of hydrate nucleation. Additionally, polyvinylpyrrolidone molecules adsorb onto the hydrate crystal surface, altering the distribution of water molecules and inhibiting secondary hydrate formation. This study reveals the microscopic mechanism by which polyvinylpyrrolidone inhibits natural gas hydrate formation under ultradeepwater conditions, providing theoretical support for developing efficient kinetic inhibitors and offering valuable insights for ultradeepwater oil and gas operations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Zhijun</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7742-6769</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Unconventional Oil &amp; Gas Development, China University of Petroleum (East China), Ministry of Education, Qingdao 266580, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">74591</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Petroleum Engineering, China University of Petroleum (East China), Qingdao 266580, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guan</LastName><ForeName>Jian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-8917-2115</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Qingdao NMEI Group Co. Ltd, Qingdao 266000, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">74742</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jintang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Unconventional Oil &amp; Gas Development, China University of Petroleum (East China), Ministry of Education, Qingdao 266580, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">74591</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Petroleum Engineering, China University of Petroleum (East China), Qingdao 266580, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Hao</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Qingdao NMEI Group Co. Ltd, Qingdao 266000, China.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">74742</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Omega</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101691658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-1343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41078806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12508964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.5c06271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Onwuka O. U., Adu A.. Sustainable strategies in onshore gas exploration: Incorporating carbon capture for environmental compliance. Eng. Sci. Technol. Int J. 2024;5:1184&#x2013;1202. doi: 10.51594/estj.v5i4.995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.51594/estj.v5i4.995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolosi, E. R. ; Dutra, E. S. S. ; Guerra, L. C. F. ; de Freitas, L. R. ; Filho, E. L.V. C ; Prado, D. D. ; Giovani, R. S. ; Fernandes, A. A. F. , Decommissioning of Offshore Oil and Gas Installations in Campos Basin-Brazil: Main Challenges and Achievements, InOffshore Technology Conference; One Petro: Houston, Texas, USA, 2024,p D011S002R006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rijtema, S. ; de Haas, R. , Creating sustainable offshore developments in the ultra-deep water. In Offshore Technology Conference; One Petro, 2015, 25873&#x2013;MS.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell, J. M. ; Chin, Y. D. ; Hanrahan, S. , State-of-the-art of ultra deepwater production technologies. In Offshore Technology Conference; One Petro, 2005, OTC-17615&#x2013;MS.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang G., Qu H., Chen G., Zhao C., Zhang F., Yang H., Zhao Z., Ma M.. Giant discoveries of oil and gas fields in global deepwaters in the past 40 years and the prospect of exploration. J. Nat. Gas Geosci. 2019;4:1&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1016/j.jnggs.2019.03.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnggs.2019.03.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinder D.. Offshore oil and gas: Global resource knowledge and technological change. Ocean.Coastal Manag. 2001;44:579&#x2013;600. doi: 10.1016/S0964-5691(01)00070-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0964-5691(01)00070-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCabe, P. J. Oil and natural gas: Global resources Fossil Energy Springer; 2012. 5&#x2013;16 10.1007/978-1-4939-9763-3_71</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-4939-9763-3_71</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhixin W., Lunkun W., Yadong W., Zhengjun H., Yonghua W.. Formation Conditions and Segment Corelation of the Giant Oil-Gas Fields in Passive Continental Margin Basins in West Africa. Xinjiang Pet. Geol. 2013;34:607&#x2013;613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen Z., Wang J., Wang Z., He Z., Song C., Liu X., Zhang N., Ji T.. Analysis of the world deepwater oil and gas exploration situation. Pet. Explor. Dev. 2023;50:1060&#x2013;1076. doi: 10.1016/S1876-3804(23)60449-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1876-3804(23)60449-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochulor O. J., Sofoluwe O. O., Ukato A., Jambol D. D.. Technological advancements in drilling: A comparative analysis of onshore and offshore applications. World J. Adv. Res. Rev. 2024;22:602&#x2013;611. doi: 10.30574/wjarr.2024.22.2.1333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.30574/wjarr.2024.22.2.1333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirkland, B. ; Pepper, A. . Source rocks and petroleum systems in deepwater plays Deepwater Sedimentary Systems Elsevier; 2022. 51&#x2013;81 10.1016/B978-0-323-91918-0.00012-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-323-91918-0.00012-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhixin W., Hong X., Zhaoming W., Zhengjun H., Chengpeng S., Xi C., Yonghua W.. Classification and hydrocarbon distribution of passive continental margin basins. Pet. Explor. Dev. 2016;43:678&#x2013;688. doi: 10.1016/S1876-3804(16)30089-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1876-3804(16)30089-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuoqian W., Zifei F. A. N., Zhang X., Baolei L. I. U., Xi C.. Status, trends and enlightenment of global oil and gas development in 2021. Pet. Explor. Dev. 2022;49:1210&#x2013;1228. doi: 10.1016/S1876-3804(22)60344-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1876-3804(22)60344-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakhmakhchev, A. ; Rushworth, P. . Global Overview of Recent Exploration Investment in Deepwater-New Discoveries, Plays and Exploration Potential. Adapted From Oral Presentation At AAPG Convention; AAPG, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han W., Yu S., Zhao H., Zhao Y., Chen L.. Strategies of efficient exploration and development of deepwater oil and gas overseas. Front. Eng. Manage. 2016;3:314&#x2013;320. doi: 10.15302/J-FEM-2016050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15302/J-FEM-2016050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qun L. E. I., Yun X. U., Zhanwei Y., Bo C. A. I., Xin W., Lang Z., Huifeng L. I. U., Minjie X. U., Liwei W., Li S.. Progress and development directions of stimulation techniques for ultra-deep oil and gas reservoirs. Pet. Explor. Dev. 2021;48:221&#x2013;231. doi: 10.1016/S1876-3804(21)60018-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1876-3804(21)60018-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tari, G. C. ; Simmons, M. D. . History of deepwater exploration in the Black Sea and an overview of deepwater petroleum play types; Geological Society: London, 2018; Vol. 464, pp. 439&#x2013;475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandrea I., Sandrea R.. Global offshore oil: Geological setting of producing provinces, E&amp;P trends, URR, and medium term supply outlook. Oil Gas J. 2007;105:34&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones C. M.. The oil and gas industry must break the paradigm of the current exploration model. J. Pet. Explor. Prod. Technol. 2018;8:131&#x2013;142. doi: 10.1007/s13202-017-0395-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13202-017-0395-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiyi Y., Qiang W.. New progress and prospect of oilfields development technologies in China. Pet. Explor. Dev. 2018;45:698&#x2013;711. doi: 10.1016/S1876-3804(18)30073-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1876-3804(18)30073-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu Z., Zhao X.. Current status and developing trend of deepwater drilling fluid technology. Special Oil.Gas Res. 2013;20:1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaturvedi K. R., Sinha A. S. K., Nair V. C., Sharma T.. Enhanced carbon dioxide sequestration by direct injection of flue gas doped with hydrogen into hydrate reservoir: Possibility of natural gas production. Energy. 2021;227:120521. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2021.120521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2021.120521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaturvedi K. R., Sharma T., Trivedi J. J., Kumar G. S.. Experimental investigation for comparative effectiveness of CO2+ N2 and CO2+ N2+ H2 on integrated methane production and carbon storage from natural hydrate media. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2023;11(2):109388. doi: 10.1016/j.jece.2023.109388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2023.109388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hembram B. K., Mahmud M., Tripathi R., Nair V. C., Sharma T.. Insights of Molecular Dynamics Simulation To Investigate the Impact of Ethylene Glycol on Methane Hydrate Dissociation. Energy Fuels. 2024;38:1923&#x2013;1933. doi: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c03854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c03854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaturvedi K. R., Fogat M., Sharma T.. Low Temperature rheological characterization of single-step silica nanofluids: An additive in refrigeration and gas hydrate drilling applications. J. Pet. Sci. Eng. 2021;204:108742. doi: 10.1016/j.petrol.2021.108742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2021.108742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaturvedi K. R., Pandey A., Kumar R., Sharma T.. Role of hydrogen to promote hydrate formation of flue gas mixture of CO2 and N2 in silica nanofluid of single-step origin. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2021;9:106591. doi: 10.1016/j.jece.2021.106591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2021.106591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., He Z., Sun J., Liu L., Li W., Liao B., Zhao K., Li Y., Xu J.. Dynamics of Horizontal Well Drilling in Deepwater Shallow Gas Hydrate Reservoirs: A Mass and Heat Transfer Study. SPE J. 2024;29:6034&#x2013;6049. doi: 10.2118/223589-PA.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2118/223589-PA</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelland M. A., M&#xf8;nig K., Iversen J. E., Lekvam K.. Feasibility Study for the Use of Kinetic Hydrate Inhibitors in Deep-Water Drilling Fluids. Energy Fuels. 2008;22:2405&#x2013;2410. doi: 10.1021/ef800109e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ef800109e</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., He Z., Yan Y., Liu L., Yan J., Liao B., Zhao K., Li Y., Chen L.. Development of a dual-functional inhibitor for natural gas hydrates and construction of drilling fluid system. Gas Sci. Eng. 2024;122:205218. doi: 10.1016/j.jgsce.2024.205218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jgsce.2024.205218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Liao B., Liu L., Chen L., Huang Y., Zhao K., Sun X., Lv K., Zheng Y., Sun J.. The effect of multi-component Inhibitor systems on hydrate formation. Gas Sci. Eng. 2024;122:205214. doi: 10.1016/j.jgsce.2024.205214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jgsce.2024.205214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T., Hu Y., Gao M., Yi D., Bao W., Li H.. Evaluation and application of a combined natural gas hydrate inhibitor. Chem. Eng. Oil Gas. 2019;48:39&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saberi A., Alamdari A., Rasoolzadeh A., Mohammadi A. H.. Insights into kinetic inhibition effects of MEG, PVP, and L-tyrosine aqueous solutions on natural gas hydrate formation. Pet. Sci. 2021;18:495&#x2013;508. doi: 10.1007/s12182-020-00515-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12182-020-00515-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan S.S., Guo K., Wang Y.H., Lang X.. Present situation and prospect of performance evaluation methods for kinetic hydrate inhibitors (KHIs. Nat. Gas Ind. 2018;38:103&#x2013;113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S., Li Q., Li L., Yu X.. Synthesis and properties of novel kinetic inhibit ors for natural gas hydrate. Petrochem. Technol. 2017;46:467&#x2013;470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao K., Liu Y., Zhang P., Han Q., Jiang H.. Synthesis and performance of new hydrate kinetic inhibitors. Natural Gas Chemical Industry. 2013;38:51&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelland M. A.. History of the development of low dosage hydrate inhibitors. Energy Fuels. 2006;20:825&#x2013;847. doi: 10.1021/ef050427x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ef050427x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A., Suri A.. A review on gas hydrates and kinetic hydrate inhibitors based on acrylamides. J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng. 2020;83:103539. doi: 10.1016/j.jngse.2020.103539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2020.103539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mali, G. A. Investigation of Kinetic Hydrate Inhibitor performance and the mechanism of inhibition; Heriot-Watt University, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du C. Y., Guerra A., McElligott A., Mari&#x107; M., Rey A., Servio P.. Effects of Poly&#xad;(styrene/Pentafluorostyrene-block-vinylpyrrolidone) Amphiphilic Kinetic Hydrate Inhibitors on the Dynamic Viscosity of Methane Hydrate Systems at High-Pressure Driving Forces. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2023;62:11795. doi: 10.1021/acs.iecr.3c00997.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.iecr.3c00997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelland M. A., Pomicpic J.. Key Structural Features for an Effective Kinetic Hydrate Inhibitor&#xe5f8;You Need Them All! Energy Fuels. 2025;39:9802&#x2013;9817. doi: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c01744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.5c01744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paez, J. E. ; Blok, R. ; Vaziri, H. ; Islam, M. R. . Problems in hydrates: Mechanisms and elimination methods. In SPE Oklahoma City Oil and Gas Symposium/Production and Operations Symposium; SPE, 2001; pp. SPE-67322&#x2013;MS.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sloan, E. D., Jr ; Koh, C. A. ; Koh, C. A. ; Clathrate Hydrates of Natural Gases, 3rd ed; CRC Press: Boca Raton, 2007. 10.1201/9781420008494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1201/9781420008494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C., Bai S., Li X., Zhao Y., Ren L., Zhu K., Yuan X.. Amphiphilic Copolymers Containing POSS and SBMA with N-Vinylcaprolactam and N-Vinylpyrrolidone for THF Hydrate Inhibition. ACS Omega. 2018;3:7371. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.8b00602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.8b00602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6644730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31458896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng L., Wang L., Li Z., Liu B., Chen G.. Inhibition Effect of Kinetic Hydrate Inhibitors on the Growth of Methane Hydrate in Gas&#x2013;Liquid Phase Separation State. Energies. 2019;12:4482. doi: 10.3390/en12234482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en12234482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Z., Wang J., Liao B., Bai Y., Shao Z., Huang X., Wang Q., Li Y.. Molecular Simulation of Interactions between High-Molecular-Polymer Flocculation Gel for Oil-Based Drilling Fluid and Clay Minerals. Gels. 2022;8:442. doi: 10.3390/gels8070442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/gels8070442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9322032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35877527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao B., Wang J., Sun J., Lv K., Liu L., Wang Q., Wang R., Lv X., Wang Y., Chen Z.. Microscopic insights into synergism effect of different hydrate inhibitors on methane hydrate formation: Experiments and molecular dynamics simulations. Fuel. 2023;340:127488. doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2023.127488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2023.127488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao B., Wang J., Han X., Wang R., Lv K., Bai Y., Jiang H., Shao Z., Wang Y., Sun J.. Microscopic molecular insights into clathrate methane hydrates dissociation in a flowing system. Chem. Eng. J. 2022;430:133098. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2021.133098.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2021.133098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Z., Xu H., Wang J., Sun J., Liu L., Li W., Cai W., Zhao K., Li Y., Bai B., Zheng Q.. Molecular dynamics study on the Micro-Mechanism of modified nano-silica for inhibiting shale surface hydration. Fuel. 2025;393:134967. doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134967.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Wang H., Guo J., Chen G., Zhong J., Yan Y., Zhang J.. Molecular insights into the kinetic hydrate inhibition performance of Poly&#xad;(N-vinyl lactam) polymers. J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng. 2020;83:103504. doi: 10.1016/j.jngse.2020.103504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2020.103504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storr M. T., Taylor P. C., Monfort J.-P., Rodger P. M.. Kinetic Inhibitor of Hydrate Crystallization. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2004;126:1569&#x2013;1576. doi: 10.1021/ja035243g.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ja035243g</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14759217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao B., Sun J., Wang J., Lv X., Wang J., Guo J., KaiheLv R. W., Zheng J., Chen Z.. Development of novel natural gas hydrate inhibitor and the synergistic inhibition mechanism with NaCl: Experiments and molecular dynamics simulation. Fuel. 2023;353:129162. doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2023.129162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2023.129162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao B., Wang J., Li M.-C., Lv K., Wang Q., Li J., Huang X., Wang R., Lv X., Chen Z., Sun J.. Microscopic molecular and experimental insights into multi-stage inhibition mechanisms of alkylated hydrate inhibitor. Energy. 2023;279:128045. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2023.128045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2023.128045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenz A., Ojam&#xe4;e L.. Structures of the I-, II- and H-Methane Clathrates and the Ice&#x2013;Methane Clathrate Phase Transition from Quantum-Chemical Modeling with Force-Field Thermal Corrections. J. Phys. Chem. A. 2011;115:6169&#x2013;6176. doi: 10.1021/jp111328v.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp111328v</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21341763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutt C., Asmussen B., Press W., Johnson M. R., Handa Y. P., Tse J. S.. The structure of deuterated methane&#x2013;hydrate. J. Chem. Phys. 2000;113:4713&#x2013;4721. doi: 10.1063/1.1288789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.1288789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun H.. COMPASS: An ab Initio Force-Field Optimized for Condensed-Phase ApplicationsOverview with Details on Alkane and Benzene Compounds. J. Phys. Chem. B. 1998;102:7338&#x2013;7364. doi: 10.1021/jp980939v.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp980939v</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao Z., Wang J., Lv K., Liao B., Wang Z., Bai Y., Wang R., Sun J.. Experimental and molecular dynamics studies of zwitterionic inhibitors of methane hydrate dissociation. Fuel. 2022;318:123059. doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2021.123059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2021.123059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin B. S., Kim E. S., Kwak S. K., Lim J. S., Kim K.-S., Kang J. W.. Thermodynamic inhibition effects of ionic liquids on the formation of condensed carbon dioxide hydrate. Fluid Phase Equilib. 2014;382:270&#x2013;278. doi: 10.1016/j.fluid.2014.09.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fluid.2014.09.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reshadi P., Modarress H., Dabir B., Amjad-Iranagh S.. Molecular dynamics simulation for studying the stability of structure H clathrate-hydrates of argon and large guest molecules. J. Dispersion Sci. Technol. 2018;39:1572&#x2013;1581. doi: 10.1080/01932691.2018.1446145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01932691.2018.1446145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu J., Wang H., Guo J., Chen G., Zhong J., Yan Y., Zhang J.. Molecular insights into the kinetic hydrate inhibition performance of Poly (N-vinyl lactam) polymers. J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng. 2020;83:103504. doi: 10.1016/j.jngse.2020.103504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2020.103504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reshadi P., Modarress H., Dabir B., Amjad-Iranagh S.. A study on dissociation of sII krypton hydrate and the effect of hydrocarbon guest molecules as stabilizer by molecular dynamics simulation. Phase Transitions. 2017;90:1128&#x2013;1142. doi: 10.1080/01411594.2017.1309404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01411594.2017.1309404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoover W. G.. Canonical dynamics: Equilibrium phase-space distributions. Phys. Rev. A. 1985;31:1695&#x2013;1697. doi: 10.1103/PhysRevA.31.1695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1103/PhysRevA.31.1695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9895674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao B., Qiu L., Wang D., Bao W., Wei Y., Wang Y.. The behaviour of water on the surface of kaolinite with an oscillating electric field. RSC Adv. 2019;9:21793&#x2013;21803. doi: 10.1039/C9RA04269E.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C9RA04269E</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9066472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35518887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldman M., Hagler A.T.. New combining rules for rare gas van der waals parameters. J. Comput. Chem. 1993;14(9):1077&#x2013;1084. doi: 10.1002/jcc.540140909.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcc.540140909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C., Zi M., Wu G., Zou X., Liu K., Chen D.. Concentration effect of kinetic hydrate inhibitor on hydrate formation and inhibition. Fuel. 2022;323:124448. doi: 10.1016/j.fuel.2022.124448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuel.2022.124448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ke W., Kelland M. A.. Kinetic hydrate inhibitor studies for gas hydrate systems: A review of experimental equipment and test methods. Energy Fuels. 2016;30:10015&#x2013;10028. doi: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.6b02739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.6b02739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>