<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39439135</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1613-6829</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>52</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Small (Weinheim an der Bergstrasse, Germany)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Small</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Bifunctional Portable Powder for Freshwater Production With Moisture Harvesting and Undrinkable Water Purification.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2407681</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2407681</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/smll.202407681</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Freshwater scarcity threatens human survival, particularly in extreme environments like deserts, oceans, and space. Compatible atmospheric water harvesting and undrinkable water purification offer an affordable approach to solving freshwater scarcity in these extreme environments. Nonetheless, developing composite sorbent to attain efficient atmospheric water harvesting and undrinkable water purification remains challenging. Hence, a portable hybrid hygroscopic powder (HLC powder) consisting of hydroxypropyl chitosan, dibenzaldehyde-functional poly(ethylene glycol), lithium chloride (LiCl), and nano carbon black is proposed. The HLC powder with optimized LiCl load can capture moisture from the air, showing a high water uptake of 1.76&#xa0;g g<sup>-1</sup> at 34% relative humidity (RH) and appropriate over a wide humidity from 34% to 75% RH. pH-responsive sol-gel transition induced by Schiff base bonds transforms the HLC solution into hydrogel, inhibiting hydrated salt leakage. Meanwhile, to achieve efficient undrinkable water purification, the LiCl-free hybrid powder is utilized to convert the undrinkable water, including seawater, dye water, and human urine, to photothermal hydrogel evaporators with low evaporation enthalpies and high evaporation rates ranging from 1.81 to 2.05 kg m<sup>-2</sup> h<sup>-1</sup> under one sun. This strategy establishes a new path to conveniently obtaining freshwater, breaking hydrological restrictions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Wiley&#x2010;VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yue</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center of Advanced Rare Earth Materials (Ministry of Education), Department of Chemistry, Tsinghua University, Beijing, 100084, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tian</LastName><ForeName>Ye</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center of Advanced Rare Earth Materials (Ministry of Education), Department of Chemistry, Tsinghua University, Beijing, 100084, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Wenqing</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center of Advanced Rare Earth Materials (Ministry of Education), Department of Chemistry, Tsinghua University, Beijing, 100084, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Shuaiheng</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center of Advanced Rare Earth Materials (Ministry of Education), Department of Chemistry, Tsinghua University, Beijing, 100084, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qiu</LastName><ForeName>Yingqi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center of Advanced Rare Earth Materials (Ministry of Education), Department of Chemistry, Tsinghua University, Beijing, 100084, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Lin</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6208-4436</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Engineering Research Center of Advanced Rare Earth Materials (Ministry of Education), Department of Chemistry, Tsinghua University, Beijing, 100084, P. R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2022YFB3804901</GrantID><Agency>National Key Research and Development Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022YFB3804900</GrantID><Agency>National Key Research and Development Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52173111</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Small</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101235338</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1613-6810</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">atmospheric water harvesting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diverse hydrological conditions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hybrid hygroscopic powder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hygroscopic hydrogel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">solar&#x2010;driven water purification</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39439135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202407681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>M. M. Mekonnen, A. Y. Hoekstra, Sci. Adv. 2016, 2, e1500323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Lord, A. Thomas, N. Treat, M. Forkin, R. Bain, P. Dulac, C. H. Behroozi, T. Mamutov, J. Fongheiser, N. Kobilansky, S. Washburn, C. Truesdell, C. Lee, P. H. Schmaelzle, Nature 2021, 598, 611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. D. Kocher, A. K. Menon, Energy Environ. Sci. 2023, 16, 4983.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Yu, J. Zhang, S. Li, Z. Zhou, Z. Qin, H. Liu, Y. Lai, S. Fu, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2023, 33, 2210730.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Xie, Y. Du, W. Zhou, W. Xu, C. Zhang, R. Niu, T. Wu, J. Qu, Small 2023, 19, 2300915.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Fu, L. Wu, S. Ai, Z. Guo, W. Liu, Nano Today 2023, 52, 101979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Song, J. Liu, M. Li, S. Li, M. Kappl, H. J. Butt, Y. Hou, K. L. Yeung, Small 2023, 19, 2301561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Xu, X. Huo, T. Yan, P. Wang, Z. Bai, J. Chao, R. Yang, R. Wang, T. Li, Energy Environ. Sci. 2024, 17, 4988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Xu, T. Li, T. Yan, S. Wu, M. Wu, J. Chao, X. Huo, P. Wang, R. Wang, Energy Environ. Sci. 2021, 14, 5979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Guo, T. Li, P. Li, Y. Zhai, J. Li, Desalination 2020, 473, 114195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Chen, M. Burhan, M. Kum Ja, Y. Li, K. Choon Ng, Energy Conv. Manag. 2021, 245, 114570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Wang, D. Feng, Y. Chen, D. He, M. Elimelech, Environ. Sci. Technol. 2021, 55, 10714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Song, W. Dong, Y. Zhang, H. M. Abdel&#x2010;Ghafar, A. Toghan, H. Jiang, Exploration 2022, 2, 20220054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Mu, J. Zhou, P. Wang, H. Chen, T. Yang, S. Chen, L. Miao, T. Mori, Energy Environ. Sci. 2022, 15, 3388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Chen, N. Yang, Y. Wang, H. He, J. Wang, J. Wan, H. Jiang, B. Xu, L. Wang, R. Yu, L. Tong, L. Gu, Q. Xiong, C. Chen, S. Zhang, D. Wang, Adv. Mater. 2022, 34, 2107400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Yao, P. Zhang, C. Yang, Q. Liao, X. Hao, Y. Huang, M. Zhang, X. Wang, T. Lin, H. Cheng, J. Yuan, L. Qu, Energy Environ. Sci. 2021, 14, 5330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Xu, T. Li, J. Chao, S. Wu, T. Yan, W. Li, B. Cao, R. Wang, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2020, 59, 5202.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Kim, S. Yang, S. R. Rao, S. Narayanan, E. A. Kapustin, H. Furukawa, A. S. Umans, O. M. Yaghi, E. N. Wang, Science 2017, 356, 430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Zhu, Z. Yu, H. Sun, D. Zheng, Y. Zheng, Y. Qian, Y. Wei, J. Lee, S. Srebnik, W. Chen, G. Chen, F. Jiang, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2306653.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Hoogendoorn, M. Huertas, P. Nitz, N. Qi, J. Baller, C. Prinz, G. Graeber, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 34, 2314680.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Cai, Y. Chen, F. Cheng, Z. Wei, W. Zhou, Y. Fu, ACS Nano 2024, 18, 4376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. LaPotin, Y. Zhong, L. Zhang, L. Zhao, A. Leroy, H. Kim, S. R. Rao, E. N. Wang, Joule 2021, 5, 166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Krajnc, J. Varlec, M. Mazaj, A. Risti&#x107;, N. Z. Logar, G. Mali, Adv. Energy Mater. 2017, 7, 1601815.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Gwadera, K. Kupiec, Adsorpt. Sci. Technol. 2015, 33, 499.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. T. Chua, K. C. Ng, A. Chakraborty, N. M. Oo, M. A. Othman, J. Chem. Eng. Data 2002, 47, 1177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Luo, X. Liang, W. Chen, S. Wang, X. Gao, Z. Zhang, Y. Fang, Small 2023, 19, 2304477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. H. Alawadhi, S. Chheda, G. D. Stroscio, Z. Rong, D. Kurandina, H. L. Nguyen, N. Rampal, Z. Zheng, L. Gagliardi, O. M. Yaghi, J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2024, 146, 2160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Luo, M. Chen, D. Yu, T. Zhang, J. Zhao, L. Zhang, X. Han, M. Zhou, Y. Hou, Y. Zheng, ACS Nano 2024, 18, 14650.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Shi, W. Guan, C. Lei, G. Yu, Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2022, 61, 202211267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Li, Y. Shi, M. Alsaedi, M. Wu, L. Shi, P. Wang, Environ. Sci. Technol. 2018, 52, 11367.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Shan, Z. Zeng, X. Yang, P. Poredo&#x161;, J. Yu, Z. Chen, R. Wang, ACS Energy Lett. 2023, 8, 5184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. N. Abd Elwadood, A. S. F. Farinha, Y. Al Wahedi, A. Al Alili, G. J. Witkamp, L. F. Dumee, G. N. Karanikolos, Small 2024, 20, 2400420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Wang, G. Ma, S. Cui, K. Sun, W. Li, H. Peng, Small 2023, 20, 2307416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Zhang, F. Zhao, W. Shi, H. Lu, X. Zhou, Y. Guo, G. Yu, Adv. Mater. 2022, 34, 2110548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Zhang, X. Shen, E. Kim, M. Wang, J. H. Lee, H. Chen, G. Zhang, J. K. Kim, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2022, 32, 2111794.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Su, D. Hao, M. Sun, T. Wei, D. Xu, X. Ai, X. Guo, T. Zhao, L. Jiang, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2022, 32, 2108135.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Xia, C. Wang, N. Xu, J. Yang, G. Gao, J. Ding, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2023, 33, 2214769.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Zhao, X. Zhou, Y. Shi, X. Qian, M. Alexander, X. Zhao, S. Mendez, R. Yang, L. Qu, G. Yu, Nat. Nanotechnol. 2018, 13, 489.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N. Ding, B. Liang, X. Gao, D. Yao, J. Chen, C. Liu, C. Lu, X. Pang, Chem. Eng. J. 2024, 495, 153470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Graeber, C. D. Diaz&#x2010;Marin, L. C. Gaugler, Y. Zhong, B. El Fil, X. Liu, E. N. Wang, Adv. Mater. 2023, 36, 2211783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Fan, R. M. Pashley, J. Solution Chem. 2015, 44, 131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Lu, W. Shi, J. H. Zhang, A. C. Chen, W. Guan, C. Lei, J. R. Greer, S. V. Boriskina, G. Yu, Adv. Mater. 2022, 34, 2205344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Shan, P. Poredo&#x161;, H. Qu, X. Yang, M. Zhou, L. Bai, J. Shi, W. Chen, R. Wang, S. C. Tan, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 34, 2402839.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhang, L. Tao, S. Li, Y. Wei, Biomacromolecules 2011, 12, 2894.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Prakash, N. K. Katiyar, M. Y. Suarez&#x2010;Villagran, J. H. Miller, L. D. Machado, C. S. Tiwary, K. Biswas, K. Chattopadhyay, Mater. Today Commun. 2023, 36, 106388.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization, Guidelines for Drinking&#x2010;Water, Quality Fourth Edition 2017.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>