<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37406334</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1539-0667</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>46</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><MedlineDate>2023 Jul-Aug 01</MedlineDate></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of infusion nursing : the official publication of the Infusion Nurses Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Infus Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>International Consensus Recommendation Guidelines for Subcutaneous Infusions of Hydration and Medication in Adults: An e-Delphi Consensus Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>199</StartPage><EndPage>209</EndPage><MedlinePgn>199-209</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/NAN.0000000000000511</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Infusion of fluids and medications is traditionally performed intravenously. However, venous depletion in patients has led to the quest for vessel health preservation. A safe, effective, acceptable, and efficient alternative is the subcutaneous route. A lack of organizational policies may contribute to the slow uptake of this practice. This modified e-Delphi (electronic) study aimed to derive international consensus on practice recommendations for subcutaneous infusions of fluids and medications. A panel of 11 international clinicians, with expertise in subcutaneous infusion research and/or clinical practice, rated and edited subcutaneous infusion practice recommendations from evidence, clinical practice guidelines, and clinical expertise within an Assessment, Best Practice, and Competency (ABC) domain guideline model. The ABC Model for Subcutaneous Infusion Therapy provides a systematic guideline of 42 practice recommendations for the safe delivery of subcutaneous infusions of fluids and medications in the adult population in all care settings. These consensus recommendations provide a guideline for health care providers, organizations, and policy makers to optimize use of the subcutaneous access route.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Broadhurst</LastName><ForeName>Daphne</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8309-8060</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Alliance for Vascular Access Teaching and Research (AVATAR) Group, Menzies Health Institute Queensland, Gold Coast, Queensland, Australia (Mss Broadhurst, Cooke, and Sriram); Infusion Excellence Consulting, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada (Ms Broadhurst); School of Nursing and Midwifery, Nathan Campus, Griffith University, Nathan, Queensland, Australia (Ms Cooke); Needle Calm Pty, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia (Ms Barber); Clinical Nutrition and Dietetics Unit, Fondazione IRCCS Policlinico San Matteo, Pavia, Italy (Mr Caccialanza); Department of Geriatric Medicine, Aalborg University Hospital, Aalborg, Denmark [ORCID https://orcid.org/0000-0001-7431-5257 ] (Mr Danielsen); Optum Complex Care Management, Horsham, Pennsylvania (Ms Ebersold); Ascension at Home, Indianapolis, Indiana (Ms Gorski); The Johns Hopkins Home Care Group, Baltimore, Maryland (Mr Hirsch); Centre for Nurse Education, Cork University Hospital, Cork, Ireland (Ms Lynch); FAMS Institution: Division of Supportive and Palliative Care, National Cancer Centre, Singapore (Ms Neo); Roubaud CHU de Bordeaux, P&#xf4;le de G&#xe9;rontologie Clinique, Bordeaux, France (Ms Roubaud-Baudron); Clinical Pharmacy Partners, Tampa, Florida (Ms Gray).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cooke</LastName><ForeName>Marie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sriram</LastName><ForeName>Deepa</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barber</LastName><ForeName>Lauren</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caccialanza</LastName><ForeName>Riccardo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Danielsen</LastName><ForeName>Mathias Brix</ForeName><Initials>MB</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ebersold</LastName><ForeName>Stacie Lynne</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gorski</LastName><ForeName>Lisa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hirsch</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lynch</LastName><ForeName>Gerardine</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Neo</LastName><ForeName>Shirlyn Hui-Shan</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roubaud-Baudron</LastName><ForeName>Claire</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gray</LastName><ForeName>Brenda</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Infus Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101124170</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1533-1458</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003697" MajorTopicYN="N">Delphi Technique</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055104" MajorTopicYN="N">Infusions, Subcutaneous</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007263" MajorTopicYN="N">Infusions, Parenteral</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014680" MajorTopicYN="Y">Veins</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest/Author Disclosures: D.B. reports employment with Nipro Canada and speakers honorarium from BD Canada. M.C. has received grant funding from Children's Hospital Foundation and National Health and Medical Research Council paid to her employer, Griffith University. L.B. reports employment with Needle Calm and is a non-executive director and board member at the Medical Technology Association of Australia. L.G. reports book royalties with FA Davis, Springer Publishers. C.R.-B. has received a grant for a study on an antibiotic administered by SC Route (PK), French National Drugs Agency. B.G. reports consultancy for Fresenius Kabi. For the remaining authors, none were declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37406334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10306332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NAN.0000000000000511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00129804-202307000-00002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Broadhurst D, Cooke M, Sriram D, Gray B. Subcutaneous hydration and medications infusions (effectiveness, safety, acceptability): a systematic review of systematic reviews. PloS One. 2020;15(8):e0237572. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0237572</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7446806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32833979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helm RE, Klausner JD, Klemperer JD, Flint LM, Huang E. Accepted but unacceptable: peripheral IV catheter failure. J Infus Nurs. 2015;38(3):189&#x2013;203. doi:10.1097/NAN.0000000000000100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25871866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murayama R, Uchida M, Oe M, et al. Removal of peripheral intravenous catheters due to catheter failures among adult patients. J Infus Nurs. 2017;40(4):224&#x2013;231. doi:10.1097/NAN.0000000000000168</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28683001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caccialanza R, Constans T, Cotogni P, Zaloga GP, Pontes-Arruda A. Subcutaneous infusion of fluids for hydration or nutrition: a review. JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr. 2018;2(2):296&#x2013;307. doi:10.1177/0148607116676593</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29443395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Civetta G, Cortesi S, Mancardi M, et al. EA-DIVA score (Enhanced Adult DIVA score): a new scale to predict difficult preoperative venous cannulation in adult surgical patients. J Vasc Access. 2019;20(3):281&#x2013;289. doi:10.1177/1129729818804994</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30324841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armenteros-Yeguas V, Garate-Echenique L, Tomas-Lopez MA, et al. Prevalence of difficult venous access and associated risk factors in highly complex hospitalised patients. J Clin Nurs. 2017;26(23-24):4267&#x2013;4275. doi:10.1111/jocn.13750</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6084302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28165645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallam C, Weston V, Denton A, et al. Development of the UK Vessel Health and Preservation (VHP) framework: a multi-organisational collaborative. J Infect Prev. 2016;17(2):65&#x2013;72. doi:10.1177/1757177415624752</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5074217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28989456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duems-Noriega O, Ari&#xf1;o-Blasco S. Subcutaneous fluid and drug delivery: safe, efficient and inexpensive. Rev Clin Gerontol. 2015;25(2):117&#x2013;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rouhani S, Meloney L, Ahn R, Nelson BD, Burke TF. Alternative rehydration methods: a systematic review and lessons for resource-limited care. Pediatrics. 2011;127(3):e748&#x2013;e757. doi:10.1542/peds.2010-0952</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21321023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Annes LMB, da Cunha Andrade RGA, de Albuquerque Pontes IE, Sena GR, Telles J, de Orange FA. Subcutaneous versus intravenous rehydration in hospitalized older adults: a meta-analysis. J Infus Nurs. 2020;43(5):283&#x2013;291. doi:10.1097/NAN.0000000000000388</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32881815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danielsen MB, Andersen S, Worthington E, Jorgensen MG. Harms and benefits of subcutaneous hydration in older patients: systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2020;68(12):2937&#x2013;2946. doi:10.1111/jgs.16707</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33411351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emergency Nurses Association. Clinical practice guideline: difficult intravenous access. www.ena.org/docs/default-source/resource-library/practice-resources/cpg/difficultivaccesscpg.pdf?sfvrsn=9944da58_122015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickman A, Schneider J. The Syringe Driver: Continuous Subcutaneous Infusions In Palliative Care: Oxford University Press; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caba&#xf1;ero-Martinez MJ, Ramos-Pichardo JD, Velasco-&#xc1;lvarez ML, Garcia-Sanjuan S, Lillo-Crespo M, Cabrero-Garcia J. Availability and perceived usefulness of guidelines and protocols for subcutaneous hydration in palliative care settings. J Clin Nurs. 2019;28(21-22):4012&#x2013;4020. doi:10.1111/jocn.15036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31410903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortis LJ, Ward PR, McKinnon RA, Koczwara B. Integrated care in cancer: what is it, how is it used and where are the gaps? A textual narrative literature synthesis. Eur J Cancer Care. 2017;26:e12689. doi:10.1111/ecc.12689</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28426142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khemani R, Smith L, Zimmerman J, et al. Pediatric acute respiratory distress syndrome: definition, incidence, and epidemiology: proceedings from the Pediatric Acute Lung Injury Consensus Conference. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2015;16(5 Suppl 1):S23&#x2013;S40. doi:10.1097/PCC.0000000000000432</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26035358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loblaw DA, Prestrud AA, Somerfield MR, et al. American Society of Clinical Oncology Clinical Practice Guidelines: formal systematic review-based consensus methodology. J Clin Oncol. 2012;30(25):3136&#x2013;3140. doi:10.1200/JCO.2012.42.0489</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22778311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schults J, Kleidon T, Chopra V, et al. International recommendations for a vascular access minimum dataset: a Delphi consensus-building study. BMJ Qual Saf. 2020;30(9):722&#x2013;730. doi:10.1136/bmjqs-2020-011274</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8380895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32963025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller HH, McCullough J, Davidson B, et al. The integrated nutrition pathway for acute care (INPAC): building consensus with a modified Delphi. Nutr J. 2015;14:63. doi:10.1186/s12937-015-0051-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4473836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26089037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boulkedid R, Abdoul H, Loustau M, Sibony O, Alberti C. Using and reporting the Delphi method for selecting healthcare quality indicators: a systematic review. PLoS One. 2011;6(6):e20476. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0020476</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3111406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21694759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourr&#xe9;e F, Michel P, Salmi LR. Consensus methods: review of original methods and their main alternatives used in public health [in French]. Rev Epidemiol Sante Publique. 2008;56(6):e415&#x2013;e423. doi:10.1016/j.respe.2008.09.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3838316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19013039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor RM, Feltbower RG, Aslam N, Raine R, Whelan JS, Gibson F. Modified international e-Delphi survey to define healthcare professional competencies for working with teenagers and young adults with cancer. BMJ Open. 2016;6(5):e011361. doi:10.1136/bmjopen-2016-011361</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4861123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27142859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorski L, Hadaway L, Hagle M, et al. Infusion therapy standards of practice. J Infus Nurs. 2021;44(15):1&#x2013;224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33394637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moureau NL, Carr PJ. Vessel health and preservation: a model and clinical pathway for using vascular access devices. Br J Nurs. 2018;27(8):S28&#x2013;S35. doi:10.12968/bjon.2018.27.8.S28</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29683752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>OCEBM Levels of Evidence Working Group. The Oxford 2011 Levels of Evidence. Oxford Centre for Evidence-Based Medicine; 2011. https://www.cebm.net/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitch K, Bernstein SJ, Aguilar MD, Burnand B, LaCalle JR. The RAND/UCLA Appropriateness Method User's Manual. Rand Corp; 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adleman J, Gillan C, Caissie A, et al. Development of a quality and safety competency curriculum for radiation oncology residency: an international Delphi study. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2017;98(2):428&#x2013;437. doi:10.1016/j.ijrobp.2016.11.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28366572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthur AO. Innovations in subcutaneous infusions. J Infus Nurs. 2015;38(3):179&#x2013;187. doi:10.1097/NAN.0000000000000099</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25871865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Quality Ontario. Home-based subcutaneous infusion of immunoglobulin for primary and secondary immunodeficiencies: a health technology assessment. Ont Health Technol Assess Ser. 2017;17(16):1&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6548531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31210833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoner KL, Harder H, Fallowfield LJ, Jenkins VA. Intravenous versus subcutaneous drug administration: which do patients prefer? A systematic review [published online ahead of print Jul 12, 2014]. Patient. doi:10.1007/s40271-014-0075-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25015302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vidal MMD, Hui DMD, Williams J, Bruera EMD. A prospective study of hypodermoclysis performed by caregivers in the home setting. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2016;52(4):570&#x2013;574.9. doi:10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2016.04.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27640727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canadian Vascular Access Association. Canadian Vascular Access And Infusion Therapy Guidelines. Pappin Communications; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabriel J. Subcutaneous fluid administration and the hydration of older people. Br J Nurs. 2014;23(14):S10&#x2013;S14. doi:10.12968/bjon.2014.23.sup14.s10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25158361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Royal College of Nursing. Standards for Infusion Therapy: 4th Edition. Royal College of Nursing; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. Intravenous fluid therapy in adults in hospital. Nice Clin Guidel. 2017:1&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32101393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colin E, Baldolli A, Verdon R, Saint-Lorant G. Subcutaneously administered antibiotics. Med Mal Infect. 2020;50(3):231&#x2013;242. doi:10.1016/j.medmal.2019.06.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31300245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fonzo-Christe C, Vukasovic C, Wasilewski-Rasca A-F, Bonnabry P. Subcutaneous administration of drugs in the elderly: survey of practice and systematic literature review. Palliat Med. 2005;19(3):208&#x2013;219. doi:10.1191/0269216304pm1006oa</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15920935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes NS, Silva A, Zago LB, Silva E, Barichello E. Nursing knowledge and practices regarding subcutaneous fluid administration. Rev Bras Enferm. 2017;70(5):1096&#x2013;1105. doi:10.1590/0034-7167-2016-0424</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28977240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabriel J. A guide to subcutaneous infusion. Br J Nurs. 2019;28(Sup14c):1&#x2013;7. doi:10.12968/bjon.2019.28.Sup14c.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31446769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabriel J. The use of subcutaneous infusion in medication administration. Br J Nurs. 2013;22(14):S6, S8, S10 passim. doi:10.12968/bjon.2013.22.Sup14.S6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24261001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macmillan K, Macmillan A, Bruera E, Kuehn N, Selmser P. A prospective comparison study between a butterfly needle and a Teflon cannula for subcutaneous narcotic administration. J Pain Symptom Manage. 1994;9(2):82&#x2013;84. doi:10.1016/0885-3924(94)90160-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8021539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neo SH-S, Khemlani MH, Sim LK, Seah AST. Winged metal needles versus plastic winged and nonwinged cannulae for subcutaneous infusions in palliative care: a quality improvement project to enhance patient care and medical staff safety in a Singaporean hospital. J Palliat Med. 2016;19(3):318&#x2013;322. doi:10.1089/jpm.2015.0085</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26583758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torre MC. Subcutaneous infusion: non-metal cannulae vs metal butterfly needles. Br J Community Nurs. 2002;7(7):365&#x2013;369. doi:10.12968/bjcn.2002.7.7.10636</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12131852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Immunoglobulin National Society. Immunoglobulin Therapy Standards of Practice 2<sup>nd</sup>Edition. Immunoglobulin National Society; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Australian Diabetes Educators Association. Clinical guiding principles for subcutaneous injection technique: technical guidelines. https://www.adea.com.au/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/Injection-Technique-Final-digital-version2.pdf2017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forbat L, Kunicki N, Chapman M, Lovell C. How and why are subcutaneous fluids administered in an advanced illness population: a systematic review. J Clin Nurs. 2017;26(9/10):1204&#x2013;1216. doi:10.1111/jocn.13683</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27982484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frisoli AJ, de Paula AP, Feldman D, Nasri D. Subcutaneous hydration by hypodermoclysis: a practical and low cost treatment for elderly patients. Drugs Aging. 2000;16(4):313&#x2013;319. doi:10.2165/00002512-200016040-00007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10874526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaudet LM, Singh K, Weeks L, Skidmore B, Tsertsvadze A, Ansari MT. Effectiveness of terbutaline pump for the prevention of preterm birth: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PloS One. 2012;7(2):e31679. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0031679</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3283660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22363704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruera E, Belzile M, Watanabe S, Fainsinger RL. Volume of hydration in terminal cancer patients. Support Care Cancer. 1996;4(2):147&#x2013;150. doi:10.1007/BF01845764</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8673352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruera E, Neumann C, Pituskin E, Calder K, Ball G, Hanson J. A randomized controlled trial of local injections of hyaluronidase versus placebo in cancer patients receiving subcutaneous hydration. Ann Oncol. 1999;10(10):1255&#x2013;1258. doi:10.1023/a:1008331727535</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10586347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Challiner YC, Jarrett D, Hayward MJ, al-Jubouri MA, Julious SA. A comparison of intravenous and subcutaneous hydration in elderly acute stroke patients. Postgrad Med J. 1994;70(821):195&#x2013;197. doi:10.1136/pgmj.70.821.195</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2397852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8183752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rochon PA, Gill SS, Litner J, Fischbach M, Goodison AJ, Gordon M. A systematic review of the evidence for hypodermoclysis to treat dehydration in older people. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 1997;52(3):M169&#x2013;M176. doi:10.1093/gerona/52a.3.m169</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9158559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilhelm K. A systematic review of hyaluronidase-assisted subcutaneous fluid administration in pediatrics and geriatrics and its potential application in low resource settings. The University of Arizona; 2017. https://repository.arizona.edu/bitstream/handle/10150/623621/WilhelmK%20Thesis.pdf?sequence=2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lingman-Framme J, Fasth A. Subcutaneous immunoglobulin for primary and secondary immunodeficiencies: an evidence-based review. Drugs. 2013;73(12):1307&#x2013;1319. doi:10.1007/s40265-013-0094-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23861187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slesak G, Schn&#xfc;rle JW, Kinzel E, Jakob J, Dietz PK. Comparison of subcutaneous and intravenous rehydration in geriatric patients: a randomized trial. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2003;51(2):155&#x2013;160. doi:10.1046/j.1532-5415.2003.51052.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12558710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruera E, Hui D, Dalal S, et al. Parenteral hydration in patients with advanced cancer: a multicenter, double-blind, placebo-controlled randomized trial. J Clin Oncol. 2013;31(1):111&#x2013;118. doi:10.1200/JCO.2012.44.6518</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3530688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23169523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schults J, Calleja P, Slaughter E, et al. Peripheral intravenous catheter insertion and use of ultrasound in patients with difficult intravenous access: Australian patient and practitioner perspectives to inform future. PLoS One. 2022;17(6):e0269788. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0269788</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9231778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35749443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsh N, Webster J, Larsen E, Cooke M, Mihala G, Rickard C. Observational study of peripheral intravenous catheter outcomes in adult hospitalised patients: a multivariable analysis of peripheral intravenous catheter failure. J Hosp Med. 2018;13(2):83&#x2013;89. doi:10.12788/jhm.2867</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29073316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adebiyi BO, Mukumbang FC, Okop KJ, Beytell A-M. A modified Delphi study towards developing a guideline to inform policy on fetal alcohol spectrum disorders in South Africa: a study protocol. BMJ Open. 2018;8(4):e019907. doi:10.1136/bmjopen-2017-019907</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5922479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29703853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Ruiz V, Forestier E, Gavazzi G, et al. Subcutaneous antibiotic therapy: the why, how, which drugs and when. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2020;22(1):50&#x2013;55.e6. doi:10.1016/j.jamda.2020.04.035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32674952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neame MT, Chacko J, Surace AE, Sinha IP, Hawcutt DB. A systematic review of the effects of implementing clinical pathways supported by health information technologies. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2019;26(4):356&#x2013;363. doi:10.1093/jamia/ocy176</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7647175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30794311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>