<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41807463</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The LS/CS ratio-performance relationship in DG-activated hybrid cements.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">8865</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-026-38577-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">The waste residues produced by metallurgical industry have caused great harm to the environment. Three kinds of residues, lithium slag (LS), copper slag (CS), and desulfurized gypsum (DG) were employed as partial cement replacements to develop an eco-friendly cementitious composite. It was found that the essential particles were generated using wet ball milling 10.0 wt. % LS and 20.0 wt. % CS, upon activation with 6.0 wt. % desulfurization DG, the hydration quality of the slurry was markedly enhanced as an additive to substitute the equivalent percentage of ordinary Portland cement (OPC). The &#x2018;low-alkali activation and optimal ratio&#x2019; synergistic approach effectively enhances the reactivity of the LS-CS composites. Meanwhile, the nucleation effect of LS and the filling effect of CS, contributes to the microstructural refinement. The result showed that the optimized specimen attained 77.78 and 95.76% of the control (C0)&#x2019;s compressive strength at 3 and 28 days, respectively. The hydration was comprehensively characterized by quantitative X-ray diffraction (QXRD), SEM and FTIR spectroscopy, and the surface fractal was analyzed by MIP data. Furthermore, the test data indicated that LS exhibited substantial calcium hydroxide (CH) consumption while concurrently activating CS hydration, resulting in enhanced C- (A, F)-S-H phase formation. Overall, this investigation presents an effective approach for the thorough utilization of LS and CS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUPPLEMENTARY INFORMATION">The online version contains supplementary material available at 10.1038/s41598-026-38577-6.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiang</LastName><ForeName>Bingzhi</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Engineering and Technology, China University of Geosciences, Beijing, 100083, China. xiangbingzhi@jxut.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Zhongjian</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Engineering and Technology, China University of Geosciences, Beijing, 100083, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Guoxiang</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Engineering and Technology, China University of Geosciences, Beijing, 100083, China. yanggx@cugb.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Ruifeng</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nanchang Key Laboratory of Functional Materials for Solid Waste and Environmental Protection, Jiangxi Institute of Technology, Nanchang, 330098, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Jielu</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nanchang Key Laboratory of Functional Materials for Solid Waste and Environmental Protection, Jiangxi Institute of Technology, Nanchang, 330098, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>ZR2109</GrantID><Agency>The Natural Project of Jiangxi Institute of Technology (ZR2109)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>GJJ2402506</GrantID><Agency>Science and Technology Project of Jiangxi Provincial Department of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>23ZRZD02</GrantID><Agency>The Natural Project of Jiangxi Institute of Technology</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Copper slag</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lithium slag</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Microstructure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Optimal ratio</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Synergistic hydration</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41807463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12988228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-026-38577-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-026-38577-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gu, T. et al. Review: the formation, characteristics, and resource utilization of lithium slag. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>432</b>, 136648 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khair, S., Rahman, S. A., Shaikh, F. U. A. &amp; Sarker, P. K. Evaluating lithium slag for geopolymer concrete: a review of its properties and sustainable construction applications. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mater.</i><b>20</b>, e02822 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang, B. et al. Synergistic effect of MWCNTs and GO as a reinforcing phase on copper slag-based cement composites. <i>Sci. Rep.</i><b>15</b> (1), 13283 (2025).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-97227-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12006484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40246972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casagrande, C. A. et al. Copper slag in cementitious composites: A systematic review. <i>J. Building Eng.</i><b>78</b>, 107725 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.107725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Y. et al. A critical review on the use of copper slag (CS) as a substitute constituent in concrete. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>363</b>, 129692 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prabha, S. L., Gopalakrishnan, M. &amp; Neelamegam, M. Development of high-strength nano-cementitious composites using copper slag. <i>ACI Mater. J.</i><b>117</b> (4), 37&#x2013;46 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong, F. H. et al. Effects of different activators on workability, mechanical properties and microstructure of alkali-activated slag-copper slag. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>463</b>, 140151 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.140151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng, D. L. et al. Research progress on solidification/stabilization of sludge with Alkali&#x2013;Activated cementitious materials: A review. <i>Sustainable Chem. Pharm.</i><b>43</b>, 101904 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scp.2025.101904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javed, U., Shaikh, F. U. A. &amp; Sarker, P. K. Microstructural investigation of lithium slag geopolymer pastes containing silica fume and fly Ash as additive chemical modifiers. <i>Cem. Concr. Compos.</i><b>134</b>, 104736 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javed, U., Shaikh, F. U. A. &amp; Sarker, P. K. A comprehensive micro-nano investigative approach to study the development of aluminosilicate gel in binary blends of lithium slag geopolymer. <i>Cem. Concr. Compos.</i><b>145</b>, 105338 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2023.105338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, J. et al. Investigation into the alkali-activation of lithium slag: A sustainable alternative to conventional cement with optimized mechanical properties. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>416</b>, 135022 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu, K. et al. Preparation of new copper smelting slag-based mine backfill material and investigation of its mechanical properties. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>382</b>, 131228 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.131228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Q. et al. Utilization of modified copper slag activated by Na2SO4 and CaO for unclassified lead/zinc mine tailings based cemented paste backfill. <i>J. Environ. Manage.</i><b>290</b>, 112608 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2021.112608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33901826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lan, W., Wu, A. &amp; Yu, P. Development of a new controlled low strength filling material from the activation of copper slag: influencing factors and mechanism analysis. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>246</b>, 119060 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2019.119060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Y. et al. Mechanical and environmental characteristics of cemented paste backfill containing lithium slag-blended binder. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>271</b>, 121567 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javed, U., Shaikh, F. U. A. &amp; Sarker, P. K. Microstructural investigation of thermo-mechanically processed lithium slag for geopolymer precursor using various characterization techniques. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>342</b>, 127952 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.127952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soultana, A. et al. Properties of inorganic polymers produced from brick waste and metallurgical slag. <i>Minerals</i><b>9</b> (9), 551 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min9090551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, Y. et al. Comparison of ternary and dual combined waste-derived alkali activators on the durability of volcanic ash-based geopolymers. <i>Cem. Concr. Compos.</i><b>136</b>, 104886 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, L. et al. Utilization of flue gas desulfurization gypsum as an activation agent for high-volume slag concrete. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>205</b>, 589&#x2013;598 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2018.09.145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, S., Fan, K. &amp; Yao, Y. Preparation and characterization of quaternary clinker-free cementitious materials containing phosphorus slag, calcium carbide slag, desulfurization gypsum, and metakaolin. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>411</b>, 134602 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, J., Gencturk, B., Jain, A. &amp; Hanifehzadeh, M. Mitigating alkali-silica reaction induced concrete degradation through cement substitution by Metakaolin and bentonite. <i>Appl. Clay Sci.</i><b>182</b>, 105257 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clay.2019.105257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Larrard, F. <i>Concrete Mixture Proportioning: a Scientific Approach</i> (CRC, 1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fagerlund, G. Chemically bound water as measure of degree of hydration: method and potential errors. (2009).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei, J. &amp; Gencturk, B. Hydration of ternary Portland cement blends containing Metakaolin and sodium bentonite. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>123</b>, 105772 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.05.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu, X. et al. Synergistic effect and mechanism of lithium slag on mechanical properties and microstructure of steel slag-cement system. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>396</b>, 131768 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.131768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, B. &amp; Li, S. Determination of the surface fractal dimension for porous media by mercury porosimetry. <i>Ind. Eng. Chem. Res.</i><b>34</b> (4), 1383&#x2013;1386 (1995).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ie00043a044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui, S., Liu, P., Cui, E., Su, J. &amp; Huang, B. Experimental study on mechanical property and pore structure of concrete for shotcrete use in a hot-dry environment of high geothermal tunnels. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>173</b>, 124&#x2013;135 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.03.191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue, G., Fu, Q., Xu, S. &amp; Li, J. Macroscopic mechanical properties and microstructure characteristics of steel slag fine aggregate concrete. <i>J. Building Eng.</i><b>56</b>, 104742 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. &amp; Diamond, S. A fractal study of the fracture surfaces of cement pastes and mortars using a stereoscopic SEM method. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>31</b> (10), 1385&#x2013;1392 (2001).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0008-8846(01)00591-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. et al. Quantitative determination of quaternary solid waste-based binders and its hydrates by XRD. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>425</b>, 135888 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debye, P. &amp; Scherrer, P. Interferenzen an Regellos orientierten teilchen Im R&#xf6;ntgenlicht. I. <i>Nachr. Von Der Gesellschaft Der Wissenschaften Zu G&#xf6;ttingen Mathematisch-Physikalische Klasse</i>. <b>1916</b>, 1&#x2013;15 (1916).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaur, R. &amp; Kothiyal, N. C. Positive synergistic effect of superplasticizer stabilized graphene oxide and functionalized carbon nanotubes as a 3-D hybrid reinforcing phase on the mechanical properties and pore structure refinement of cement nanocomposites. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>222</b>, 358&#x2013;370 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.06.152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noguchi, N. et al. Hydration of ferrite-rich Portland cement: evaluation of Fe-hydrates and Fe uptake in calcium-silicate-hydrates. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>288</b>, 123142 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nsiah-Baafi, E. Investigation of strategies for risk minimisation of adverse alkali-silica reaction in concrete. (Doctoral dissertation, University of Technology Sydney (Australia)), 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun, R. et al. Effect of white mud on properties of alkali activated slag. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>392</b>, 131944 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.131944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, W., Mao, Z., Xu, G., Chang, H., Hong, J., Zhao, H., Liu, Z. Study on the early cement hydration process in the presence of cationic asphalt emulsion. <i>Construct. Build. Mater.</i><b>261</b>, 120025 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge, W., Zhang, Z., Ashour, A., Li, W., Jiang, H., Hu, Y., Cao, D. Hydration characteristics, hydration products and microstructure of reactive powder concrete. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>69</b>, 106306 (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao, J., Gao, J., Zhao, Y. &amp; Chen, X. Study on the pozzolanic reaction of clay brick powder in blended cement pastes. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>213</b>, 209&#x2013;215 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.03.307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, X. &amp; Wang, C. Influence of Al/Fe ratio on the hydration of brownmillerite in the presence of calcium sulfate. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>423</b>, 135614 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAN, Y. F. &amp; LUAN, H. Y. Pore structure in concrete exposed to acid deposit. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>49</b>, 407&#x2013;416 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2013.08.075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, T., Ma, B., Wu, S., Jin, Z. &amp; Wang, J. Mechanical properties and hydration process of steel slag-cement binder containing nano-SiO2. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>314</b>, 125660 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.125660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhan, P., Xu, J., Wang, J. &amp; Jiang, C. Multi-scale study on synergistic effect of cement replacement by Metakaolin and typical supplementary cementitious materials on properties of ultra-high performance concrete. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>307</b>, 125082 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.125082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishai, O. The time-dependent deformational behaviour of cement paste, mortar and concrete. In <i>Proceedings of Conference on Structure of Concrete and its Behavior Under Load, Cement and Concrete Association</i> (pp. 345&#x2013;364). (1968).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta, P. K. High-performance, high-volume fly ash concrete for sustainable development. In <i>Proceedings of the International Workshop on Sustainable Development and Concrete Technology</i> (pp. 3&#x2013;14). Ames, IA, USA: Iowa State University. (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powers, T. C. The physical structure and engineering properties of concrete (No. 90). (1958).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halamickova, P., Detwiler, R. J., Bentz, D. P. &amp; Garboczi, E. J. Water permeability and chloride ion diffusion in Portland cement mortars: relationship to sand content and critical pore diameter. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>25</b> (4), 790&#x2013;802 (1995).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0008-8846(95)00069-O</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, H. et al. Pore structure representations based on nitrogen adsorption experiments and an FHH fractal model: case study of the block Z shales in the Ordos Basin, China. <i>J. Petrol. Sci. Eng.</i><b>203</b>, 108661 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2021.108661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu, H., Zhang, D., Wang, T., McBain, M. &amp; Li, V. C. Intrinsic self-stressing and low carbon engineered cementitious composites (ECC) for improved sustainability. <i>Cem. Concr. Res.</i><b>149</b>, 106580 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2021.106580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L. et al. Study on the reinforcing mechanisms of nano silica to cement-based materials with theoretical calculation and experimental evidence. <i>J. Compos. Mater.</i><b>50</b> (29), 4135&#x2013;4146 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0021998316632602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Q., Liu, B., Sun, Z., Li, Q., Wang, S., Lu, X., Zhang, S. Preparation and hydration process of copper slag-granulated blast furnace slag-cement composites. <i>Construct. Build. Materi.</i><b>421</b>, 135717. (2024).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>