<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40269113</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2731-9377</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BJC reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BJC Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring the effect of differing centre hydration and anti-emetic policies on acute gastrointestinal and renal toxicities in the De-ESCALaTE trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>25</StartPage><MedlinePgn>25</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">25</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s44276-025-00132-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The De-ESCALaTE trial confirmed the superiority of cisplatin over cetuximab in combination with radiotherapy for the treatment of low risk HPV+ oropharyngeal cancer (HPV&#x2009;+&#x2009;OPC). However, there were concerns about certain toxicities with the use of cisplatin, in particular nausea, vomiting, dehydration and renal toxicities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The De-ESCALaTE trial collected data on several centre level policies on hydration and anti-emetic use. Univariable and backwards stepwise multivariable logistic regression models were used to model the association between centre level policy variables and severe adverse events (SAEs) of interest and severe (grade 3-5) acute toxicities of interest. In addition, the predictive performance of each model was assessed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Centre level policies including the use of a triple anti-emetics regimen pre and post chemotherapy, increased volumes of IV fluids given before and during cisplatin chemotherapy as well as oral fluids advised post chemotherapy, were all associated with a reduced odds of SAEs of interest. Only a policy to give diuretics was associated with a reduction of severe (grade 3-5) acute toxicities of interest.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">For centres with HPV&#x2009;+&#x2009;OPC patients undergoing chemoradiation, we recommend the use of specific hydration and anti-emetic policies to reduce the rates of relevant SAEs and severe acute toxicities.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Kong</LastName><ForeName>Anthony</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Comprehensive Cancer Centre, King's College London, Guy's Campus, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hazell</LastName><ForeName>Matthew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Warwick Clinical Trials Unit, Warwick Medical School, University of Warwick, Coventry, CV4 7AL, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iqbal</LastName><ForeName>Gulnaz</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Warwick Clinical Trials Unit, Warwick Medical School, University of Warwick, Coventry, CV4 7AL, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Dunn</LastName><ForeName>Janet</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Warwick Clinical Trials Unit, Warwick Medical School, University of Warwick, Coventry, CV4 7AL, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Mehanna</LastName><ForeName>Hisham</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5544-6224</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Head and Neck Studies and Education, Robert Aitken Building, University of Birmingham, Birmingham, UK. h.mehanna@bham.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>C19677/A12834</GrantID><Acronym>CRUK_</Acronym><Agency>Cancer Research UK</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>C19677/A12834</GrantID><Acronym>CRUK_</Acronym><Agency>Cancer Research UK</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BJC Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918752188106676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2731-9377</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>Competing interests: AK received fees for consulting, advisory, speaker&#x2019;s roles and/or research funding from PUMA BioTechnology, AstraZeneca, Merck, MSD, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Avvinity Therapeutics. HM has personal financial interests with AstraZeneca, MSD, GSK, Sanofi Pasteur, Merck, Warwickshire Head Neck Clinic Ltd; institutional financial interests with AstraZeneca, GSK PLC, Sanofi Pasteur, MSD, GSK Biologicals, Silence Therapeutics; leadership roles: Chief of Liteform Trial Steering Committee, Chair of NIMRAD Trial Steering Committee, President of the British Association of Head Neck Oncologists, Trial Steering Group member of the MRC CTU Cancer Trials Steering Committee, Council member of the International Association of Oral Oncology, Director of the Institute for Head Neck Studies and Education, Secretary of the Head Neck Cancer InterGroup. HM is a National Institute for Health Research (NIHR) Senior Investigator. The views expressed in this article are those of the author(s) and not necessarily those of the NIHR, or the Department of Health and Social Care. All other authors have no conflict of interest. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Ethical approval was obtained for the De-ESCALaTE trial, the details of which can be found in the previous publication [5]. Full protocol of the De-ESCALaTE trial can be accessed on https://www.inhanse.org/patient-research/de-escalate/ .</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40269113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12019484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s44276-025-00132-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s44276-025-00132-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pignon JP, le, Maitre A, Maillard E, Bourhis J, Group M-NC. Meta-analysis of chemotherapy in head and neck cancer (MACH-NC): an update on 93 randomised trials and 17,346 patients. Radiother Oncol J Eur Soc Therapeutic Radiol Oncol. 2009;92:4&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.radonc.2009.04.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19446902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanchard P, Baujat B, Holostenco V, Bourredjem A, Baey C, Bourhis J, et al. Meta-analysis of chemotherapy in head and neck cancer (MACH-NC): a comprehensive analysis by tumour site. Radiother Oncol J Eur Soc Therapeutic Radiol Oncol. 2011;100:33&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.radonc.2011.05.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21684027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehanna H, Robinson M, Hartley A, Kong A, Foran B, Fulton-Lieuw T, et al. Radiotherapy plus cisplatin or cetuximab in low-risk human papillomavirus-positive oropharyngeal cancer (De-ESCALaTE HPV): an open-label randomised controlled phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2019;393:51&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6319250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30449623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillison ML, Trotti AM, Harris J, Eisbruch A, Harari PM, Adelstein DJ, et al. Radiotherapy plus cetuximab or cisplatin in human papillomavirus-positive oropharyngeal cancer (NRG Oncology RTOG 1016): a randomised, multicentre, non-inferiority trial. Lancet. 2019;393:40&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6541928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30449625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noronha V, Joshi A, Patil VM, Agarwal J, Ghosh-Laskar S, Budrukkar A, et al. Once-a-week versus once-every-3-weeks cisplatin chemoradiation for locally advanced head and neck cancer: a phase III randomized noninferiority trial. J Clin Oncol. 2018;36:1064&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2017.74.9457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29220295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanley JA, Barbara JM. The meaning and use of the area under a receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve. Radiology. 1982;143:29&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiology.143.1.7063747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7063747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steyerberg EW. Clinical prediction models: a practical approach to development, validation, and updating. New York: Springer-Verlag; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiyota N, Tahara M, Mizusawa J, Kodaira T, Fujii H, Yamazaki T, et al. Weekly cisplatin plus radiation for postoperative head and neck cancer (JCOG1008): a multicenter, noninferiority, phase II/III Randomized Controlled Trial. J Clin Oncol. 2022;40:1980&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.21.01293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9197353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35230884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal MS, Chaw C, Kovarik J, Aslam S, Jackson A, Kelly J, et al. Primary Concurrent Chemoradiation in Head and Neck Cancers with Weekly Cisplatin Chemotherapy: Analysis of Compliance, Toxicity and Survival. Int Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2017;21:171&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0036-1594020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5375948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28382126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crona DJ, Faso A, Nishijima TF, McGraw KA, Galsky MD, Milowsky MI. A Systematic Review of Strategies to Prevent Cisplatin-Induced Nephrotoxicity. Oncologist. 2017;22:609&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1634/theoncologist.2016-0319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5423518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28438887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lajer H, Kristensen M, Hansen HH, Nielsen S, Fr&#xf8;kiaer J, Ostergaard LF, et al. Magnesium depletion enhances cisplatin-induced nephrotoxicity. Cancer Chemother Pharm. 2005;56:535&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00280-005-1010-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15947931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans TR, Harper CL, Beveridge IG, Wastnage R, Mansi JL. A randomised study to determine whether routine intravenous magnesium supplements are necessary in patients receiving cisplatin chemotherapy with continuous infusion 5-fluorouracil. Eur J Cancer. 1995;31A:174&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0959-8049(94)00420-A</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7718321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodgkinson E, Neville-Webbe HL, Coleman RE. Magnesium depletion in patients receiving cisplatin-based chemotherapy. Clin Oncol. 2006;18:710&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clon.2006.06.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17100159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frick GA, Ballentine R, Driever CW, Kramer WG. Renal excretion kinetics of high-dose cis-dichlorodiammineplatinum(II) administered with hydration and mannitol diuresis. Cancer Treat Rep. 1979;63:13&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">421230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakaida E, Iwasawa S, Kurimoto R, Ebata T, Imai C, Oku T, et al. Safety of a short hydration method for cisplatin administration in comparison with a conventional method&#x2014;a retrospective study. Jpn J Clin Oncol. 2016;46:370&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jjco/hyv203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4886127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26755829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horinouchi H, Kubota K, Itani H, Taniyama TK, Nakamichi S, Wakui H, et al. Short hydration in chemotherapy containing cisplatin (&#x2265;75 mg/m2) for patients with lung cancer: a prospective study. Jpn J Clin Oncol. 2013;43:1105&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jjco/hyt122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24006505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hotta K, Takigawa N, Hisamoto-Sato A, Ichihara E, Kudo K, Uchida K, et al. Reappraisal of short-term low-volume hydration in cisplatin-based chemotherapy: results of a prospective feasibility study in advanced lung cancer in the Okayama Lung Cancer Study Group Trial 1002. Jpn J Clin Oncol. 2013;43:1115&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jjco/hyt128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24082005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins GS, Dhiman P, Ma J, Schlussel MM, Archer L, Van Calster B, et al. Evaluation of clinical prediction models (part 1): from development to external validation. BMJ. 2024;384:e074819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj-2023-074819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10772854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38191193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piantadosi S, Byar DP, Green SB. The ecological fallacy. Am J Epidemiol. 1988;127:893&#x2013;904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/oxfordjournals.aje.a114892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3282433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith G. Step away from stepwise. J Big Data. 2018;5:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40537-018-0143-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callejo A, Sed&#xf3;-Cabez&#xf3;n L, Juan ID, Llorens J. Cisplatin-Induced Ototoxicity: Effects, Mechanisms and Protection Strategies. Toxics. 2015;3:268&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/toxics3030268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5606684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29051464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>