<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38138665</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>24</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigation of Preparation and Shrinkage Characteristics of Multi-Source Solid Waste-Based Cementitious Materials.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">7522</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma16247522</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cement-stabilized macadam (CEM-SM) base layers on highways are prone to early shrinkage cracking in extremely cold and arid regions, mainly caused by the large drying shrinkage of traditional cement-stabilized base materials. A multi-component solid waste cementitious material (SWCM) was designed based on the response surface method. The synergistic reaction mechanism of SWCM was analyzed using X-ray diffractometer (XRD), Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FT-IR) and thermogravimetric analysis (TG). A shrinkage testing system was developed to evaluate the anti-cracking characteristics of stable macadam using multiple solid waste cementitious materials (SWCM-SM), and the strength growth law and frost resistance were analyzed. The results show that the Box-Behnken response surface model was used to obtain the optimal parameter combination for SWCM, including 60% slag, 30% steel slag, and 10% desulfurization gypsum. The compressive strength and flexural strength of SWCM-SM were 24.1% and 26.7% higher than those of CEM-SM after curing 180 days. The frost resistance of SWCM-SM was basically equivalent to that of CEM-SM, and the dry shrinkage strain of SWCM-SM was reduced by 30.7% compared to CEM-SM. It can be concluded that steel slag and desulfurization gypsum stimulate the hydration reaction of slag, thereby improving the bonding strength. Compared to CEM-SM, SWCM-SM exhibits slower hydration reaction and longer hydration duration, exhibiting characteristics of low early strength and high later strength. The early microstrain of the semi-rigid base layer is mainly caused by the occurrence of early water loss shrinkage, and the water loss rate of SWCM-SM is lower than that of CEM-SM. This study concludes that SWCM has good early crack resistance performance for stabilized crushed stones.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Xu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gansu Transportation Planning, Survey and Design Institute Co., Ltd., Lanzhou 730030, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gansu-Highway Traffic Construction Group Co., Ltd., Lanzhou 730000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Bo</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Lanzhou Jiaotong University, Lanzhou 730070, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wei</LastName><ForeName>Dingbang</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gansu Transportation Planning, Survey and Design Institute Co., Ltd., Lanzhou 730030, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gansu-Highway Traffic Construction Group Co., Ltd., Lanzhou 730000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guo</LastName><ForeName>Fucheng</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Lanzhou Jiaotong University, Lanzhou 730070, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Special Area Highway Engineering of Ministry of Education, Chang'an University, Xi'an 710064, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ji</LastName><ForeName>Haidong</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Civil Engineering, Lanzhou Jiaotong University, Lanzhou 730070, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>51868042</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>22ZY1QA005</GrantID><Agency>Special Funds for Guiding Local Scientific and Technological Development by The Central Government</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>21ZD3GA002</GrantID><Agency>Gansu Science and Technology Major Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>22ZD6GA010</GrantID><Agency>Gansu Science and Technology Major Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022BFE02006&#x3001;2022BEG02009</GrantID><Agency>the Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region Key R&amp;D Plan Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>22YF7GA135</GrantID><Agency>Gansu Provincial Key R&amp;D Program</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022BDE02010</GrantID><Agency>the Key Research and Development Program of Ningxia Autonomous Region of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2022-2-72</GrantID><Agency>Lanzhou Science and Technology Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">compressive strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">crack resistance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multiple solid waste cementitious materials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">response surface method</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">synergistic reaction</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Author Xu Wu and Dingbang Wei was employed by the company Gansu Transportation Planning, Survey and Design Institute Co., Ltd. and Gansu-Highway Traffic Construction Group Co., Ltd. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38138665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10744477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16247522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma16247522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y. The hotspot and frontier of solid waste comprehensive utilization research&#x2014;Big data visualization research based on scientific literature. Chem. Miner. Geol. 2022;2:183&#x2013;192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen S. Study on the Preparation Mechanism and Performance of Inorganic Polymerized Porous Materials in Multiple Solid Waste Systems. Hubei Univetity; Wuhan, China: 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farhan Z., Johari M., Demirboga R. Assessment of important parameters involved in the synthesis of geopolymer composites: A review. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;264:120276. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luukkonen T., Abdollahnejad Z., Yliniemi J. One-part alkali-activated materials: A review. Cem. Concr. Res. 2018;103:21&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2017.10.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2017.10.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasaki S., Zhang B., Guarecuco R. Geopolymer for use in heavy metals adsorption, and advanced oxidative processes: A critical review. J. Cleanner Prod. 2019;213:42&#x2013;58. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2018.12.145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2018.12.145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiventera J., Lancellotti I., Catauro M. Alkali activation as new option for gold mine tailing sinertization. J. Clean. Prod. 2018;187:76&#x2013;84. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2018.03.182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2018.03.182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bumanis G., Novais R., Carvalheiras J. Metals removal from aqueous solutions by tailored porous waste-based granulated alkali-activated materials. Appl. Clay Slay Sci. 2019;179:105147.1&#x2013;105147.9. doi: 10.1016/j.clay.2019.105147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clay.2019.105147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uliasz-Boche&#x144;czyk A., Pawluk A., Pyzalski M. The mineralsequestration of CO2 with theuse of flyash from the co-combustion of coal and biomass. Gospod. Surowcami Miner./Miner. Manag. 2017;33:143&#x2013;156. doi: 10.1515/gospo-2017-0044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/gospo-2017-0044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalid H., Lee N., Park S. Synthesis of geopolymer-supported zeolites via robust one-step method and their adsorption potential. J. Hazard. Maz. Mater. 2018;353:522&#x2013;533. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2018.04.049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2018.04.049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29723813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y., Zhang S., Wen N., Qi H. Immobilisation of high-arsenic-containing tailings by using metallurgical slag-cementing materials. Chemosphere. 2019;223:117&#x2013;123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30772590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qing S., Xiao L., Zeng Z., Chao W., Chun X. Synergistic utilization of blast furnace slag with other industrial solid wastes in cement and concrete industry: Synergistic mechanisms, applications, and challenges. Green Energy Resour. 2023;100012:2949&#x2013;7205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park S., Wu S., Liu Z., Pyo S. The role of supplementary cementitious materials (SCMs) in ultra high performance concrete (UHPC): A review. Materials. 2021;14:1472. doi: 10.3390/ma14061472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma14061472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8002722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33802943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahirwar J., Kaur M., Eet A. Compare the strength of fly ash based geopolymer concrete with demolition waste. Int. J. Civ. Eng. 2018;5:20&#x2013;24. doi: 10.14445/23488352/IJCE-V5I1P104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14445/23488352/IJCE-V5I1P104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menglim H., Runglawan R., Suksun H., Arul A., Mehdi M. Effect of wetting&#x2013;drying cycles on compressive strength and microstructure of recycled asphalt pavement&#x2013;Fly ash geopolymer. Constr. Build. Mater. 2017;144:624&#x2013;634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar R., Goyal S., Srivastava A. A comprehensive study on the influence of supplementary cementitious materials on physico-mechanical, microstructural and durability properties of low carbon cement composites. Powder Technol. 2021;394:645&#x2013;668.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathak K., Pandey V., Murari K., Singh P. Soil stabilisation using ground granulated blast furnace slag. Int. J. Eng. Res. Appl. 2014;4:164&#x2013;171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arulrajah A., Mohammadinia A., Phummiphan I. Stabilization of recycled demolition aggregates by geopolymers comprising calcium carbide residue, fly ash and slag precursors. Constr. Build. Mater. 2016;114:864&#x2013;873. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.03.150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.03.150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen W., Zhou M., Ma W. Investigation on the application of steel slag&#x2013;fly ash&#x2013;phosphogypsum solidified material as road base material. J. Hazard. Mater. 2009;164:99&#x2013;104. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2008.07.125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2008.07.125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18801617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teerawattanasuk C., Voottipruex P. Comparison between cement and fly ash geopolymer for stabilized marginal lateritic soil as road material. Int. J. Pavement Eng. 2018;20:1264&#x2013;1274. doi: 10.1080/10298436.2017.1402593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10298436.2017.1402593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y., Zhang H., Lin H., Wu X., Li H., Liu Y., Xu F. Factors affecting the strength formation mechanism and water stability of geopolymer stabilized phosphogypsum in road construction. Coatings. 2023;13:1652. doi: 10.3390/coatings13091652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/coatings13091652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji X., Wang Z., Zhang H., Wang X., Huo J., Zhang T. Optimization design and characterization of slag cementitious composites containing carbide slag and desulfurized gypsum based on response surface methodology. J. Build. Eng. 2023;77:107441. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2023.107441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.107441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan D., Wu H., Wei F., Song H., Ma Z., Chen Z., Cheng F. Preparation, characterization, and rheological analysis of eco-friendly geopolymer grouting cementitious materials based on industrial solid wastes. J. Build. Eng. 2023;78:107451. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2023.107451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.107451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernando S., Gunasekara C., Law W., Nasvi M., Setunge S., Dissanayake R. Engineering properties of waste-based alkali activated concrete brick containing low calcium fly ash and rice husk ash: A comparison with traditional Portland cement concrete brick. J. Build. Eng. 2022;46:103810. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103810.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ground granulated blast furnace slag used for cement, mortar and concrete. The National Standards of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China; Beijing, China: 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Test method of cement mortar strength (ISO method) The National Standards of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China; Beijing, China: 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Test method for activity of industrial waste slag used as addition to cement. The National Standards of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China; Beijing, China: 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Technical Specification for Application of Mineral Admixtures. The National Standards of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China; Beijing, China: 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Test Specification for Inorganic Binder Stabilized Materials in Highway Engineering. Ministry of Transport of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China; Beijing, China: 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Liu X., Li Z., Ren Y., Wang Y., Zhang W. Preparation, characterization and application of red mud, fly ash and desulfurized gypsum based eco-friendly road base materials. J. Clean. Prod. 2021;284:124777. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.124777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.124777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omur T., Kabay N., Miyan N., &#xd6;zkan H., &#xd6;zkan &#xc7;. The effect of alkaline activators and sand ratio on the physico- mechanical properties of blast furnace slag based mortars. J. Build. Eng. 2022;58:104998. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durczak K., Pyzalski M., Brylewski T., Sujak A. Effect of variable synthesis conditions on the formation of ye&#x2019;elimite-aluminate-calcium (YAC) cement and its hydration in the presence of portland cement (OPC) and several accessory additives. Materials. 2023;16:6052. doi: 10.3390/ma16176052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16176052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10488678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37687744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pyzalski M., D&#x105;bek J., Adamczyk A., Brylewski T. Physicochemical study of the self-disintegration of calcium orthosilicate (&#x3b2;&#x2192;&#x3b3;) in the presence of the C12A7 aluminate phase. Materials. 2021;14:6459. doi: 10.3390/ma14216459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma14216459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8585463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34771985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv Y., Qiao J., Han W., Pan B., Jin X., Peng H. Modification effect of Ca(OH)2 on the carbonation resistance of fly ash-metakaolin-based geopolymer. Materials. 2023;16:2305. doi: 10.3390/ma16062305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16062305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10056939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36984186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abadel A., Alghamdi H., Alharbi R., Alamri M., Khawaji M., Abdulaziz A., Nehdi L. Investigation of alkali-activated slag-based composite incorporating dehydrated cement powder and red mud. Materials. 2023;16:1551. doi: 10.3390/ma16041551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16041551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9959808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36837180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson G., Brough R., Groves W., Dobson M. The characterization of hardened alkali-activated blast-furnace slag pastes and the nature of the calcium silicate hydrate (CSH) phase. Cem. Concr. Res. 1994;24:813&#x2013;829. doi: 10.1016/0008-8846(94)90002-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0008-8846(94)90002-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B., Pang L., Zhou Z., Chang Q., Fu P. Study on the hydration properties of a ternary cementitious material system containing activated gold tailings and granulated blast furnace slag. J. Build. Eng. 2023;63:105574. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2022.105574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.105574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>