<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38288399</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1939-795X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of exercise science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Exerc Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of An Isotonic Medinilla Speciosa During and After Exercise.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1269</StartPage><EndPage>1283</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1269-1283</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Maintaining an adequate fluid balance is crucial during extended physical activity. It is currently unknown how drinking an isotonic medinilla speciosa beverage affects the autonomic regulation of heart function during and after exercise. The purpose of this study is to examine how drinking isotonic beverages affects heart rate variability (HRV) during and after intense exercise. A maximal exercise test to assess protocol loading, a control group, and an experimental group were all carried out by twenty-one young man (19.3 &#xb1; 1.2 years) over the course of three distinct protocols, with a 48-hour break in between each stage. The protocol called for 10 minutes of rest with the subject lying down, 90 minutes of treadmill work at 70% of one's maximum oxygen uptake, and 60 minutes of rest in the dorsal decubitus position. In the control group, no rehydration beverages could be consumed. No matter the level of hydration, alterations in the sympathetic nervous system (SNS) and the parasympathetic nervous system (PSNS) were seen, showing an increase in the former and a reduction in the latter. Hydration with isotonic solutions during recovery causes considerable alterations in cardiac autonomic regulation, hastening the recovery of the linear HRV index. Exercise-induced HRV was not significantly impacted by isotonic hydration, however it does speed up the recovery of linear indices after exercise.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rohmansyah</LastName><ForeName>Nur Azis</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Education Program, Universitas PGRI Semarang, INDONESIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nurdyansyah</LastName><ForeName>Fafa</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Food Technology Program, Universitas PGRI Semarang, INDONESIA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hiruntrakul</LastName><ForeName>Ashira</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports and Exercise Science Program, Faculty of Interdisciplinary Studies, Khon Kaen University, Nong Khai Campus, THAILAND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phumphitarkpanya</LastName><ForeName>Mancharee</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Exercise and Sport Sciences Program, Graduate School, Khon Kaen University, THAILAND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Exerc Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101513127</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1939-795X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autonomic nervous system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">isotonic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medinilla speciosa rehydration solutions</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38288399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10824306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.70252/JCJR1849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ijes-16-2-1269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Butts CL, Luhring KE, Smith CR, Tucker MA, Moyen NE, Ganio MS, et al. Effects of mild hypohydration on cooling during cold-water immersion following exertional hyperthermia. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2016;116(4):687&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26781710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catai AM, Pastre CM, de Godoy MF, daSilva E, Takahashi AC, de M, Vanderlei LCM. Heart rate variability: are you using it properly? Standardisation checklist of procedures. Brazilian Journal of Physical Therapy. 2020;24(2):91&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7082649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30852243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerezal Mezquita P, Espinosa &#xc1;lvarez C, Palma Ram&#xed;rez J, Bugue&#xf1;o Mu&#xf1;oz W, Salinas Fuentes F, Ruiz-Dom&#xed;nguez MDC. Isotonic beverage pigmented with water-dispersible emulsion from astaxanthin oleoresin. Molecules. 2020;25(4):841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7070863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32075065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deus LA, Sousa CV, Rosa TS, Filho JMS, Santos PA, Barbosa LD, et al. Heart rate variability in middle-aged sprint and endurance athletes. Physiol Behav. 2019;205:39&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30389479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estupi&#xf1;an DC, Schwartz SJ, Garz&#xf3;n GA. Antioxidant activity, total phenolics content, anthocyanin, and color stability of isotonic model beverages colored with andes berry (rubus glaucus benth) anthocyanin powder. J Food Sci. 2011;76(1):S26&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3879789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21535712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher XP. Cardiac autonomic regulation during hypoxic exercise. 308. American Journal of Physiology - Heart and Circulatory Physiology. 2015;308(12):1474&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25934098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fushtey I, Filimonova I, Sid E. Change of heart rate variability under the influence of fluvoxamine in patients with ischemic heart disease and myocardial infarction after myocardial revascularization. Psychiatry, Psychotherapy and Clinical Psychology. 2016;7(4):639&#x2013;647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giron&#xe9;s-Vilaplana A, Villa&#xf1;o D, Moreno DA, Garc&#xed;a-Viguera C. New isotonic drinks with antioxidant and biological capacities from berries (maqui, a&#xe7;a&#xed; and blackthorn) and lemon juice. Int J Food Sci Nutr. 2013;64(7):897&#x2013;906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23815554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harshini SS, Sridevi G, Preetha S. Effect of sustained isometric and isotonic exercises on blood pressure and heart rate variability &#x2013; a comparative study. J Pharm Res Int. 2021;33(47B):908&#x2013;915.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayano J, Yuda E. Pitfalls of assessment of autonomic function by heart rate variability. Journal of Physiological Anthropology. 2019;38(1):3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6416928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30867063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Cruz G, Estrada-Meneses EF, Ramos-Jim&#xe9;nez A, Rangel-Colmenero BR, Reynoso-S&#xe1;nchez LF, Miranda-Mendoza J, et al. Relationship between physical exercise type and fatigue quantified through HRV, CK, and blood lactate. Retos. 2022;44:81&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hillman A, Vince R, Taylor L, Mcnaughton L, Mitchell N, Siegler J. Exercise-induced dehydration with and without environmental heat stress results in increased oxidative stress. Applied Physiology, Nutrition and Metabolism. 2011;36(5):698&#x2013;706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21980993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iellamo F, Volterrani M, di Gianfrancesco A, Fossati C, Casasco M. The effect of exercise training on autonomic cardiovascular regulation. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2018;17(12):473&#x2013;479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30531466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaabudak E. Validity and reliability of beverage intake questionnaire: evaluating hydration status. Nutr Hosp. 2016;33(5):577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27759981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khoo HE, Azlan A, Tang ST, Lim SM. Anthocyanidins and anthocyanins: Colored pigments as food, pharmaceutical ingredients, and the potential health benefits. Food and Nutrition Research. 2017;61(1):1361779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5613902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28970777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JKW, Nio AQX, Ang WH, Law LYL, Lim CL. Effects of ingesting a sports drink during exercise and recovery on subsequent endurance capacity. Eur J Sport Sci. 2011;11(2):77&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maughan RJ, Watson P, Cordery PAA, Walsh NP, Oliver SJ, Dolci A, et al. A randomized trial to assess the potential of different beverages to affect hydration status: development of a beverage hydration index. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition. 2016;103(3):717&#x2013;723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26702122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mears SA, Shirreffs SM. Assessing hydration status and reported beverage intake in the workplace. American Journal of Lifestyle Medicine. 2015;9(2):157&#x2013;168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta SP, Jarvis A, Standifer D, Warnimont C. International physical activity questionnaire. Critical Reviews in Physical and Rehabilitation Medicine. 2018;30(2):125&#x2013;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gasmi Amin. What is fast fourier transform?. [Technical Report] Soci&#xe9;t&#xe9; Francophone de Nutrith&#xe9;rapie et de Nutrig&#xe9;n&#xe9;tique Appliqu&#xe9;e. 2022:hal-03741810f.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nissensohn M, L&#xf3;pez-Ufano M, Castro-Quezada I, Serra-Majem L, Mariela N. Assessment of beverage intake and hydration status. Nutr HospNutr HospNutr Hosp. 2015;313131(3):62&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25719773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patwardhan K, Tripathi PK, Singh G. The Basic cardiovascular responses to postural changes, exercise, and cold pressor test: Do they vary in accordance with the dual constitutional types of ayurveda? Evidence-based Complementary and Alternative Medicine. 2011;2011:251850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2952295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20953421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham T, Lau ZJ, Chen SHA, Makowski D. Heart rate variability in psychology: a review of HRV indices and an analysis tutorial. Sensors. 2021;21(12):3998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8230044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34207927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohmansyah NA, Rahmadhani W, Setiyawan S, Hiruntrakul A. Respon kapasitas daya tahan dan aldosterone: Efek minuman isotonik. Jurnal Keolahragaan. 2020;8(2):174&#x2013;182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosa L, Teixeira AAS, Lira FS, Tufik S, Mello MT, Santos RVT. Moderate acute exercise (70% VO2 peak) induces TGF-&#x3b2;, &#x3b1;-amylase and IgA in saliva during recovery. Oral Dis. 2014;20(2):186&#x2013;190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23464508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarma S, Levine BD. Beyond the Bruce protocol: advanced exercise testing for the sports cardiologist. Cardiology Clinics. 2016;34(4):603&#x2013;608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27692228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Secher M, Ritz P, Ritz P. Hydration and cognitive performance Jnha: Clinical Neurosciences. J Nutr. 2012;16(4):325&#x2013;329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22499450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaffer F, Ginsberg JP. An overview of heart rate variability metrics and norms. 5. Frontiers in Public Health. 2017;5:258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5624990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29034226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanderlei FM, Moreno IL, Vanderlei LCM, Pastre CM, de Abreu LC, Ferreira C. Comparison of the effects of hydration with water or isotonic solution on the recovery of cardiac autonomic modulation. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2015;25(2):145&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25029557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watso JC, Farquhar WB. Hydration status and cardiovascular function. Nutrients. 2019;11(8):1866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6723555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31405195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>tao Yin W, yang Song Z. An innovative method to calculate oxygen consumption rate. J Cent South Univ. 2019;26(4):873&#x2013;880.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>