<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39776723</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physiological Changes in Women's Skin During the Menstrual Cycle: A Scoping Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e75286</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e75286</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e75286</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.75286</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Multiple physiological changes occur during the menstrual cycle; many are&#xa0;attributed to fluctuations in estrogen, luteinizing hormone, follicle-stimulating hormone, and progesterone. These hormones differentially affect the menstrual cycle's follicular, ovulation, and luteal phases. Skin is one of the organs affected by changes in a woman's menstrual cycle. However, the understanding of the impact of these composite changes on skin biophysical and physiological parameters is limited. This scoping review was performed to help clarify the extent of physiological changes in the skin during a woman's menstrual cycle. Skin elasticity, hydration, temperature, blood flow, and sweating were the parameters assessed in this review. Embase, Ovid MEDLINE (Medical Literature Analysis and Retrieval System Online), and Web of Science databases were used to search for peer-reviewed articles in English relating to skin physiological changes during healthy women's menstrual cycles. The initial search yielded 666 unique articles that met the&#xa0;inclusion criteria. After critical appraisal, further screening produced 192 full texts that resulted in 26 articles that were investigated for skin elasticity, hydration, temperature, blood flow, and sweating during the menstrual cycle. The review clarifies the connection between female reproductive hormone fluctuations, phases of the menstrual cycle, and its subsequent impacts on the&#xa0;skin's physiological properties. An increase was seen in skin elasticity during ovulation compared to women in the follicular phase. No significant changes were seen in skin hydration across the three menstrual cycle phases. A higher basal skin temperature has been reported during the luteal phase than the follicular phase. A statistically significant increase in skin blood flow was also seen during the mid-luteal phase compared to the follicular phase. Lastly, an increased sweating rate was also observed in the luteal phase compared to the follicular phase for the parameter of sweating. However, higher sweating rates were also reported during the early follicular phase than in the mid-luteal phase. The overall findings of this review highlight how skin physiology varies within the menstrual cycle. This information can be useful in aligning treatment for women with abnormal menstrual cycles or possible maintenance of healthy menstrual flow. This review provides valuable information in a dermatological context to further explore how healthcare providers can apply personalized therapeutic approaches that align with certain phases of a woman's menstrual cycle, allowing for better skin condition management&#xa0;and improved patient care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024, Nguyen et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nguyen</LastName><ForeName>Mai-Linh</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical School, Nova Southeastern University Dr. Kiran C. Patel College of Osteopathic Medicine, Davie, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nguyen</LastName><ForeName>Sherilyn</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical School, Nova Southeastern University Dr. Kiran C. Patel College of Osteopathic Medicine, Davie, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sood</LastName><ForeName>Nikita</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical School, Nova Southeastern University Dr. Kiran C. Patel College of Osteopathic Medicine, Davie, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marivada</LastName><ForeName>Snigdha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical School, Nova Southeastern University Dr. Kiran C. Patel College of Osteopathic Medicine, Davie, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Magaldino</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical School, Nova Southeastern University Dr. Kiran C. Patel College of Osteopathic Medicine, Davie, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mayrovitz</LastName><ForeName>Harvey N</ForeName><Initials>HN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Education, Nova Southeastern University Dr. Kiran C. Patel College of Allopathic Medicine, Davie, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000098583">Scoping Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">menstrual cycle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skin blood flow</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skin elasticity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skin physiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skin sweating</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skin temperature</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tissue hydration</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39776723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11703644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.75286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Physiology of the menstrual cycle. Owen JA Jr. Am J Clin Nutr. 1975;28:333&#x2013;338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1091131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed BG, Carr BR. Endotext [Internet] South Dartmouth (MA): MDText.com, Inc.; 2016. The normal menstrual cycle and the control of ovulation.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiyagarajan DK, Basit H, Jeanmonod R. Statpearls [Internet] Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2024. Physiology, menstrual cycle.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monis CN, Tetrokalashvili M. Statpearls [Internet] Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2022. Menstrual cycle proliferative and follicular phase.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physiological changes associated with the menstrual cycle: a review. Farage MA, Neill S, MacLean AB. Obstet Gynecol Surv. 2009;64:58&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19099613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demonstration of estrogen receptors in the skin. Punnonen R, L&#xf6;vgren T, Kouvonen I. J Endocrinol Invest. 1980;3:217&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7430556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beneficial regulation of type I collagen and matrixmetalloproteinase-1 expression by estrogen, progesterone, and its combination in skin fibroblasts. Philips N, Devaney J. J Am Aging Assoc. 2003;26:59&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3456089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23604918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skin collagen changes in postmenopausal women receiving different regimens of estrogen therapy. Brincat M, Versi E, Moniz CF, Magos A, de Trafford J, Studd JW. Obstet Gynecol. 1987;70:123&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3601260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biology of estrogens in skin: implications for skin aging. Verdier-S&#xe9;vrain S, Bont&#xe9; F, Gilchrest B. Exp Dermatol. 2006;15:83&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16433679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skin water-holding capacity and transdermal estrogen therapy for menopause: a pilot study. Pi&#xe9;rard-Franchimont C, Letawe C, Goffin V, Pi&#xe9;rard GE. Maturitas. 1995;22:151&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8538484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of systemic hormonal cyclicity on skin. Muizzuddin N, Marenus KD, Schnittger SF, Sullivan M, Maes DH. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/16258697/ J Cosmet Sci. 2005;56:311&#x2013;321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16258697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Influence of female reproductive hormones on local thermal control of skin blood flow. Charkoudian N, Stephens DP, Pirkle KC, Kosiba WA, Johnson JM. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1999;87:1719&#x2013;1723.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10562614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sex hormone effects on autonomic mechanisms of thermoregulation in humans. Charkoudian N, Stachenfeld N. Auton Neurosci. 2016;196:75&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26674572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Temperature regulation in women: effects of the menstrual cycle. Baker FC, Siboza F, Fuller A. Temperature (Austin) 2020;7:226&#x2013;262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7575238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33123618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skin extensibility time in women. Changes in relation to sex hormones. Berardesca E, Gabba P, Farinelli N, Borroni G, Rabbiosi G. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/2572112/ Acta Derm Venereol. 1989;69:431&#x2013;433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2572112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of menstrual cycle on laser induced hyperpigmentation. Al Mohizea S. https://jddonline.com/articles/the-effect-of-menstrual-cycle-on-laser-induced-hyperpigmentation-S1545961613P1335X/ J Drugs Dermatol. 2013;12:1335&#x2013;1336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24301233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effects of isotretinoin on the menstrual cycle: a cross-sectional study. Alhetheli G, Alhazmi S, Almutairi S, et al. Clin Pract. 2022;12:908&#x2013;917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9680279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36412674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Influence of the menstrual cycle on the sweating response measured by direct calorimetry in women exposed to warm environmental conditions. Frascarolo P, Schutz Y, J&#xe9;quier E. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1992;64:449&#x2013;454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1612086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higher sweating rate and skin blood flow during the luteal phase of the menstrual cycle. Lee H, Petrofsky J, Shah N, Awali A, Shah K, Alotaibi M, Yim J. Tohoku J Exp Med. 2014;234:117&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25230913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sex- and menstrual cycle-related differences in sweating and cutaneous blood flow in response to passive heat exposure. Inoue Y, Tanaka Y, Omori K, Kuwahara T, Ogura Y, Ueda H. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2005;94:323&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15729550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Determination of fertility interval with ovulation time estimation using differential skin surface temperature (dst) measurement. Shah A, Sathyanarayana Rao KH, Ruedi B, Magrini G. Fertility Sterility. 1984;41:771&#x2013;774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6714455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estrogens and aging skin. Thornton MJ. Dermatoendocrinol. 2013;5:264&#x2013;270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3772914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24194966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Influence of the menstrual cycle on breast skin elasticity. Coumar&#xe9; R, Bouten L, Barbier F. Comput Methods Biomech Biomed Engin. 2015;18 Suppl 1:1912&#x2013;1913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26273846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menopause induces changes to the stratum corneum ceramide profile, which are prevented by hormone replacement therapy. Kendall AC, Pilkington SM, Wray JR, et al. Sci Rep. 2022;12:21715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9755298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36522440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>JBI Manual for Evidence Synthesis. South Australia, AU: JBI; 2024. JBI Manual for Evidence Synthesis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>South Australia, AU: The Joanna Briggs Institute; 2015. The Joanna Briggs Institute Reviewers&#x2019; Manual 2015: Methodology for JBI Scoping Reviews.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endogenous hormones subtly alter women's response to heat stress. Carpenter AJ, Nunneley SA. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1988;65:2313&#x2013;2317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3145282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The menstrual cycle and Raynaud's phenomenon. Greenstein D, Jeffcote N, Ilsley D, Kester RC. Angiology. 1996;47:427&#x2013;436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8644939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>On exercise thermoregulation in females: interaction of endogenous and exogenous ovarian hormones. Lei TH, Cotter JD, Schlader ZJ, Stannard SR, Perry BG, Barnes MJ, M&#xfc;ndel T. J Physiol. 2019;597:71&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6312528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30320879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of the menstrual cycle phase on foot skin temperature during menthol application in young women. Uchida Y, Tsunekawa C, Sato I, Morimoto K. J Therm Biol. 2019;85:102401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31657743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparative study on skin temperature response to menstruation at acupuncture points in healthy volunteers and primary dysmenorrhea patients. She Y, Ma L, Zhu J, et al. J Tradit Chin Med. 2017;37:220&#x2013;228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29960295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of menstrual cycle on thermal perception and autonomic thermoregulatory responses during mild cold exposure. Matsuda-Nakamura M, Yasuhara S, Nagashima K. J Physiol Sci. 2015;65:339&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10717610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25762225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Changes in sleeping energy metabolism and thermoregulation during menstrual cycle. Zhang S, Osumi H, Uchizawa A, et al. Physiol Rep. 2020;8:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6981303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31981319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modern fertility awareness methods: wrist wearables capture the changes in temperature associated with the menstrual cycle. Shilaih M, Goodale BM, Falco L, K&#xfc;bler F, De Clerck V, Leeners B. Biosci Rep. 2018;38</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6265623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29175999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menstrual cycle phase affects temperature regulation during endurance exercise. Pivarnik JM, Marichal CJ, Spillman T, Morrow JR Jr. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1992;72:543&#x2013;548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1559930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menstrual variations in thermal properties of the human breast. Nassar AM, Smith RE. J Appl Physiol. 1975;39:806&#x2013;811.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1184519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laser Doppler-recorded reactive hyperaemia in the forearm skin during the menstrual cycle. Bungum L, Kvernebo K, Oian P, Maltau JM. Br J Obstet Gynaecol. 1996;103:70&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8608101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menstrual cycle and oral contraceptive use do not modify postexercise heat loss responses. Kenny GP, Leclair E, Sigal RJ, et al. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2008;105:1156&#x2013;1165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18687980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of luteal phase elevation in core temperature on forearm blood flow during exercise. Kolka MA, Stephenson LA. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1997;82:1079&#x2013;1083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9104842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of sex and menstrual cycle on skin sensory nerve contribution to local heating. MA ZT, SH CA, KI BM, NA PR, DE DE AT. https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC6886618/#:~:text=ML%20females%20exhibited%20a%20greater,hormones%20during%20the%20ML%20phase. Int J Exerc Sci. 2019;12:1265&#x2013;1279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6886618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31839845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Specific physiological responses in women with severe primary dysmenorrhea during the menstrual cycle. Park MK, Watanuki S. J Physiol Anthropol Appl Human Sci. 2005;24:601&#x2013;609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16377945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ovarian hormones modulate endothelin-1 receptor responses in young women. Sebzda KN, Kuczmarski AV, Pohlig RT, Lennon SL, Edwards DG, Wenner MM. Microcirculation. 2018;25:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7577781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29999581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luteal phase of the menstrual cycle increases sweating rate during exercise. Garcia AM, Lacerda MG, Fonseca IA, Reis FM, Rodrigues LO, Silami-Garcia E. Braz J Med Biol Res. 2006;39:1255&#x2013;1261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16981051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of menstrual cycle and physical training on heat loss responses during dynamic exercise at moderate intensity in a temperate environment. Kuwahara T, Inoue Y, Abe M, Sato Y, Kondo N. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2005;288:0&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15677525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of menstrual cycle phase on fluid regulation during walking exercise. Nose Y, Fujita K, Wada T, Nishimura K, Hakoda M. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32874109/ J Sports Sci Med. 2020;19:556&#x2013;563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7429427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32874109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of sex and menstrual cycle on sweating during isometric handgrip exercise and postexercise forearm occlusion. Okamoto Y, Amano T. Exp Physiol. 2021;106:1508&#x2013;1523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33899281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esophageal temperature threshold for sweating decreases before ovulation in premenopausal women. Stephenson LA, Kolka MA. J Appl Physiol (1985) 1999;86:22&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9887109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greater reduction of balance as a result of increased plantar fascia elasticity at ovulation during the menstrual cycle. Petrofsky J, Lee H. Tohoku J Exp Med. 2015;237:219&#x2013;226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26537843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Relationship of cutaneous moisture, sebum and ph changes of healthy skin with menstrual cycle. K&#xfc;&#xe7;&#xfc;kaydo&#x11f;an N, &#x15e;avk E, Uslu M, &#x15e;endur N, Karaman G, Demirkan S. Turkderm Turkish Arch Dermatol Venereol. 2020;54:90&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayrovitz HN. Analysis and Assessment of Cardiovascular Function. New York, NY: Springer; 1998. Assessment of human microvascular function; pp. 248&#x2013;273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessment of the microcirculation: Laser Doppler and transcutaneous oxygen. Mayrovitz HN. http://www.clinsoft.org/drmayrovitz/PAPERS-HNM-LINKED/1994_047a_Assessment%20of%20Microcirc.pdf J Vasc Technol. 1994;18:269&#x2013;275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skin tissue water and laser Doppler blood flow during a menstrual cycle. Mayrovitz HN, Brown-Cross D, Washington Z. Clin Physiol Funct Imaging. 2007;27:54&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17204039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steward K, Raja A. Statpearls [Internet] Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2023. Physiology, ovulation and basal body temperature.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Factors influencing skin aging and the important role of estrogens and selective estrogen receptor modulators (SERMs) Lephart ED, Naftolin F. Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol. 2022;15:1695&#x2013;1709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9397534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36017417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>