<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38877127</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Analysis of physical characteristics and mechanism of retarder to stratified cemented backfill.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>13711</StartPage><MedlinePgn>13711</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">13711</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-024-64507-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The stratified structural plane caused by stratified backfill will reduce the strength of backfill, and the introduction of retarder will make up for the defect. Three retarders, sodium tripoly-phosphate, citric acid and sucrose, were introduced. After determining the optimal dosage of retarder, they were added into the filling slurry with a ratio of lime to sand of 1:6 and a mass concentration of 75%. Based on the hydration reaction mechanism and damage mechanics theory of cement, the setting time test and uniaxial compressive strength test were carried out. With the help of scanning electron microscopy and X-ray diffraction, the influence mechanism of retarder on the physical characteristics of stratified cemented filling was investigated.The main research contents and achievements are as follows:. The results showed that the three retarding agents can delay the setting time of the cement filling slurry, and the retarding effect is sucrose&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;citric acid&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;sodium tripolyphosphate. The addition of retarder can improve the uniaxial compressive strength and integrity of stratified consolidated backfill, and the best filling interval time (FIT) is 12&#xa0;h. Appropriate addition of retarder will increase the amount of cement hydration products, make the structure of hydration products more dense, reduce the formation of stratified structural plane, and help to improve the strength of stratified cemented backfill.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ai</LastName><ForeName>Chunming</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Safety Science and Engineering, Liaoning Technical University, Huludao, 125000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Thermal Disaster and Prevention, Ministry of Education, Huludao, 125000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Anju</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Safety Science and Engineering, Liaoning Technical University, Huludao, 125000, China. 849119477@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Thermal Disaster and Prevention, Ministry of Education, Huludao, 125000, China. 849119477@qq.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Chao</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Norin Mining Limited, 12A Guang An Men Nan Jie, Beijing, 100053, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Tao</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Norin Mining Limited, 12A Guang An Men Nan Jie, Beijing, 100053, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2022-MS-395</GrantID><Agency>The Natural Science Foundation Program of Liaoning Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Physical characteristics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Retarder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stratified cemented backfill</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38877127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11178888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-024-64507-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-024-64507-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Li L, Aubertin M, Belem T. Formulation of a three dimensional analytical solution to evaluate stresse val time s in backfilled vertical narrow openings. Can. Geotech. J. 2005;42:1705&#x2013;1717. doi: 10.1139/t05-084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/t05-084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu AX, Yang Y, Cheng HY, et al. Status and prospects of paste technology in China. Chin. J. Eng. 2018;40(5):517&#x2013;525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang P, Li HQ, Li Y, et al. Stability analysis of backfilling in subsiding area and optimization of the stoping sequence. J. Rock Mech. Geotech. Eng. 2013;5:478&#x2013;485. doi: 10.1016/j.jrmge.2013.07.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jrmge.2013.07.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu AX, Li H, Cheng HY, et al. Status and prospects of researches on rheology of paste backfill using unclassified-tailings (Part 1): Concepts, characteristics and models. Chin. J. Eng. 2020;42:803&#x2013;813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao S, Du CF, Tan YY, et al. Mechanical model analysis of consolidated filling pillar using stage-delayed backfill in metal mines. Rock Soil Mech. 2015;36:2370&#x2013;2376.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin SH, Shao YJ, Wu AX, et al. Assessment of expansion and strength properties of sulfidic cemented paste backfill cored from deep underground stopes. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;23:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Fu JX, Song WD, et al. Mechanical behavior, acoustic emission properties and damage evolution of cemented paste backfill considering structural feature. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;261:119958&#x2013;119974. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YY, Zhou TT, Yu ZQ, et al. Study on the mechanical properties of layered cemented backfill under different curing ages. Min. Res. Dev. 2021;41:52&#x2013;55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Song WD, Tan YY, et al. Damage constitutive model and strength criterion of horizontal stratified cemented backfill. Rock Soil Mech. 2021;40:1731&#x2013;1739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang YN, Fu JX, Song WD, et al. Mechanical properties and crack evolution of int-erbedded cemented tailings backfill. Chin. J. Eng. 2020;42(10):1286&#x2013;1298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen HM, Wu AX, Jiao HZ, et al. Reduction effect of stope filling layering times on filling body streng. Modern Min. 2021;37(10):74&#x2013;78+83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasap T, Yilmaz E, Sari M, et al. Predicting long-term impact of cementitious mine fill considering sand as a copper-tailings substitution. Powder Technol. 2023;428:118887. doi: 10.1016/j.powtec.2023.118887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.powtec.2023.118887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guner NU, Yilmaz E, Sari M, et al. Cementitious backfill with partial replacement of Cu-rich mine tailings by sand: Rheological, mechanical and microstructural properties. Minerals. 2023;13(3):437. doi: 10.3390/min13030437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min13030437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao S, Song WD, Yilmaz E. Influence of structural factors on uniaxial compressive strength of cemented tailings backfill. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;174:190&#x2013;201. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.04.126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.04.126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao S, Song WD, Xue GL, et al. Tests of strength reduction of cemented tailings filling considering layering character. Min. Res. Dev. 2015;36:2869&#x2013;2876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu WB, Cao Y, Liu BH. Strength efficiency evaluation of cemented tailings backfill with different stratified structures. Eng. Struct. 2019;180:18&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2018.11.030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2018.11.030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sowoidnich T, Rachowski T, R&#xf6;&#xdf;ler C, et al. Calcium complexation and cluster formation as principal modes of action of polymers used as superplasticizer in cement systems. Cement Concrete Res. 2015;73:42&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2015.01.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2015.01.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong XM, Li QH. Properties and microstructure of polymer modified mortar based on different acrylate latexes. J. Chin. Ceramic Soc. 2009;37:107&#x2013;114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill JR, Plank J. Retardation of setting of plaster of paris by organic acids: Understanding the mechanism through molecular modeling. J. Computat. Chem. 2004;25:1438&#x2013;1448. doi: 10.1002/jcc.20070.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcc.20070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15224388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu X, Yu C, Ran QP, Liu JP. Retarding mechanism of hydroxy carboxylic acid retarder on cement hydration. J. Chinese Ceramic Soc. 2018;46:181&#x2013;186.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo PF, Yu YH, Huang YY. The retarding effect of different retarders and their influence on cement hydration. New Build. Mater. 2022;49:22&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu JG, Wang PM. Mechanism of regulation set of sucrose in portland cement. J. Chin. Ceramic Soc.. 1998;26:38&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang XP, Liu Y, Li L, et al. Effect of hydration heat inhibitors and retarders on cement monomine and cement hydration. New Build. Mater. 2022;49:76&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansen D, Neubauer J, Goetz-Neunhoeffer F, Haerzschel R, Hergeth WD. Change in reaction kinetics of a Portland cement caused by a superplasticizer&#x2014;Calculation of heat flow curves from XRD data. Cement Concrete Res. 2012;42:327&#x2013;332. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2011.10.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2011.10.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>