<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41156895</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>20</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Temperature-Dependent Effects of Hydroxyethyl Methyl Cellulose on Rheological Properties and Microstructural Evolution of Robotic Plastering Mortars.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4664</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma18204664</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Temperature-induced instability in early-age rheology poses a major challenge to the pumpability and application of robotic plastering mortars. This study systematically investigates the temperature-dependent effects of a high-viscosity (75,000 mPa&#xb7;s) hydroxyethyl methyl cellulose (HEMC) on the rheological properties and early microstructural evolution of mortars at 5 &#xb0;C, 20 &#xb0;C, and 40 &#xb0;C. Mortars with HEMC dosages from 0 to 0.25 wt% were tested using rheological measurements, ultrasonic pulse velocity (UPV), and complementary microstructural analyses (XRD, FTIR, and SEM-EDS). Results show that HEMC reduced the initial static yield stress while monotonically increasing plastic viscosity, with the thickening effect more pronounced at higher temperatures. Notably, at 40 &#xb0;C, the initial plastic viscosity of a 0.25% HEMC mix reached 14.4 Pa&#xb7;s, a 133% increase compared to the control group. HEMC also effectively retarded the time-dependent increase in yield stress and stabilized plastic viscosity, thereby mitigating the adverse influence of elevated temperature. UPV confirmed that HEMC delayed microstructural formation, in agreement with the observed retardation of hydration reactions. At 40 &#xb0;C, a 0.10% HEMC dosage postponed the percolation threshold from 67 min to 150 min, highlighting its strong retardation effect. Microstructural tests further revealed that HEMC delayed CH formation, refined C-S-H gels, and reduced the crystallinity of AFt, supporting the rheological and ultrasonic findings. A statistically significant, moderate-to-strong correlation (r = 0.88, R<sup>2</sup> = 0.77, <i>p</i> &lt; 0.001) was established between static yield stress and UPV, indicating that macroscopic rheological resistance responds to microstructural evolution. Based on these results, the recommended HEMC dosages to achieve stable rheological performance are 0.05-0.10% at 5 &#xb0;C, 0.10-0.15% at 20 &#xb0;C, and 0.15-0.20% at 40 &#xb0;C.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ling</LastName><ForeName>Guangjie</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 201804, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Hongbin</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Weibuild Technology Co., Ltd., Shanghai 200949, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Sifeng</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5909-9477</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Materials Science and Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai 201804, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Performance Evolution and Control for Engineering Structures (Ministry of Education), Tongji University, 1239, Siping Rd., Shanghai 200092, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydroxyethyl methyl cellulose</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rheology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">robotic plastering mortar</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">temperature</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ultrasonic pulse velocity</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Author Hongbin Yang was employed by the Shanghai Weibuild Technology Co., Ltd. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41156895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12565420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma18204664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma18204664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Xie L., Chen J., Chen M., Hu T., Liao H., Sun S., Chen J. Mortar Spraying and Plastering Integrated Robot for Wall Construction. Autom. Constr. 2024;165:105533. doi: 10.1016/j.autcon.2024.105533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autcon.2024.105533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z., Chen D., Eldosoky M.A., Ye Z., Jiang X., Liu Y., Ge S.S. Puttybot: A Sensorized Robot for Autonomous Putty Plastering. J. Field Robot. 2024;41:1744&#x2013;1764. doi: 10.1002/rob.22351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rob.22351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitterberger D., Ercan Jenny S., Vasey L., Lloret-Fritschi E., Aejmelaeus-Lindstr&#xf6;m P., Gramazio F., Kohler M. Interactive Robotic Plastering: Augmented Interactive Design and Fabrication for on-Site Robotic Plastering; Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems; New Orleans, LA, USA. 29 April&#x2013;5 May 2022; pp. 1&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petit J.-Y., Khayat K.H., Wirquin E. Coupled Effect of Time and Temperature on Variations of Yield Value of Highly Flowable Mortar. Cem. Concr. Res. 2006;36:832&#x2013;841. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2005.11.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2005.11.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghafoori N., Diawara H. Influence of Temperature on Fresh Performance of Self-Consolidating Concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2010;24:946&#x2013;955. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2009.11.023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2009.11.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petit J.-Y., Wirquin E., Khayat K.H. Effect of Temperature on the Rheology of Flowable Mortars. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2010;32:43&#x2013;53. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2009.10.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2009.10.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang T., Yuan Q., Zuo S., Yao H., Zhang K., Wang Y., Xie Y., Shi C. Physio-Chemical Effects on the Temperature-Dependent Elasticity of Cement Paste during Setting. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2022;134:104769. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng K., Ma K., Yang H., Long G., Xie Y., Zeng X., Tang Z., Usman I.U. Influence of Cellulose Ethers on Rheological Properties of Cementitious Materials: A Review. J. Build. Eng. 2024;95:110347. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2024.110347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.110347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D., Zhang Y., Xiao J., Shi J., Chen Y., Pang B., Wu M., Liu G., Yang Y. Study on Dynamic and Static Structural Build-up of Fresh Cement Paste with Limestone Powder Based on Structural Kinetics Model. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;305:124598. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Ren Q., Dai X., Tao Y., Zhang Y., Jiang Z., Van Tittelboom K., De Schutter G. A Potential Active Rheology Control Approach for 3D Printable Cement-Based Materials: Coupling of Temperature and Viscosity Modifiers. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2024;149:105496. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2024.105496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2024.105496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subramaniam K.V., Wang X. An Investigation of Microstructure Evolution in Cement Paste through Setting Using Ultrasonic and Rheological Measurements. Cem. Concr. Res. 2010;40:33&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2009.09.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2009.09.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojeda-Far&#xed;as O., Lootens D., H&#xe9;braud P. Build-up and Consolidation of an Attractive Network of Particles in Cement-Based Pastes. Cem. Concr. Res. 2024;183:107573. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2024.107573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2024.107573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S., Zhang G., Wang Z., Luo S., Huang T., Wu M. Long-Term Performance and Hydration of Cement Mortars with Hydroxyethyl Methyl Cellulose Cured at 5 &#xb0;C Low Temperature. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;307:124963. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dada H., Belaidi A.S.E., Soualhi H., Kadri E.-H., Benabed B. Influence of Temperature on the Rheological Behaviour of Eco-Mortar with Binary and Ternary Cementitious Blends of Natural Pozzolana and Marble Powder. Powder Technol. 2021;384:223&#x2013;235. doi: 10.1016/j.powtec.2021.02.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.powtec.2021.02.019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lothenbach B., Winnefeld F., Alder C., Wieland E., Lunk P. Effect of Temperature on the Pore Solution, Microstructure and Hydration Products of Portland Cement Pastes. Cem. Concr. Res. 2007;37:483&#x2013;491. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2006.11.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2006.11.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan J., Li X., Wang Z., Liu R., Zhang C., Zhu Z., Cheng B., Ma C., Chen M. Effect of Silica Fume and Hydroxyethyl Methyl Cellulose on the Properties of Cement-Sodium Silicate Grout at High Temperatures. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;409:134130. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bessaies-Bey H., Khayat K.H., Palacios M., Schmidt W., Roussel N. Viscosity Modifying Agents: Key Components of Advanced Cement-Based Materials with Adapted Rheology. Cem. Concr. Res. 2022;152:106646. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2021.106646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2021.106646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faiyas A.P.A., Erich S.J.F., Huinink H.P., Adan O.C.G., Nijland T.G. Effect of MHEC on Evaporation and Hydration Characteristics of Glue Mortar. Cem. Concr. Res. 2016;83:97&#x2013;103. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2016.01.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2016.01.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patural L., Marchal P., Govin A., Grosseau P., Ruot B., Dev&#xe8;s O. Cellulose Ethers Influence on Water Retention and Consistency in Cement-Based Mortars. Cem. Concr. Res. 2011;41:46&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2010.09.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2010.09.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brumaud C., Bessaies-Bey H., Mohler C., Baumann R., Schmitz M., Radler M., Roussel N. Cellulose Ethers and Water Retention. Cem. Concr. Res. 2013;53:176&#x2013;184. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2013.06.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2013.06.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marliere C., Mabrouk E., Lamblet M., Coussot P. How Water Retention in Porous Media with Cellulose Ethers Works. Cem. Concr. Res. 2012;42:1501&#x2013;1512. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2012.08.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2012.08.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;lichen D., Kainz J., Plank J. Working Mechanism of Methyl Hydroxyethyl Cellulose (MHEC) as Water Retention Agent. Cem. Concr. Res. 2012;42:953&#x2013;959. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2012.03.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2012.03.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brumaud C., Baumann R., Schmitz M., Radler M., Roussel N. Cellulose Ethers and Yield Stress of Cement Pastes. Cem. Concr. Res. 2014;55:14&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2013.06.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2013.06.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pourchez J., Peschard A., Grosseau P., Guyonnet R., Guilhot B., Vall&#xe9;e F. HPMC and HEMC Influence on Cement Hydration. Cem. Concr. Res. 2006;36:288&#x2013;294. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2005.08.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2005.08.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ou Z.H., Ma B.G., Jian S.W. Influence of Cellulose Ethers Molecular Parameters on Hydration Kinetics of Portland Cement at Early Ages. Constr. Build. Mater. 2012;33:78&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2012.01.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2012.01.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma B., Peng Y., Tan H., Jian S., Zhi Z., Guo Y., Qi H., Zhang T., He X. Effect of Hydroxypropyl-Methyl Cellulose Ether on Rheology of Cement Paste Plasticized by Polycarboxylate Superplasticizer. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;160:341&#x2013;350. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.11.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.11.010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen F.X., Leng Y., Zhang G.Z., Wei K., Jin L., Yin T.Y., Yu R. Revealing the Effect of Hydroxyethyl Methyl Cellulose Ether on Rheological Characteristics and Hydration Kinetics of Ultra-High Performance Concrete with High Thixotropy. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;457:139388. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.139388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.139388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pichniarczyk P., Niziurska M. Properties of Ceramic Tile Adhesives Modified by Different Viscosity Hydroxypropyl Methylcellulose. Constr. Build. Mater. 2015;77:227&#x2013;232. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.12.110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.12.110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu L., Liu T., Wu K., Yang Z., Wen Z., Zhang Z., Li H. Temperature-Dependent Water Retention and Bleeding of Fresh Cement-Based Materials with VEAs. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2022;130:104539. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim C., Song Y.H., Song Y., Seo J.H., Hwang D.S., Lee D.W. Adaptive Amphiphilic Interaction Mechanism of Hydroxypropyl Methylcellulose in Water. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2021;565:150535. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2021.150535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2021.150535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yim H.J., Bae Y.H., Jun Y. Hydration and Microstructural Characterization of Early-Age Cement Paste with Ultrasonic Wave Velocity and Electrical Resistivity Measurements. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;303:124508. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robeyst N., Grosse C.U., De Belie N. Measuring the Change in Ultrasonic P-Wave Energy Transmitted in Fresh Mortar with Additives to Monitor the Setting. Cem. Concr. Res. 2009;39:868&#x2013;875. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2009.06.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2009.06.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Z., Voigt T., Shah S.P. Rheometric and Ultrasonic Investigations of Viscoelastic Properties of Fresh Portland Cement Pastes. Cem. Concr. Res. 2006;36:278&#x2013;287. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2005.08.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2005.08.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Longlong H., Yan H., Huaicheng C., Yuli C., Peng L., Dongyu X. Ultrasonic Propagation Characteristics and Microstructure Analysis of Cement Paste Doped with Cellulose Ether. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;420:135653. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.135653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robeyst N., De Schutter G., Grosse C., De Belie N. Monitoring the Effect of Admixtures on Early-Age Concrete Behaviour by Ultrasonic, Calorimetric, Strength and Rheometer Measurements. Mag. Concr. Res. 2011;63:707&#x2013;721. doi: 10.1680/macr.2011.63.10.707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1680/macr.2011.63.10.707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye G., Lura P., Van Breugel K., Fraaij A.L.A. Study on the Development of the Microstructure in Cement-Based Materials by Means of Numerical Simulation and Ultrasonic Pulse Velocity Measurement. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2004;26:491&#x2013;497. doi: 10.1016/S0958-9465(03)00081-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0958-9465(03)00081-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Standardization Administration Common Portland Cement. State Administration for Market Regulation; Beijing, China: 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Standardization Administration Test Methods of Physical Property for Dry-Mix Mortar. General Administration of Quality Supervision, Inspection and Quarantine of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China; Beijing, China: 2013.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>