<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39734011</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1089-8611</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>155</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nitric oxide : biology and chemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nitric Oxide</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The impact of ciliary length on the mechanical response of osteocytes to fluid shear stress.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>11</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-11</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.niox.2024.12.003</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1089-8603(24)00156-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Osteocytes are crucial for detecting mechanical stimuli and translating them into biochemical responses within the bone. The primary cilium, a cellular 'antenna,' plays a vital role in this process. However, there is a lack of direct correlation between cilium length changes and osteocyte mechanosensitivity changes. This study aims to reveal the relationship between ciliary length and nitric oxide (NO) release in osteocytes to show how primary cilia may be involved in reducing osteocyte mechanosensitivity caused by microgravity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We used the MLO-Y4 cell line and primary osteoblasts to adjust the ciliary length using chloral hydrate (CH) for shortening and lithium ions (Li<sup>+</sup>) for elongation. We then examined the impact of varied ciliary lengths on osteocyte response to fluid shear stress, focusing on the PC1/PC2-Ca<sup>2+</sup>-NO signaling pathway. Co-culture systems assessed downstream effects on osteoblast function, including collagen secretion and mineralization.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We observed a significant correlation between ciliary length and osteocyte mechanosensitivity, with longer primary cilia enhancing Ca<sup>2+</sup> influx and NO release in response to fluid shear stress. However, contrary to expectations, calmodulin (CaM) expression did not increase with ciliary length, suggesting alternative pathways, such as PKC or Akt/PKB, may modulate p-eNOS activity. Co-cultured osteoblasts showed altered osteogenic functions regulated by osteocyte-derived signals influenced by primary cilia length.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our findings clarify the role of primary cilia length in modulating osteocyte mechanosensitivity and their influence on osteoblast function, highlighting a complex regulatory network that may not solely rely on CaM for NO release. These insights contribute to a deeper understanding of bone mechanotransduction and could have implications for developing therapeutic targets for osteocyte-related disorders.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024. Published by Elsevier Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ding</LastName><ForeName>Dong</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Infrastructures for Translational Medicine, Institute of Clinical Medicine, Peking Union Medical College Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences and Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, 100730, China; Key Laboratory of Biomechanics and Mechanobiology (Beihang University), Ministry of Education, Key Laboratory of Innovation and Transformation of Advanced Medical Devices, Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, National Medical Innovation Platform for Industry-Education Integration in Advanced Medical Devices (Interdiscipline of Medicine and Engineering), School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering, Beihang University, Beijing, 100191, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tian</LastName><ForeName>Ran</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Biomechanics and Mechanobiology (Beihang University), Ministry of Education, Key Laboratory of Innovation and Transformation of Advanced Medical Devices, Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, National Medical Innovation Platform for Industry-Education Integration in Advanced Medical Devices (Interdiscipline of Medicine and Engineering), School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering, Beihang University, Beijing, 100191, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Xiao</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Biomechanics and Mechanobiology (Beihang University), Ministry of Education, Key Laboratory of Innovation and Transformation of Advanced Medical Devices, Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, National Medical Innovation Platform for Industry-Education Integration in Advanced Medical Devices (Interdiscipline of Medicine and Engineering), School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering, Beihang University, Beijing, 100191, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Zhe</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Biomechanics and Mechanobiology (Beihang University), Ministry of Education, Key Laboratory of Innovation and Transformation of Advanced Medical Devices, Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, National Medical Innovation Platform for Industry-Education Integration in Advanced Medical Devices (Interdiscipline of Medicine and Engineering), School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering, Beihang University, Beijing, 100191, China; Hospital of Beihang University, Beijing, 100191, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jing</LastName><ForeName>Zhi-Cheng</ForeName><Initials>ZC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Guangdong Cardiovascular Institute, Guangdong Provincial People's Hospital Guangdong Academy of Medical Sciences, Southern Medical University. Guangdong Academy of Medical Sciences, Southern Medical University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Xin-Tong</ForeName><Initials>XT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Biomechanics and Mechanobiology (Beihang University), Ministry of Education, Key Laboratory of Innovation and Transformation of Advanced Medical Devices, Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, National Medical Innovation Platform for Industry-Education Integration in Advanced Medical Devices (Interdiscipline of Medicine and Engineering), School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering, Beihang University, Beijing, 100191, China. Electronic address: xintongw@buaa.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sun</LastName><ForeName>Lian-Wen</ForeName><Initials>LW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Biomechanics and Mechanobiology (Beihang University), Ministry of Education, Key Laboratory of Innovation and Transformation of Advanced Medical Devices, Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, National Medical Innovation Platform for Industry-Education Integration in Advanced Medical Devices (Interdiscipline of Medicine and Engineering), School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering, Beihang University, Beijing, 100191, China. Electronic address: sunlw@buaa.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Nitric Oxide</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9709307</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1089-8603</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>31C4KY9ESH</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009569">Nitric Oxide</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>SY7Q814VUP</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002118">Calcium</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn"><RefSource>Nitric Oxide. 2025 Dec;159:38-39. doi: 10.1016/j.niox.2025.09.001.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">40915202</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010011" MajorTopicYN="Y">Osteocytes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="N">cytology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002923" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cilia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009569" MajorTopicYN="N">Nitric Oxide</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013314" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stress, Mechanical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002460" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D040542" MajorTopicYN="N">Mechanotransduction, Cellular</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010006" MajorTopicYN="N">Osteoblasts</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002118" MajorTopicYN="N">Calcium</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bone homeostasis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mechanosensitivity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nitric oxide</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Osteocytes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Primary cilia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of interests Dong Ding, Ran Tian, Xiao Yang, Zhe Ren, Zhi-Cheng Jing, Xin-Tong Wu, and Lian-Wen Sun declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39734011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.niox.2024.12.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1089-8603(24)00156-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>