<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40835807</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2035</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>55</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effect of Heat Stress and Dehydration on Carbohydrate Use During Endurance Exercise: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2825</StartPage><EndPage>2847</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2825-2847</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40279-025-02294-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Carbohydrate metabolism during prolonged endurance exercise can be influenced by heat stress and dehydration. While heat exposure and dehydration have been shown to independently affect glycogen use and carbohydrate oxidation, their combined impact remains unclear. No previous review has systematically evaluated the effects of these factors on carbohydrate metabolism during prolonged endurance exercise or undertaken a meta-analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim was to systematically review the literature and meta-analyse the effects of heat stress (hot compared to temperate conditions) and dehydration (dehydrated compared to hydrated status) on (1) respiratory exchange ratio, (2) carbohydrate oxidation and (3) glycogen use.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses (PRISMA)-compliant systematic review with meta-analysis was completed ( https://osf.io/uq8n5 ). PubMed/MEDLINE and SportDiscus databases were searched for original articles (published up to November 2024) that assessed changes in (main outcomes) (1) respiratory exchange ratio, (2) carbohydrate oxidation or (3) glycogen use. The population included healthy, active, trained adults (&gt;&#x2009;18&#xa0;years). Interventions involved exercise in hot conditions compared to temperate conditions and/or dehydration compared to a hydrated state. The exercise duration was required to be&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;15&#xa0;min. Meta-analysis was performed using a random-effects model to calculate standardised mean differences (SMDs) between experimental conditions (hot compared to temperate conditions and/or dehydrated compared to hydrated statuses). Heterogeneity was assessed using &#x3c7;<sup>2</sup> and I<sup>2</sup> statistics, with significance set at P&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;0.05.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Fifty-one studies (502 participants; 31 females) were included. Carbohydrate oxidation (SMD 0.29, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.006) and glycogen use (SMD 0.78, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.006) were greater in hot conditions compared to temperate conditions. In a dehydrated state, carbohydrate oxidation (SMD 0.31, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.002) and glycogen use (SMD 0.62, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.003) were greater compared to in a hydrated state. Greater carbohydrate oxidation in a dehydrated compared to a hydrated state was observed in hot (SMD 0.37, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.001) but not in temperate conditions (SMD 0.27, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.199).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Carbohydrate utilisation increases during prolonged endurance exercise in hot conditions. Dehydration appears to increase carbohydrate use, especially when combined with heat stress; however, these effects are not consistently observed under temperate conditions. Consequently, dehydration does not appear to be the primary driver of elevated carbohydrate utilisation but may play a significant role by affecting thermoregulatory responses.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mougin</LastName><ForeName>Lo&#xef;s</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-9401-6080</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Exercise and Health Sciences, Loughborough University, Loughborough, Leicestershire, LE11 3TU, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Macrae</LastName><ForeName>Heather Z</ForeName><Initials>HZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Exercise and Health Sciences, Loughborough University, Loughborough, Leicestershire, LE11 3TU, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taylor</LastName><ForeName>Lee</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8483-7187</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Exercise and Health Sciences, Loughborough University, Loughborough, Leicestershire, LE11 3TU, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Exercise and Rehabilitation, Faculty of Health, University of Technology Sydney, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Human Performance Research Centre, University of Technology Sydney, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>James</LastName><ForeName>Lewis J</ForeName><Initials>LJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6514-5823</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Exercise and Health Sciences, Loughborough University, Loughborough, Leicestershire, LE11 3TU, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mears</LastName><ForeName>Stephen A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3941-9426</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Sport, Exercise and Health Sciences, Loughborough University, Loughborough, Leicestershire, LE11 3TU, UK. s.a.mears@lboro.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8412297</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0112-1642</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9005-79-2</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006003">Glycogen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003681" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dehydration</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010807" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physical Endurance</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050260" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carbohydrate Metabolism</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006003" MajorTopicYN="N">Glycogen</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006358" MajorTopicYN="N">Hot Temperature</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018869" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heat-Shock Response</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018882" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heat Stress Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Funding: LM is a doctoral researcher funded by a Vice-Chancellor's Fellowship at Loughborough University, with funding aligned to the Sports for Climate Action and Nature (SCAN) cluster. Conflict of interest: SAM has current/previous funding from Entrinsic Beverage Company LLP and Herbalife Europe Ltd and has received conference funding from Danone Nutricia and Unilever. LJJ has current/previous funding from Bunge Loders Croklaan B.V., Herbalife Europe Ltd, Bridge Farm Nurseries Ltd, Entrinsic Beverage Company LLP, Decathlon SA, PepsiCo Inc. and Volac International, has performed consultancy for The British Horseracing Authority, Lucozade, Ribena Suntory and PepsiCo Inc. and has received conference fees from PepsiCo Inc. and Danone Nutricia. In all cases, monies have been paid to LJJ's institution. LJJ is part of the National Institute for Health Research&#x2019;s Leicester Biomedical Research Centre, which is a partnership between University Hospitals of Leicester NHS Trust, Loughborough University, and the University of Leicester. The remaining authors have no conflicts of interest to declare. Data availability: Data are available on request from the corresponding author. Author contributions: LM, SAM, LJJ and LT designed the review; LM and HZM performed screening and study quality assessment; LM and HZM analysed the data with the help of SAM and LJJ; LM wrote the manuscript; LM, SAM, LJJ, LT and HZM reviewed the manuscript. All authors read and approved the final version. Ethics approval: Not applicable. Informed consent: Not applicable.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40835807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12559103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-025-02294-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40279-025-02294-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sawka MN, Leon LR, Montain SJ, Sonna LA. Integrated physiological mechanisms of exercise performance, adaptation, and maladaptation to heat stress. Compr Physiol. 2011;1:1883&#x2013;928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23733692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-alonso J, Crandall CG, Johnson JM. The cardiovascular challenge of exercising in the heat. J Physiol. 2008;586:45&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2375553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17855754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;riard JD, Caillaud C, Thompson MW. The role of aerobic fitness and exercise intensity on endurance performance in uncompensable heat stress conditions. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2012;112:1989&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21947407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantzios K, Ioannou LG, Panagiotaki ZOE, Ziaka S, P&#xe9;riard JD, Racinais S, Nybo L, Flouris AD. Effects of weather parameters on endurance running performance: discipline-specific analysis of 1258 races. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2022;54:153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8677617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34652333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Febbraio MA, Snow RJ, Stathis CG, Hargreaves M, Carey MF. Effect of heat stress on muscle energy metabolism during exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1994;77:2827&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7896628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Febbraio MA, Snow RJ, Hargreaves M, Stathis CG, Martin IK, Carey MF. Muscle metabolism during exercise and heat stress in trained men: effect of acclimation. J Appl Physiol. 1994;76:589&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8175568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fink WJ, Costill DL, Van Handel PJ. Leg muscle metabolism during exercise in the heat and cold. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1975;34:183&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1181181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young AJ, Sawka MN, Levine L, Cadarette BS, Pandolf KB. Skeletal muscle metabolism during exercise is influenced by heat acclimation. J Appl Physiol. 1985;59:1929&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4077800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Alonso J, Calbet JAL, Nielsen B. Metabolic and thermodynamic responses to dehydration-induced reductions in muscle blood flow in exercising humans. J Physiol. 1999;520:577&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2269598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10523424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hargreaves M, Angus D, Howlett K, Conus NM, Febbraio M. Effect of heat stress on glucose kinetics during exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1996;81:1594&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8904574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nybo L, Nielsen B. Middle cerebral artery blood velocity is reduced with hyperthermia during prolonged exercise in humans. J Physiol. 2001;534:279&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2278686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11433008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi K, Honda Y, Ogawa T, Kondo N, Nishiyasu T. Relationship between ventilatory response and body temperature during prolonged submaximal exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2006;100:414&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16239617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagnon DD, Perrier L, Dorman SC, Oddson B, Larivi&#xe8;re C, Serresse O. Ambient temperature influences metabolic substrate oxidation curves during running and cycling in healthy men. Eur J Sport Sci. 2020;20:90&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31079551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Alonso J, Calbet JAL, Nielsen B. Muscle blood flow is reduced with dehydration during prolonged exercise in humans. J Physiol. 1998;513:895&#x2013;905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2231307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9824726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Alonso J, Mora-Rodr&#xed;guez R, Below PR, Coyle EF. Dehydration markedly impairs cardiovascular function in hyperthermic endurance athletes during exercise. J Appl Physiol (1985). 1997;82:1229&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9104860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Alonso J, Mora-Rodriguez R, Below PR, Coyle EF. Dehydration reduces cardiac output and increases systemic and cutaneous vascular resistance during exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1995;79:1487&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8594004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hargreaves M, Dillo P, Angus D, Febbraio M. Effect of fluid ingestion on muscle metabolism during prolonged exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1996;80:363&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8847329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-El&#xed;as VE, Hamouti N, Ortega JF, Mora-Rodr&#xed;guez R. Hyperthermia, but not muscle water deficit, increases glycogen use during intense exercise. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2015;25(Suppl 1):126&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25943663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logan-Sprenger HM, Heigenhauser GJF, Killian KJ, Spriet LL. Effects of dehydration during cycling on skeletal muscle metabolism in females. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44:1949&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22543739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logan-Sprenger HM, Heigenhauser GJF, Jones GL, Spriet LL. Increase in skeletal-muscle glycogenolysis and perceived exertion with progressive dehydration during cycling in hydrated men. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2013;23:220&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23114793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logan-Sprenger HM, Heigenhauser GJF, Jones GL, Spriet LL. The effect of dehydration on muscle metabolism and time trial performance during prolonged cycling in males. Physiol Rep. 2015;3: e12483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4562569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26296770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funnell MP, Mears SA, Bergin-Taylor K, James LJ. Blinded and unblinded hypohydration similarly impair cycling time trial performance in the heat in trained cyclists. J Appl Physiol. 2019;126:870&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30629476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Febbraio MA. Alterations in energy metabolism during exercise and heat stress. Sports Med. 2001;31:47&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11219501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett S, Tiollier E, Owens DJ, Brocherie F, Louis JB. Implications of heat stress-induced metabolic alterations for endurance training. Int J Sports Med. 2024;45:422&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38401534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frayn KN. Calculation of substrate oxidation rates in vivo from gaseous exchange. J Appl Physiol Respir Environ Exerc Physiol. 1983;55:628&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6618956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarins ZA, Wallis GA, Faghihnia N, Johnson ML, Fattor JA, Horning MA, Brooks GA. Effects of endurance training on cardiorespiratory fitness and substrate partitioning in postmenopausal women. Metabolism. 2009;58:1338&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2728793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19573883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. Syst Rev. 2021;10:89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8008539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Torres O, Rodr&#xed;guez-Longobardo C, Escribano-Tabernero R, Fern&#xe1;ndez-El&#xed;as E. Hydration, hyperthermia, glycogen, and recovery: crucial factors in exercise performance&#x2014;a systematic review and meta-analysis. Nutrients. 2023;15:4442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10610078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37892517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Rosendal SP, Osborne MA, Fassett RG, Coombes JS. Guidelines for glycerol use in hyperhydration and rehydration associated with exercise. Sports Med. 2010;40:113&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20092365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jadad AR, Moore RA, Carroll D, Jenkinson C, Reynolds DJM, Gavaghan DJ, McQuay HJ. Assessing the quality of reports of randomized clinical trials: is blinding necessary? Control Clin Trials. 1996;17:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8721797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JPT, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. 2003;327:557&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lakens D. Calculating and reporting effect sizes to facilitate cumulative science: a practical primer for t-tests and ANOVAs. Front Psychol. 2013;4:62627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3840331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24324449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheuvront SN, Haymes EM. Ad libitum fluid intakes and thermoregulatory responses of female distance runners in three environments. J Sports Sci. 2001;19:845&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11695506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallowfield JL, Williams C, Booth J, Choo BH, Growns S. Effect of water ingestion on endurance capacity during prolonged running. J Sports Sci. 1996;14:497&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8981288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman MD, Snipe RMJ, Costa RJS. Ad libitum drinking adequately supports hydration during 2 h of running in different ambient temperatures. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2018;118:2687&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30267225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoeberlein MI, Frisiras CE, Coffman KE. The effect of heat on lung diffusing capacity for carbon monoxide (DLCO) during cycling exercise. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2024;124:469&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37548661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster J, Balmain BN, Wilhite DP, Watso JC, Babb TG, Cramer MN, BelvaL LN, Crandall CG. Inhibiting regional sweat evaporation modifies the ventilatory response to exercise: interactions between core and skin temperature. J Appl Physiol. 2023;134:1011&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10110718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36892886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mora-Rodriguez R, Moreno-Caba&#xf1;as A, Alvarez-Jimenez L, Mora-Gonzalez D, Ortega JF, Morales-Palomo F. A bout of aerobic exercise in the heat increases carbohydrate use but does not enhance the disposal of an oral glucose load, in healthy active individuals. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2024;326:E648&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38568152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young AJ, Sawka MN, Levine L, Burgoon PW, Latzka WA, Gonzalez RR, Pandolf KB. Metabolic and thermal adaptations from endurance training in hot or cold water. J Appl Physiol (1985). 1995;78:793&#x2013;801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7775320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casa DJ, Maresh CM, Armstrong LE, Kavouras SA, Herrera JA, Hacker FT, Keith NR, Elliott TA. Intravenous versus oral rehydration during a brief period: responses to subsequent exercise in the heat. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32:124&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10647539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merry TL, Ainslie PN, Cotter JD. Effects of aerobic fitness on hypohydration-induced physiological strain and exercise impairment. Acta Physiol (Oxf). 2010;198:179&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19807723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy BD, Green HJ, Burnett M. Prolonged exercise after diuretic-induced hypohydration: effects on substrate turnover and oxidation. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2000;279:E1383&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11093927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James LJ, Moss J, Henry J, Papadopoulou C, Mears SA. Hypohydration impairs endurance performance: a blinded study. Physiol Rep. 2017;5: e13315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5492205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28637708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolny DG. Lemon PWR (1988) Effect of ambient temperature on protein breakdown during prolonged exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1985;64:550&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3372413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnett A, Maughan RJ. Response of unacclimatized males to repeated weekly bouts of exercise in the heat. Br J Sports Med. 1993;27:39&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1332106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8457812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snow R, Febbraio M, Carey M, Hargreaves M. Heat stress increases ammonia accumulation during exercise in humans. Exp Physiol. 1993;78:847&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8311952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen B, Kroug P. Optimal fluid replacement during long-lasting exercise in 18C and 32C ambient temperature. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 1994;4:173&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galloway SDR, Maughan RJ. Effects of ambient temperature on the capacity to perform prolonged cycle exercise in man. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1997;29:1240&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9309637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marino FE, Mbambo Z, Kortekaas E, Wilson G, Lambert MI, Noakes TD, Dennis SC. Influence of ambient temperature on plasma ammonia and lactate accumulation during prolonged submaximal and self-paced running. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2001;86:71&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11820326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jentjens RLPG, Wagenmakers AJM, Jeukendrup A. Heat stress increases muscle glycogen use but reduces the oxidation of ingested carbohydrates during exercise. J Appl Physiol. 2002;92:1562&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11896023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamashita Y, Kaya M, Koyama K, Tsujita J, Hori S. Decreased energy expenditure during prolonged sub-maximal exercise in a warm environment. Eur J Sport Sci. 2005;5:153&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hettinga FJ, De Koning JJ, de Vrijer A, W&#xfc;st RCI, Daanen HAM, Foster C. The effect of ambient temperature on gross-efficiency in cycling. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2007;101:465&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2039810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17661069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shorten AL, Wallman KE, Guelfi KJ. Acute effect of environmental temperature during exercise on subsequent energy intake in active men. Am J Clin Nutr. 2009;90:1215&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19793848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Hearn K, Tingelstad HC, Blondin D, Tang V, Filion LG, Haman F. Heat exposure increases circulating fatty acids but not lipid oxidation at rest and during exercise. J Therm Biol. 2016;55:39&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26724196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins CW, Shute RJ, Heesch MWS, Slivka DR. The effect of environmental temperature on exercise-dependent release of brain-derived neurotrophic factor. Temperature. 2017;4:305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5605157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28944272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maunder ED, Plews DJ, Merien F, Kilding AE. Exercise intensity regulates the effect of heat stress on substrate oxidation rates during exercise. Eur J Sport Sci. 2020;20:935&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31566098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosbrook P, Sweet D, Qiao JB, Looney DP, Margolis LM, Hostler D, Pryor RR, Pryor JL. Heat stress increases carbohydrate oxidation rates and oxygen uptake during prolonged load carriage exercise. Temperature. 2024;11:170&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11152092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38846526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh RM, Noakes TD, Hawley JA, Dennis SC. Impaired high-intensity cycling performance time at low levels of dehydration. Int J Sports Med. 1994;15:392&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8002117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fritzsche RG, Switzer TW, Hodgkinson BJ, Lee SH, Martin JC, Coyle EF. Water and carbohydrate ingestion during prolonged exercise increase maximal neuromuscular power. J Appl Physiol. 2000;88:730&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10658044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vallier JM, Grego F, Basset F, Lepers R, Bernard T, Brisswalter J. Effect of fluid ingestion on neuromuscular function during prolonged cycling exercise. Br J Sports Med. 2005;39: e17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1725175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15793075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert TR, Martin DT, Bullock N, Mujika I, Quod MJ, Farthing LA, Burke LM, Withers RT. Influence of hydration status on thermoregulation and cycling hill climbing. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39:323&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17277597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Coso J, Estevez E, Mora-Rodriguez R. Caffeine effects on short-term performance during prolonged exercise in the heat. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2008;40:744&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18317369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagnon D, Lynn AG, Binder K, Boushel RC, Kenny GP. Mean arterial pressure following prolonged exercise in the heat: influence of training status and fluid replacement. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2012;22:e99&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22830505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly PJ, Guelfi KJ, Wallman KE, Fairchild TJ. Mild dehydration does not reduce postexercise appetite or energy intake. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2012;44:516&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21857372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campa F, Piras A, Raffi M, Trof&#xe8; A, Perazzolo M, Mascherini G, Toselli S. The effects of dehydration on metabolic and neuromuscular functionality during cycling. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17:1161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7068562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32059577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funnell MP, Embleton D, Morris T, Macrae HZ, Hart N, Mazzotta T, Lockyer W, Juett LA, Mears SA, James LJ. Exercise-induced hypohydration impairs 3 km treadmill-running performance in temperate conditions. J Sports Sci. 2023;41:1171&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37733070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maxwell NS, Gardner F, Nimmo MA. Intermittent running: muscle metabolism in the heat and effect of hypohydration. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1999;31:675&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10331887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Febbraio MA, Carey MF, Snow RJ, Stathis CG, Hargreaves M. Influence of elevated muscle temperature on metabolism during intense, dynamic exercise. Am J Physiol. 1996;271:R1251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8945960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King DS, Costill DL, Fink WJ, Hargreaves M, Fielding RA. Muscle metabolism during exercise in the heat in unacclimatized and acclimatized humans. J Appl Physiol. 1985;59:1350&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4066564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirwan JP, Costill DL, Kuipers H, Burrell MJ, Fink WJ, Kovaleski JE, Fielding RA. Substrate utilization in leg muscle of men after heat acclimation. J Appl Physiol. 1987;63:31&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3624132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koz&#x142;owski S, Brzezi&#x144;ska Z, Kruk B, Kaciuba-U&#x15b;ci&#x142;ko H, Greenleaf JE, Nazar K. Exercise hyperthermia as a factor limiting physical performance: temperature effect on muscle metabolism. J Appl. 1985;59:766&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4055565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowell LB. Human cardiovascular adjustments to exercise and thermal stress. Physiol Rev. 1974;54:75&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4587247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen B, Savard G, Richter EA, Hargreaves M, Saltin B. Muscle blood flow and muscle metabolism during exercise and heat stress. J Appl Physiol. 1990;69:1040&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2246151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen B, Hales JR, Strange S, Christensen NJ, Warberg J, Saltin B. Human circulatory and thermoregulatory adaptations with heat acclimation and exercise in a hot, dry environment. J Physiol. 1993;460:467&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1175224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8487204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark MG, Colquhoun EQ, Rattigan S, Dora KA, Eldershaw TPD, Hall JL, Ye J. Vascular and endocrine control of muscle metabolism. Am J Physiol. 1995;268:E797-812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7762631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galbo H. The hormonal response to exercise. Proc Nutr Soc. 1985;44:257&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3931084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter EA, Ruderman NB, Gavras H. Muscle glycogenolysis during exercise: dual control by epinephrine and contractions. Am J Physiol. 1982;242:E25-32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7058885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charoensap T, Kilding AE, Maunder E. Carbohydrate, but not fat, oxidation is reduced during moderate-intensity exercise performed in 33 vs. 18 &#xb0;C at matched heart rates. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2023;123:2073&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10193330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37199760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hargreaves M, Febbraio M. Limits to exercise performance in the heat. Int J Sports Med. 1998;19:S115&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9694414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howlett K, Galbo H, Lorentsen J, Bergeron R, Zimmerman-Belsing T, B&#xfc;low J, Feldt-Rasmussen U, Kj&#xe6;r M. Effect of adrenaline on glucose kinetics during exercise in adrenalectomised humans. J Physiol. 1999;519:911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2269528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10457100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howlett K, Febbraio M, Hargreaves M. Glucose production during strenuous exercise in humans: role of epinephrine. Am J Physiol. 1999;276:E1130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10362627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaspelkis BB, Scroop GC, Wilmore KM, Ivy JL. Carbohydrate metabolism during exercise in hot and thermoneutral environments. Int J Sports Med. 1993;14:13&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8440539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;ussinger D. The role of cellular hydration in the regulation of cell function. Biochem J. 1996;313(Pt 3):697&#x2013;710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1216967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8611144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang F, Stehle T, H&#xe4;ussinger D. Water, K+, H+, lactate and glucose fluxes during cell volume regulation in perfused rat liver. Pflugers Arch. 1989;413:209&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2717371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graf J, Haddad P, Haeussinger D, Lang F. Cell volume regulation in liver. Ren Physiol Biochem. 1988;11:202&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3074399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbiss CR, Burnett A, Nosaka K, Green JP, Foster JK, Laursen PB. Effect of hot versus cold climates on power output, muscle activation, and perceived fatigue during a dynamic 100-km cycling trial. J Sports Sci. 2010;28:117&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20391088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neufer PD, Young AJ, Sawka MN. Gastric emptying during exercise: effects of heat stress and hypohydration. Eur J Appl Physiol Occup Physiol. 1989;58:433&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2920721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen MD, Kregel KC, Tim Wall P, Gisolfi CV. Effects of ingesting carbohydrate beverages during exercise in the heat. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1986;18:568&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3773674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehrer NJ, Beckers EJ, Brouns F, Ten HF, Saris WHM. Effects of dehydration on gastric emptying and gastrointestinal distress while running. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1990;22:790&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2287256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>