<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39388227</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1462-2920</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Environmental microbiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Environ Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Genome-wide differentiation corresponds to climatic niches in two species of lichen-forming fungi.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e16703</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e16703</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1462-2920.16703</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Lichens can withstand fluctuating environmental conditions such as hydration-desiccation cycles. Many species distribute across climate zones, suggesting population-level adaptations to conditions such as freezing and drought. Here, we aim to understand how climate affects population genomic patterns in lichenized fungi. We analysed population structure along elevational gradients in closely related Umbilicaria phaea (North American; two gradients) and Umbilicaria pustulata (European; three gradients). All gradients showed clear genomic breaks splitting populations into low-elevation (Mediterranean zone) and high-elevation (cold temperate zone). A total of 3301 SNPs in U. phaea and 138 SNPs in U. pustulata were driven to fixation between the two ends of the gradients. The difference between the species is likely due to differences in recombination rate: the sexually reproducing U. phaea has a higher recombination rate than the primarily asexually reproducing U. pustulata. Cline analysis revealed allele frequency transitions along all gradients at approximately 0&#xb0;C, coinciding with the transition between the Mediterranean and cold temperate zones, suggesting freezing is a strong driver of population differentiation. Genomic scans further confirmed temperature-related selection targets. Both species showed similar differentiation patterns overall, but different selected alleles indicate convergent adaptation to freezing. Our results enrich our knowledge of fungal genomic functions related to temperature and climate, fungal population genomics, and species responses to environmental heterogeneity.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Author(s). Environmental Microbiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wong</LastName><ForeName>Edgar L Y</ForeName><Initials>ELY</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0203-2458</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Ecology, Evolution and Diversity, Goethe University Frankfurt, Frankfurt am Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Senckenberg Biodiversity and Climate Research Centre, Frankfurt am Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LOEWE Centre for Translational Biodiversity Genomics (LOEWE-TBG), Frankfurt am Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Valim</LastName><ForeName>Henrique F</ForeName><Initials>HF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Ecology, Evolution and Diversity, Goethe University Frankfurt, Frankfurt am Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Senckenberg Biodiversity and Climate Research Centre, Frankfurt am Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LOEWE Centre for Translational Biodiversity Genomics (LOEWE-TBG), Frankfurt am Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schmitt</LastName><ForeName>Imke</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Ecology, Evolution and Diversity, Goethe University Frankfurt, Frankfurt am Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Senckenberg Biodiversity and Climate Research Centre, Frankfurt am Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LOEWE Centre for Translational Biodiversity Genomics (LOEWE-TBG), Frankfurt am Main, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>LOEWE/1/10/519/03/03.001(0014)/52</GrantID><Agency>Hessen State Ministry of Higher Education, Research and the Arts (HMWK) (LOEWE/1/10/519/03/03.001(0014)/52) (through LOEWE-Centre for Translational Biodiversity Genomics</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Environ Microbiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100883692</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1462-2912</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008011" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lichens</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016681" MajorTopicYN="Y">Genome, Fungal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020641" MajorTopicYN="Y">Polymorphism, Single Nucleotide</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002980" MajorTopicYN="Y">Climate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001203" MajorTopicYN="N">Ascomycota</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>22</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39388227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1462-2920.16703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Adrion, J.R., Galloway, J.G. &amp; Kern, A.D. (2020) Predicting the landscape of recombination using deep learning. Molecular Biology and Evolution, 37, 1790&#x2013;1808.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agrawal, A.F. &amp; Hartfield, M. (2016) Coalescence with background and balancing selection in systems with bi&#x2010; and uniparental reproduction: contrasting partial asexuality and selfing. Genetics, 202, 313&#x2013;326.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alachiotis, N. &amp; Pavlidis, P. (2018) RAiSD detects positive selection based on multiple signatures of a selective sweep and SNP vectors. Communications Biology, 1, 79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almaguer Ch&#xe1;vez, M. (2022) Thermotolerance and adaptation to climate change. In: The impact of climate change on fungal diseases. Cham: Springer International Publishing, pp. 37&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almer, J., Resl, P., Gudmundsson, H., Warshan, D., Andr&#xe9;sson, &#xd3;.S. &amp; Werth, S. (2023) Symbiont&#x2010;specific responses to environmental cues in a threesome lichen symbiosis. Molecular Ecology, 32, 1045&#x2013;1061.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong, R.A. (2017) Adaptation of lichens to extreme conditions. In: Plant adaptation strategies in changing environment. Singapore: Springer Singapore, pp. 1&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atkins, K.E. &amp; Travis, J.M.J. (2010) Local adaptation and the evolution of species' ranges under climate change. Journal of Theoretical Biology, 266, 449&#x2013;457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barreno, E. (1991) Phytogeography of terricolous lichens in the Iberian Peninsula and the Canary Islands. Bot Chron, 10, 199&#x2013;210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates, O.K. &amp; Bertelsmeier, C. (2021) Climatic niche shifts in introduced species. Current Biology, 31, R1252&#x2013;R1266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bengtsson, B.O. (2003) Genetic variation in organisms with sexual and asexual reproduction. Journal of Evolutionary Biology, 16, 189&#x2013;199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolger, A., Lohse, M. &amp; Usadel, B. (2014) Trimmomatic: a flexible trimmer for Illumina sequence data. Bioinformatics, 30, 2114&#x2013;2120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casano, L.M., Del Campo, E.M., Garc&#xed;a&#x2010;Breijo, F.J., Reig&#x2010;Armi&#xf1;ana, J., Gasulla, F., Del Hoyo, A. et al. (2011) Two Trebouxia algae with different physiological performances are ever&#x2010;present in lichen thalli of Ramalina farinacea. Coexistence versus competition? Environmental Microbiology, 13, 806&#x2013;818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavender&#x2010;Bares, J., Cortes, P., Rambal, S., Joffre, R., Miles, B. &amp; Rocheteau, A. (2005) Summer and winter sensitivity of leaves and xylem to minimum freezing temperatures: a comparison of co&#x2010;occurring Mediterranean oaks that differ in leaf lifespan. The New Phytologist, 168, 597&#x2013;612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y., Yang, X., Zhang, L., Wu, Q., Li, S., Gou, J. et al. (2023) Tryptophan&#x2010;centered metabolic alterations coincides with lipid&#x2010;mediated fungal response to cold stress. Heliyon, 9, e13066.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chrismas, N., Tindall&#x2010;Jones, B., Jenkins, H., Harley, J., Bird, K. &amp; Cunliffe, M. (2024) Metatranscriptomics reveals diversity of symbiotic interaction and mechanisms of carbon exchange in the marine cyanolichen Lichina pygmaea. The New Phytologist, 241, 2243&#x2013;2257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper, T.F. (2007) Recombination speeds adaptation by reducing competition between beneficial mutations in populations of Escherichia coli. PLoS Biology, 5, e225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coxson, D.S. &amp; Kershaw, K.A. (2011) The ecology of Rhizocarpon superficielle. I. The rock surface boundary&#x2010;layer microclimate. Canadian Journal of Botan, 61, 3009&#x2013;3018. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1139/b83-338</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cubero, O.F. &amp; Crespo, A. (2002) Isolation of nucleic acids from lichens. In: Protocols in lichenology. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer, pp. 381&#x2013;391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dal Grande, F., Jamilloux, V., Choisne, N., Calchera, A., Rolshausen, G., Petersen, M. et al. (2021) Transposable elements in the genome of the lichen&#x2010;forming fungus Umbilicaria pustulata and their distribution in different climate zones along elevation. Biology, 11, 24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dal Grande, F., Sharma, R., Meiser, A., Rolshausen, G., B&#xfc;del, B., Mishra, B. et al. (2017) Adaptive differentiation coincides with local bioclimatic conditions along an elevational cline in populations of a lichen&#x2010;forming fungus. BMC Evolutionary Biology, 17, 93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danecek, P., Auton, A., Abecasis, G., Albers, C.A., Banks, E., DePristo, M.A. et al. (2011) The variant call format and VCFtools. Bioinformatics, 27, 2156&#x2013;2158.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danecek, P., Bonfield, J.K., Liddle, J., Marshall, J., Ohan, V., Pollard, M.O. et al. (2021) Twelve years of SAMtools and BCFtools. GigaScience, 10, giab008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dastogeer, K.M.G., Zahan, M.I., Rhaman, M.S., Sarker, M.S.A. &amp; Chakraborty, A. (2022) Microbe&#x2010;mediated thermotolerance in plants and pertinent mechanisms&#x2014;a meta&#x2010;analysis and review. Frontiers in Microbiology, 13, 833566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davydov, E.A., Per&#x161;oh, D. &amp; Rambold, G. (2017) Umbilicariaceae (lichenized Ascomycota) &#x2013; trait evolution and a new generic concept. Taxon, 66, 1282&#x2013;1303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Maayer, P., Anderson, D., Cary, C. &amp; Cowan, D.A. (2014) Some like it cold: understanding the survival strategies of psychrophiles. EMBO Reports, 15, 508&#x2013;517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vallavieille&#x2010;Pope, C., Bahri, B., Leconte, M., Zurfluh, O., Belaid, Y., Maghrebi, E. et al. (2018) Thermal generalist behaviour of invasive Puccinia striiformis f. sp. tritici strains under current and future climate conditions. Plant Pathology, 67, 1307&#x2013;1320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Den Bakker, H.C., Vankuren, N.W., Morton, J.B. &amp; Pawlowska, T.E. (2010) Clonality and recombination in the life history of an asexual arbuscular mycorrhizal fungus. Molecular Biology and Evolution, 27, 2474&#x2013;2486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derryberry, E.P., Derryberry, G.E., Maley, J.M. &amp; Brumfield, R.T. (2013) hzar: hybrid zone analysis using an R software package. Molecular Ecology Resources, 14, 652&#x2013;663.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai, M.M. &amp; Fisher, D.S. (2007) Beneficial mutation&#x2013;selection balance and the effect of linkage on positive selection. Genetics, 176, 1759&#x2013;1798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dettman, J.R., Sirjusingh, C., Kohn, L.M. &amp; Anderson, J.B. (2007) Incipient speciation by divergent adaptation and antagonistic epistasis in yeast. Nature, 447, 585&#x2013;588.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drenth, A., McTaggart, A.R. &amp; Wingfield, B.D. (2019) Fungal clones win the battle, but recombination wins the war. IMA Fungus, 10, 1&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duran, R., Cary, J.W. &amp; Calvo, A.M. (2010) Role of the osmotic stress regulatory pathway in morphogenesis and secondary metabolism in filamentous fungi. Toxins, 2, 381.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards, C., Canfield, J., Copes, N., Brito, A., Rehan, M., Lipps, D. et al. (2015) Mechanisms of amino acid&#x2010;mediated lifespan extension in Caenorhabditis elegans. BMC Genetics, 16, 1&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellison, C.E., Hall, C., Kowbel, D., Welch, J., Brem, R.B., Glass, N.L. et al. (2011) Population genomics and local adaptation in wild isolates of a model microbial eukaryote. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 108, 2831&#x2013;2836.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eufemio, R.J., De Almeida Ribeiro, I., Sformo, T.L., Laursen, G.A., Molinero, V., Fr&#xf6;hlich&#x2010;Nowoisky, J. et al. (2023) Lichen species across Alaska produce highly active and stable ice nucleators. Biogeosciences, 20, 2805&#x2013;2812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez&#x2010;Mendoza, F., Domaschke, S., Garc&#xed;a, M.A., Jordan, P., Mart&#xed;n, M.P. &amp; Printzen, C. (2011) Population structure of mycobionts and photobionts of the widespread lichen Cetraria aculeata. Molecular Ecology, 20, 1208&#x2013;1232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerrish, P.J. &amp; Lenski, R.E. (1998) The fate of competing beneficial mutations in an asexual population. Genetica, 102, 127&#x2013;144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godinho, C.P., Costa, R. &amp; S&#xe1;&#x2010;Correia, I. (2021) The ABC transporter Pdr18 is required for yeast thermotolerance due to its role in ergosterol transport and plasma membrane properties. Environmental Microbiology, 23, 69&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goertz, A., Zuehlke, S., Spiteller, M., Steiner, U., Dehne, H.W., Waalwijk, C. et al. (2010) Fusarium species and mycotoxin profiles on commercial maize hybrids in Germany. European Journal of Plant Pathology, 128, 101&#x2013;111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez, M., P&#xe9;rez&#x2010;Gallardo, R.V., S&#xe1;nchez, L.A., D&#xed;az&#x2010;P&#xe9;rez, A.L., Cort&#xe9;s&#x2010;Rojo, C., Carmen, V.M. et al. (2014) Malfunctioning of the iron&#x2013;sulfur cluster assembly machinery in Saccharomyces cerevisiae produces oxidative stress via an iron&#x2010;dependent mechanism, causing dysfunction in respiratory complexes. PLoS One, 9, 111585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunde&#x2010;Cimerman, N., Sonjak, S., Zalar, P., Frisvad, J.C., Diderichsen, B. &amp; Plemenita&#x161;, A. (2003) Extremophilic fungi in arctic ice: a relationship between adaptation to low temperature and water activity. Physics and Chemistry of the Earth Parts A/B/C, 28, 1273&#x2013;1278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe1;jek, J., Bart&#xe1;k, M. &amp; Dubov&#xe1;, J. (2006) Inhibition of photosynthetic processes in foliose lichens induced by temperature and osmotic stress. Biologia Plantarum, 50, 624&#x2013;634.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;llfors, M.H., Liao, J., Dzurisin, J., Grundel, R., Hyv&#xe4;rinen, M., Towle, K. et al. (2016) Addressing potential local adaptation in species distribution models: implications for conservation under climate change. Ecological Applications, 26, 1154&#x2013;1169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hestmark, G. (1992) Sex, size, competition and escape: strategies of reproduction and dispersal in Lasallia pustulata (Umbilicariaceae, ascomycetes). Oecologia, 92, 305&#x2013;312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hestmark, G. (2004) Umbilicaria. In: Nash III, T., Ryan, B.D., Diederich, P., Gries, C., &amp; Bungartz, F. (eds.): Lichen Flora of the Greater Sonoran Desert Region. Tempe, Arizona. Lichens Unlimited. Arizona State University. Vol. 2: 548&#x2010;556.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hijmans, R.J., Cameron, S.E., Parra, J.L., Jones, P.G. &amp; Jarvis, A. (2005) Very high resolution interpolated climate surfaces for global land areas. International Journal of Climatology, 25, 1965&#x2013;1978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann, A.A. &amp; Sgr&#xf3;, C.M. (2011) Climate change and evolutionary adaptation. Nature, 470, 479&#x2013;485.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honegger, R. (2003) Functional aspects of the lichen. Symbiosis, 42, 553&#x2013;578. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.pp42060191003005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu, X., Zhang, Y.J., Xiao, G.H., Zheng, P., Xia, Y.L., Zhang, X.Y. et al. (2013) Genome survey uncovers the secrets of sex and lifestyle in caterpillar fungus. Chinese Science Bulletin, 58, 2846&#x2013;2854.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inouye, M. &amp; Phadtare, S. (2014) Cold&#x2010;shock response and adaptation to near&#x2010;freezing temperature in cold&#x2010;adapted yeasts. In: Cold&#x2010;adapted yeasts: biodiversity, adaptation strategies and biotechnological significance. Berlin Heidelberg: Springer&#x2010;Verlag, pp. 243&#x2013;257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandror, O., Bretschneider, N., Kreydin, E., Cavalieri, D. &amp; Goldberg, A.L. (2004) Yeast adapt to near&#x2010;freezing temperatures by STRE/Msn2,4&#x2010;dependent induction of trehalose synthesis and certain molecular chaperones. Molecular Cell, 13, 771&#x2013;781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kappen, L. (1993) Plant activity under snow and ice, with particular reference to lichens. Arctic, 46, 297&#x2013;302.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kappen, L., Schroeter, B., Hestmark, G. &amp; Winkler, J.B. (1996) Field measurements of photosynthesis of Umbilicarious lichens in winter. Botanica Acta: Journal of the German Botanical Society, 109, 292&#x2013;298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kappen, L., Schroeter, B., Scheidegger, C., Sommerkorn, M. &amp; Hestmark, G. (1996) Cold resistance and metabolic activity of lichens below 0&#xb0;C. Advances in Space Research, 18, 119&#x2013;128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kieft, T.L. &amp; Ahmadjian, V. (1989) Biological ice nucleation activity in lichen mycobionts and photobionts. Lichenol, 21, 355&#x2013;362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kieft, T.L. &amp; Lindow, S. (1988) Ice nucleation activity in lichens. Applied and Environmental Microbiology, 54, 1678&#x2013;1681.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kieft, T.L. &amp; Ruscetti, T. (1990) Characterization of biological ice nuclei from a lichen. Journal of Bacteriology, 172, 3519&#x2013;3523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kofler, R., Pandey, R. &amp; Schl&#xf6;tterer, C. (2011) PoPoolation2: identifying differentiation between populations using sequencing of pooled DNA samples (Pool&#x2010;Seq). Bioinformatics, 27, 3435&#x2013;3436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;rner, C. (2007) The use of &#x201c;altitude&#x201d; in ecological research. Trends in Ecology &amp; Evolution, 22, 569&#x2013;574.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korunes, K. &amp; Samuk, K. (2021) pixy: unbiased estimation of nucleotide diversity and divergence in the presence of missing data. Molecular Ecology Resources, 21, 1359&#x2013;1368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraus, P.R. &amp; Heitman, J. (2003) Coping with stress: calmodulin and calcineurin in model and pathogenic fungi. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 311, 1151&#x2013;1157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lange, O.L., Kilian, E. &amp; Ziegler, H. (1986) Water vapor uptake and photosynthesis of lichens: performance differences in species with green and blue&#x2010;green algae as phycobionts. Oecologia, 71, 104&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lendenmann, M.H., Croll, D., Palma&#x2010;Guerrero, J., Stewart, E.L. &amp; Mcdonald, B.A. (2016) QTL mapping of temperature sensitivity reveals candidate genes for thermal adaptation and growth morphology in the plant pathogenic fungus Zymoseptoria tritici. Hered 2016, 1164(116), 384&#x2013;394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, H. &amp; Durbin, R. (2009) Fast and accurate short read alignment with burrows&#x2013;wheeler transform. Bioinformatics, 25, 1754&#x2013;1760.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins, L., Knuesting, J., Bariat, L., Dard, A., Freibert, S.A., Marchand, C.H. et al. (2020) Redox modification of the iron&#x2010;sulfur glutaredoxin GRXS17 activates holdase activity and protects plants from heat stress. Plant Physiology, 184, 676&#x2013;692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattoon, E.R., Casadevall, A. &amp; Cordero, R.J. (2021) Beat the heat: correlates, compounds, and mechanisms involved in fungal thermotolerance. Fungal Biology Reviews, 36, 60&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mboup, M., Bahri, B., Leconte, M., De Vallavieille&#x2010;Pope, C., Kaltz, O. &amp; Enjalbert, J. (2012) Genetic structure and local adaptation of European wheat yellow rust populations: the role of temperature&#x2010;specific adaptation. Evolutionary Applications, 5, 341&#x2013;352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merges, D., Dal Grande, F., Valim, H., Singh, G. &amp; Schmitt, I. (2023) Gene abundance linked to climate zone: parallel evolution of gene content along elevation gradients in lichenized fungi. Frontiers in Microbiology, 14, 1097787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milgroom, M.G., Jim&#xe9;nez&#x2010;Gasco, M.D.M., Olivares&#x2010;Garc&#xed;a, C., Drott, M.T. &amp; Jim&#xe9;nez&#x2010;D&#x301;iaz, R.M. (2014) Recombination between clonal lineages of the asexual fungus verticillium dahliae detected by genotyping by sequencing. PLoS One, 9, e106740.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montiel, P. (2000) Soluble carbohydrates (trehalose in particular) and cryoprotection in polar biota. Cryo Letters, 21, 83&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nardini, A., Salleo, S., Lo Gullo, M.A. &amp; Pitt, F. (2000) Different responses to drought and freeze stress of Quercus ilex L. growing along a latitudinal gradient. Plant Ecology, 148, 139&#x2013;147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neher, R.A. (2013) Genetic draft, selective interference, and population genetics of rapid adaptation. Annual Review of Ecology, Evolution, and Systematics, 44, 195&#x2013;215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niederer, M., Pankow, W. &amp; Wiemken, A. (1992) Seasonal changes of soluble carbohydrates in mycorrhizas of Norway spruce and changes induced by exposure to frost and desiccation. European Journal of Forest Pathology, 22, 291&#x2013;299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nimis, P. &amp; Tretiach, M. (1995) The lichens of Italy. A phytoclimatic outline. Cryptogamic Botany, 5, 199&#x2013;208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nnadi, N.E. &amp; Carter, D.A. (2021) Climate change and the emergence of fungal pathogens. PLoS Pathogens, 17, e1009503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palumbo, R.J., McKean, N., Leatherman, E., Namitz, K.E.W., Connell, L., Wolfe, A. et al. (2022) Coevolution of the Ess1&#x2010;CTD axis in polar fungi suggests a role for phase separation in cold tolerance. Science Advances, 8, eabq3235.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panadero, J., Pallotti, C., Rodr&#xed;guez&#x2010;Vargas, S., Randez&#x2010;Gil, F. &amp; Prieto, J.A. (2006) A downshift in temperature activates the high osmolarity glycerol (HOG) pathway, which determines freeze tolerance in Saccharomyces cerevisiae. The Journal of Biological Chemistry, 281, 4638&#x2013;4645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peksa, O. &amp; &#x160;kaloud, P. (2011) Do photobionts influence the ecology of lichens? A case study of environmental preferences in symbiotic green alga Asterochloris (Trebouxiophyceae). Molecular Ecology, 20, 3936&#x2013;3948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popa, C.V., Dumitru, I., Ruta, L.L., Danet, A.F. &amp; Farcasanu, I.C. (2010) Exogenous oxidative stress induces Ca2+ release in the yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae. The FEBS Journal, 277, 4027&#x2013;4038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prentice, I.C., Cramer, W., Harrison, S.P., Leemans, R., Monserud, R.A. &amp; Solomon, A.M. (1992) A global biome model based on plant physiology and dominance, soil properties and climate. Journal of Biogeography, 19, 134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redman, R.S., Sheehan, K.B., Stout, R.G., Rodriguez, R.J., Henson, J.M., Bateson, M. et al. (2002) Thermotolerance generated by plant/fungal symbiosis. Science, 298, 1581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rethinavelu, G., Lavanya, M., Krishnamoorthy, S., Baskaran, N. &amp; Sivanandham, V. (2023) Edible lichens and its unique bioactives: a review of its pharmacological and food applications. Food and Humanity, 1, 1598&#x2013;1609.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson, C. (2001) Cold adaptation in Arctic and Antarctic fungi. The New Phytologist, 151, 341&#x2013;353.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocap, G., Larimer, F.W., Lamerdin, J., Malfatti, S., Chain, P., Ahlgren, N.A. et al. (2003) Genome divergence in two Prochlorococcus ecotypes reflects oceanic niche differentiation. Nature, 4246952(424), 1042&#x2013;1047.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolshausen, G., Dal Grande, F., Otte, J. &amp; Schmitt, I. (2022) Lichen holobionts show compositional structure along elevation. Molecular Ecology, 32, 1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolshausen, G., Dal Grande, F., Sadowska&#x2010;De&#x15b;, A.D., Otte, J. &amp; Schmitt, I. (2018) Quantifying the climatic niche of symbiont partners in a lichen symbiosis indicates mutualist&#x2010;mediated niche expansions. Ecography, 41, 1380&#x2013;1392.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scharnagl, K., Tagirdzhanova, G. &amp; Talbot, N.J. (2023) The coming golden age for lichen biology. Current Biology, 33, R512&#x2013;R518.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seymour, F.A., Crittenden, P.D. &amp; Dyer, P.S. (2005) Sex in the extremes: lichen&#x2010;forming fungi. Mycologist, 19, 51&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, G., Calchera, A., Schulz, M., Drechsler, M., Bode, H.B., Schmitt, I. et al. (2021) Climate&#x2010;specific biosynthetic gene clusters in populations of a lichen&#x2010;forming fungus. Environmental Microbiology, 23, 4260&#x2013;4275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, P., Singh, S.M. &amp; Roy, U. (2016) Taxonomic characterization and the bio&#x2010;potential of bacteria isolated from glacier ice cores in the high Arctic. Journal of Basic Microbiology, 56, 275&#x2013;285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soloway, B. (2016) &#x201c;mus co shee&#x201d;: indigenous plant foods and horticultural imperialism in the Canadian Sub&#x2010;Arctic. Canadian Bulletin of Medical History, 32, 253&#x2013;273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinh&#xe4;user, S.S., Andr&#xe9;sson, &#xd3;.S., P&#xe1;lsson, A. &amp; Werth, S. (2016) Fungal and cyanobacterial gene expression in a lichen symbiosis: effect of temperature and location. Fungal Biology, 120, 1194&#x2013;1208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storey, J.D., Bass, A.J. &amp; Dabney, A. (2023) qvalue: Q&#x2010;value estimation for false discovery rate control. R Packag Version 2340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsuji, M., Fujiu, S., Xiao, N., Hanada, Y., Kudoh, S., Kondo, H. et al. (2013) Cold adaptation of fungi obtained from soil and lake sediment in the Skarvsnes ice&#x2010;free area, Antarctica. FEMS Microbiology Letters, 346, 121&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turk, M., Plemenita&#x161;, A. &amp; Gunde&#x2010;Cimerman, N. (2011) Extremophilic yeasts: plasma&#x2010;membrane fluidity as determinant of stress tolerance. Fungal Biology, 115, 950&#x2013;958.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valim, H., Dal Grande, F., Otte, J., Singh, G., Merges, D. &amp; Schmitt, I. (2022) Identification and expression of functionally conserved circadian clock genes in lichen&#x2010;forming fungi. Scientific Reports, 12, 15884.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valim, H.F., Grande, F.D., Wong, E.L.Y. &amp; Schmitt, I. (2024) Circadian clock&#x2010; and temperature&#x2010;associated genes contribute to overall genomic differentiation along elevation in lichenized fungi. Molecular Ecology, 33, e17252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van&#x10d;urov&#xe1;, L., Mal&#xed;&#x10d;ek, J., Steinov&#xe1;, J. &amp; &#x160;kaloud, P. (2021) Choosing the right life partner: ecological drivers of lichen symbiosis. Frontiers in Microbiology, 12, 769304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldvogel, A.&#x2010;M., Feldmeyer, B., Rolshausen, G., Exposito&#x2010;Alonso, M., Rellstab, C., Kofler, R. et al. (2020) Evolutionary genomics can improve prediction of species' responses to climate change. Evolution Letters, 4, 4&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, G.Z., Ma, C.J., Luo, Y., Zhou, S.S., Zhou, Y., Ma, X.L. et al. (2018) Proteome and transcriptome reveal involvement of heat shock proteins and indoleacetic acid metabolism process in Lentinula edodes thermotolerance. Cellular Physiology and Biochemistry, 50, 1617&#x2013;1637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, M., Tian, J., Xiang, M. &amp; Liu, X. (2017) Living strategy of cold&#x2010;adapted fungi with the reference to several representative species. Mycology, 8, 178&#x2013;188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werth, S. &amp; Sork, V.L. (2014) Ecological specialization in Trebouxia (Trebouxiophyceae) photobionts of Ramalina menziesii (Ramalinaceae) across six range&#x2010;covering ecoregions of western North America. American Journal of Botany, 101, 1127&#x2013;1140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whittaker, K.A. &amp; Rynearson, T.A. (2017) Evidence for environmental and ecological selection in a microbe with no geographic limits to gene flow. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 114, 2651&#x2013;2656.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>You, B., Kim, Y., Hwang, J., Kim, S., Jeon, N., Dong, X. et al. (2015) Antioxidative effects of enzymatic hydrolysates of Umbilicaria esculenta. Planta Medica, 81, PW_02.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>