<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37881475</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2095</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2023</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Aquaculture nutrition</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Aquac Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Combined Supplementation of AZOMITE and Citric Acid Promoted the Growth, Intestinal Health, Antioxidant, and Resistance against <i>Aeromonas hydrophila</i> for Largemouth Bass, <i>Micropterus salmoides</i>.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5022456</StartPage><MedlinePgn>5022456</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">5022456</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/2023/5022456</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Citric acid is an organic acid extensively used in feed industry, and AZOMITE is a hydrated aluminosilicate compound rich in rare earth elements and trace mineral elements. This study investigated the supplemental effects of AZOMITE and citric acid individual or in combination on the growth performance, intestinal microbiota, morphology, digestive enzyme activity, serum indexes, and disease resistance of juvenile largemouth bass. Six diets were designed, including the control diet (CON) and the five additive-supplemented diets with the addition of 4 or 8&#x2009;g/kg citric acid (CA4, CA8), 3&#x2009;g/kg AZOMITE (A3), and their combined addition as 4&#x2009;g/kg citric acid&#x2009;+&#x2009;1.5&#x2009;g/kg AZOMITE) (C4A1.5) and 8&#x2009;g/kg citric acid&#x2009;+&#x2009;3&#x2009;g/kg AZOMITE (C8A3). Juvenile largemouth bass with initial body weight of 22.01&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;0.09&#x2009;g were fed the six diets for 56 days. The results revealed that the combined addition of 4&#x2009;g/kg citric acid and 1.5&#x2009;g/kg AZOMITE (C4A1.5) increased weight gain by 7.99% (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05), and decreased feed conversion ratio by 0.07 (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). The protein retention in the C4A1.5 group and the lipid retention in all additive-supplemented groups were significantly higher than those in the control group (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). In serum, all additive-supplemented groups showed significantly higher glutathione peroxidase activity than the control group (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). The activities of superoxide dismutase and catalase in the CA8, A3, C4A1.5, and C8A3 groups were significantly higher (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05), while the concentration of malondialdehyde was significantly lower than those in the control group (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). Moreover, the total antioxidant capacity in the A3 and C4A1.5 groups, and lysozyme activity in the A3, C4A1.5, and C8A3 groups were significantly increased when compared to the control group (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). In digestive enzyme, the protease activity in the A3, C4A1.5 groups, and amylase activity in the CA4, CA8, and C4A1.5 groups were significantly higher than those in the control group (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). In intestinal microbiota, <i>Firmicutes</i> abundance was elevated in all additive groups, while the <i>Fusobacteriota</i> and <i>Plesiomonas shigelloides</i> abundance were decreased. In the intestinal histology, the CA8, A3, and C4A1.5 groups showed significantly higher villus height than the control group (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05). After the infection with <i>Aeromonas hydrophila</i>, the cumulative mortality of all additive-supplemented groups was significantly lower (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.05), and the C4A1.5 group demonstrated the lowest mortality. In conclusion, the combined supplementation of 4&#x2009;g/kg citric acid&#x2009;+&#x2009;1.5&#x2009;g/kg AZOMITE increased the growth, antioxidant, immune capacity, improved the intestinal morphology and microbial flora of juvenile largemouth bass, and promoted the resistance against <i>Aeromonas hydrophila</i> infection.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Yugui Zhang et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yugui</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-1086-045X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Demonstration Center for Experimental Fisheries Science Education, Shanghai Ocean University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Research on Environmental Ecology and Fish Nutrition (CREEFN) of the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs, Shanghai Ocean University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Collaborative Innovation for Aquatic Animal Genetics and Breeding, Shanghai Ocean University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Hongfei</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Demonstration Center for Experimental Fisheries Science Education, Shanghai Ocean University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Research on Environmental Ecology and Fish Nutrition (CREEFN) of the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs, Shanghai Ocean University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Collaborative Innovation for Aquatic Animal Genetics and Breeding, Shanghai Ocean University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chang</LastName><ForeName>William T H</ForeName><Initials>WTH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lytone Enterprise Inc., Taipei 221, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoqin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3562-9389</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Demonstration Center for Experimental Fisheries Science Education, Shanghai Ocean University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Research on Environmental Ecology and Fish Nutrition (CREEFN) of the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs, Shanghai Ocean University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Collaborative Innovation for Aquatic Animal Genetics and Breeding, Shanghai Ocean University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leng</LastName><ForeName>Xiangjun</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0164-5463</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Demonstration Center for Experimental Fisheries Science Education, Shanghai Ocean University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Research on Environmental Ecology and Fish Nutrition (CREEFN) of the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs, Shanghai Ocean University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Collaborative Innovation for Aquatic Animal Genetics and Breeding, Shanghai Ocean University, Shanghai 201306, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Aquac Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101630630</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1353-5773</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37881475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10597733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2023/5022456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs of China. China Fishery Statistics Yearbook . China Agriculture Press; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo J.-L., Zhou Y.-L., Zhao H., Chen W.-Y., Chen Y.-J., Lin S.-M. Effect of dietary lipid level on growth, lipid metabolism and oxidative status of largemouth bass, Micropterus salmoides. Aquaculture . 2019;506:394&#x2013;400. doi: 10.1016/j.aquaculture.2019.04.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aquaculture.2019.04.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabello F. C. Heavy use of prophylactic antibiotics in aquaculture: a growing problem for human and animal health and for the environment. Environmental Microbiology . 2006;8(7):1137&#x2013;1144. doi: 10.1111/j.1462-2920.2006.01054.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1462-2920.2006.01054.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16817922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabello F. C., Godfrey H. P., Tomova A., et al. Antimicrobial use in aquaculture re-examined: its relevance to antimicrobial resistance and to animal and human health. Environmental Microbiology . 2013;15(7):1917&#x2013;1942. doi: 10.1111/1462-2920.12134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1462-2920.12134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23711078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo W. Y., Chen Z., Leung H. M., Leung A. O. W. Application of veterinary antibiotics in China&#x2019;s aquaculture industry and their potential human health risks. Environmental Science and Pollution Research . 2017;24:8978&#x2013;8989. doi: 10.1007/s11356-015-5607-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-015-5607-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26498964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain A., Habibullah-Al-Mamun M., Nagano I., Masunaga S., Kitazawa D., Matsuda H. Antibiotics, antibiotic-resistant bacteria, and resistance genes in aquaculture: risks, current concern, and future thinking. Environmental Science and Pollution Research . 2022;29:11054&#x2013;11075. doi: 10.1007/s11356-021-17825-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-021-17825-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35028843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FAO. The FAO Action Plan on Antimicrobial Resistance 2021&#x2013;2025 . Rome: Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Wilson A. E., Su B., Dunham R. A. Functionality of dietary antimicrobial peptides in aquatic animal health: multiple meta-analyses. Animal Nutrition . 2023;12:200&#x2013;214. doi: 10.1016/j.aninu.2022.10.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aninu.2022.10.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9860427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36712402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du X., Chen C., Wang L., Liu G., Gu X., Yu X. The application of AZOMITE on water-saving drought-resistant rice. Chinese Agricultural Science Bulletin . 2013;29(24):90&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kusi N. Y. O., Temu V. W., Kering M. K., Atalay A., Rutto L. K., Solomon J. K. Q. Growth response of alfalfa to AZOMITE composite micronutrient fertilizer on four lime-amended Virginia soils. Grassland Science . 2021;67(3):225&#x2013;233. doi: 10.1111/grs.12309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/grs.12309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juzaitis-Boelter C. P., Benson A. P., Ahammad M. U., Jones M. K., Ferrel J., Davis A. J. Dietary inclusion of AZOMITE improves feed efficiency in broilers and egg production in laying and broiler breeder hens. Poultry Science . 2021;100(6) doi: 10.1016/j.psj.2021.101144.101144</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psj.2021.101144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8131723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33975050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pirzado S. A., Zhengke W., Purba A., et al. Effect of AZOMITE on growth performance, nutrient retention, immunity and bone mineralization of broiler chickens. Pakistan Journal of Zoology . 2022;54(2):737&#x2013;744. doi: 10.17582/journal.pjz/20200130040147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17582/journal.pjz/20200130040147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu A. J., Leng X. J., Li X. Q., Wang L. P., Luo Y. X., Zhu J. R. Effects of AZOMITE on growth,intestinal structure and non-specific immunity of tilapia (Oreochromis niloticus&#xd7;O.aureus) Chinese Journal of Animal Nutrition . 2009;21:1006&#x2013;1011. (In Chinese, with English abstract)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu M. Z., Leng X. J., Li X. Q., Xiao C. W., Chen D. R. Effects of AZOMITE on growth performance, intestinal digestive enzyme activities and serum nonspecific immune of grass carp (Ctenopharyngodon idella) Journal of the Zhejiang University&#x2013;Agriculture and Life Science . 2011;37:312&#x2013;318. (In Chinese, with English abstract)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musthafa M. S., Ali A. R. J., Mohamed M. J., et al. Protective efficacy of AZOMITE enriched diet in Oreochromis mossambicus against Aeromonas hydrophila. Aquaculture . 2016;451:310&#x2013;315. doi: 10.1016/j.aquaculture.2015.09.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aquaculture.2015.09.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng W., Koh C. Application of organic acids in aquafeeds: impacts on fish growth, nutrient utilization and disease resistance, stand acidifiers princ. Use org. Acids Anim. Nutr. Nottm. Univ. Press Nottm. U. K. 2011. pp. 49&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romano N., Koh C.-B., Ng W.-K. Dietary microencapsulated organic acids blend enhances growth, phosphorus utilization, immune response, hepatopancreatic integrity and resistance against Vibrio harveyi in white shrimp, Litopenaeus vannamei. Aquaculture . 2015;435:228&#x2013;236. doi: 10.1016/j.aquaculture.2014.09.037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aquaculture.2014.09.037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elala N. M. A., Ragaa N. M. Eubiotic effect of a dietary acidifier (potassium diformate) on the health status of cultured Oreochromis niloticus. Journal of Advanced Research . 2015;6(4):621&#x2013;629. doi: 10.1016/j.jare.2014.02.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jare.2014.02.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4506962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26199753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castillo S., Rosales M., Pohlenz C., Gatlin D. M., III Effects of organic acids on growth performance and digestive enzyme activities of juvenile red drum Sciaenops ocellatus. Aquaculture . 2014;433:6&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1016/j.aquaculture.2014.05.038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aquaculture.2014.05.038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramli N., Heindl U., Sunanto S. Effect of potassium-diformate on growth performance of tilapia challenged with Vibrio anguillarum, in: World Aquac. Soc. Conf. Abstr. CD-Rom Bali Indones. 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baruah K., Pal A. K., Sahu N. P., Jain K. K., Mukherjee S. C., Debnath D. Dietary protein level, microbial phytase, citric acid and their interactions on bone mineralization of Labeo rohita (Hamilton) juveniles. Aquaculture Research . 2005;36(8):803&#x2013;812. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2109.2005.01290.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2109.2005.01290.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarker S. A., Satoh S., Kiron V. Supplementation of citric acid and amino acid-chelated trace element to develop environment-friendly feed for red sea bream, Pagrus major. Aquaculture . 2005;248(1&#x2013;4):3&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1016/j.aquaculture.2005.04.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aquaculture.2005.04.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarker M. S. A., Satoh S., Kamata K., Haga Y., Yamamoto Y. Supplementation effect(s) of organic acids and/or lipid to plant protein-based diets on juvenile yellowtail, Seriola quinqueradiata Temminck et Schlegel 1845, growth and, nitrogen and phosphorus excretion. Aquaculture Research . 2012;43(4):538&#x2013;545. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2109.2011.02859.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2109.2011.02859.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J. S., Li J. L., Wu T. T. Effects of non-starch polysaccharides enzyme, phytase and citric acid on activities of endogenous digestive enzymes of tilapia (Oreochromis niloticus&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;Oreochromis aureus) Aquaculture Nutrition . 2009;15(4):415&#x2013;420. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2095.2008.00606.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2095.2008.00606.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai J., Li Y., Yang P., et al. Citric acid as a functional supplement in diets for juvenile turbot, Scophthalmus maximus L.: effects on phosphorus discharge, growth performance, and intestinal health. Aquaculture . 2018;495:643&#x2013;653. doi: 10.1016/j.aquaculture.2018.04.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aquaculture.2018.04.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L., Zhang P., Xia C., Cheng Y., Guo X., Li Y. Effects of malic acid and citric acid on growth performance, antioxidant capacity, haematology and immune response of Carassius auratus gibelio. Aquaculture Research . 2020;51(7):2766&#x2013;2776. doi: 10.1111/are.14616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/are.14616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H., Yi L., Sun R., et al. Effects of dietary citric acid on growth performance, mineral status and intestinal digestive enzyme activities of large yellow croaker Larimichthys crocea (Richardson, 1846) fed high plant protein diets. Aquaculture . 2016;453:147&#x2013;153. doi: 10.1016/j.aquaculture.2015.11.032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aquaculture.2015.11.032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X.-Q., Cui W.-O., Leng X.-J. Citric acid substituted the inclusion of inorganic phosphorus in diet of rainbow trout (Oncorhynchus mykiss) Aquaculture Research . 2017;48(3):1089&#x2013;1098. doi: 10.1111/are.12951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/are.12951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hern&#xe1;ndez A. J., Satoh S., Kiron V. Supplementation of citric acid and amino acid chelated trace elements in low-fish meal diet for rainbow trout affect growth and phosphorus utilization. Journal of the World Aquaculture Society . 2012;43(5):688&#x2013;696. doi: 10.1111/j.1749-7345.2012.00589.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1749-7345.2012.00589.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandey A., Satoh S. Effects of organic acids on growth and phosphorus utilization in rainbow trout Oncorhynchus mykiss. Fisheries Science . 2008;74:867&#x2013;874. doi: 10.1111/j.1444-2906.2008.01601.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1444-2906.2008.01601.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25522509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugiura S. H., Gabaudan J., Dong F. M., Hardy R. W. Dietary microbial phytase supplementation and the utilization of phosphorus, trace minerals and protein by rainbow trout [ Oncorhynchus mykiss (Walbaum)] fed soybean meal-based diets. Aquaculture Research . 2001;32(7):583&#x2013;592. doi: 10.1046/j.1365-2109.2001.00581.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-2109.2001.00581.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarker M. S. A., Satoh S., Kamata K., Haga Y., Yamamoto Y. Partial replacement of fish meal with plant protein sources using organic acids to practical diets for juvenile yellowtail, Seriola quinqueradiata. Aquaculture Nutrition . 2012;18(1):81&#x2013;89. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2095.2011.00880.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2095.2011.00880.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X., Li X., Xu Z., Yao W., Leng X. Dietary AZOMITE, a natural trace mineral complex, improved the growth, immunity response, intestine health and resistance against bacterial infection in largemouth bass (Micropterus salmoides) Fish &amp; Shellfish Immunology . 2021;108:53&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1016/j.fsi.2020.11.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fsi.2020.11.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33248252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AOAC. Official Methods of Analysis . 18th. Washington DC, Method: Association of Official Analytical Chemists; 2005. pp. 935.14&#x2013;935.24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su X., Li X., Leng X., et al. The improvement of growth, digestive enzyme activity and disease resistance of white shrimp by the dietary citric acid. Aquaculture International . 2014;22:1823&#x2013;1835. doi: 10.1007/s10499-014-9785-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10499-014-9785-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah S. Z. H., Afzal M., Khan S. Y., Hussain S. M., Habib R. Z. Prospects of using citric acid as fish feed supplement. International Journal of Agriculture &amp; Biology . 2015;17(1):1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan C.-G., Li X.-Q., Leng X.-J., et al. Effects of supplemental AZOMITE in diets on growth, immune function and disease resistance of white shrimp (Litopenaeus vannamei) Aquaculture Nutrition . 2014;20(3):324&#x2013;331. doi: 10.1111/anu.12081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anu.12081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karimi M., Mousavi S. M., Zolgharnain H., Zakeri M. Dietary montmorillonite as growth promoter and immunomodulator in rainbow trout (Oncorhynchus mykiss) Chemosphere . 2020;252 doi: 10.1016/j.chemosphere.2020.126459.126459</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2020.126459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32199164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Q.-L., Xie J., Ge X.-P., Habte-Tsion H. M., Liu B., Ren M. Growth performance and immune responses of gibel carp, Carassius auratus gibelio, fed with graded level of rare earth-chitosan chelate. Aquaculture International . 2016;24:453&#x2013;463. doi: 10.1007/s10499-015-9937-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10499-015-9937-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Xu W., Zuo R., et al. Effect of dietary chitosan oligosaccharide complex with Ce (IV) on growth, immunity and disease resistance against Vibrio splendidus of sea cucumber, Apostichopus japonicas. Aquaculture Research . 2017;48(3):1158&#x2013;1167. doi: 10.1111/are.12957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/are.12957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xun W., Shi L., Hou G., et al. Effect of rare earth elements on feed digestibility, rumen fermentation, and purine derivatives in sheep. Italian Journal of Animal Science . 2014;13(2) doi: 10.4081/ijas.2014.3205.3205</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/ijas.2014.3205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He M. L., Wehr U., Rambeck W. A. Effect of low doses of dietary rare earth elements on growth performance of broilers. Journal of Animal Physiology and Animal Nutrition . 2010;94(1):86&#x2013;92. doi: 10.1111/j.1439-0396.2008.00884.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1439-0396.2008.00884.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19364383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valavanidis A., Vlahogianni T., Dassenakis M., Scoullos M. Molecular biomarkers of oxidative stress in aquatic organisms in relation to toxic environmental pollutants. Ecotoxicology and Environmental Safety . 2006;64(2):178&#x2013;189. doi: 10.1016/j.ecoenv.2005.03.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecoenv.2005.03.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16406578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halliwell B., Gutteridge J. M. C. Free Radicals in Biology and Medicine . 5th. USA: Oxford Academic; 2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/acprof:oso/9780198717478.001.0001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3939136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapple I. L. C. Reactive oxygen species and antioxidants in inflammatory diseases. Journal of Clinical Periodontology . 1997;24(5):287&#x2013;296. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-051X.1997.tb00760.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-051X.1997.tb00760.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9178107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-&#xc1;lvarez R. M., Morales A. E., Sanz A. Antioxidant defenses in fish: biotic and abiotic factors. Reviews in Fish Biology and Fisheries . 2005;15:75&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1007/s11160-005-7846-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11160-005-7846-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao G. D., Thomas P. D., Lopaschuk G. D., Poznansky M. J. Superoxide dismutase (SOD)-catalase conjugates. Role of hydrogen peroxide and the Fenton reaction in SOD toxicity. Journal of Biological Chemistry . 1993;268(1):416&#x2013;420. doi: 10.1016/S0021-9258(18)54167-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0021-9258(18)54167-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8380162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao J., Wang S., Qiu H., et al. Modulation of growth performance, antioxidant capacity, non-specific immunity and disease resistance in largemouth bass (Micropterus salmoides) upon compound probiotic cultures inclusion. Fish &amp; Shellfish Immunology . 2022;127:804&#x2013;812. doi: 10.1016/j.fsi.2022.07.031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fsi.2022.07.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35843521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Llesuy S., Evelson P., Campos A. M., Lissi E. Methodologies for evaluation of total antioxidant activities in complex mixtures. A critical review. Biological Research . 2001;34(2):51&#x2013;73. doi: 10.4067/s0716-97602001000200009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4067/s0716-97602001000200009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11715209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birnie-Gauvin K., Costantini D., Cooke S. J., Willmore W. G. A comparative and evolutionary approach to oxidative stress in fish: a review. Fish and Fisheries . 2017;18(5):928&#x2013;942. doi: 10.1111/faf.12215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/faf.12215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z., Zhao S., Liu Y., et al. Dietary citric acid supplementation alleviates soybean meal-induced intestinal oxidative damage and micro-ecological imbalance in juvenile turbot, Scophthalmus maximus L. Aquaculture Research . 2018;49(12):3804&#x2013;3816. doi: 10.1111/are.13847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/are.13847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C., Zhao L.-P., Shen Y.-Q. A systematic review of advances in intestinal microflora of fish. Fish Physiology and Biochemistry . 2021;47:2041&#x2013;2053. doi: 10.1007/s10695-021-01027-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10695-021-01027-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34750711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang A. R., Ran C., Ring&#xf8; E., Zhou Z. G. Progress in fish gastrointestinal microbiota research. Reviews in Aquaculture . 2018;10(3):626&#x2013;640. doi: 10.1111/raq.12191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/raq.12191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang H., Bian Y., Huang L., et al. Effects of replacing fish meal with fermented soybean meal on the growth performance, intestinal microbiota, morphology and disease resistance of largemouth bass (Micropterus salmoides) Aquaculture Reports . 2022;22 doi: 10.1016/j.aqrep.2021.100954.100954</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aqrep.2021.100954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He M., Li X., Poolsawat L., et al. Effects of fish meal replaced by fermented soybean meal on growth performance, intestinal histology and microbiota of largemouth bass (Micropterus salmoides) Aquaculture Nutrition . 2020;26(4):1058&#x2013;1071. doi: 10.1111/anu.13064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/anu.13064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou M., Liang R., Mo J., et al. Effects of brewer&#x2019;s yeast hydrolysate on the growth performance and the intestinal bacterial diversity of largemouth bass (Micropterus salmoides) Aquaculture . 2018;484:139&#x2013;144. doi: 10.1016/j.aquaculture.2017.11.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aquaculture.2017.11.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bano N., DeRae Smith A., Bennett W., Vasquez L., Hollibaugh J. T. Dominance of mycoplasma in the guts of the long-jawed mudsucker, Gillichthys mirabilis, from five California salt marshes. Environmental Microbiology . 2007;9:2636&#x2013;2641. doi: 10.1111/j.1462-2920.2007.01381.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1462-2920.2007.01381.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17803786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holben W. E., Williams P., Saarinen M., S&#xe4;rkilahti L. K., Apajalahti J. H. A. Phylogenetic analysis of intestinal microflora indicates a novel mycoplasma phylotype in farmed and wild salmon. Microbial Ecology . 2002;44:175&#x2013;185. doi: 10.1007/s00248-002-1011-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00248-002-1011-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12082453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen M., Wang D., Pan Y., Zhang C., Yun T. A review of research progress on pathoegenic Plesiomonas shigelloides from Fish. Fisheries Science . 2020;39(5):780&#x2013;786. doi: 10.16378/j.cnki.1003-1111.2020.05.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16378/j.cnki.1003-1111.2020.05.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang H., Zhuang Y., Tang X.-S., Wang N.-A., Yuan K., Zhong G.-F. Dietary acidic calcium sulfate enhances growth, digestive enzyme activities, intestinal histology and resistance against Aeromonas hydrophila in juvenile largemouth bass, Micropterus salmoides. Aquaculture Reports . 2023;29 doi: 10.1016/j.aqrep.2023.101467.101467</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aqrep.2023.101467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng C., Cao J., Chi S., et al. Dietary phosphorus supplementation in the diet of Pacific white shrimp (Litopenaeus vannamei) alleviated the adverse impacts caused by high Clostridium autoethanogenum protein. Fish &amp; Shellfish Immunology . 2022;131:137&#x2013;149. doi: 10.1016/j.fsi.2022.10.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fsi.2022.10.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36206997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Huang H., Chang W. T. H., Li X., Leng X. The combined supplementation of AZOMITE and citric acid promoted the growth, immunity, antioxidant and resistance against aeromonas hydrophila for largemouth bass, micropterus salmoides. 2023. 21</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/ssrn.4512961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10597733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37881475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>