<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41769554</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physical Activity in Patients With Epilepsy: A Risk Factor or a Healthy Habit?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e102363</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e102363</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e102363</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.102363</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The approach to physical activity in patients with epilepsy has substantially changed over the last decade. Despite multiple positive effects of physical activity on general health and well-being, patients with epilepsy have long been advised not to engage in sports activities. Recent studies have led physicians to formulate updated recommendations and to encourage patients to remain active. It has been demonstrated that sport does not increase seizure prevalence, and the rate of sport-induced injuries in people with epilepsy is comparable to that of the general population. Additionally, physical activity modulates brain plasticity through a number of mechanisms, including the effect of brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF), gamma-aminobutyric acid (GABA)/glutamate balance, and maintaining long-term potentiation states in synapses. The International League Against Epilepsy (ILAE) classifies sports into three categories according to the potential risk of injury in the event of a seizure. While most activities fall into low- or moderate-risk groups, high-risk sports include aviation, climbing, diving, horse racing, motor sports, parachuting, rodeo, scuba diving, ski jumping, solitary sailing, surfing, and windsurfing. Qualification for sports participation requires individual assessments of predispositions, seizure type and frequency, reaction to specific sports disciplines, respiratory function, and adjustment of hydration and nutrition. The intensity of training should be increased gradually to avoid triggering factors, such as hyperventilation, alkalosis, and hyperthermia. Seizure occurrence differs between aerobic and anaerobic sports, which is another aspect that needs to be included. Exercise electroencephalographic (EEG) and ambulatory EEG monitoring should be taken into account in patients with exercise-induced seizures to optimize their training plan. Despite the evolving recommendations, it is difficult to formulate universal recommendations for everyone. Each patient with epilepsy should undergo an individual qualification process and be appropriately monitored.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026, Zakrys et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zakrys</LastName><ForeName>Katarzyna</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Practice, Uniwersytecki Szpital Kliniczny w Poznaniu, Pozna&#x144;, POL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zakrys</LastName><ForeName>Mikolaj</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Practice, Szpital Wojew&#xf3;dzki w Poznaniu, Pozna&#x144;, POL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stupnicki</LastName><ForeName>Szymon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Practice, Wojew&#xf3;dzki Szpital Wielospecjalistyczny im. Dr. Jana Jonstona w Lesznie, Leszno, POL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Szot</LastName><ForeName>Mateusz</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Practice, Uniwersytecki Szpital Kliniczny w Poznaniu, Pozna&#x144;, POL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oparcik</LastName><ForeName>Aleksandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Practice, Centrum Medyczne Hipolit Cegielski Poznan (HCP) Medical Center, Pozna&#x144;, POL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tarczykowski</LastName><ForeName>Jakub</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Practice, Uniwersytecki Szpital Kliniczny w Poznaniu, Pozna&#x144;, POL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kwasniewska</LastName><ForeName>Natalia</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>General Practice, Wojskowy Instytut Medyczny-Pa&#x144;stwowy Instytut Badawczy, Warszawa, POL.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eeg</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epilepsy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise-induced seizures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-traumatic seizures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">risk assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">seizures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sport discipline</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: All authors have declared that they have no financial relationships at present or within the previous three years with any organizations that might have an interest in the submitted work. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41769554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12936616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.102363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Prevalence and incidence of epilepsy: a systematic review and meta-analysis of international studies. Fiest KM, Sauro KM, Wiebe S, et al. Neurology. 2017;88:296&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5272794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27986877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Participation in sports activities in people with epilepsy. &#xc7;etin &#xd6;E, Uyan&#x131;k O. Arch Epilepsy. 2023;29:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trends and disparities in the prevalence of physical activity among US adults with epilepsy, 2010-2022. Zhang J, Yu Y, Chen Z, Wang Y. Epilepsy Behav. 2024;157:109850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38820682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epilepsy, seizures, physical exercise, and sports: a report from the ILAE Task Force on Sports and Epilepsy. Capovilla G, Kaufman KR, Perucca E, Mosh&#xe9; SL, Arida RM. Epilepsia. 2016;57:6&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26662920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sport and physical activity in epilepsy: a systematic review. van den Bogard F, Hamer HM, Sassen R, Reinsberger C. Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2020;117:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7008149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32008605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modulation of synaptic plasticity by exercise training as a basis for ischemic stroke rehabilitation. Nie J, Yang X. Cell Mol Neurobiol. 2017;37:5&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11482112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26910247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of exercise training on long-term potentiation and NMDA receptor channels in rats with cerebral infarction. Yu Q, Li X, Wang J, Li Y. Exp Ther Med. 2013;6:1431&#x2013;1436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3829711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24250723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of voluntary exercise on hippocampal long-term potentiation in morphine-dependent rats. Miladi-Gorji H, Rashidy-Pour A, Fathollahi Y, Semnanian S, Jadidi M. Neuroscience. 2014;256:83&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24141180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effects of exercise on BDNF levels in adolescents: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Azevedo KP, de Oliveira VH, Medeiros GC, et al. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17:6056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7503913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32825341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical exercise alters the activation of downstream proteins related to BDNF-TrkB signaling in male Wistar rats with epilepsy. de Almeida AA, Gomes da Silva S, Lopim GM, Vannucci Campos D, Fernandes J, Cabral FR, Arida RM. J Neurosci Res. 2018;96:911&#x2013;920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29098710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correspondence to "Exploring the impact of exercise induced BDNF on neuroplasticity in neurodegenerative and neuropsychiatric conditions" [Molecular Biology Reports (2025) 52:140] de Almeida AA, Arida RM. Mol Biol Rep. 2025;52:398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40237944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effects of physical exercise on plasma brain-derived neurotrophic factor in neurodegenerative disorders: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Ruiz-Gonz&#xe1;lez D, Hern&#xe1;ndez-Mart&#xed;nez A, Valenzuela PL, Morales JS, Soriano-Maldonado A. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2021;128:394&#x2013;405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34087277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effectiveness of high-intensity interval training on peripheral brain-derived neurotrophic factor in adults: a&#xa0;systematic review and network meta-analysis. Rodr&#xed;guez-Guti&#xe9;rrez E, Torres-Costoso A, Saz-Lara A, Bizzozero-Peroni B, Guzm&#xe1;n-Pav&#xf3;n MJ, S&#xe1;nchez-L&#xf3;pez M, Mart&#xed;nez-Vizca&#xed;no V. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2024;34:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37728896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Changes of brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF) levels after different exercise protocols: a systematic review of clinical studies in Parkinson's disease. Paterno A, Polsinelli G, Federico B. Front Physiol. 2024;15:1352305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10912511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38444767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>High-intensity aerobic exercise acutely increases brain-derived neurotrophic factor. Ross RE, Saladin ME, George MS, Gregory CM. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51:1698&#x2013;1709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6629513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30829963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of exercise on GABA signaling pathway in the model of chemically induced seizures. Barzroodi Pour M, Bayat M, Golab F, Eftekharzadeh M, Katebi M, Soleimani M, Karimzadeh F. Life Sci. 2019;232:116667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31326567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acute modulation of cortical glutamate and GABA content by physical activity. Maddock RJ, Casazza GA, Fernandez DH, Maddock MI. J Neurosci. 2016;36:2449&#x2013;2457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6705493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26911692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Incidence of sport-related traumatic brain injury and risk factors of severity: a population-based epidemiologic study. Selassie AW, Wilson DA, Pickelsimer EE, Voronca DC, Williams NR, Edwards JC. Ann Epidemiol. 2013;23:750&#x2013;756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4021712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24060276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exercise-induced seizures and lateral asymmetry in patients with temporal lobe epilepsy. Kamel JT, Badawy RA, Cook MJ. Epilepsy Behav Case Rep. 2014;2:26&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4308088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25667863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epileptic seizure induced by rapid repetitive limb movements. Zhang J, Wu D, Ji C, Li Y, Zhang X, Sun L, Wang K. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2022;28:2331&#x2013;2334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9627360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36069341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epilepsy essentials: physical activity and epilepsy. Harris KMJ. https://practicalneurology.com/diseases-diagnoses/epilepsy-seizures/epilepsy-essentials-physical-activity-and-epilepsy/31775/ Pract Neurol. 2021;2021:24&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seizures induced by physical exercise: report of two cases. Schmitt B, Thun-Hohenstein L, Vontobel H, Boltshauser E. Neuropediatrics. 1994;25:51&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8208354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leisure time habits and physical fitness in adults with epilepsy. Bj&#xf8;rholt PG, Nakken KO, R&#xf8;hme K, Hansen H. Epilepsia. 1990;31:83&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2303016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical exercise in outpatients with epilepsy. Nakken KO. Epilepsia. 1999;40:643&#x2013;651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10386535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical exercise in epilepsy: what kind of stressor is it? Arida RM, Scorza FA, Terra VC, Scorza CA, de Almeida AC, Cavalheiro EA. Epilepsy Behav. 2009;16:381&#x2013;387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19836311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physiological and electroencephalographic responses to acute exhaustive physical exercise in people with juvenile myoclonic epilepsy. de Lima C, Vancini RL, Arida RM, et al. Epilepsy Behav. 2011;22:718&#x2013;722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21985960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardiorespiratory and electroencephalographic responses to exhaustive acute physical exercise in people with temporal lobe epilepsy. Vancini RL, de Lira CAB, Scorza FA, et al. Epilepsy Behav. 2010;19:504&#x2013;508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20926351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Experimental and clinical findings from physical exercise as complementary therapy for epilepsy. Arida RM, de Almeida AC, Cavalheiro EA, Scorza FA. Epilepsy Behav. 2013;26:273&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23099288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exercise-induced central and peripheral sympathetic activity in a community-based group of epilepsy patients differ from healthy controls. van den Bongard F, Gowik JK, Coenen J, Jakobsmeyer R, Reinsberger C. Exp Brain Res. 2024;242:1301&#x2013;1310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11108887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38551692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical activity and epilepsy: proven and predicted benefits. Arida RM, Cavalheiro EA, da Silva AC, Scorza FA. Sports Med. 2008;38:607&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18557661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epilepsy and athletics. Fountain NB, May AC. Clin Sports Med. 2003;22:605&#x2013;616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12852689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epilepsy and physical exercise. Pimentel J, Tojal R, Morgado J. Seizure. 2015;25:87&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25458104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of physical training on aerobic capacity, seizure occurrence, and serum level of antiepileptic drugs in adults with epilepsy. Nakken KO, Bj&#xf8;rholt PG, Johannessen SI, L&#xf8;yning T, Lind E. Epilepsia. 1990;31:88&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2303017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idiopathic generalized tonic-clonic seizures limited to exercise in a young adult. Werz MA. Epilepsy Behav. 2005;6:98&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15652741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seizures induced by exercise. Ogunyemi AO, Gomez MR, Klass DW. Neurology. 1988;38:633&#x2013;634.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3352923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seizures after jogging. Simpson RK Jr, Grossman RG. N Engl J Med. 1989;321:835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2770817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exercise-induced temporal lobe epilepsy. Sturm JW, Fedi M, Berkovic SF, Reutens DC. Neurology. 2002;59:1246&#x2013;1248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12391356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Concussion incidence and trends in 20 high school sports. Kerr ZY, Chandran A, Nedimyer AK, Arakkal A, Pierpoint LA, Zuckerman SL. Pediatrics. 2019;144:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31615955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medical retirement from sport after concussions: a practical guide for a difficult discussion. Davis-Hayes C, Baker DR, Bottiglieri TS, Levine WN, Desai N, Gossett JD, Noble JM. Neurol Clin Pract. 2018;8:40&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5839677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29517059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding K, Gupta PK, Diaz-Arrastia R. Translational Research in Traumatic Brain Injury. Frontiers in Neuroscience. Boca Raton, FL: CRC Press/Taylor and Francis Group; [ Dec; 2025 ]. 2016. Epilepsy after traumatic brain injury.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26583175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traumatic brain injury and epilepsy: underlying mechanisms leading to seizure. Lucke-Wold BP, Nguyen L, Turner RC, et al. Seizure. 2015;33:13&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12767287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26519659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>EEG biomarkers for the prediction of post-traumatic epilepsy-a systematic review of an emerging field. Pyrzowski J, Ka&#x142;as M, Mazurkiewicz-Be&#x142;dzi&#x144;ska M, Siemi&#x144;ski M. Seizure. 2024;119:71&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38796954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Use and abuse of EEG in the diagnosis of idiopathic generalized epilepsies. Koutroumanidis M, Smith S. Epilepsia. 2005;46:96&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16302882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subtypes of post-traumatic epilepsy: clinical, electrophysiological, and imaging features. Gupta PK, Sayed N, Ding K, et al. J Neurotrauma. 2014;31:1439&#x2013;1443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4132580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24693960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-traumatic epilepsy and comorbidities: advanced models, molecular mechanisms, biomarkers, and novel therapeutic interventions. Golub VM, Reddy DS. Pharmacol Rev. 2022;74:387&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8973512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35302046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idiopathic-generalized epilepsy shows profound white matter diffusion-tensor imaging alterations. Focke NK, Diederich C, Helms G, Nitsche MA, Lerche H, Paulus W. Hum Brain Mapp. 2014;35:3332&#x2013;3342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6869818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25050427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Functional neuroimaging abnormalities in idiopathic generalized epilepsy. McGill ML, Devinsky O, Wang X, et al. Neuroimage Clin. 2014;6:455&#x2013;462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4221627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25383319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inflammation in epileptogenesis after traumatic brain injury. Webster KM, Sun M, Crack P, O'Brien TJ, Shultz SR, Semple BD. J Neuroinflammation. 2017;14:10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5237206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28086980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unveiling the hidden connection: the blood-brain barrier's role in epilepsy. Han J, Wang Y, Wei P, Lu D, Shan Y. Front Neurol. 2024;15:1413023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11349696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39206290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neural circuit mechanisms of post-traumatic epilepsy. Hunt RF, Boychuk JA, Smith BN. Front Cell Neurosci. 2013;7:89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3684786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23785313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Early hippocampal high-amplitude rhythmic spikes predict post-traumatic epilepsy in mice. Shannon T, Levine N, Dirickson R, et al. Front Neurosci. 2024;18:1422449.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11390562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39268032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biomolecular mechanisms of epileptic seizures and epilepsy: a review. Sumadewi KT, Harkitasari S, Tjandra DC. Acta Epileptol. 2023;5:28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11960269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40217521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical approach to posttraumatic epilepsy. Rao VR, Parko KL. Semin Neurol. 2015;35:57&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25714868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Practice parameter: antiepileptic drug prophylaxis in severe traumatic brain injury: report of the Quality Standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Chang BS, Lowenstein DH. Neurology. 2003;60:10&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12525711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidelines for the management of severe traumatic brain injury. VIII. Intracranial pressure thresholds. Bratton SL, Chestnut RM, Ghajar J, et al. J Neurotrauma. 2007;24:0&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17511546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-traumatic epilepsy: current and emerging treatment options. Szaflarski JP, Nazzal Y, Dreer LE. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2014;10:1469&#x2013;1477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4136984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25143737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk of seizure recurrence after the first late posttraumatic seizure. Haltiner AM, Temkin NR, Dikmen SS. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1997;78:835&#x2013;840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9344302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Road to refractory epilepsy: the Glasgow story. Brodie MJ. Epilepsia. 2013;54:5&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23646962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Managing common complex symptomatic epilepsies: tumors and trauma: American Epilepsy Society-2012 annual course summary. Burneo JG, Sirven JI, Kiesel LW, et al. Epilepsy Curr. 2013;13:232&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3854733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24348117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epilepsy: responsive neurostimulation-modulating the epileptic brain. Ben-Menachem E, Krauss GL. Nat Rev Neurol. 2014;10:247&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24752127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evidence-based guideline update: vagus nerve stimulation for the treatment of epilepsy: report of the Guideline Development Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Morris GL 3rd, Gloss D, Buchhalter J, Mack KJ, Nickels K, Harden C. Neurology. 2013;81:1453&#x2013;1459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3806910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23986299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical exercise and seizure activity. Arida RM. Biochim Biophys Acta-Mol Basis Dis. 2021;1867:165979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32980461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Does physical exercise influence the occurrence of epileptiform EEG discharges in children? Nakken KO, L&#xf8;yning A, L&#xf8;yning T, Gl&#xf8;ersen G, Larsson PG. Epilepsia. 1997;38:279&#x2013;284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9070589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The yield of ambulatory EEG-video monitoring. Primiani CT, Rivera-Cruz A, Trudeau P, Sullivan L, MacIver S, Benbadis SR. Clin EEG Neurosci. 2021;52:274&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32808544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>EEG-based brain-computer interfaces (BCIs): a survey of recent studies on signal sensing technologies and computational intelligence approaches and their applications. Gu X, Cao Z, Jolfaei A, Xu P, Wu D, Jung TP, Lin CT. IEEE/ACM Trans Comput Biol Bioinform. 2021;18:1645&#x2013;1666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33465029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Application and development of EEG acquisition and feedback technology: a review. Qin Y, Zhang Y, Zhang Y, Liu S, Guo X. Biosensors (Basel) 2023;13:930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10605290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37887123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>