<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38179388</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Prehabilitation in Lung Cancer Patients Undergoing Lobectomy: A Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e49940</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e49940</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e49940</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.49940</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Deaths from lung cancer are mostly caused by smoking. Cough, dyspnea, fatigue, weight loss, and Horner's syndrome are among the symptoms. Non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) and small cell lung cancer (SCLC) are the two categories into which lung cancer may be divided. Because of its effectiveness and lower death rates, lobectomy is the primary line of therapy for benign and early-stage lung illnesses. Pulmonary rehabilitation is a routine treatment for thoracic surgery individuals who are at a high risk to improve functional ability, avoid postoperative deterioration, avoid postoperative&#xa0;deterioration, and reduce complications and even&#xa0;hospital stays. Pulmonary rehabilitation is a multifaceted continuum of services intended to help individuals with pulmonary disease and their families reach and sustain their highest possible degree of independence and community functioning, typically provided by an interdisciplinary team of specialists.&#xa0; The objective of this research was to gather preliminary information and assess the effects of pre-rehabilitation&#xa0;on those suffering from lung cancer and having lobectomy. The pre-rehabilitation program's outcomes include increased lung functional capacity, enhanced quality of life, patient independence in daily living activities, and a shorter hospital stay. Gradually increasing walking distance over time can build endurance, requiring consistency, pacing, proper hydration, nutrition, and regular breaks. This review analyzed the effect of&#xa0;pre-rehabilitation in lung cancer patients undergoing lobectomy.&#xa0;Pre-rehabilitation program for individuals with lung cancer improves both preoperative and postoperative health through various exercises. Pulmonary rehabilitation is a multidisciplinary approach that encourages physical activity, learning about disease, treatment options, and coping mechanisms.&#xa0;Instead of curing the illness, its goal is to lessen its symptoms and limitations. Patients with pulmonary diseases or undergoing thoracic surgery prefer&#xa0;pre-rehabilitation programs due to their non-traumatic nature and fewer resources required. Elastic resistance band exercises are beneficial for lung cancer patients' pre-rehabilitation by strengthening and stretching muscle groups, improving exercise capacity, and supporting white blood cell counts. These exercises can be customized to individual needs, making them a safe and effective addition to a patient's exercise routine. They have to be carried out at least three days a week. Pulmonary exercise, including the use of a tri-ball pulmonary exerciser or three-ball spirometer, can improve lung function, respiratory muscle strength, and exercise capacity in lung cancer patients. It involves breathing techniques, cough exercises, and inflating a balloon. Pulmonary rehabilitation has a positive impact on patient health. Improved lung vital capacity, shorter hospital stays, and fewer problems following surgery are all achieved with pulmonary rehabilitation.&#xa0;The pre-rehabilitation plan allows the patient to resume their daily routines.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023, Sharma et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharma</LastName><ForeName>Vaishnavi S</ForeName><Initials>VS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiorespiratory Physiotherapy, Ravi Nair Physiotherapy College, Datta Meghe Institute of Higher Education &amp; Research (DU), Wardha, Maharashtra, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yadav</LastName><ForeName>Vaishnavi</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiorespiratory Physiotherapy, Ravi Nair Physiotherapy College, Datta Meghe Institute of Higher Education &amp; Research (DU), Wardha, Maharashtra, IND.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">6mwt</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">length of hospital stay</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lobectomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lung cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality of life</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>58</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38179388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10765220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.49940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>M-Health in lung cancer: a literature review. Sereno M, Iniesta-Chamorro JM, Garrido-Rubiales B, Gomez EJ, Casado S&#xe1;enz E. SAGE Open Med. 2023;11:20503121231172011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10186577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37205155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cancer treatment and survivorship statistics, 2016. Miller KD, Siegel RL, Lin CC, et al. CA Cancer J Clin. 2016;66:271&#x2013;289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27253694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preoperative exercise therapy in lung surgery patients: a systematic review. Pouwels S, Fiddelaers J, Teijink JA, Woorst JF, Siebenga J, Smeenk FW. Respir Med. 2015;109:1495&#x2013;1504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26303337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Primary prevention, smoking, and smoking cessation: implications for future trends in lung cancer prevention. Burns DM. Cancer. 2000;89:2506&#x2013;2509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11147637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physiotherapy management of lung cancer. Granger CL. J Physiother. 2016;62:60&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26992323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Low physical activity levels and functional decline in individuals with lung cancer. Granger CL, McDonald CF, Irving L, et al. Lung Cancer. 2014;83:292&#x2013;299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24360323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Non-small cell lung cancer: epidemiology, risk factors, treatment, and survivorship. Molina JR, Yang P, Cassivi SD, Schild SE, Adjei AA. Mayo Clin Proc. 2008;83:584&#x2013;594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2718421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18452692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anatomic lung resections for benign pulmonary diseases by video-assisted thoracoscopic surgery (VATS) Reichert M, Kerber S, P&#xf6;sentrup B, et al. Langenbecks Arch Surg. 2016;401:867&#x2013;875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27456676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preoperative pulmonary evaluation for lung resection. Roy PM. J Anaesthesiol Clin Pharmacol. 2018;34:296&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6194844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30386009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk factors for morbidity after lobectomy for lung cancer in elderly patients. Berry MF, Hanna J, Tong BC, Burfeind WR Jr, Harpole DH, D'Amico TA, Onaitis MW. Ann Thorac Surg. 2009;88:1093&#x2013;1099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19766786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Study protocol for VIdeo assisted thoracoscopic lobectomy versus conventional Open LobEcTomy for lung cancer, a UK multicentre randomised controlled trial with an internal pilot (the VIOLET study) Lim E, Batchelor T, Shackcloth M, et al. BMJ Open. 2019;9:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6797374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31615795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prehabilitation in thoracic surgery. Sanchez-Lorente D, Navarro-Ripoll R, Guzman R, Moises J, Gimeno E, Boada M, Molins L. J Thorac Dis. 2018;10:0&#x2013;600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6178292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30345096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulmonary rehabilitation. Spruit MA. Eur Respir Rev. 2014;23:55&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9487255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24591662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prehabilitation and rehabilitation for surgically treated lung cancer patients. Li TC, Yang MC, Tseng AH, Lee HH. J Cancer Res Pract. 2017;4:89&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulmonary rehabilitation in lung cancer. Pasqua F, Geraneo K, Nardi I, Lococo F, Cesario A. Monaldi Arch Chest Dis. 2013;79:73&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24354095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulmonary rehabilitation research. Fishman AP. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 1994;149:825&#x2013;833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8118655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The value of preoperative pulmonary rehabilitation. Takaoka ST, Weinacker AB. Thorac Surg Clin. 2005;15:203&#x2013;211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15999518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preoperative pulmonary rehabilitation in patients undergoing lung resection for non-small cell lung cancer. Bobbio A, Chetta A, Ampollini L, et al. Eur J Cardiothorac Surg. 2008;33:95&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18006327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of pulmonary rehabilitation on postoperative complications in patients with lung cancer and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Saito H, Hatakeyama K, Konno H, Matsunaga T, Shimada Y, Minamiya Y. Thorac Cancer. 2017;8:451&#x2013;460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5582456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28696575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Is preoperative physiotherapy/pulmonary rehabilitation beneficial in lung resection patients? Nagarajan K, Bennett A, Agostini P, Naidu B. Interact Cardiovasc Thorac Surg. 2011;13:300&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21586476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Outcomes of pulmonary rehabilitation after lung resection in patients with lung cancer. &#x15e;ahin H, Naz &#x130;, Aksel N, G&#xfc;ldaval F, Gayaf M, Yazgan S, Ceylan KC. Turk Gogus Kalp Damar Cerrahisi Derg. 2022;30:227&#x2013;234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9473605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36168581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effect of physical manipulation pulmonary rehabilitation on lung cancer patients after thoracoscopic lobectomy. Zhou T, Sun C. Thorac Cancer. 2022;13:308&#x2013;315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8807280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34882313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Two-week multimodal prehabilitation program improves perioperative functional capability in patients undergoing thoracoscopic lobectomy for lung cancer: a randomized controlled trial. Liu Z, Qiu T, Pei L, et al. Anesth Analg. 2020;131:840&#x2013;849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31348053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Combined aerobic exercise and high-intensity respiratory muscle training in patients surgically treated for non-small cell lung cancer: a pilot randomized clinical trial. Messaggi-Sartor M, Marco E, Mart&#xed;nez-T&#xe9;llez E, et al. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2019;55:113&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29984565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Impact of prehabilitation on morbidity and mortality after pulmonary lobectomy by minimally invasive surgery: a cohort study. Boujibar F, Bonnevie T, Debeaumont D, et al. J Thorac Dis. 2018;10:2240&#x2013;2248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5949464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29850128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Exercise training for people following curative intent treatment for non-small cell lung cancer: a randomized controlled trial. Cavalheri V, Jenkins S, Cecins N, Gain K, Phillips MJ, Sanders LH, Hill K. Braz J Phys Ther. 2017;21:58&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5537441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28442076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehabilitation in patients with radically treated respiratory cancer: a randomised controlled trial comparing two training modalities. Salhi B, Haenebalcke C, Perez-Bogerd S, et al. Lung Cancer. 2015;89:167&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26051445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulmonary rehabilitation and non-invasive ventilation before lung surgery in very high-risk patients [article in French] Bagan P, Oltean V, Ben Abdesselam A, Dakhil B, Raynaud C, Couffinhal JC, De Cr&#xe9;moux H. Rev Mal Respir. 2013;30:414&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23746815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A randomized controlled trial of postthoracotomy pulmonary rehabilitation in patients with resectable lung cancer. Stigt JA, Uil SM, van Riesen SJ, Simons FJ, Denekamp M, Shahin GM, Groen HJ. J Thorac Oncol. 2013;8:214&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23238118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preoperative pulmonary rehabilitation in patients with lung cancer and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Divisi D, Di Francesco C, Di Leonardo G, Crisci R. Eur J Cardiothorac Surg. 2013;43:293&#x2013;296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22588033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safety and feasibility of a combined exercise intervention for inoperable lung cancer patients undergoing chemotherapy: a pilot study. Quist M, R&#xf8;rth M, Langer S, et al. Lung Cancer. 2012;75:203&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21816503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evaluation of an early exercise intervention after thoracotomy for non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC), effects on quality of life, muscle strength and exercise tolerance: randomised controlled trial. Arbane G, Tropman D, Jackson D, Garrod R. Lung Cancer. 2011;71:229&#x2013;234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20541832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preoperative pulmonary rehabilitation before lung cancer resection: results from two randomized studies. Benzo R, Wigle D, Novotny P, et al. Lung Cancer. 2011;74:441&#x2013;445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3191236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21663994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post-operative respiratory rehabilitation after lung resection for non-small cell lung cancer. Cesario A, Ferri L, Galetta D, et al. Lung Cancer. 2007;57:175&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17442449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulmonary rehabilitation: joint ACCP/AACVPR evidence-based clinical practice guidelines. Ries AL, Bauldoff GS, Carlin BW, et al. Chest. 2007;131:4&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17494825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>