<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37176329</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of Mineral Admixtures on the Mechanical and Shrinkage Performance of MgO Concrete.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">3448</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma16093448</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Shrinkage deformation of concrete has been one of the difficulties in the process of concrete performance research. Cracking of concrete caused by self-shrinkage and temperature-drop shrinkage has become a common problem in the concrete world, and cracking leads to a decrease in the durability of concrete and even a safety hazard. Mineral admixtures, such as fly ash and mineral powder, are widely used to improve the temperature drop shrinkage of mass concrete; fly ash can reduce the temperature rise of concrete while also reducing the self-shrinkage of concrete, there are different results on the effect of mineral powder on the self-shrinkage of concrete, but the admixture of fly ash will reduce the strength of concrete, and mineral admixtures have an inhibitory effect on the shrinkage compensation effect of MgO expander(MEA). The paper investigates the effect of mineral admixtures on the mechanical and deformation properties of C50 mass concrete with a MgO expander(MEA), aiming to determine the proportion of C50 mass concrete with good anti-cracking properties under working conditions. The experiments investigated the effect of fly ash admixture, mineral powder admixture and MgO expander admixture on the compressive strength and deformation of concrete under simulated working conditions of variable temperature and analyzed the effect of hydration of magnesite in MgO expander and pore structure of cement paste on deformation. The following main conclusions were obtained: 1. When the concrete compounded with mineral admixture was cured under variable temperature conditions, the compounded 30% fly ash and mineral powder decreased by 4.3%, 6.0% and 8.4% at 7d age, and the compounded 40% fly ash and mineral powder decreased by 3.4%, 2.8% and 2.3% at 7d age, respectively. The incorporation of MEA reduced the early compressive strength of concrete; when the total amount of compounding remained unchanged, the early compressive strength of concrete was gradually smaller as the proportion of compounding decreased. 2. The results of concrete deformation showed that when the temperature rose, the concrete expanded rapidly, and when the temperature dropped, the concrete also showed a certain shrinkage, and the deformation of concrete basically reached stability at 18d. 3. The compounding of 30% fly ash and mineral powder As the compounding ratio decreases, the deformation of concrete increases, and the 28d deformation of concrete with a compounding ratio of 2:1 is 280 &#xd7; 10<sup>-6</sup>, while the final stable deformation of concrete with a compounding ratio of 2:1 in compounding 40% fly ash and mineral powder is the largest, with a maximum value of 230 &#xd7; 10<sup>-6</sup>, respectively. Overall, the concrete with a total compounding of 30% and a compounding ratio of 2:1 has the best shrinkage resistance performance.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Xuan</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Materials Science and Engineering, Nanjing Tech University, Nanjing 211800, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mao</LastName><ForeName>Zhongyang</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Materials Science and Engineering, Nanjing Tech University, Nanjing 211800, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Materials-Oriented Chemical Engineering, Nanjing 211800, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luo</LastName><ForeName>Penghui</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Materials Science and Engineering, Nanjing Tech University, Nanjing 211800, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Materials-Oriented Chemical Engineering, Nanjing 211800, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deng</LastName><ForeName>Min</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Materials Science and Engineering, Nanjing Tech University, Nanjing 211800, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Materials-Oriented Chemical Engineering, Nanjing 211800, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2021CEM012</GrantID><Agency>the Open Fund project of National Laboratory for High Performance Civil Engineering Materials</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>PAPD</GrantID><Agency>the Priority Academic Program Development of Jiangsu Higher Education Institutions</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MEA</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">compressive strength</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fly ash</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mineral admixture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mineral powder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-shrinkage</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37176329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10180498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16093448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma16093448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Barr B., Hoseinian S., Beygi M. Shrinkage of concrete stored in natural environments. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2003;25:19&#x2013;29. doi: 10.1016/S0958-9465(01)00044-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0958-9465(01)00044-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West R.P., Holmes N. Predicting moisture movement during the drying of concrete floors using finite elements. Constr. Build. Mater. 2005;19:674&#x2013;681. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2005.02.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2005.02.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H., Jiang K., Hong B., Yang R., Xu W., Tian Q., Liu J. Experimental and Numerical Analysis on Coupled Hy-gro-Thermo-Chemo-Mechanical Effect in Early-Age Concrete. J. Mater. Civ. Eng. 2021;33:04021064. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0003666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0003666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W., Huang Z., Hu G., Duan W.H., Shah S.P. Early-age shrinkage development of ultra-high-performance concrete under heat curing treatment. Constr. Build. Mater. 2017;131:767&#x2013;774. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.11.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.11.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M., Xu W., Wang Y., Tian Q., Liu J. Shrinkage crack inhibiting of cast in situ tunnel concrete by double regulation on temperature and deformation of concrete at early age. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;240:117834. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.117834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo L., Deng M., Tang M., Al-Tabbaa A. MgO expansive cement and concrete in China: Past, present and future. Cem. Concr. Res. 2014;57:1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2013.12.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2013.12.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao P., Lu X., Geng F., Li X., Hou J., Lin H., Shi N. Expansive admixtures (mainly ettringite) Cem. Concr. Compos. 1998;20:163&#x2013;170. doi: 10.1016/s0958-9465(97)00064-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0958-9465(97)00064-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao P.W., Lu X.L., Geng F., Li X., Hou J., Lin H., Shi N. Production of MgO-type expansive agent in dam concrete by use of industrial by-products. Build. Environ. 2008;43:453&#x2013;457. doi: 10.1016/j.buildenv.2007.01.037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.buildenv.2007.01.037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi S.-W., Jang B.-S., Kim J.-H., Lee K.-M. Durability characteristics of fly ash concrete containing lightly-burnt MgO. Constr. Build. Mater. 2014;58:77&#x2013;84. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.01.080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.01.080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao P.-W., Wu S.-X., Lin P.-H., Wu Z.-R., Tang M.-S. The characteristics of air void and frost resistance of RCC with fly ash and expansive agent. Constr. Build. Mater. 2006;20:586&#x2013;590. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2005.01.039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2005.01.039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue C., Li W., Luo Z., Wang K., Castel A. Effect of chloride ingress on self-healing recovery of smart cementitious composite incor-porating crystalline admixture and MgO expansive agent. Cem. Concr. Res. 2021;139:106252. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2020.106252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2020.106252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W., Huang Z., Zu T., Shi C., Duan W.H., Shah S.P. Influence of Nanolimestone on the Hydration, Mechanical Strength, and Autogenous Shrinkage of Ultrahigh-Performance Concrete. J. Mater. Civil. Eng. 2016;28:04015068. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0001327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0001327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J. Recent advance of MgO expansive agent in cement and concrete. J. Build. Eng. 2022;45:103633. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C. Review of quick damming technology of MgO concrete. Adv. Sci. Technol. Water Resour. 2013;33:82&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amaral L., Oliveira I., Salom&#xe3;o R., Frollini E., Pandolfelli V. Temperature and common-ion effect on magnesium oxide (MgO) hydration. Ceram. Int. 2010;36:1047&#x2013;1054. doi: 10.1016/j.ceramint.2009.12.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceramint.2009.12.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang D., Li X., Lv Y., Li C., Zhang T., He C., Leng D., Wu K. Early-age hydration process and autogenous shrinkage evolution of high performance cement pastes. J. Build. Eng. 2022;45:103436. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian G., Xu G., Li H., Li A. The effect of autoclave temperature on the expansion and hydrothermal products of high-MgO blended cements. Cem. Concr. Res. 1998;28:1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/S0008-8846(97)00202-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0008-8846(97)00202-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deschner F., Winnefeld F., Lothenbach B., Seufert S., Schwesig P., Dittrich S., Goetz-Neunhoeffer F., Neubauer J. Hydration of Portland cement with high replacement by siliceous fly ash. Cem. Concr. Res. 2012;42:1389&#x2013;1400. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2012.06.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2012.06.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentz D.P. Powder Additions to Mitigate Retardation in High-Volume Fly Ash Mixtures. ACI Mater. J. 2010;107:508&#x2013;514.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanif A., Lu Z., Li Z. Utilization of fly ash cenosphere as lightweight filler in cement-based composites&#x2014;A review. Constr. Build. Mater. 2017;144:373&#x2013;384. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.03.188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.03.188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Jia L., Ma Q. Influence of fly ash, slag powder on the workability and strength of low-grade concrete. Concrete. 2014;75:43&#x2013;52.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia L., Ni T., Liu Z. Effect of Mineral Admixture on Workability and Mechanical Properties of Box Girder C50 Concrete. Bull. Chin. Ceram. Soc. 2017;36:1193&#x2013;1197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jansen D., Neubauer J., Goetz-Neunhoeffer F., Haerzschel R., Hergeth W.D. Change in reaction kinetics of a Portland cement caused by a super-plasticizer&#x2014;Calculation of heat flow curves from XRD data. Cem. Concr. Res. 2012;42:327&#x2013;332. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2011.10.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2011.10.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Lv T., Han Q., Zhu Y., Hou D., Dong B. Effects of fly ash on MgO-based shrinkage-compensating cement: Microstructure and properties. Constr. Build. Mater. 2022;339:127648. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.127648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.127648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo L., Liu M., Al-Tabbaa A., Deng M. Deformation and mechanical properties of the expansive cements produced by in-ter-grinding cement clinker and MgOs with various reactivities. Constr. Build. Mater. 2015;80:1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.01.066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.01.066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C.L., Fang K.H., Jiang J. Influence of fly ash content on autogenic volume change of concrete mixed with MgO. Concrete. 2012;29:67&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Y., Deng M., Mo L., Tang M. Strength and Expansive Stresses of Concrete with MgO Type Expansive Agent under Restrain Conditions. J. Build. Mater. 2012;15:446&#x2013;450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S., Mo L., Deng M., Cheng S. Mitigation on the autogenous shrinkage of ultra-high performance concrete via using MgO ex-pansive agent. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;312:125422. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.125422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.125422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Zhang T., Hu J., Tang Y., Niu Y., Wei J., Yu Q. Characterization of reaction products and reaction process of MgO-SiO2-H2O system at room temperature. Constr. Build. Mater. 2014;61:252&#x2013;259. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.03.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.03.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dung N., Unluer C. Carbonated MgO concrete with improved performance: The influence of temperature and hydration agent on hydration, carbonation and strength gain. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2017;82:152&#x2013;164. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2017.06.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2017.06.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filippou D., Katiforis N., Papassiopi N., Adam K. On the kinetics of magnesia hydration in magnesium acetate solutions. J. Chem. Technol. Biotechnol. 1999;74:322&#x2013;328. doi: 10.1002/(SICI)1097-4660(199904)74:4&lt;322::AID-JCTB35&gt;3.0.CO;2-L.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1097-4660(199904)74:4&lt;322::AID-JCTB35&gt;3.0.CO;2-L</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dung N.T., Unluer C. Sequestration of CO2 in reactive MgO cement-based mixes with enhanced hydration mechanisms. Constr. Build. Mater. 2017;143:71&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.03.038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.03.038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matabola K.P., van der Merwe E.M., Strydom C.A., Labuschagne F.J.W. The influence of hydrating agents on the hydration of industrial magnesium oxide. J. Chem. Technol. Biotechnol. 2010;85:1569&#x2013;1574. doi: 10.1002/jctb.2467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jctb.2467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuenzel C., Zhang F., Ferrandiz-Mas V., Cheeseman C.R., Gartner E.M. The mechanism of hydration of MgO-hydromagnesite blends. Cem. Concr. Res. 2018;103:123&#x2013;129. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2017.10.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2017.10.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alarcon-Ruiz L., Platret G., Massieu E., Ehrlacher A. The use of thermal analysis in assessing the effect of temperature on a cement paste. Cem. Concr. Res. 2005;35:609&#x2013;613. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2004.06.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2004.06.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahafid S., Ghabezloo S., Duc M., Faure P., Sulem J. Effect of the hydration temperature on the microstructure of Class G cement: C-S-H composition and density. Cem. Concr. Res. 2017;95:270&#x2013;281. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2017.02.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2017.02.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Z., Qu X., Li J. Microstructure and properties of fly ash/cement-based pastes activated with MgO and CaO under hydrothermal conditions. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2020;114:103739. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2020.103739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2020.103739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>