<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41197119</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1520-5126</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>147</Volume><Issue>46</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>19</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the American Chemical Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Am Chem Soc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Dynamic Reconstruction and Microenvironment Modulation of a Pd-Doped CuS Electrocatalyst for Nearly Unity-Efficiency Ammonia Electrosynthesis from Nitrate.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>43067</StartPage><EndPage>43076</EndPage><MedlinePgn>43067-43076</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/jacs.5c16232</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Copper-based catalysts are known for their high ammonia selectivity in the electrochemical nitrate reduction reaction (NO<sub>3</sub>RR), yet the underlying mechanisms of this selectivity remain insufficiently understood and warrant further investigation. This study employs single-atom palladium-doped copper sulfide (Pd<sub>1</sub>/CuS) as a model precatalyst to elucidate the mechanisms driving its high selectivity. Comprehensive characterization reveals that Pd<sub>1</sub>/CuS undergoes in situ transformation into Cu while maintaining isolated palladium sites. The activated catalyst achieves near-unity (&#x223c;100%) selectivity for ammonia at -0.5 V vs RHE, along with high yield rates that significantly surpass those of the undoped catalyst, maintaining over 98.2% selectivity across 15 consecutive cycles. Mechanistic studies using in situ spectroscopies, theoretical calculations, and ab initio molecular dynamics simulations demonstrate that the incorporation of Pd promotes the partial desolvation of hydrated alkali ions, enhances water dissociation, improves intermediate adsorption in NO<sub>3</sub>RR, and facilitates proton transfer by strengthening the hydrogen-bond network while thermodynamically suppressing the recombination of adsorbed protons (*H). These effects synergistically promote the ammonia-selective pathway. This work provides fundamental insights into the relationship between dynamic structural evolution and catalytic performance in the NO<sub>3</sub>RR, advancing the rational design of high-selectivity copper-based catalysts.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Qun</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8359-4438</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, City University of Hong Kong, Kowloon 999077, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shi</LastName><ForeName>Zhangsheng</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2341-2422</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, City University of Hong Kong, Kowloon 999077, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Dongxue</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, City University of Hong Kong, Kowloon 999077, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zuo</LastName><ForeName>Yunpeng</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, City University of Hong Kong, Kowloon 999077, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Synchrotron Radiation Laboratory, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei 230029, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Hengjie</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6499-3935</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Synchrotron Radiation Laboratory, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei 230029, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Chuanqiang</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8549-9685</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Information Materials and Intelligent Sensing Laboratory of Anhui Province, Key Laboratory of Structure and Functional Regulation of Hybrid Materials of Ministry of Education, Institutes of Physical Science and Information Technology, Anhui University, Hefei 230601, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Li</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0585-8519</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Synchrotron Radiation Laboratory, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei 230029, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2686-466X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, City University of Hong Kong, Kowloon 999077, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Am Chem Soc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7503056</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0002-7863</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41197119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12817242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.5c16232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhu Z.-S., Zhong S., Cheng C., Zhou H., Sun H., Duan X., Wang S.. Microenvironment engineering of heterogeneous catalysts for liquid-phase environmental catalysis. Chem. Rev. 2024;124:11348&#x2013;11434. doi: 10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39383063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang S., Xie M., Yu S., Zhan X., Wei R., Wang M., Guan W., Zhang B., Wang Y., Zhou H., Zheng G., Liu Y., Warner J. H., Yu G.. General synthesis of high-entropy single-atom nanocages for electrosynthesis of ammonia from nitrate. Nat. Commun. 2024;15:6932. doi: 10.1038/s41467-024-51112-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-024-51112-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11322612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39138150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao Z.-L., Ali A., Ren Y., Su J.-F., Wang Z.. A mechanistic review on aerobic denitrification for nitrogen removal in water treatment. Sci. Total Environ. 2022;847:157452. doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2022.157452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2022.157452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35868390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samatya S., Kabay N., Yuksel U., Arda M., Yuksel M.. Removal of nitrate from aqueous solution by nitrate selective ion exchange resins. React. Funct. Polym. 2006;66:1206&#x2013;1214. doi: 10.1016/j.reactfunctpolym.2006.03.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.reactfunctpolym.2006.03.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H., Bai L., Bergmann A., Cuenya B. R., Luo J.. Electrocatalytic reduction of nitrogen oxide species to ammonia. Chem. 2024;10:2963&#x2013;2986. doi: 10.1016/j.chempr.2024.07.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chempr.2024.07.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langevelde P. H., Katsounaros I., Koper M. T. M.. Electrocatalytic nitrate reduction for sustainable ammonia production. Joule. 2021;5:290&#x2013;294. doi: 10.1016/j.joule.2020.12.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joule.2020.12.025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao X., Qin H., Zhang J., Chen X., Jiao L.. Regulation of oxide pathway mechanism for sustainable acidic water oxidation. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2024;146:32049&#x2013;32058. doi: 10.1021/jacs.4c12942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.4c12942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39529602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao X., Miao L., Jia W., Qin H., Lin G., Ma R., Jin T., Jiao L.. Strain heterogeneity in RuO2 for efficient acidic oxygen evolution reaction in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis. Nat. Commun. 2025;16:6217. doi: 10.1038/s41467-025-58570-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-025-58570-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12228735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40617809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y., Sun Y., Wang Y., Zhang X., Zhang W., Huang Z.-F., Yin L., Han A., Liu G.. Self-triggering a locally alkaline microenvironment of Co4Fe6 for highly efficient neutral ammonia electrosynthesis. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2025;147:8893&#x2013;8905. doi: 10.1021/jacs.5c00688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.5c00688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40019172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Z., Zhao Y., Huang H., Liu G., Zhang H., Yan Y., Li H., Liu L., Liu M., Wang D., Zeng J.. Isolated copper atoms boost *NO3 adsorption and active hydrogen retention over zinc oxide for ammonia electrosynthesis at ampere-level current densities. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2025;147:18737&#x2013;18746. doi: 10.1021/jacs.5c01863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.5c01863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40400257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Q., Luo L., Guo X., Wang R., Liu J., Fan W., Feng Z., Zhang F.. Modulation of the second-beyond coordination structure in single-atom electrocatalysts for confirmed promotion of ammonia synthesis. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2025;147:1884&#x2013;1892. doi: 10.1021/jacs.4c14498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.4c14498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39812081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Wang Q., Zhong L., Yan C., Shi Z., Ou Y., Shang Y., Zhang C., Tian S., Liu H., Liu D., Song P., Qi Z., Song L., Lv C.. Boosting ammonia electrosynthesis via interfacial tandem nitrate reduction enabled by an amorphous@crystalline electrocatalyst. Mater. Today. 2025;85:49&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1016/j.mattod.2025.02.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mattod.2025.02.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z., Shi Z., Ou Y., Zhong L., Yan C., Zhang C., Song K., Liu H., Liu D., Song P., Yin C., Qi Z., Song L., Lv C.. Pulsed electrocatalysis driven efficient ammonia synthesis by facilitating *NOOH formation and balancing *H supply. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2025;64:e202510287. doi: 10.1002/anie.202510287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202510287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40708400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo W., Guo Z., Ye L., Wu S., Jiang Y., Xu P., Wang H., Qian J., Zhou X., Tang H., Ge Y., Guan J., Yang Z., Nie H.. Electrical-driven directed-evolution of copper nanowires catalysts for efficient nitrate reduction to ammonia. Small. 2024;20:2311336. doi: 10.1002/smll.202311336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202311336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38385851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang Z., Lu Y.-R., Meng L., Lan J., Xie F., Gao S., Li J., Luo M., Peng M., Tan Y.. Active hydrogen enrichment on Cu6Sn5-type high entropy intermetallics for efficient nitrate reduction reaction. Adv. Mater. 2025;37:2501886. doi: 10.1002/adma.202501886.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202501886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40326147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y., Wang Y., Xu Y., Liu H., Liu X., Shan L., Wu C., Yang L., Song L.. Optimizing local configuration of interphase copper oxide by Ru atoms incorporation for high-efficient nitrate reduction to ammonia. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024;35:2417486. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202417486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202417486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J., Gao R., Guo X., Truong Nguyen N., Wu L., Wang L.. Electrochemical nitrate reduction to ammonia on AuCu single-atom alloy aerogels under wide potential window. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2025;64:e202415975. doi: 10.1002/anie.202415975.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202415975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39264141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim J., Cullen D. A., Stavitski E., Lee S. W., Hatzell M. C.. Atomically ordered PdCu electrocatalysts for selective and stable electrochemical nitrate reduction. ACS Energy Lett. 2023;8:4746&#x2013;4752. doi: 10.1021/acsenergylett.3c01672.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsenergylett.3c01672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10644382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37969250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa G. F., Winkler M., Mariano T., Pinto M. R., Messias I., Souza J. B., Neckel I. T., Santos M. F. C., Tormena C. F., Singh N., Nagao R.. Identifying the active site of Cu/Cu2O for electrocatalytic nitrate reduction reaction to ammonia. Chem. Catal. 2024;4:100850. doi: 10.1016/j.checat.2023.100850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.checat.2023.100850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z., Feng X., Zhang Z., Chen L., Liu W., Tong L., Gao X., Zhang J.. Graphdiyne enabled nitrogen vacancy formation in copper nitride for efficient ammonia synthesis. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2024;146:14898&#x2013;14904. doi: 10.1021/jacs.4c04985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.4c04985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38749059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao W., Xie K., Xie J., Wang X., Zhang H., Chen S., Wang H., Li Z., Li C.. Alloying of Cu with Ru enabling the relay catalysis for reduction of nitrate to ammonia. Adv. Mater. 2023;35:2202952. doi: 10.1002/adma.202202952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202202952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36871207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen F.-Y., Wu Z.-Y., Gupta S., Rivera D. J., Lambeets S. V., Pecaut S., Kim J. Y. T., Zhu P., Finfrock Y. Z., Meira D. M., King G., Gao G., Xu W., Cullen D. A., Zhou H., Han Y., Perea D. F., Muhich C. L., Wang H.. Efficient conversion of low-concentration nitrate sources into ammonia on a Ru-dispersed Cu nanowire electrocatalyst. Nat. Nanotechnol. 2022;17:759&#x2013;767. doi: 10.1038/s41565-022-01121-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41565-022-01121-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35501378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo Y., Sun M., Li T., Sun L., Han S., Chai Y., Huang B., Wang X.. Capturing copper single atom in proton donor stimulated O-end nitrate reduction. Adv. Mater. 2025;37:2415632. doi: 10.1002/adma.202415632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202415632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11938000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39967378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Zhou W., Jia R., Yu Y., Zhang B.. Unveiling the activity origin of a copper-based electrocatalyst for selective nitrate reduction to ammonia. Angew. Chem., Int. Ed. 2020;59:5350&#x2013;5354. doi: 10.1002/anie.201915992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.201915992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31965695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen G.-F., Yuan Y., Jiang H., Ren S.-Y., Ding L.-X., Ma L., Wu T., Lu J., Wang H.. Electrochemical reduction of nitrate to ammonia via direct eight-electron transfer using a copper&#x2013;molecular solid catalyst. Nat. Energy. 2020;5:605&#x2013;613. doi: 10.1038/s41560-020-0654-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41560-020-0654-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daiyan R., Tran-Phu T., Kumar P., Iputera K., Tong Z., Leverett J., Khan M. H. A., Esmailpour A. A., Jalili A., Lim M., Tricoli A., Liu R.-S., Lu X., Lovell E., Amal R.. Nitrate reduction to ammonium: from CuO defect engineering to waste NOx-to-NH3 economic feasibility. Energy Environ. Sci. 2021;14:3588&#x2013;3598. doi: 10.1039/D1EE00594D.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D1EE00594D</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun S., Dai C., Zhao P., Xi S., Ren Y., Tan H. R., Lim P. C., Lin M., Diao C., Zhang D., Wu C., Yu A., Koh J. C. J., Lieu W. Y., Seng D. H. L., Sun L., Li Y., Tan T. L., Zhang J., Xu Z. J., She Z. W.. Spin-related Cu-Co pair to increase electrochemical ammonia generation on high-entropy oxides. Nat. Commun. 2024;15:260. doi: 10.1038/s41467-023-44587-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-023-44587-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10766993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38177119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shim M., Ko J., Kim Y., Jung Y., Byon H. R.. Oxygen poisoning of copper surfaces in the presence of cesium ions during electrochemical nitrate reduction to ammonia. ACS Catal. 2025;15:11695&#x2013;11704. doi: 10.1021/acscatal.5c02252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acscatal.5c02252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H., Han A., Yang Y., Wu H., Zhang H., Yao C., Bu Y., Fu Z., Lu Y., Liu G., Baek J.-B., Li F., Zhao D.. Synthesis of ultrathin mesoporous CuxRu nanomeshes for efficient kilowatt-level nitrate reduction to ammonia. Adv. Mater. 2025;37:2507892. doi: 10.1002/adma.202507892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202507892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40391637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C., Jin H., Wang P., Sun X., Jaroniec M., Zheng Y., Qiao S.-Z.. Local reaction environment in electrocatalysis. Chem. Soc. Rev. 2024;53:2022&#x2013;2055. doi: 10.1039/D3CS00669G.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D3CS00669G</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38204405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auyoong Y. L., Yap P. L., Huang X., Hamid S. B. A.. Optimization of reaction parameters in hydrothermal synthesis: a strategy towards the formation of CuS hexagonal plates. Chem. Cent. J. 2013;7:67. doi: 10.1186/1752-153X-7-67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1752-153X-7-67</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3641970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23575312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Das M., Das D., Sil S., Ray P. P.. Development of hierarchical copper sulfide-carbon nanotube (CuS-CNT) composites and utilization of their superior carrier mobility in efficient charge transport towards photodegradation of Rhodamine B under visible light. Nanoscale Adv. 2023;5:3655&#x2013;3663. doi: 10.1039/D3NA00204G.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D3NA00204G</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10334374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37441255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao Y., Wu S., Wang Y., Liu F., Liu M., Wang Y., Zhang P., Wang Y., Zheng Y.. Fatty amine-mediated synthesis of hierarchical copper sulfide nanoflowers for efficient NIR-II photothermal conversion and antibacterial performance. Langmuir. 2024;40:604&#x2013;613. doi: 10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c02823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.langmuir.3c02823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38108826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He X., Cheng R., Sun X., Sun F., Fu Y., Li Y., Li P., Li Z., Xu H., Laine R. M., Zou J.. Organic heterophase composites induced sulfur vacancies and internal electric field enhancement for advanced magnesium storage of copper sulfide cathodes. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024;35:2413893. doi: 10.1002/adfm.202413893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adfm.202413893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang J., Zhu S., Delmo E. P., Li T., Zhao Q., Wang Y., Zhang L., Huang H., Ge J., Shao M.. Facile design of oxide-derived Cu nanosheet electrocatalyst for CO2 reduction reaction. EcoMater. 2023;5:e12334. doi: 10.1002/eom2.12334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eom2.12334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao S., Shou H., Xu W., Cao Y., Zhou Y., Wang Z., Wu X., He Q., Song L.. Regulating and identifying the structures of PdAu alloys with splendid oxygen reduction activity for rechargeable zinc&#x2013;air batteries. Energy Environ. Sci. 2023;16:5842&#x2013;5851. doi: 10.1039/D3EE02719H.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D3EE02719H</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J., Xi Z., Su J., Jing P., Xu X., Liu B., Wang Y., Zhang J.. Influence of active hydrogen on pathway selection in electrochemical nitrate reduction. eScience. 2025;5:100350. doi: 10.1016/j.esci.2024.100350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.esci.2024.100350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resasco J., Chen L. D., Clark E., Tsai C., Hahn C., Jaramillo T. F., Chan K., Bell A. T.. Promoter effects of alkali metal cations on the electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2017;139:11277&#x2013;11287. doi: 10.1021/jacs.7b06765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jacs.7b06765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28738673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan B., Wang Y., Li Y.. Understanding and leveraging the effect of cations in the electrical double layer for electrochemical CO2 reduction. Chem. Catal. 2022;2:1267&#x2013;1276. doi: 10.1016/j.checat.2022.03.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.checat.2022.03.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He Q., Zhou Y., Mou L., Wu C., Liu D., Ge B., Jiang J., Song L.. Iron-doped ruthenium with good interfacial environment achieving superior hydrogen evolution activity under alkaline condition. Energy Environ. Sci. 2025;18:1984&#x2013;1991. doi: 10.1039/D4EE05356G.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D4EE05356G</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao R., Wang Q., Yao Y., Wang R., Zhao L., Hu Z., Kao C.-W., Chan T.-S., Li W., Zheng Q., Wang J., Zou X., Wang K., Dai J., Gu X.-K., Zhang L.. Pd single atoms guided proton transfer along an interfacial hydrogen bond network for efficient electrochemical hydrogenation. Sci. Adv. 2025;11:eadu1602. doi: 10.1126/sciadv.adu1602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.adu1602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12333693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40779631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>