<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41276589</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of lithium slag dosage on macroscopic properties and hydration of cement pastes: a comparative study of OPC, UPC, and CSC systems.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>45189</StartPage><MedlinePgn>45189</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">45189</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-025-28980-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Investigating the effects of lithium slag (LS) as an admixtures on the properties of different cement pastes can expand its potential applications in construction materials. This study examines the influence of LS content (0%, 10%, 20%, and 30%) on the performance of ordinary Portland cement (OPC), ultra-fine ordinary Portland cement (UPC), and calcium sulfoaluminate cement (CSC) pastes. The underlying mechanisms are explored using scanning electron microscopy (SEM), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and Fourier-transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR). The results indicate that incorporating LS reduces the fluidity, setting time, and bleeding rate of cement pastes but enhances their compressive strength at 1, 7, and 28 days. Specifically, LS improves the long-term strength of OPC pastes, whereas it primarily enhances the early-age strength of UPC pastes. For CSC pastes, LS significantly promotes both early and later-age strength. SEM, XRD, and FTIR analyses reveal that the effects of LS stem from a filling effect and the activation of hydration reactions, where reactive components and gypsum in LS promote the formation of hydration products such as calcium silicate hydrate (C-S-H) and ettringite. These findings provide a theoretical basis for the application of LS in diverse cementitious systems.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Xianliang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of the Ministry of Education for Advanced Catalysis Materials, College of Chemistry and Materials, Zhejiang Normal University, Jinhua, 321004, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jinhua Xinsheng Zeolite Development Co., Ltd., Jinhua, 321000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Architecture and Civil Engineering, Xihua University, Chengdu, 610039, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Liwei</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zhongdu Engineering Design Co., Ltd., Chengdu, 610066, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Xi</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Architecture and Civil Engineering, Xihua University, Chengdu, 610039, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zheng</LastName><ForeName>Yantao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Guizhou Chengqian Mining Development Co., Ltd., Guiyang, 551000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dai</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of the Ministry of Education for Advanced Catalysis Materials, College of Chemistry and Materials, Zhejiang Normal University, Jinhua, 321004, China. daiweizjnuedu@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Yingda</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Architecture and Civil Engineering, Xihua University, Chengdu, 610039, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>[2023] General project:777</GrantID><Agency>Guizhou Province Science and Technology Cooperation Achievement Project.</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Calcium sulfoaluminate cement (CSC)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lithium slag</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mechanism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ordinary portland cement (OPC)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ultra-fine portland cement (UPC)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: No, I declare that the Xianliang Zhou, Liwei Ma, Xi Zhu, Yantao Zheng, Wei Dai and Yingda Zhang have no competing interests as defined by Nature Research, or other interests that might be perceived to influence the results and/or discussion reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>49</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41276589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12749953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-28980-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-025-28980-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>He, Z. H., Li, L. Y. &amp; Du, S. G. Mechanical properties, drying shrinkage, and creep of concrete containing lithium slag. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>147</b>, 296&#x2013;304 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.04.166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemougna, P. N. et al. Recycling lithium mine tailings in the production of low temperature (700&#x2013;900&#x2103;) ceramics: effect of ladle slag and sodium compounds on the processing and final properties. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>221</b>, 332&#x2013;344 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.06.078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y. R., Wang, D. M., Cui, Y., Zheng, D. P. &amp; Liu, Z. Micro-morphology and phase composition of lithium slag from lithium carbonate production by sulphuric acid process. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>203</b>, 304&#x2013;313 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.01.099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu, T. et al. The formation, characteristics, and resource utilization of lithium slag. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>432</b>, 136648 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, J. Z., Lian, P. H., Huang, S. W. &amp; Huang, L. Recycling of lithium slag extracted from lithium mica by Preparing white Portland cement. <i>J. Environ. Manage.</i><b>265</b>, 110551 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2020.110551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32275252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J. X., Han, L., Liu, Z. &amp; Wang, D. M. Setting controlling of lithium slag-based geopolymer by activator and sodium tetraborate as a retarder and its effects on mortar properties. <i>Cem. Concrete Comp.</i><b>110</b>, 103598 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2020.103598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Y. et al. Mechanical and environmental characteristics of cemented paste backfill containing lithium slag-blended binder. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>271</b>, 121567 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.121567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, X. X. et al. Production of an electro-biological particle electrode (EBPE) from lithium slag and its removal performance to Salicylic acid in a three-dimensional electrocatalytic biological coupling reactor (3D-EBCR). <i>Chemosphere</i><b>282</b>, 131020 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chemosphere.2021.131020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34118629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah, S. F. A., Chen, B., Ahmad, M. R. &amp; Haque, M. A. Development of cleaner One-part geopolymer from lithium slag. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>291</b>, 125241 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.125241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng, C. W. et al. Leaching behavior of lithium slag at various pH conditions. <i>Cem. Concrete Comp.</i><b>159</b>, 105985 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2025.105985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chinnu, S. N., Minnu, S. N., Bahurudeen, A. &amp; Senthilkumar, R. Reuse of industrial and agricultural by-products as Pozzolan and aggregates in lightweight concrete. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>302</b>, 124172 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.124172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, J., Liu, X. M., Zhang, Z. Q. &amp; Liu, Y. Synergistic utilization, critical mechanisms, and environmental suitability of bauxite residue (red mud) based multi-solid wastes cementitious materials and special concrete. <i>J. Environ. Manage.</i><b>361</b>, 121255 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.121255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38815426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, M. S. et al. The effects of lithium slag on microstructure and mechanical performance of metakaolin-based geopolymers designed by response surface method (RSM). <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>299</b>, 123950 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.123950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, W. B. et al. The use of contaminated soil and lithium slag for the production of sustainable lightweight aggregate. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>348</b>, 131361 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.131361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong, H. M. et al. Study on sintering behavior and properties of lithium slag-based foamed ceramics. <i>J. Non-Cryst Solids</i>. <b>617</b>, 122499 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnoncrysol.2023.122499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo, X. D. et al. Performance characterization and optimization of cement-lithium powder-grain slag composite cementitious materials. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>409</b>, 133851 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, C. B., Zhang, G. F., Liu, D. Z. &amp; Wang, M. T. Preparation of lightweight ceramsite from solid waste lithium slag and fly Ash. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>398</b>, 132419 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, X. L., Tang, Z. P., Zheng, Y. T., Zhang, Y. D. &amp; Wu, F. Research on the properties and mechanism of a fiber-reinforced alkali-activated lithium slag artificial lightweight aggregate. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>472</b>, 140866 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.140866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, B. H. et al. Recycling lithium slag into eco-friendly ultra-high performance concrete: hydration process, microstructure development, and environmental benefits. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>91</b>, 109563 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.109563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khair, S., Rahman, S. A., Shaikh, F. U. A. &amp; Sarker, P. K. Evaluating lithium slag for geopolymer concrete: a review of its properties and sustainable construction applications. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mat.</i><b>20</b>, e02822 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, L. et al. Effects of two activators on the hydration characteristics and microstructure of lithium slag-steel slag-containing composite cementitious materials. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>483</b>, 141749 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.141749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan, L. Q. et al. Feasibility study of lithium slag as cementitious material with high-content application in cement stabilized macadam bases. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>457</b>, 139224 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.139224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman, S. A., Shaikh, F. U. A. &amp; Sarker, P. K. Fresh, mechanical, and microstructural properties of lithium slag concretes. <i>Cem. Concrete Comp.</i><b>148</b>, 105469 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2024.105469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Z. H., Du, S. G. &amp; Chen, D. Microstructure of ultra high performance concrete containing lithium slag. <i>J. Hazard. Mater.</i><b>353</b>, 35&#x2013;43 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2018.03.063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29631045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, H. B. et al. Effect of wet grinded lithium slag on compressive strength and hydration of sulphoaluminate cement system. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>267</b>, 120465 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.120465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sha, F., Kong, H., Zhang, L. Y., Meng, Q. S. &amp; Wang, Q. F. Rheological properties of CEMI type microfine cement slurry with different fineness. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>404</b>, 133253 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.133253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du, C. B., Li, D. Z., Yi, F., Wang, M. &amp; Niu, B. Experimental study on fiber-reinforced cement tailings sand-based grouting material Preparation and factors influencing the grouting effect. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>438</b>, 137104 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.137104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo, C. C., Chen, N. &amp; Wang, R. Study on hydroxypropyl Methylcellulose modified Portland cement-sulphoaluminate cement composites: Rheology, setting time, mechanical strength, resistance to chloride ingress, early reaction kinetics and microstructure. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>98</b>, 111070 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2024.111070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, S. Z., Zhang, Z. C. &amp; Zhu, Y. Effect of lithium slag on hydration behavior of Portland cement paste. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>463</b>, 138909 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.138909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He, Y., Liu, S. H., Hooton, R. D., Zhang, X. &amp; He, S. Effects of TEA on rheological property and hydration performance of lithium slag-cement composite binder. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>318</b>, 125757 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.125757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, K. et al. Influence of cement particle size, ultra-fine fly ash, and ultra-fine silica fume on the physical and microscopic properties of slurry. <i>Case Stud. Constr. Mat.</i><b>22</b>, e04337 (2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bentz, D. P., Garboczi, E. J., Haecker, C. J. &amp; Jensen, O. M. Effects of cement particle size distribution on performance properties of Portland cement-based materials. <i>Cem. Concrete Res.</i><b>29</b> (10), 1663&#x2013;1671 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0008-8846(99)00163-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong, S. K. et al. Investigation of the performance of cement mortar incorporating lithium slag as a super-fine aggregate. <i>Front. Mater.</i><b>10</b>, 1134622 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmats.2023.1134622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahmani, H. &amp; Mostofinejad, D. Microstructure of ultra-high-performance concrete (UHPC)&#x2013;a review study. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>50</b>, 104118 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.104118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, X. C., Peng, B. J., Luo, X. D. &amp; Wu, T. Effects of composite admixture on the mechanical properties and microstructure of mortar. <i>Mater. Lett.</i><b>337</b>, 133855 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matlet.2023.133855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, M. Y. et al. Insight to workability, compressive strength and microstructure of lithium slag-steel slag based cement under standard condition. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>75</b>, 107076 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.107076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie, J. T. et al. Calcium sulphoaluminate cement from solid waste with nano-TiO<sub>2</sub> addition for high-efficiency CO<sub>2</sub> capture. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>367</b>, 130267 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.130267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi, G. L. et al. Study on the carbonation resistance of sulphoaluminate cement grouting materials enhanced by acrylamide in-situ polymerization modification. <i>Developments Built Environ.</i><b>22</b>, 100684 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dibe.2025.100684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, H. H. et al. Hydration characteristics and heavy metal leaching risk of sewage sludge-based sulphoaluminate cement. <i>J. Environ. Chem. Eng.</i><b>13</b> (3), 116996 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2025.116996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, H. B. et al. Preparation for micro-lithium slag via wet grinding and its application as accelerator in Portland cement. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>250</b>, 119528 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2019.119528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, Y. N., Yang, B. H., Gu, X. W., Han, D. &amp; Wang, Q. J. Improving the performance of ultra-high performance concrete containing lithium slag by incorporating limestone powder. <i>J. Build. Eng.</i><b>72</b>, 106610 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2023.106610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, H. B. et al. Utilization of lithium slag by wet-grinding process to improve the early strength of sulphoaluminate cement paste. <i>J. Clean. Prod.</i><b>205</b>, 536&#x2013;551 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2018.09.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu, X. W. et al. Synergistic effect and mechanism of lithium slag on mechanical properties and microstructure of steel slag-cement system. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>396</b>, 131768 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.131768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng, X. F. et al. Comparison on early hydration of Portland cement and sulphoaluminate cement in the presence of nano ettringite. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>360</b>, 129516 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, L. et al. Desulfurized gypsum regulates the hydration and hardening process of all-solid-waste-based Belite sulphoaluminate cement paste. <i>Constr. Build. Mater.</i><b>456</b>, 139260 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.139260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>