<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41050992</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1613-6829</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>48</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Small (Weinheim an der Bergstrasse, Germany)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Small</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Stomata-Inspired Intelligent High-Performance Hydrogel With on-Demand Gateable Electromagnetic-Interference Shielding.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e10156</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e10156</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/smll.202510156</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The development of intelligently adaptive electromagnetic interference (EMI) shielding materials remains constrained by the inherent trade-offs among dynamic tunability, mechanical robustness, and multifunctional integration. Inspired by stomatal regulation in plant guard cells, it has engineered an intelligent poly(N-isopropylacrylamide) (PNIPAM)/MXene-silver nanowires (AgNWs) (PMA) hydrogel whose biomimetic kinematics transcend trade-offs. This novel design deliberately emulated biological principles of osmotic-like actuation via PNIPAM phase transition, dynamic microchannel reconfiguration using a zinc oxide (ZnO) template, and ion-flux-inspired electron pathways through MXene-AgNWs networks interfaced with a zinc ion (Zn&#xb2;&#x207a;) &#xa0;electrolyte. Such structural ingenuity enables the simultaneous, on-demand tuning of electrical conductivity, hierarchical microarchitectures, and multifunctional properties. The resulting hydrogel exhibited a remarkable dynamic EMI shielding modulation of 61.1&#xa0;dB, actuated solely through hydration-governed percolation. Crucially, the divergent stimulus responses imparted an intrinsic versatility that global electrothermal shrinkage to emulate stomatal closure for EMI shielding tunability, while localized photothermal bending reproduced guard-cell kinematics for soft actuators. Simultaneously, Zn<sup>2+</sup>-riveted cross-links endowed the hydrogel with exceptional mechanical toughness of 360.6&#xa0;kJ&#xa0;m<sup>-3</sup>, while a wrinkle-nanobridge architecture integrated high-precision sensing, retaining a gauge factor (GF) of 2.11 across a 394% deformation window. Demonstrated in wireless communication toggling and muscle-movement monitoring, this biomimetic strategy establishes a paradigm for intelligent hydrogels, offering transformative potential for smart wearables and human-machine interfaces.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Wiley&#x2010;VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Junwei</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Key Lab. of D&amp;A for Metal-Functional Materials, Key Laboratory of Advanced Civil Engineering Materials of Ministry of Education, School of Materials Science &amp; Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai, 201804, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiang</LastName><ForeName>Zhen</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4151-334X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Key Lab. of D&amp;A for Metal-Functional Materials, Key Laboratory of Advanced Civil Engineering Materials of Ministry of Education, School of Materials Science &amp; Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai, 201804, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yin</LastName><ForeName>Yongqi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Key Lab. of D&amp;A for Metal-Functional Materials, Key Laboratory of Advanced Civil Engineering Materials of Ministry of Education, School of Materials Science &amp; Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai, 201804, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Zichen</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Key Lab. of D&amp;A for Metal-Functional Materials, Key Laboratory of Advanced Civil Engineering Materials of Ministry of Education, School of Materials Science &amp; Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai, 201804, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Qiang</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Key Lab. of D&amp;A for Metal-Functional Materials, Key Laboratory of Advanced Civil Engineering Materials of Ministry of Education, School of Materials Science &amp; Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai, 201804, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yuan</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Key Lab. of D&amp;A for Metal-Functional Materials, Key Laboratory of Advanced Civil Engineering Materials of Ministry of Education, School of Materials Science &amp; Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai, 201804, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lu</LastName><ForeName>Wei</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shanghai Key Lab. of D&amp;A for Metal-Functional Materials, Key Laboratory of Advanced Civil Engineering Materials of Ministry of Education, School of Materials Science &amp; Engineering, Tongji University, Shanghai, 201804, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024YFE0100600</GrantID><Agency>National Key Research and Development Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52101229</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>52373303</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2021SHZDZX0100</GrantID><Agency>Shanghai Municipal Science and Technology Major Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Small</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101235338</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1613-6810</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biomimetic architecture</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydrogels</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intelligent EMI shielding</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">on&#x2010;demand gating</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41050992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/smll.202510156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>F. Shahzad, M. Alhabeb, C. Hatter, B. Anasori, S. Hong, C. Koo, Y. Gogotsi, Science 2016, 353, 1137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Zhou, P. Min, Y. Liu, M. Jin, Z. Yu, H. Zhang, Science 2024, 385, 1205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Cheng, W. Zhu, X. Lu, C. Wang, Nano Energy 2022, 98, 107229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Zeng, F. Jiang, Y. Yue, D. Han, L. Lin, S. Zhao, Y. Zhao, Z. Pan, C. Li, G. Nystr&#xf6;m, J. Wang, Adv. Mater. 2020, 32, 1908496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Wang, Y. Jiang, Z. Ma, Y. Shi, Y. Zhu, R. Huang, Y. Feng, Z. Wang, M. Hong, J. Gao, L. Tang, P. Song, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2023, 33, 2306884.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Wei, S. Pei, X. Qian, H. Liu, Z. Liu, W. Zhang, T. Zhou, Z. Zhang, X. Zhang, H. Cheng, W. Ren, Adv. Mater. 2020, 32, 1907411.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Chang, H. Zhai, Z. Hu, J. Li, Compos. Part B Eng. 2022, 246, 110269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Yuan, Y. Fei, H. Zhang, B. Qiu, L. Shen, X. He, M. Liang, S. Zhou, Y. Chen, H. Zou, Compos. Part B Eng. 2022, 233, 109622.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Liu, Y. Li, X. Sun, W. Tang, G. Deng, Y. Liu, Z. Song, Y. Yu, R. Yu, L. Dai, J. Shui, Matter 2021, 4, 1735.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Tang, Y. Gao, T. Li, R. Qin, Q. Qi, F. Meng, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025, 35, 2504959.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Fang, L. Huang, Z. Cui, P. Yi, H. Zou, X. Li, G. Deng, C. Chen, Z. Geng, J. He, X. Sun, J. Shui, R. Yu, X. Liu, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025, 35, 2418870.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Yan, Z. Liu, J. Xiong, H. Lian, H. Chen, T. Fei, Y. Chen, H. Zheng, X. Zhao, L. Xu, F. Xue, Y. Zhong, X. Ma, L. Shi, Q. Peng, X. He, Adv. Sci. 2025, 12, 05551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Chen, D. Yi, X. Jia, G. Wang, Z. Sun, L. Zhang, Y. Liu, B. Shen, W. Zheng, J. Mater. Sci. Technol. 2022, 103, 98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Li, H. Zhu, L. Rao, M. Huang, Y. Qian, L. Wang, Y. Liu, J. Zhang, Y. Lai, R. Che, Small 2024, 20, 2308581.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Habibpour, Y. Rahimi&#x2010;Darestani, M. Salari, K. Zarshenas, S. Taromsari, Z. Tan, M. Hamidinejad, C. Park, A. Yu, Small 2024, 20, 2404876.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Yao, X. Xu, H. Li, Z. Han, J. Hao, G. Yang, Z. Xie, Y. Chen, W. Liu, Q. Wang, H. Wang, Chem. Eng. J. 2021, 410, 128288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhang, A. Liu, Y. Tian, Y. Tian, X. Qi, H. Qiu, M. He, K. Zhou, J. Gu, Adv. Mater. 2025, 37, 2505521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Chen, W. Jiang, Z. Zeng, D. Sun, X. Qi, J. Yang, Y. Wang, Chem. Eng. J. 2023, 466, 143373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Fan, N. Li, M. Li, S. Wang, S. Li, T. Tang, Chem. Eng. J. 2022, 427, 131635.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Zeng, C. Wang, G. Siqueira, D. Han, A. Huch, S. Abdolhosseinzadeh, J. Heier, F. N&#xfc;esch, C. Zhang, G. Nystr&#xf6;m, Adv. Sci. 2020, 7, 2000979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Wang, C. Wang, H. Yang, H. Zhang, D. Jiang, S. Li, Carbon 2025, 235, 120068.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Liao, X. Wang, H. Huang, Y. Shi, Q. Wang, Y. Hu, P. Zhu, R. Sun, C. Wong, Y. Wan, Chem. Eng. J. 2023, 464, 142596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Bai, J. Ju, Y. Pan, B. Zhang, D. Wang, X. Li, Chem. Eng. J. 2024, 500, 156896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Lu, J. Yu, Z. Jiang, Y. Zhang, H. Zhang, Y. Yu, D. Qi, J. Wang, Cellulose 2024, 31, 9215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Feng, H. Cai, S. Feng, Y. Liu, Z. Li, X. He, S. Liang, X. Bu, J. Huang, Y. Zhou, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025, 35, 2422487.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Yu, Z. Cui, J. Lu, J. Zhao, Y. Zhang, G. Fan, S. Liu, Y. He, Y. Yu, D. Qi, Compos. Part B Eng. 2021, 224, 109193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W. Wang, C. Wu, K. Zhu, F. Chen, J. Zhou, Y. Shi, C. Zhang, R. Li, M. Wu, S. Zhuo, H. Zhang, P. Wang, ACS Appl. Polym. Mater. 2021, 3, 1747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Li, P. Wang, Y. Li, Z. Yong, K. Wu, Y. Zhang, J. Wang, D. Hu, Nano Res. 2024, 17, 8521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Zhao, C. Lo, L. Ruan, C. Pi, C. Kim, Y. Alsaid, I. Frenkel, R. Rico, T. Tsao, X. He, Sci. Robot. 2021, 6, abd5483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Hu, Y. Cheng, Z. Wei, Y. Zhan, R. Zhang, H. Xia, X. Jiang, Chem. Eng. J. 2024, 493, 152533.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Liu, R. Zhang, Y. Xiao, J. Li, W. Chang, D. Qian, Z. Liu, Mater. Horiz. 2021, 8, 1783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Khan, K. Yu, J. Li, X. Leng, M. Wang, X. Zhang, B. An, B. Fei, W. Wei, H. Zhuang, M. Shafiq, L. Bao, Z. Liu, X. Zhou, Adv. Fiber Mater. 2022, 4, 1572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Leng, X. Zhou, J. Liu, Y. Xiao, J. Sun, Y. Li, Z. Liu, Mater. Horiz. 2021, 8, 1538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Liao, X. Wang, X. Li, Y. Wan, T. Zhao, Y. Hu, P. Zhu, R. Sun, C. Wong, Chem. Eng. J. 2021, 422, 129962.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Zhang, Y. Zhang, Y. Wang, Y. Huang, Mater. Horiz 2025, 8, 1538.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Luo, L. Huo, L. Wang, X. Huang, J. Li, Z. Guo, Q. Gao, M. Hu, H. Xue, J. Gao, Chem. Eng. J. 2020, 391, 123537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Zhang, Z. Song, W. Cao, G. Gao, L. Yang, Y. He, J. Han, Z. Zhang, T. Wang, J. Zhu, Light Sci. Appl. 2024, 13, 223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Wei, N. Wu, B. Li, J. Liu, F. Pan, J. Liu, Z. Zeng, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2025, 35, 2424312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Brodribb, S. McAdam, Science 2011, 331, 582.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Liu, S. Hou, O. Rodrigues, P. Wang, D. Luo, S. Munemasa, J. Lei, J. Liu, F. Ortiz&#x2010;Morea, X. Wang, K. Nomura, C. Yin, H. Wang, W. Zhang, K. Zhu&#x2010;Salzman, S. He, P. He, L. Shan, Nature 2022, 605, 332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. K. Mishra, G. Modi, V. Cretu, V. Postica, O. Lupan, T. Reimer, I. Paulowicz, V. Hrkac, W. Benecke, L. Kienle, ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2015, 7, 14303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. E. Cho, J. M. Park, W. J. Song, M. G. Lee, J. Y. Sun, Adv. Mater. 2024, 36, 2406103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Hauck, L. M. Saure, B. Zeller&#x2010;Plumhoff, S. Kaps, J. Hammel, C. Mohr, L. Rieck, A. S. Nia, X. Feng, N. M. Pugno, Adv. Mater. 2023, 35, 2302816.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. Shen, Y. Li, W. Zhai, W. Zheng, ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2016, 8, 8050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Chen, Y. Liu, Y. Li, H. Qi, ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2021, 13, 30020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Wang, X. Cheng, W. Song, C. Ma, X. Bian, M. Chen, Chem. Eng. J. 2018, 344, 342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. Sun, J. Chen, X. Jia, G. Wang, B. Shen, W. Zheng, Mater. Today Phys. 2021, 21, 100521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Chen, B. Shen, X. Jia, Y. Liu, W. Zheng, Mater. Today Phys. 2022, 24, 100695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Jiang, H. Yu, H. Lu, Y. Si, Y. Dong, Y. Zhu, C. Qian, Y. Fu, ACS Appl. Polym. Mater. 2023, 5, 4400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Xia, C. Wei, J. Tang, J. Yan, ACS Sustainable Chem. Eng. 2021, 9, 13999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R. Zhu, Z. Li, G. Deng, Y. Yu, J. Shui, R. Yu, C. Pan, X. Liu, Nano Energy 2022, 92, 106700.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. He, Y. Shao, Y. Xiao, J. Yang, X. Qi, Y. Wang, ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2022, 14, 6057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Jia, B. Shen, L. Zhang, W. Zheng, Chem. Eng. J. 2021, 405, 126927.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Cai, X. Tang, X. Chen, M. Wang, Compos. Part A&#x2010;Appl. Sci. Manuf. 2021, 140, 106188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Singh, A. Mondal, P. Maity, B. Khatua, J. Mater. Chem. C 2023, 11, 10584.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Li, L. Liu, Q. Wang, H. Zhang, W. Chen, G. Yin, Z. Yu, ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces 2022, 14, 12703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Li, S. Li, M. Wu, Z. Weng, Q. Ren, P. Xiao, L. Wang, W. Zheng, Chem. Eng. J. 2023, 455, 140860.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Y. Wei, C. Hu, Z. Dai, Y. Zhang, W. Zhang, X. Lin, Compos. Part AAppl. Sci. Manuf. 2023, 168, 107476.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P. Jiang, Z. Deng, P. Min, L. Ye, C. Qi, H. Zhao, J. Liu, H. Zhang, Z. Yu, Nano Res. 2024, 17, 1585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B. &#xdc;nver, &#xd6;. Pekcan, G. Eving&#xfc;r, J. Appl. Polym. Sci. 2023, 140, 53539.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Wang, Y. Wu, K. Zhao, G. Liu, R. Wang, Y. Zhao, Y. Liu, Y. Ge, X. Jiang, X. Gu, ACS Appl. Polym. Mater. 2025, 7, 3670.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Liu, M. Gao, X. Fan, Z. Lu, Y. Li, J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2025, 684, 469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Long, H. Yu, P. Zhang, C. Qian, M. Lu, Y. Fu, Colloids Surf. Physicochem. Eng. Asp. 2025, 709, 136129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Zhang, H. Ding, Z. Li, Y. Bai, L. Zhang, Mater. Horiz. 2024, 11, 835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Q. Yan, R. Ding, H. Zheng, P. Li, Z. Liu, Z. Chen, J. Xiong, F. Xue, X. Zhao, Q. Peng, X. He, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2023, 33, 2301982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>X. Ding, M. Wang, L. Wei, L. Wang, M. Yuan, F. Yu, H. Yang, Iran. Polym. J. 2023, 33, 273.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Wang, F. Liu, J. Qian, Z. Wu, R. Xiao, Soft Matter 2021, 17, 10421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Zhang, T. Gao, L. Jiang, X. Meng, J. Wang, N. Ma, H. Wei, X. Zhang, Eur. Polym. J. 2022, 173, 111266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. Zhu, Y. Meng, J. Zhou, Y. Hu, S. Gao, S. Li, J. Liu, S. Wang, Y. Xia, ACS Appl. Nano Mater. 2023, 6, 6984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H. Liu, C. Du, L. Liao, H. Zhang, H. Zhou, W. Zhou, T. Ren, Z. Sun, Y. Lu, Z. Nie, Nat. Commun. 2022, 13, 3420.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z.&#x2010;C. Xu, Y.&#x2010;Q. Yang, X.&#x2010;W. Pang, Y.&#x2010;T. Xu, L.&#x2010;X. Gong, L.&#x2010;C. Tang, S.&#x2010;N. Li, J. Mater. Sci. Technol. 2025, 237, 10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Z. F. Zeng, Y. Q. Yang, X. W. Pang, B. Jiang, L. X. Gong, Z. Liu, L. Peng, S. N. Li, Adv. Funct. Mater. 2024, 34, 2409855.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>