<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37964022</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Scientific reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Development of an antimicrobial inorganic polymer based on fly ash and metakaolin incorporated by nano-TiO<sub>2</sub> for reactive dye removal.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>19889</StartPage><MedlinePgn>19889</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">19889</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-023-47032-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Advanced and eco-friendly construction materials are being developed to reduce pollution and improve wastewater treatment efficiency. One such material is a photocatalytic nanocomposite that uses industrial wastes and natural substances to eliminate pollution. A recent study explored using an inorganic polymer composite (FM) made from a mixture of 70% fly ash and 30% metakaolin, with sodium hydroxide and sodium silicate as an alkali activator. The study evaluated the mechanical and hydration characteristics of the FM composite after 28&#xa0;days in 100% humidity at room temperature. The study also examined the effect of adding 2.5 wt.% of Nano-TiO<sub>2</sub> to FM composite and how it affects its properties. Results indicate that adding Nano-TiO<sub>2</sub> to FM composite enhances its mechanical, antibacterial, and photocatalytic capabilities. Specifically, FM-TiO<sub>2</sub> composite showed 90% removal of reactive blue 19 dye effluent in sunlight after 90&#xa0;min, making it an excellent choice for sustainable wastewater treatment. This study presents a cost-effective, eco-friendly solution to wastewater treatment, with added antimicrobial properties from Nano-TiO<sub>2</sub>.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Doaa A</ForeName><Initials>DA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chemistry Department, Faculty of Women for Arts, Science and Education, Ain Shams University, Cairo, 11757, Egypt. doaaali@women.asu.edu.eg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Apasery</LastName><ForeName>Morsy A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dyeing, Printing and Textile Auxiliaries Department, Textile Research and Technology Institute, National Research Centre, 33 El Buhouth St, Cairo, 12622, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ragai</LastName><ForeName>Shereen M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chemistry Department, Faculty of Women for Arts, Science and Education, Ain Shams University, Cairo, 11757, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37964022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10645941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-47032-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-023-47032-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kabra AN, Khandare RV, Govindwar SP. Development of a bioreactor for remediation of textile effluent and dye mixture: A plantbacterial synergistic strategy. Water Res. 2013;47(3):1035&#x2013;1048. doi: 10.1016/j.watres.2012.11.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.watres.2012.11.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23245543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kansal SK, Singh M, Sud D. Studies on photodegradation of two commercial dyes in aqueous phase using different photocatalysts. J. Hazard Mater. 2007;141(3):581&#x2013;590. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2006.07.035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2006.07.035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16919871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mittal A, Mittal J, Malviya A, Kaur D, Gupta VK. Adsorption of hazardous dye crystal violet from wastewater by waste materials. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2010;343:463&#x2013;473. doi: 10.1016/j.jcis.2009.11.060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2009.11.060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20045526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aksu Z, Ak&#x131;n AB. Comparison of remazol black B biosorptive properties of live and treated activated sludge. Chem. Eng. J. 2010;165(1):184&#x2013;193. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2010.09.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2010.09.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erta&#x15f; M, Acemio&#x11f;lu B, Alma MH, Usta M. Removal of methylene blue from aqueous solution using cotton stalk, cotton waste and cotton dust. J. Hazard. Mater. 2010;183(1&#x2013;3):421&#x2013;427. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2010.07.041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2010.07.041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20691537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta VK, Jain R, Nayak A, Agarwal S, Shrivastava M. Removal of the hazardous dye&#x2014;tartrazine by photodegradation on titanium dioxide surface. Mater. Sci. Eng. C. 2011;31(5):1062&#x2013;1067. doi: 10.1016/j.msec.2011.03.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msec.2011.03.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozcan A, Omeroglu C, Erdogan Y, Ozcan AS. Modification of bentonite with a cationic surfactant: An adsorption study of textile dye reactive blue 19. J. Hazard. Mater. 2007;140:173&#x2013;179. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2006.06.138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2006.06.138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16920256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrero F, Periolatto M. Functionalized fibrous materials for the removal of dyes. Clean. Technol. Environ. Policy. 2012;14:487&#x2013;494. doi: 10.1007/s10098-011-0442-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10098-011-0442-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holkar CR, Arora H, Halder D, Pinjari DV. Biodegradation of Reactive Blue 19 with simultaneous electricity generation by the newly isolated electrogenic klebsiella sp. C NCIM 5546 bacteriam in a microbial fuel cell. Int. Biodeterior. Biodegrad. 2018;133:194&#x2013;201. doi: 10.1016/j.ibiod.2018.07.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ibiod.2018.07.011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel H, Vashi RT. Treatment of textile wastewater by adsorption and coagulation. E J Chem. 2010;7(4):1468&#x2013;1476. doi: 10.1155/2010/987620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2010/987620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed DA, El-Apasery MA, Aly AA, Ragai SM. Green synthesis of the effectively environmentally safe Metakaolin-based geopolymer for the removal of hazardous industrial wastes using two different methods. Polymers. 2023;15(13):2865. doi: 10.3390/polym15132865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym15132865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10347054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37447510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vidhya TA, Gayathri KV, Kathawala TM. Treatment of mixed azo dyes in an aerobic sequential batch reactor and toxicity assessment using vigna radiata. Bio Rxiv. 2019;2:680249. doi: 10.1101/680249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/680249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gadore V, Ahmaruzzaman Md. Fly ash&#x2013;based nanocomposites: A potential material for effective photocatalytic degradation/elimination of emerging organic pollutants from aqueous stream. Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res. 2021;28(34):46910&#x2013;46933. doi: 10.1007/s11356-021-15251-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11356-021-15251-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34263399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogozea EA, Petcu AR, Olteanu NL, Lazar CA, Cadar D, Mihaly M. Tandem adsorption-photodegradation activity induced by light on NIO&#x2013;ZnO p&#x2013;N couple modified silica nanomaterials. Mater. Sci. Semicond. Process. 2017;57:1&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1016/j.mssp.2016.10.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mssp.2016.10.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olteanu NL, Rogozea EA, Popescu SA, Petcu AR, Laz&#x103;r CA, Meghea A, Mihaly M. One-pot synthesis of au&#x2013;ZnO&#x2013;SiO2 nanostructures for sunlight photodegradation. J. Mol. Catal A Chem. 2016;414:148&#x2013;159. doi: 10.1016/j.molcata.2016.01.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molcata.2016.01.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogozea EA, Olteanu NL, Petcu AR, Lazar CA, Meghea A, Mihaly M. Extension of optical properties of ZnO/SiO2 materials induced by incorporation of Au or NiO nanoparticles. Opt. Mater. 2016;56:45&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1016/j.optmat.2015.12.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.optmat.2015.12.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visa M, Cosnita M, Moldovan M, Marin CA, Mihaly M. Fly Ash waste recycling by PT/TiO2 incorporation for industrial dye removal. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health. 2021;18(8):3887. doi: 10.3390/ijerph18083887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18083887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8068039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33917242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun P, Xue R, Zhang W, Zada I, Liu Q, Gu J, Su H, Zhang Z, Zhang J, Zhang D. Photocatalyst of organic pollutants decomposition: TiO2/glass fiber cloth composites. Catal. Today. 2016;274:2&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1016/j.cattod.2016.04.036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cattod.2016.04.036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar KY, Saini H, Pandiarajan D, Prashanth MK, Parashuram L, Raghu MS. Controllable synthesis of TiO2 chemically bonded graphene for photocatalytic hydrogen evolution and Dye degradation. Catalysis Today. 2020;340:170&#x2013;177. doi: 10.1016/j.cattod.2018.10.042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cattod.2018.10.042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cazan C, Enesca A, Isac L, Andronic L, Cosnita M. Accelerated aging of polymeric composites based on waste with TiO2 fillers. ACS Appl. Polym. Mater. 2023;5(6):3958&#x2013;3970. doi: 10.1021/acsapm.3c00129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsapm.3c00129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purbasari A, Ariyanti D, Sumardiono S, Shofa M, Manullang R. Comparison of alkali modified fly ash and alkali activated fly ash as zn(ii) ions adsorbent from aqueous solution. Sci. Sinter. 2022;54(1):49&#x2013;58. doi: 10.2298/sos2201049p.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2298/sos2201049p</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visa M, Pricop F, Duta A. Sustainable treatment of wastewaters resulted in textile dyeing industry. J. Clean Techn. Environ. Policy. 2012;13:855&#x2013;861. doi: 10.1007/s10098-011-0362-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10098-011-0362-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng K, Chen L, Gbozee M. Thermal stability of geopolymers used as supporting materials for TiO2 film coating through sol-gel process: Feasibility and improvement. Constr. Build. Mater. 2016;125:1114&#x2013;1126. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.09.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.09.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh N. Fly ash-based geopolymer binder: A future construction material. Minerals. 2018;8(7):299. doi: 10.3390/min8070299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min8070299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Alouani M, Saufi H, Moutaoukil G, Alehyen S, Nematollahi B, Belmaghraoui W, Taibi M. Application of geopolymers for treatment of water contaminated with organic and inorganic pollutants: State-of-the-art review. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2021;9(2):105095. doi: 10.1016/j.jece.2021.105095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jece.2021.105095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallah M, MacKenzie KJD, Hanna JV, Page SJ. Novel photoactive inorganic polymer composites of inorganic polymers with copper(I) oxide nanoparticles. J. Mater. Sci. 2015;50:7374&#x2013;7383. doi: 10.1007/s10853-015-9295-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10853-015-9295-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hertel T, Novais RM, Murillo R. Use of modified bauxite residue-based porous journal pre-proof 34 inorganic polymer monoliths as adsorbents of methylene blue. J. Clean. Prod. 2019;227:877&#x2013;889. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2019.04.084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2019.04.084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falah M, MacKenzie KJD, Knibbe R, Page SJ, Hanna JV. New composites of nanoparticle Cu (I) oxide and titania in a novel inorganic polymer (geopolymer) matrix for destruction of dyes and hazardous organic pollutants. J. Hazard. Mater. 2016;318:772&#x2013;782. doi: 10.1016/j.jhazmat.2016.06.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhazmat.2016.06.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27329791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang YJ, He PY, Zhang YX, Chen H. A novel electroconductive graphene fly ash-based geopolymer composite and its photocatalytic performance. Chem. Eng. J. 2018;334:2459&#x2013;2466. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2017.11.171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2017.11.171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafari H, Afshar S. Improved photodegradation of organic contaminants using nano-TiO2 and TiO2 &#x2013; SiO2 deposited on portland cement concrete blocks. Photochem. Photobiol. 2016;92:87&#x2013;101. doi: 10.1111/php.12554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/php.12554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26648581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Z, Wang Q, Yin R, Chen B, Li Z. A novel TiO2/foam cement composite with enhanced photodegradation of methyl blue. Constr. Build. Mater. 2016;129:159&#x2013;162. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.10.105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.10.105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janus M, Zatorska J, Czy A, Bubacz K, Kusiak-nejman E, Morawski AW. Self cleaning properties of cement plates loaded with N, C-modified TiO2 photocatalysts. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2015;330:200&#x2013;206. doi: 10.1016/j.apsusc.2014.12.113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apsusc.2014.12.113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaya-&#xd6;zkiper K, Uzun A, Soyer-Uzun S. Red mud- and Metakaolin-based geopolymers for adsorption and photocatalytic degradation of methylene blue: Towards self-cleaning construction materials. J. Clean. Prod. 2021;288:125120. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.125120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2020.125120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ru&#x17e;ek V, Novos&#xe1;d J, Buczkowska KE. Geopolymer antimicrobial and hydrophobic modifications: A review. Ceramics. 2023;6:1749&#x2013;1764. doi: 10.3390/ceramics6030107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ceramics6030107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Etaibi AM, El-Apasery MA. Nano TiO2 imparting multifunctional performance on dyed polyester fabrics with some disperse dyes using high temperature dyeing as an environmentally benign method. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health. 2020;17:1377. doi: 10.3390/ijerph17041377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17041377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7068265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32093364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selim F, Ahmed DA, Kishar EA. Effect of alkali concentration on physico-chemical and mechanical properties of slag based geopolymer cement. J. Sci. Res. Sci. 2021;38(1):210&#x2013;232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Meawad A, Struble LJ. Method to stop geopolymer reaction. J. Am. Ceram. Soc. 2014;97(10):13071. doi: 10.1111/jace.13071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jace.13071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-apasery MA, Ahmed DA. A sustainable approach for immobilization dyeing bath effluents of reactive yellow 145 by using different types of eco-friendly geopolymer cement. Egypt. J. Chem. 2023;66(3):169&#x2013;177. doi: 10.21608/EJCHEM.2022.157273.6818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/EJCHEM.2022.157273.6818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed DA, El-Apasery MA, Ragai SM. Immobilization approach as a creative strategy to remove reactive dye red 195 and Cu2+ ions from wastewater using environmentally benign geopolymer cement. Polymers. 2023;15(7):1797. doi: 10.3390/polym15071797.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym15071797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10098900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37050411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elapasery MA, Ahmed DA, Aly AA. Decolorization of reactive dyes, part II: Eco-friendly approach of reactive dye effluents decolorization using geopolymer cement based on slag. Egypt. J. Chem. 2022;65(11):49&#x2013;54. doi: 10.21608/EJCHEM.2022.146015.6355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/EJCHEM.2022.146015.6355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elapasery MA, Ahmed DA, Aly AA. Decolorization of reactive dyes, part V: Eco-friendly approach of reactive red 195 dye effluents decolorization using geopolymer cement based on metakaolin. Egypt. J. Chem. 2022;65(12):129&#x2013;135. doi: 10.21608/EJCHEM.2022.149781.6473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/EJCHEM.2022.149781.6473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed SM, Aly AA, El-Apasery MA, Ragai SM. Decolorization of reactive dyes, part VI: Eco-friendly approach of reactive dye effluents decolorization using geopolymer cement based on metakaolin backed by slag. Egypt. J. Chem. 2022;65:683&#x2013;688. doi: 10.21608/ejchem.2022.176459.7223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/ejchem.2022.176459.7223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashem A, Okeil A, Fikry M, Aly A, Aniagor CO. Isotherm and kinetics parametric studies for aqueous Hg(II) uptake onto N-[2-(Methylamino)Ethyl]Ethane-1,2-diaminated acrylic fiber. Arab. J. Sci. Eng. 2021;46(7):6703&#x2013;6714. doi: 10.1007/s13369-021-05416-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13369-021-05416-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aly AA, Mahmoud SA, El-Apasery MA. Decolorization of reactive dyes, Part I: eco-friendly approach of reactive dye effluents decolorization using cationized sugarcane bagasse. Pigment Resin Technol. 2018;47(2):108&#x2013;115. doi: 10.1108/PRT-10-2016-0092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/PRT-10-2016-0092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdulhady YMA, El-Shazly MM, El-Kased RF. Evaluation of antibacterial activity and toxic metal removal of chemically synthesized magnetic iron oxide titanium coated nanoparticles and application in bacterial treatment. J. Environ. Sci. Health Part A. 2018;53(3):205&#x2013;212. doi: 10.1080/10934529.2017.1387012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10934529.2017.1387012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29148917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelmoteleb KMA, El-Apasery MA, Wasfy AAF, Ahmed SM. Synthesis of new monoazo disperse dyes for dyeing polyester fabric using two different dyeing methods: Demonstration of their antibacterial and anticancer activities. Polymers. 2023;15:3052. doi: 10.3390/polym15143052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym15143052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10384552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37514441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koneman EW, Allen SD, Janda WM, Schreckenberger PC, Winn WC. Diagnostic microbiology. In: Koneman EW, editor. Lippincott. 1997. pp. 803&#x2013;841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabil N, Ahmed DA, Kishar EA. Effect of elevated temperatures on the performance of metakaolin geopolymer pastes incorporated by cement kiln dust. Egypt. J. Chem. 2021;64(4):1911&#x2013;1926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuvel RR, Prince AG, Anand N, Kanagaraj B, Lubloy E, Naser MZ. Nanomaterials in geopolymer composites: A review. Dev. Built Environ. 2023;13:100114. doi: 10.1016/j.dibe.2022.100114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dibe.2022.100114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zidi Z, Ltifi M, Ben Z, Ayadi LE, N&#xf3;voa XR. Effect of nano-ZnO on mechanical and thermal properties of geopolymer. J. Asian Ceram. Soc. 2020;8(1):1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1080/21870764.2019.1693682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21870764.2019.1693682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagadesh P, Nagarajan V, Karthik Prabhu T, Arunachalam K. Effect of nano titanium di oxide on mechanical properties of fly ash and ground granulated blast furnace slag based geopolymer concrete. J. Build. Eng. 2022;61:105235. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2022.105235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2022.105235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gopala Krishna Sastry KVS, Sahitya P, Ravitheja A. Influence of nano TiO2 on strength and durability properties of geopolymer concrete. Mater. Today Proc. 2021;45(2):1017&#x2013;1025. doi: 10.1016/j.matpr.2020.03.139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matpr.2020.03.139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duan P, Yan C, Luo W, Zhou W. Effects of adding nano-TiO2 on compressive strength, drying shrinkage, carbonation and microstructure of fluidized bed fly ash based geopolymer paste. Constr. Build. Mater. 2016;106:115&#x2013;125. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.12.095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2015.12.095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang LY, Jia ZJ, Zhang YM, Dai JG. Effects of nano-TiO2 on strength, shrinkage and microstructure of alkali activated slag pastes. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2015;57:1&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2014.11.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2014.11.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khater H. Effect of cement kiln dust on geopolymer composition and its resistance to sulfate attack. Green Mater. 2013;1(1):36&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1680/gmat.12.00003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1680/gmat.12.00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khatib K, Lahmyed L, El Azhari M. Synthesis, characterization, and application of geopolymer/TiO2 nanoparticles composite for efficient removal of Cu(II) and Cd(II) ions from aqueous media. Minerals. 2022;12:1445. doi: 10.3390/min12111445r.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min12111445r</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syamsidar D, Nurfadilla S. The properties of nano TiO2-geopolymer composite as a material for functional surface application. MATEC Web Conf. 2017;97:1459652. doi: 10.1051/matecconf/20179701013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1051/matecconf/20179701013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sahitya P. Sastry. KVSGK Influence of nano TiO2 on geopolymer concrete. Int. J. Emerg. Technol. Innov. Res. 2018;5:760&#x2013;763.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guti&#xe9;rrez RM, Villaquir&#xe1;n-Caicedo M, Ram&#xed;rez-Benavides S, Astudillo M, Mej&#xed;a D. Evaluation of the antibacterial activity of a geopolymer mortar based on metakaolin supplemented with TiO2 and CuO particles using glasswaste as fine aggregate. Coatings. 2020;10:157. doi: 10.3390/coatings10020157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/coatings10020157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaramillo-Fierro X, Gaona S, Ram&#xf3;n J, Valarezo E. Porous geopolymer/ZnTiO3/TiO2 composite for adsorption and photocatalytic degradation of methylene blue dye. Polymers. 2023;15(12):2697. doi: 10.3390/polym15122697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym15122697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10305444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37376343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falah M, MacKenzie KJD. Photocatalytic nanocomposite materials based on inorganic polymers (Geopolymers): A review. Catalysts. 2020;66(10):1158. doi: 10.3390/catal10101158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/catal10101158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Pandey G. A review on the factors affecting the photocatalytic degradation of hazardous materials. Mater. Sci. Eng. Int. J. 2017;1(3):106&#x2013;114.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>