<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41408751</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1542-0086</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biophysical journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biophys J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Arrhythmia risk predictions from molecular simulations of cardiac ion channel-drug interactions.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0006-3495(25)03493-9</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.bpj.2025.12.015</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Unintended block of cardiac ion channels, particularly hERG (K<sub>V</sub>11.1), remains a key concern in drug development as disruption of ion channel function can lead to deadly arrhythmia. To assess proarrhythmic risk, we investigated how drugs interact with hERG in its open and inactivated states and whether drug interactions with other cardiac channels like Na<sub>V</sub>1.5 and Ca<sub>V</sub>1.2 mitigate that risk. Using cryo-EM structures, we modeled open and inactivated conformations of these channels with Rosetta structural modeling. We then applied SILCS (site identification by ligand competitive saturation), a physics-based precomputed ensemble docking method, to predict drug binding affinities. SILCS leverages molecular-simulation-generated free energy maps for high-throughput docking against hydrated lipid bilayer-embedded ion channel models. Bayesian machine learning was used to refine SILCS scoring using experimental IC<sub>50</sub> values from 53 known hERG blockers outperforming Schr&#xf6;dinger Glide, AutoDock Vina, and OpenEye FRED drug docking predictions. Computed drug binding affinities for hERG and Ca<sub>V</sub>1.2 channels were used to train machine learning models that successfully classified around 300 drugs from the CredibleMeds database. Cationic nitrogen SILCS fragment free energy scores were found to be top physical properties that are predictive of drug-induced torsades de pointes arrhythmia risk. This approach, which relies on the predicted binding free energies and predicted physical properties of drugs rather than the chemical structure of the drugs themselves as features, could be extended to facilitate the design of new drugs where rapid assessment of arrhythmia risk can be performed before experimental testing.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rouen</LastName><ForeName>Kyle C</ForeName><Initials>KC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology and Membrane Biology, University of California, Davis, Davis, California. Electronic address: kcrouen@ucdavis.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Narang</LastName><ForeName>Kush</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology and Membrane Biology, University of California, Davis, Davis, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Yanxiao</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology and Membrane Biology, University of California, Davis, Davis, California; Department of Biological Sciences, University of North Texas, Denton, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, University of California, Davis, Davis, California; Department of Biomedical Engineering, University of California, Davis, Davis, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jang</LastName><ForeName>Ensley</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, University of California, Davis, Davis, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brunkow</LastName><ForeName>Sophia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, University of California, Davis, Davis, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yarov-Yarovoy</LastName><ForeName>Vladimir</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology and Membrane Biology, University of California, Davis, Davis, California; Department of Anesthesiology and Pain Medicine, University of California, Davis, Davis, California; Center for Precision Medicine and Data Sciences, University of California, Davis, Davis, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>MacKerell</LastName><ForeName>Alexander D</ForeName><Initials>AD</Initials><Suffix>Jr</Suffix><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Sciences, School of Pharmacy, University of Maryland, Baltimore, Maryland. Electronic address: alex@outerbanks.umaryland.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vorobyov</LastName><ForeName>Igor</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology and Membrane Biology, University of California, Davis, Davis, California; Department of Pharmacology, University of California, Davis, Davis, California. Electronic address: ivorobyov@ucdavis.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Biophys J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0370626</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0006-3495</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Declaration of interests The authors declare the following potential conflicts of interest: A.D.M. is a co-founder and the chief scientific officer (CSO) of SilcsBio LLC, and I.V. is a co-inventor on the US Patent US-11749383-B2.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41408751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bpj.2025.12.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0006-3495(25)03493-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>