<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40539198</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2219-2840</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><Issue>22</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of gastroenterology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Gastroenterol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring the gut-exercise link: A systematic review of gastrointestinal disorders in physical activity.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>106835</StartPage><MedlinePgn>106835</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">106835</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3748/wjg.v31.i22.106835</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The relationship between exercise and gastrointestinal (GI) health is complex and bidirectional. While moderate exercise generally promotes gut health by enhancing motility, reducing inflammation, and supporting microbial balance, intense or prolonged physical activity may exacerbate GI symptoms, particularly in individuals with pre-existing digestive disorders. A deeper understanding of this interplay is essential for optimizing both exercise performance and GI well-being.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To synthesize current evidence on exercise-related GI disorders, exploring the prevalence, mechanisms, risk factors, and management strategies associated with exercise-induced GI symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Following PRISMA guidelines, comprehensive searches of databases, including PubMed, Scopus, Web of Science, and EMBASE were conducted. Studies were included if they focused on exercise-induced GI disorders, encompassed randomized controlled trials, cohort studies, case-control studies, and cross-sectional designs, and addressed symptoms across various exercise modalities. Data were extracted and analyzed to identify patterns and implications for clinical and athletic practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 231 studies met the inclusion criteria, highlighting both the benefits and risks of exercise on GI health. Regular moderate-intensity exercise, including activities such as walking, cycling, and yoga has been associated with improved GI function in conditions like gastroesophageal reflux disease, irritable bowel syndrome, inflammatory bowel disease, and constipation. These benefits are attributed to enhanced intestinal motility, reduced systemic inflammation, and improved gut barrier integrity. Additionally, exercise plays a role in regulating the gut-brain axis, with practices like yoga and Tai Chi demonstrating particular effectiveness in alleviating functional GI disorders. Conversely, high-intensity or prolonged exercise may contribute to symptoms such as nausea, diarrhea, and abdominal pain due to mechanisms like splanchnic hypoperfusion and increased intestinal permeability. Individual factors, including fitness level, dietary habits, hydration status, and underlying GI conditions, significantly influence the body's response to exercise.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Moderate-intensity exercise is a beneficial and well-tolerated intervention for promoting GI health, whereas high-intensity activities require careful monitoring, particularly in individuals with pre-existing GI disorders. Personalized exercise and dietary strategies are essential for balancing the benefits of physical activity with the risk of GI distress. Further research is needed to explore the long-term effects of exercise on gut microbiota composition and overall digestive health.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2025. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Beltagi</LastName><ForeName>Mohammed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Faculty of Medicine, Tanta University, Tanta 31511, Al Gharbia, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, University Medical Center, King Abdulla Medical City, Arabian Gulf University&#x200e;, Manama 26671, Bahrain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saeed</LastName><ForeName>Nermin Kamal</ForeName><Initials>NK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Microbiology Section, Department of Pathology, Salmaniya Medical Complex, &#x200e;Governmental Hospitals, Manama 12, Bahrain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Microbiology Section, Department of Pathology, Royal College of Surgeons in Ireland-Bahrain, Busaiteen 15503, Muharraq, Bahrain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bediwy</LastName><ForeName>Adel Salah</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonology, Faculty of Medicine, Tanta University, Tanta 31527, Al Gharbia, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonology, University Medical Center, King Abdulla Medical City, Arabian Gulf University, Manama 26671, Bahrain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>El-Sawaf</LastName><ForeName>Yasser</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Tropical Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Tanta University, Tanta 31527, Al Gharbia, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, University Medical Center, King Abdulla Medical City, Arabian Gulf University, Manama 26671, Bahrain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elbatarny</LastName><ForeName>Akram</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Surgery, Faculty of Medicine, Tanta University, Tanta 31527, Al Gharbia, Egypt.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elbeltagi</LastName><ForeName>Reem</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Royal College of Surgeons in Ireland-Medical University of Bahrain, Busaiteen 15503, Muharraq, Bahrain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Gastroenterol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100883448</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1007-9327</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005767" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gastrointestinal Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005769" MajorTopicYN="N">Gastrointestinal Motility</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D041981" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gastrointestinal Tract</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069196" MajorTopicYN="N">Gastrointestinal Microbiome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise-induced gastrointestinal disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gastrointestinal health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gut microbiota</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gut-brain axis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammatory bowel disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Irritable bowel syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: All the authors report no relevant conflicts of interest for this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40539198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12175863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v31.i22.106835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Monda V, Villano I, Messina A, Valenzano A, Esposito T, Moscatelli F, Viggiano A, Cibelli G, Chieffi S, Monda M, Messina G. Exercise Modifies the Gut Microbiota with Positive Health Effects. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2017;2017:3831972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5357536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28357027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribichini E, Scalese G, Cesarini A, Mocci C, Pallotta N, Severi C, Corazziari ES. Exercise-Induced Gastrointestinal Symptoms in Endurance Sports: A Review of Pathophysiology, Symptoms, and Nutritional Management. Dietetics. 2023;2:289&#x2013;307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira EP, Burini RC, Jeukendrup A. Gastrointestinal complaints during exercise: prevalence, etiology, and nutritional recommendations. Sports Med. 2014;44 Suppl 1:S79&#x2013;S85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24791919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rojas-Valverde D, Bonilla DA, G&#xf3;mez-Miranda LM, Calleja-N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez JJ, Arias N, Mart&#xed;nez-Guardado I. Examining the Interaction between Exercise, Gut Microbiota, and Neurodegeneration: Future Research Directions. Biomedicines. 2023;11:2267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10452292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37626763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wegierska AE, Charitos IA, Topi S, Potenza MA, Montagnani M, Santacroce L. The Connection Between Physical Exercise and Gut Microbiota: Implications for Competitive Sports Athletes. Sports Med. 2022;52:2355&#x2013;2369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9474385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35596883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters HP, De Vries WR, Vanberge-Henegouwen GP, Akkermans LM. Potential benefits and hazards of physical activity and exercise on the gastrointestinal tract. Gut. 2001;48:435&#x2013;439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1760153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11171839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dube A, Gouws C, Breukelman G. Effects of hypohydration and fluid balance in athletes' cognitive performance: a systematic review. Afr Health Sci. 2022;22:367&#x2013;376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9382508</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36032481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wardenaar FC, Schott KD, Mohr AE, Ortega-Santos CP, Connolly JE. An Exploratory Study Investigating the Prevalence of Gastrointestinal Symptoms in Collegiate Division I American Football Athletes. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20:6453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10418726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37568995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papantoniou K, Michailides C, Bali M, Papantoniou P, Thomopoulos K. Gastrointestinal bleeding in athletes. Ann Gastroenterol. 2023;36:267&#x2013;274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10152804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37144023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morton DP, Callister R. Factors influencing exercise-related transient abdominal pain. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2002;34:745&#x2013;749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11984289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lira CAB, Viana RB, Mesquista KP, Santos DAT, Campos MH, Andrade MS, Vancini RL. Frequency and intensity of gastrointestinal symptoms in exercisers individuals at rest and during physical exercise: an internet-based survey. Intest Res. 2019;17:537&#x2013;545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6821937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31060114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly MR, Emerson DM, McDermott BP, Atkins WC, Butts CL, Laursen RM, Troyanos C, Duckett A, Siedlik J. Gastrointestinal cell injury and perceived symptoms after running the Boston Marathon. Front Physiol. 2023;14:1268306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10615131</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37908334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atakan MM, Li Y, Ko&#x15f;ar &#x15e;N, Turnag&#xf6;l HH, Yan X. Evidence-Based Effects of High-Intensity Interval Training on Exercise Capacity and Health: A Review with Historical Perspective. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:7201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8294064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34281138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masterman BJ, Ambulkar T, Hartrick O. Exercise-Induced Ischemic Colitis From Home-Based High-Intensity Interval Training (HIIT) Cureus. 2024;16:e55791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10999238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38586719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart TL, Townsend JR, Grady NJ, Johnson KD, Littlefield LA, Vergne MJ, Fundaro G. Resistance Exercise Increases Gastrointestinal Symptoms, Markers of Gut Permeability, and Damage in Resistance-Trained Adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2022;54:1761&#x2013;1770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35612399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siboni S, Bonavina L, Rogers BD, Egan C, Savarino E, Gyawali CP, DeMeester TR. Effect of Increased Intra-abdominal Pressure on the Esophagogastric Junction: A Systematic Review. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2022;56:821&#x2013;830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9553247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36084164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall V, Taye A, Walsh B, Maguire H, Dave J, Wright A, Anderson C, Crook P. A large outbreak of gastrointestinal illness at an open-water swimming event in the River Thames, London. Epidemiol Infect. 2017;145:1246&#x2013;1255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9507846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28162113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brisebois M, Kramer S, Lindsay KG, Wu CT, Kamla J. Dietary practices and supplement use among CrossFit&#xae; participants. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2022;19:316&#x2013;335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9261745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35813850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tota &#x141;, Piotrowska A, Pa&#x142;ka T, Morawska M, Miku&#x13e;&#xe1;kov&#xe1; W, Mucha D, &#x17b;muda-Pa&#x142;ka M, Pilch W. Muscle and intestinal damage in triathletes. PLoS One. 2019;14:e0210651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6338373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30657773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson PB, Fearn R, Pugh J. Occurrence and Impacts of Gastrointestinal Symptoms in Team-Sport Athletes: A Preliminary Survey. Clin J Sport Med. 2023;33:239&#x2013;245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36476634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naderi A, Gobbi N, Ali A, Berjisian E, Hamidvand A, Forbes SC, Koozehchian MS, Karayigit R, Saunders B. Carbohydrates and Endurance Exercise: A Narrative Review of a Food First Approach. Nutrients. 2023;15:1367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10054587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36986096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonomini-Gnutzmann R, Plaza-D&#xed;az J, Jorquera-Aguilera C, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rodr&#xed;guez A, Rodr&#xed;guez-Rodr&#xed;guez F. Effect of Intensity and Duration of Exercise on Gut Microbiota in Humans: A Systematic Review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:9518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9368618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35954878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson PB, Russell H, Pugh J. Anxiety may be a risk factor for experiencing gastrointestinal symptoms during endurance races: An observational study. Eur J Sport Sci. 2021;21:421&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32251613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amawi A, AlKasasbeh W, Jaradat M, Almasri A, Alobaidi S, Hammad AA, Bishtawi T, Fataftah B, Turk N, Saoud HA, Jarrar A, Ghazzawi H. Athletes' nutritional demands: a narrative review of nutritional requirements. Front Nutr. 2023;10:1331854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10848936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38328685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiorini S, Neri LCL, Guglielmetti M, Pedrolini E, Tagliabue A, Quatromoni PA, Ferraris C. Nutritional counseling in athletes: a systematic review. Front Nutr. 2023;10:1250567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10694452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38053746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;n-Rodr&#xed;guez A, Belinch&#xf3;n-deMiguel P, Rubio-Zarapuz A, Tornero-Aguilera JF, Mart&#xed;nez-Guardado I, Villanueva-Tobaldo CV, Clemente-Su&#xe1;rez VJ. Advances in Understanding the Interplay between Dietary Practices, Body Composition, and Sports Performance in Athletes. Nutrients. 2024;16:571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10892519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38398895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Wijck K, Lenaerts K, van Loon LJ, Peters WH, Buurman WA, Dejong CH. Exercise-induced splanchnic hypoperfusion results in gut dysfunction in healthy men. PLoS One. 2011;6:e22366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3141050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21811592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sales ARK, Azevedo LF, Silva TOC, Rodrigues AG, Oliveira PA, Jord&#xe3;o CP, Andrade ACM, Urias U, Guimaraes GV, Bocchi EA, Alves MJNN, Hajjar LA, Filho RK, Grunewald ZI, Martinez-Lemus LA, Padilla J, Negr&#xe3;o CE. High-Intensity Interval Training Decreases Muscle Sympathetic Nerve Activity and Improves Peripheral Vascular Function in Patients With Heart Failure With Reduced Ejection Fraction. Circ Heart Fail. 2020;13:e007121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32673501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Archontakis-Barakakis P, Mavridis T, Chlorogiannis DD, Barakakis G, Laou E, Sessler DI, Gkiokas G, Chalkias A. Intestinal oxygen utilisation and cellular adaptation during intestinal ischaemia-reperfusion injury. Clin Transl Med. 2025;15:e70136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11670310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39724463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollander D, Kaunitz JD. The "Leaky Gut": Tight Junctions but Loose Associations? Dig Dis Sci. 2020;65:1277&#x2013;1287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7193723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31471860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo WT, Odenwald MA, Turner JR, Zuo L. Tight junction proteins occludin and ZO-1 as regulators of epithelial proliferation and survival. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2022;1514:21&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9427709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35580994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang F, Wang X, Liu Y, Zhang Z. Effects of Exercise-Induced ROS on the Pathophysiological Functions of Skeletal Muscle. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2021;2021:3846122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8500766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34630848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuke N, Nagata N, Suganuma H, Ota T. Regulation of Gut Microbiota and Metabolic Endotoxemia with Dietary Factors. Nutrients. 2019;11:2277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6835897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31547555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roca Rubio MF, Folkesson M, Kremp C, Evertsson N, Repsilber D, Eriksson U, Ganda Mall JP, Kadi F, Brummer RJ, K&#xf6;nig J. Associations between various markers of intestinal barrier and immune function after a high-intensity exercise challenge. Physiol Rep. 2024;12:e16087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11116166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38783385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa RJS, Gaskell SK, McCubbin AJ, Snipe RMJ. Exertional-heat stress-associated gastrointestinal perturbations during Olympic sports: Management strategies for athletes preparing and competing in the 2020 Tokyo Olympic Games. Temperature (Austin) 2020;7:58&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7053925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32166105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Li J, Zhou Q, Wang C, Hu J, Liu C. Effects of Physical Exercise on the Microbiota in Irritable Bowel Syndrome. Nutrients. 2024;16:2657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11356817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39203794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cella V, Bimonte VM, Sabato C, Paoli A, Baldari C, Campanella M, Lenzi A, Ferretti E, Migliaccio S. Nutrition and Physical Activity-Induced Changes in Gut Microbiota: Possible Implications for Human Health and Athletic Performance. Foods. 2021;10:3075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8700881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34945630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao M, Qu Y, Zheng Y, Guo H. The effect of exercise on depression and gut microbiota: Possible mechanisms. Brain Res Bull. 2025;220:111130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39557221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karhu E, Forsg&#xe5;rd RA, Alanko L, Alfthan H, Pussinen P, H&#xe4;m&#xe4;l&#xe4;inen E, Korpela R. Exercise and gastrointestinal symptoms: running-induced changes in intestinal permeability and markers of gastrointestinal function in asymptomatic and symptomatic runners. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2017;117:2519&#x2013;2526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5694518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29032392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerten KA, Richter HE, Wheeler TL 2nd, Pair LS, Burgio KL, Redden DT, Varner RE, Hibner M. Intraabdominal pressure changes associated with lifting: implications for postoperative activity restrictions. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2008;198:306.e1&#x2013;306.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4329922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18068145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark A, Mach N. Exercise-induced stress behavior, gut-microbiota-brain axis and diet: a systematic review for athletes. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2016;13:43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5121944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27924137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browning KN, Travagli RA. Central nervous system control of gastrointestinal motility and secretion and modulation of gastrointestinal functions. Compr Physiol. 2014;4:1339&#x2013;1368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4858318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25428846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>La Torre D, Van Oudenhove L, Vanuytsel T, Verbeke K. Psychosocial stress-induced intestinal permeability in healthy humans: What is the evidence? Neurobiol Stress. 2023;27:100579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10569989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37842017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniela M, Catalina L, Ilie O, Paula M, Daniel-Andrei I, Ioana B. Effects of Exercise Training on the Autonomic Nervous System with a Focus on Anti-Inflammatory and Antioxidants Effects. Antioxidants (Basel) 2022;11:350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8868289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35204231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh R, Zogg H, Wei L, Bartlett A, Ghoshal UC, Rajender S, Ro S. Gut Microbial Dysbiosis in the Pathogenesis of Gastrointestinal Dysmotility and Metabolic Disorders. J Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2021;27:19&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7786094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa RJS, Snipe RMJ, Kitic CM, Gibson PR. Systematic review: exercise-induced gastrointestinal syndrome-implications for health and intestinal disease. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2017;46:246&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28589631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugh JN, Impey SG, Doran DA, Fleming SC, Morton JP, Close GL. Acute high-intensity interval running increases markers of gastrointestinal damage and permeability but not gastrointestinal symptoms. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2017;42:941&#x2013;947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28511020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira EP, Burini RC. Food-dependent, exercise-induced gastrointestinal distress. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2011;8:12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3190328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21955383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor AT. High-altitude illnesses: physiology, risk factors, prevention, and treatment. Rambam Maimonides Med J. 2011;2:e0022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3678789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23908794</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popkin BM, D'Anci KE, Rosenberg IH. Water, hydration, and health. Nutr Rev. 2010;68:439&#x2013;458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2908954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20646222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herdiana Y. Functional Food in Relation to Gastroesophageal Reflux Disease (GERD) Nutrients. 2023;15:3583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10458865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37630773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ter Steege RW, Kolkman JJ. Review article: the pathophysiology and management of gastrointestinal symptoms during physical exercise, and the role of splanchnic blood flow. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2012;35:516&#x2013;528.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22229513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veniamakis E, Kaplanis G, Voulgaris P, Nikolaidis PT. Effects of Sodium Intake on Health and Performance in Endurance and Ultra-Endurance Sports. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:3651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8955583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35329337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohail MU, Yassine HM, Sohail A, Thani AAA. Impact of Physical Exercise on Gut Microbiome, Inflammation, and the Pathobiology of Metabolic Disorders. Rev Diabet Stud. 2019;15:35&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6760895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31380886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdman KA, Jones KW, Madden RF, Gammack N, Parnell JA. Dietary Patterns in Runners with Gastrointestinal Disorders. Nutrients. 2021;13:448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7912258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33572891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aasdahl L, Nilsen TIL, Meisingset I, Nordstoga AL, Evensen KAI, Paulsen J, Mork PJ, Skarpsno ES. Genetic variants related to physical activity or sedentary behaviour: a systematic review. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2021;18:15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7821484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33482856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu HJ, Wu E. The role of gut microbiota in immune homeostasis and autoimmunity. Gut Microbes. 2012;3:4&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3337124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22356853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conlon MA, Bird AR. The impact of diet and lifestyle on gut microbiota and human health. Nutrients. 2014;7:17&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4303825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25545101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau WY, Kato H, Nosaka K. Water intake after dehydration makes muscles more susceptible to cramp but electrolytes reverse that effect. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med. 2019;5:e000478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6407543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30899546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong LE, Lee EC, Armstrong EM. Interactions of Gut Microbiota, Endotoxemia, Immune Function, and Diet in Exertional Heatstroke. J Sports Med (Hindawi Publ Corp) 2018;2018:5724575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5926483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29850597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes RL, Holscher HD. Fueling Gut Microbes: A Review of the Interaction between Diet, Exercise, and the Gut Microbiota in Athletes. Adv Nutr. 2021;12:2190&#x2013;2215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8634498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34229348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang W, Liu Y, Yang G, Meng B, Yi Z, Yang G, Chen M, Hou P, Wang H, Xu X. Moderate-Intensity Physical Exercise Affects the Exercise Performance and Gut Microbiota of Mice. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2021;11:712381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8498591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34631598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubert C, Kong G, Renoir T, Hannan AJ. Exercise, diet and stress as modulators of gut microbiota: Implications for neurodegenerative diseases. Neurobiol Dis. 2020;134:104621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31628992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakagawa H, Sasai H, Kato Y, Matsumoto S, Tanaka K. Exercise, Dietary Habits, and Defecatory Dysfunction in Patients Living with Colorectal Cancer: A Preliminary Quantitative Study. Healthcare (Basel) 2024;12:1136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11171757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38891211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thyfault JP, Bergouignan A. Exercise and metabolic health: beyond skeletal muscle. Diabetologia. 2020;63:1464&#x2013;1474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7377236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32529412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candelli M, Franza L, Pignataro G, Ojetti V, Covino M, Piccioni A, Gasbarrini A, Franceschi F. Interaction between Lipopolysaccharide and Gut Microbiota in Inflammatory Bowel Diseases. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:6242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8226948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34200555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carco C, Young W, Gearry RB, Talley NJ, McNabb WC, Roy NC. Increasing Evidence That Irritable Bowel Syndrome and Functional Gastrointestinal Disorders Have a Microbial Pathogenesis. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2020;10:468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7509092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33014892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reid G, Dhir R, Bron PA. Fixing Functional GI Disorders Using Microbes: Easier Said Than Done. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2022;13:804179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8963371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35360061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Effendi RMRA, Anshory M, Kalim H, Dwiyana RF, Suwarsa O, Pardo LM, Nijsten TEC, Thio HB. Akkermansia muciniphila and Faecalibacterium prausnitzii in Immune-Related Diseases. Microorganisms. 2022;10:2382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9782003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36557635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan J, Sheng L, Li H. Akkermansia muciniphila: is it the Holy Grail for ameliorating metabolic diseases? Gut Microbes. 2021;13:1984104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8726741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34674606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin Y, Han S, Kwon J, Ju S, Choi TG, Kang I, Kim SS. Roles of Short-Chain Fatty Acids in Inflammatory Bowel Disease. Nutrients. 2023;15:4466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10609902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37892541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leech B, McIntyre E, Steel A, Sibbritt D. Risk factors associated with intestinal permeability in an adult population: A systematic review. Int J Clin Pract. 2019;73:e13385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31243854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ney LM, Wipplinger M, Grossmann M, Engert N, Wegner VD, Mosig AS. Short chain fatty acids: key regulators of the local and systemic immune response in inflammatory diseases and infections. Open Biol. 2023;13:230014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10049789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36977462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolte S, Kr&#xfc;ger K, Lenz C, Zentgraf K. Optimizing the Gut Microbiota for Individualized Performance Development in Elite Athletes. Biology (Basel) 2023;12:1491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10740793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38132317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez IG, Mika AS, Biesiekierski JR, Costa RJS. The Effect of Gut-Training and Feeding-Challenge on Markers of Gastrointestinal Status in Response to Endurance Exercise: A Systematic Literature Review. Sports Med. 2023;53:1175&#x2013;1200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10185635</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37061651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>la Torre ME, Monda A, Messina A, de Stefano MI, Monda V, Moscatelli F, Tafuri F, Saraiello E, Latino F, Monda M, Messina G, Polito R, Tafuri D. The Potential Role of Nutrition in Overtraining Syndrome: A Narrative Review. Nutrients. 2023;15:4916.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10708264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38068774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urwin CS, Main LC, Mikocka-Walus A, Skvarc DR, Roberts SSH, Condo D, Carr AJ, Convit L, Jardine W, Rahman SS, Snipe RMJ. The Relationship Between Psychological Stress and Anxiety with Gastrointestinal Symptoms Before and During a 56 km Ultramarathon Running Race. Sports Med Open. 2021;7:93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8665950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34897557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grames C, Berry-Cab&#xe1;n CS. Ischemic colitis in an endurance runner. Case Rep Gastrointest Med. 2012;2012:356895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3474219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23091744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damian MT, Vulturar R, Login CC, Damian L, Chis A, Bojan A. Anemia in Sports: A Narrative Review. Life (Basel) 2021;11:987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8472039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34575136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashton T, Young IS, Davison GW, Rowlands CC, McEneny J, Van Blerk C, Jones E, Peters JR, Jackson SK. Exercise-induced endotoxemia: the effect of ascorbic acid supplementation. Free Radic Biol Med. 2003;35:284&#x2013;291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12885590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson PB. 'I think I'm gonna hurl': A Narrative Review of the Causes of Nausea and Vomiting in Sport. Sports (Basel) 2019;7:162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6680692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31277403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaffar D, Rivera E, Schwartz S, Ali O, Greenwald BD. Soccer Game Turned Bloody: A Case of Exercise-Induced Ischemic Colitis. ACG Case Rep J. 2024;11:e01406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11191889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38912376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pugh JN, Lydon KM, O'Donovan CM, O'Sullivan O, Madigan SM. More than a gut feeling: What is the role of the gastrointestinal tract in female athlete health? Eur J Sport Sci. 2022;22:755&#x2013;764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33944684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carmichael MA, Thomson RL, Moran LJ, Wycherley TP. The Impact of Menstrual Cycle Phase on Athletes' Performance: A Narrative Review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:1667.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7916245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33572406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagim AR, Fields J, Magee MK, Kerksick CM, Jones MT. Contributing Factors to Low Energy Availability in Female Athletes: A Narrative Review of Energy Availability, Training Demands, Nutrition Barriers, Body Image, and Disordered Eating. Nutrients. 2022;14:986.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8912784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35267961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coelho AR, Cardoso G, Brito ME, Gomes IN, Cascais MJ. The Female Athlete Triad/Relative Energy Deficiency in Sports (RED-S) Rev Bras Ginecol Obstet. 2021;43:395&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10304901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34077990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oester C, Norris D, Scott D, Pedlar C, Bruinvels G, Lovell R. Inconsistencies in the perceived impact of the menstrual cycle on sport performance and in the prevalence of menstrual cycle symptoms: A scoping review of the literature. J Sci Med Sport. 2024;27:373&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38508888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niering M, Wolf-Belala N, Seifert J, Tovar O, Coldewey J, Kuranda J, Muehlbauer T. The Influence of Menstrual Cycle Phases on Maximal Strength Performance in Healthy Female Adults: A Systematic Review with Meta-Analysis. Sports (Basel) 2024;12:31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10818650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38251305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holtzman B, Ackerman KE. Recommendations and Nutritional Considerations for Female Athletes: Health and Performance. Sports Med. 2021;51:43&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8566643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34515972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumic I, Nordin T, Jecmenica M, Stojkovic Lalosevic M, Milosavljevic T, Milovanovic T. Gastrointestinal Tract Disorders in Older Age. Can J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2019;2019:6757524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6354172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30792972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhutto A, Morley JE. The clinical significance of gastrointestinal changes with aging. Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2008;11:651&#x2013;660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18685464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tursi A, Scarpignato C, Strate LL, Lanas A, Kruis W, Lahat A, Danese S. Colonic diverticular disease. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2020;6:20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7486966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32218442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Xiao X, Zhang X. Hydration Status in Older Adults: Current Knowledge and Future Challenges. Nutrients. 2023;15:2609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10255140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37299572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zabawa B, Sadowski J, M&#xf3;l P, Papie&#x17c; &#x141;S, Do&#x142;&#x119;ga J, Krzykawski K, Maciejczyk T, Sie&#x144;ko A, &#x141;abu&#x15b; M, Hudzi&#x144;ska P. The Impact of Physical Activity on Digestive System Diseases. Qual Sport. 2024;34:56112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Wijck K, Lenaerts K, Grootjans J, Wijnands KA, Poeze M, van Loon LJ, Dejong CH, Buurman WA. Physiology and pathophysiology of splanchnic hypoperfusion and intestinal injury during exercise: strategies for evaluation and prevention. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2012;303:G155&#x2013;G168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22517770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dj&#xe4;rv T, Wikman A, Nordenstedt H, Johar A, Lagergren J, Lagergren P. Physical activity, obesity and gastroesophageal reflux disease in the general population. World J Gastroenterol. 2012;18:3710&#x2013;3714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3406423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22851863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sodhi JS, Zargar SA, Javid G, Khan MA, Khan BA, Yattoo GN, Shah A, Gulzar GM, Shoukat A. Effect of bending exercise on gastroesophageal reflux in symptomatic patients. Indian J Gastroenterol. 2008;27:227&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19405255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendes-Filho AM, Moraes-Filho JP, Nasi A, Eisig JN, Rodrigues TN, Barbutti RC, Campos JM, Chinzon D. Influence of exercise testing in gastroesophageal reflux in patients with gastroesophageal reflux disease. Arq Bras Cir Dig. 2014;27:3&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4675480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24676289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu C, Wang T, Gao Y, Jiao Y, Jiang H, Bian Y, Wang W, Lin H, Xin L, Wang L. Association between physical activity and risk of gastroesophageal reflux disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci. 2024;13:687&#x2013;698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11282378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38552714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Serag HB, Ergun GA, Pandolfino J, Fitzgerald S, Tran T, Kramer JR. Obesity increases oesophageal acid exposure. Gut. 2007;56:749&#x2013;755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1954847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17127706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zdrhova L, Bitnar P, Balihar K, Kolar P, Madle K, Martinek M, Pandolfino JE, Martinek J. Breathing Exercises in Gastroesophageal Reflux Disease: A Systematic Review. Dysphagia. 2023;38:609&#x2013;621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9888515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35842548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karrfalt E. A Simple Exercise to Strengthen the Lower Esophageal Sphincter and Eliminate Gastroesophageal Reflux: An Autobiographical Case Report. Cureus. 2022;14:e24122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9106553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35573490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang JH, Kang JY. Lifestyle measures in the management of gastro-oesophageal reflux disease: clinical and pathophysiological considerations. Ther Adv Chronic Dis. 2015;6:51&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4331235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25729556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ness-Jensen E, Hveem K, El-Serag H, Lagergren J. Lifestyle Intervention in Gastroesophageal Reflux Disease. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2016;14:175&#x2013;82.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4636482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25956834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narayanan M, Reddy KM, Marsicano E. Peptic Ulcer Disease and Helicobacter pylori infection. Mo Med. 2018;115:219&#x2013;224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6140150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30228726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A, Shetty S, Mutalik S, Chandrashekar H R, K N, Mathew EM, Jha A, Mishra B, Rajpurohit S, Ravi G, Saha M, Moorkoth S. Treatment of H. pylori infection and gastric ulcer: Need for novel Pharmaceutical formulation. Heliyon. 2023;9:e20406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10550623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37810864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ribeiro FM, Petriz B, Marques G, Kamilla LH, Franco OL. Is There an Exercise-Intensity Threshold Capable of Avoiding the Leaky Gut? Front Nutr. 2021;8:627289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7982409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33763441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng Y, Macera CA, Davis DR, Blair SN. Does physical activity reduce the risk of developing peptic ulcers? Br J Sports Med. 2000;34:116&#x2013;121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1724173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10786867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shephard RJ. Peptic Ulcer and Exercise. Sports Med. 2017;47:33&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27282926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vomero ND, Colpo E. Nutritional care in peptic ulcer. Arq Bras Cir Dig. 2014;27:298&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4743227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25626944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Guo X, An Y, Xu S, Zhang D, Qin Y, Qi X. Risk Factors of Peptic Ulcer in Military Personnel: A Systematic Review of the Literature. Explor Res Hypothesis Med. 2020;5:103&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang YJ. An Overview of Current Physical Activity Recommendations in Primary Care. Korean J Fam Med. 2019;40:135&#x2013;142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6536904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31122003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang YT, Huang G, Duke G, Yang Y. Tai Chi, Yoga, and Qigong as Mind-Body Exercises. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2017;2017:8763915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5244011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28154608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie F, You Y, Huang J, Guan C, Chen Z, Fang M, Yao F, Han J. Association between physical activity and digestive-system cancer: An updated systematic review and meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci. 2021;10:4&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7856558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33010525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boytar AN, Nitert MD, Morrision M, Skinner TL, Jenkins DG. Exercise-induced changes to the human gut microbiota and implications for colorectal cancer: a narrative review. J Physiol. 2022;600:5189&#x2013;5201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10099575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36369926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerhardsson M, Floderus B, Norell SE. Physical activity and colon cancer risk. Int J Epidemiol. 1988;17:743&#x2013;746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3272134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jurdana M. Physical activity and cancer risk. Actual knowledge and possible biological mechanisms. Radiol Oncol. 2021;55:7&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7877262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33885236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spanoudaki M, Giaginis C, Karafyllaki D, Papadopoulos K, Solovos E, Antasouras G, Sfikas G, Papadopoulos AN, Papadopoulou SK. Exercise as a Promising Agent against Cancer: Evaluating Its Anti-Cancer Molecular Mechanisms. Cancers (Basel) 2023;15:5135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10648074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37958310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janjua S, Brown M, Parker R, Prue G, Closier P, Cramp F. Physical activity for the management of cancer&#x2010;related fatigue in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2022;2022:CD015348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amirsasan R, Akbarzadeh M, Akbarzadeh S. Exercise and colorectal cancer: prevention and molecular mechanisms. Cancer Cell Int. 2022;22:247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9361674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35945569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung Y, Chung J, Son H. Physical Activity Interventions for Colorectal Cancer Survivors: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials. Cancer Nurs. 2021;44:E414&#x2013;E428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8560161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34694086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koelwyn GJ, Wennerberg E, Demaria S, Jones LW. Exercise in Regulation of Inflammation-Immune Axis Function in Cancer Initiation and Progression. Oncology (Williston Park) 2015;29:908&#x2013;920, 922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4909049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26676894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciernikova S, Sevcikova A, Stevurkova V, Mego M. Diet-driven microbiome changes and physical activity in cancer patients. Front Nutr. 2023;10:1285516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10704146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38075222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell KL, Winters-Stone KM, Wiskemann J, May AM, Schwartz AL, Courneya KS, Zucker DS, Matthews CE, Ligibel JA, Gerber LH, Morris GS, Patel AV, Hue TF, Perna FM, Schmitz KH. Exercise Guidelines for Cancer Survivors: Consensus Statement from International Multidisciplinary Roundtable. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2019;51:2375&#x2013;2390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8576825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31626055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mustian KM, Sprod LK, Janelsins M, Peppone LJ, Mohile S. Exercise Recommendations for Cancer-Related Fatigue, Cognitive Impairment, Sleep problems, Depression, Pain, Anxiety, and Physical Dysfunction: A Review. Oncol Hematol Rev. 2012;8:81&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3647480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23667857</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-Vizca&#xed;no V, Cavero-Redondo I, Reina-Guti&#xe9;rrez S, Gracia-Marco L, Gil-Cosano JJ, Bizzozero-Peroni B, Rodriguez-Artalejo F, Ubago-Guisado E. Comparative effects of different types of exercise on health-related quality of life during and after active cancer treatment: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci. 2023;12:726&#x2013;738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10658325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36736726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Portincasa P, Di Ciaula A, Bonfrate L, Stella A, Garruti G, Lamont JT. Metabolic dysfunction-associated gallstone disease: expecting more from critical care manifestations. Intern Emerg Med. 2023;18:1897&#x2013;1918.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10543156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37455265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanmugam H, Molina Molina E, Di Palo DM, Faienza MF, Di Ciaula A, Garruti G, Wang DQH, Portincasa P. Physical Activity Modulating Lipid Metabolism in Gallbladder Diseases. J Gastrointestin Liver Dis. 2020;29:99&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8114792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32176752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Z, Xie J, Ni X, Yang J, Li J, Xuan Y, Gu H. Physical activity and risk of cholelithiasis: a narrative review. Front Med (Lausanne) 2024;11:1485097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11682901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39736973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molina-Molina E, Lunardi Baccetto R, Wang DQ, de Bari O, Krawczyk M, Portincasa P. Exercising the hepatobiliary-gut axis. The impact of physical activity performance. Eur J Clin Invest. 2018;48:e12958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8118139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29797516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franczyk B, Gluba-Brz&#xf3;zka A, Cia&#x142;kowska-Rysz A, &#x141;awi&#x144;ski J, Rysz J. The Impact of Aerobic Exercise on HDL Quantity and Quality: A Narrative Review. Int J Mol Sci. 2023;24:4653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10003711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36902082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shephard RJ. Physical Activity and the Biliary Tract in Health and Disease. Sports Med. 2015;45:1295&#x2013;1309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26068960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bulut G, Karabulut N. The Effects of Breathing Exercises on Patients Having Laparoscopic Cholecystectomy Surgery. Clin Nurs Res. 2023;32:805&#x2013;814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36759970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misciagna G, Centonze S, Leoci C, Guerra V, Cisternino AM, Ceo R, Trevisan M. Diet, physical activity, and gallstones--a population-based, case-control study in southern Italy. Am J Clin Nutr. 1999;69:120&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9925133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen D, Zhang H, Shao J, Tang L, Wu J, Ye Z. Summary of the best evidence of diet and physical activity management in patients with metabolic syndrome. Zhejiang Da Xue Xue Bao Yi Xue Ban. 2022;51:27&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9109769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35576114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saha L. Irritable bowel syndrome: pathogenesis, diagnosis, treatment, and evidence-based medicine. World J Gastroenterol. 2014;20:6759&#x2013;6773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4051916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24944467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunan D, Cai T, Gardener AD, Ord&#xf3;&#xf1;ez-Mena JM, Roberts NW, Thomas ET, Mahtani KR. Physical activity for treatment of irritable bowel syndrome. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2022;6:CD011497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9243367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35766861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johannesson E, Ringstr&#xf6;m G, Abrahamsson H, Sadik R. Intervention to increase physical activity in irritable bowel syndrome shows long-term positive effects. World J Gastroenterol. 2015;21:600&#x2013;608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4294172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25593485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anastasi JK, Capili B, Chang M. Managing irritable bowel syndrome. Am J Nurs. 2013;113:42&#x2013;52; quiz 54, 53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5654469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23764698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riezzo G, Prospero L, D'Attoma B, Ignazzi A, Bianco A, Franco I, Curci R, Campanella A, Bonfiglio C, Osella AR, Russo F. The Impact of a Twelve-Week Moderate Aerobic Exercise Program on Gastrointestinal Symptom Profile and Psychological Well-Being of Irritable Bowel Syndrome Patients: Preliminary Data from a Southern Italy Cohort. J Clin Med. 2023;12:5359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10455088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37629401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain MN, Lee J, Choi H, Kwak YS, Kim J. The impact of exercise on depression: how moving makes your brain and body feel better. Phys Act Nutr. 2024;28:43&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11298280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39097997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Silva A, Marshall DA, Vallance JK, Nasser Y, Rajagopalan V, Szostakiwskyj JH, Raman M. Meditation and Yoga for Irritable Bowel Syndrome: A Randomized Clinical Trial. Am J Gastroenterol. 2023;118:329&#x2013;337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9889201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36422517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Napolitano M, Fasulo E, Ungaro F, Massimino L, Sinagra E, Danese S, Mandarino FV. Gut Dysbiosis in Irritable Bowel Syndrome: A Narrative Review on Correlation with Disease Subtypes and Novel Therapeutic Implications. Microorganisms. 2023;11:2369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10609453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37894027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YS, Song BK, Oh JS, Woo SS. Aerobic exercise improves gastrointestinal motility in psychiatric inpatients. World J Gastroenterol. 2014;20:10577&#x2013;10584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4130869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25132778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schumann D, Anheyer D, Lauche R, Dobos G, Langhorst J, Cramer H. Effect of Yoga in the Therapy of Irritable Bowel Syndrome: A Systematic Review. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2016;14:1720&#x2013;1731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27112106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niemann MJ, Tucker LA, Bailey BW, Davidson LE. Strength Training and Insulin Resistance: The Mediating Role of Body Composition. J Diabetes Res. 2020;2020:7694825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7235686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32455135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radziszewska M, Smarkusz-Zarzecka J, Ostrowska L. Nutrition, Physical Activity and Supplementation in Irritable Bowel Syndrome. Nutrients. 2023;15:3662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10459186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37630852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naliboff BD, Smith SR, Serpa JG, Laird KT, Stains J, Connolly LS, Labus JS, Tillisch K. Mindfulness-based stress reduction improves irritable bowel syndrome (IBS) symptoms via specific aspects of mindfulness. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2020;32:e13828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32266762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilski J, Brzozowski B, Mazur-Bialy A, Sliwowski Z, Brzozowski T. The role of physical exercise in inflammatory bowel disease. Biomed Res Int. 2014;2014:429031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4022156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24877092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalili H, Ananthakrishnan AN, Konijeti GG, Liao X, Higuchi LM, Fuchs CS, Spiegelman D, Richter JM, Korzenik JR, Chan AT. Physical activity and risk of inflammatory bowel disease: prospective study from the Nurses' Health Study cohorts. BMJ. 2013;347:f6633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3935281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24231178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Q, Xu KQ, Qin XR, Wen-Lu, Yan-Liu, Wang XY. Association between physical activity and inflammatory bowel disease risk: A meta-analysis. Dig Liver Dis. 2016;48:1425&#x2013;1431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27671622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engels M, Cross RK, Long MD. Exercise in patients with inflammatory bowel diseases: current perspectives. Clin Exp Gastroenterol. 2018;11:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5743119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29317842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holik D, V&#x10d;ev A, Milosti&#x107;-Srb A, Salinger &#x17d;, Ivani&#x161;evi&#x107; Z, V&#x10d;ev I, Mi&#x161;kulin M. The Effect of Daily Physical Activity on the Activity of Inflammatory Bowel Diseases In Therapy-Free Patients. Acta Clin Croat. 2019;58:202&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6884387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31819315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legeret C, M&#xe4;hlmann L, Gerber M, Kalak N, K&#xf6;hler H, Holsboer-Trachsler E, Brand S, Furlano R. Favorable impact of long-term exercise on disease symptoms in pediatric patients with inflammatory bowel disease. BMC Pediatr. 2019;19:297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6710863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31455308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narula N, Fedorak RN. Exercise and inflammatory bowel disease. Can J Gastroenterol. 2008;22:497&#x2013;504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2660805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18478136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ordille AJ, Phadtare S. Intensity-specific considerations for exercise for patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Gastroenterol Rep (Oxf) 2023;11:goad004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9940700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36814502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bower JE, Irwin MR. Mind-body therapies and control of inflammatory biology: A descriptive review. Brain Behav Immun. 2016;51:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4679419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26116436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talutis SD, Kuhnen FAH. Pathophysiology and Epidemiology of Diverticular Disease. Clin Colon Rectal Surg. 2021;34:81&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7904337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33642946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strate LL, Liu YL, Aldoori WH, Giovannucci EL. Physical activity decreases diverticular complications. Am J Gastroenterol. 2009;104:1221&#x2013;1230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3144158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19367267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peery AF, Sandler RS, Ahnen DJ, Galanko JA, Holm AN, Shaukat A, Mott LA, Barry EL, Fried DA, Baron JA. Constipation and a low-fiber diet are not associated with diverticulosis. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2013;11:1622&#x2013;1627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3840096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23891924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieman DC, Wentz LM. The compelling link between physical activity and the body's defense system. J Sport Health Sci. 2019;8:201&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6523821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31193280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strate LL, Liu YL, Aldoori WH, Syngal S, Giovannucci EL. Obesity increases the risks of diverticulitis and diverticular bleeding. Gastroenterology. 2009;136:115&#x2013;122.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2643271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18996378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boynton W, Floch M. New strategies for the management of diverticular disease: insights for the clinician. Therap Adv Gastroenterol. 2013;6:205&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3625022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23634185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams PT. Incident diverticular disease is inversely related to vigorous physical activity. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41:1042&#x2013;1047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2831405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19346983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moses FM. Gastrointestinal bleeding and the athlete. Am J Gastroenterol. 1993;88:1157&#x2013;1159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8338081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baska RS, Moses FM, Graeber G, Kearney G. Gastrointestinal bleeding during an ultramarathon. Dig Dis Sci. 1990;35:276&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2302987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodr&#xed;guez de Santiago E, Aguilera Castro L, Garc&#xed;a Garc&#xed;a de Paredes A, Ferre Aracil C, Mart&#xed;n de Argila de Prados C. Upper gastrointestinal bleeding secondary to vigorous physical exercise. Rev Gastroenterol Mex (Engl Ed) 2018;83:350&#x2013;351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28347530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaub N, Spichtin HP, Stalder GA. [Ischemic colitis as a cause of intestinal bleeding after marathon running] Schweiz Med Wochenschr. 1985;115:454&#x2013;457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3873109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper BT, Douglas SA, Firth LA, Hannagan JA, Chadwick VS. Erosive gastritis and gastrointestinal bleeding in a female runner. Prevention of the bleeding and healing of the gastritis with H2-receptor antagonists. Gastroenterology. 1987;92:2019&#x2013;2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2883068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keating SE, Sabag A, Hallsworth K, Hickman IJ, Macdonald GA, Stine JG, George J, Johnson NA. Exercise in the Management of Metabolic-Associated Fatty Liver Disease (MAFLD) in Adults: A Position Statement from Exercise and Sport Science Australia. Sports Med. 2023;53:2347&#x2013;2371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10687186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37695493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halvorsen FA, Lyng J, Ritland S. Gastrointestinal bleeding in marathon runners. Scand J Gastroenterol. 1986;21:493&#x2013;497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3487825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCabe ME 3rd, Peura DA, Kadakia SC, Bocek Z, Johnson LF. Gastrointestinal blood loss associated with running a marathon. Dig Dis Sci. 1986;31:1229&#x2013;1232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3490362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi SC, Choi SJ, Kim JA, Kim TH, Nah YH, Yazaki E, Evans DF. The role of gastrointestinal endoscopy in long-distance runners with gastrointestinal symptoms. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2001;13:1089&#x2013;1094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11564961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akerman AP, Tipton M, Minson CT, Cotter JD. Heat stress and dehydration in adapting for performance: Good, bad, both, or neither? Temperature (Austin) 2016;3:412&#x2013;436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5356617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28349082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohail R, Mathew M, Patel KK, Reddy SA, Haider Z, Naria M, Habib A, Abdin ZU, Razzaq Chaudhry W, Akbar A. Effects of Non-steroidal Anti-inflammatory Drugs (NSAIDs) and Gastroprotective NSAIDs on the Gastrointestinal Tract: A Narrative Review. Cureus. 2023;15:e37080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10156439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37153279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakonyi P, Kolonics A, Aczel D, Zhou L, Mozaffaritabar S, Moln&#xe1;r K, L&#xe1;szl&#xf3; L, Kutasi B, Tanisawa K, Park J, Gu Y, Pinho RA, Radak Z. Voluntary exercise does not increase gastrointestinal motility but increases spatial memory, intestinal eNOS, Akt levels, and Bifidobacteria abundance in the microbiome. Front Physiol. 2023;14:1173636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10468588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37664431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chao WC, Huang JC, Young SL, Wu CL, Shih JC, Liao LD, Cheng B. Interplay of yoga, physical activity, and probiotics in irritable bowel syndrome management: A double-blind randomized study. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2024;57:101892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39126817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao R, Tao Y, Zhou C, Li J, Wang X, Chen L, Li F, Guo L. Exercise therapy in patients with constipation: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Scand J Gastroenterol. 2019;54:169&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30843436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolk A, Holmstr&#xf6;m B, Johansson C, Frostell C, Nilsson BY. The effect of yoga on puborectalis paradox. Int J Colorectal Dis. 1991;6:139&#x2013;142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1744484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbott R, Lavretsky H. Tai Chi and Qigong for the treatment and prevention of mental disorders. Psychiatr Clin North Am. 2013;36:109&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3917559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23538081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui J, Xie F, Yue H, Xie C, Ma J, Han H, Fang M, Yao F. Physical activity and constipation: A systematic review of cohort studies. J Glob Health. 2024;14:04197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11583288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39575759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang L, Liu Y, Wang X, Zhang X. Physical Exercise and Diet: Regulation of Gut Microbiota to Prevent and Treat Metabolic Disorders to Maintain Health. Nutrients. 2023;15:1539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10054346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36986268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stults-Kolehmainen MA, Sinha R. The effects of stress on physical activity and exercise. Sports Med. 2014;44:81&#x2013;121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3894304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24030837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner A, Kapounkov&#xe1; K, Struh&#xe1;r I. The relationship between the gut microbiome and resistance training: a rapid review. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2024;16:4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10763211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38166998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundell J. Resistance Training Is an Effective Tool against Metabolic and Frailty Syndromes. Adv Prev Med. 2011;2011:984683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3168930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21991450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shree Ganesh HR, Subramanya P, Rao M R, Udupa V. Role of yoga therapy in improving digestive health and quality of sleep in an elderly population: A randomized controlled trial. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2021;27:692&#x2013;697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34391308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakur ER, Shapiro JM, Wellington J, Sohl SJ, Danhauer SC, Moshiree B, Ford AC, Koch K. A systematic review of yoga for the treatment of gastrointestinal disorders. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2024:e14915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39285826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kloubec J. Pilates: how does it work and who needs it? Muscles Ligaments Tendons J. 2011;1:61&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3666467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23738249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staller K, Paz M, Rones R, Macklin EA, Garcia-Fischer I, Murray HB, Kuo B. Virtual Tai Chi program for patients with irritable bowel syndrome with constipation: Proof-of-concept feasibility trial. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2022;34:e14429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11294908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35833716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamasaki H. Exercise and gut microbiota: clinical implications for the feasibility of Tai Chi. J Integr Med. 2017;15:270&#x2013;281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28659231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franco I, Bianco A, Prospero L, Riezzo G, Bonfiglio C, Bagnato CB, Verrelli N, Goscilo F, D'Attoma B, Ignazzi A, Coletta S, Refolo MG, Donghia R, Russo F. StepFit-18K: Improving Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS) Symptoms with a Simple, Structured Walking Intervention. J Clin Med. 2024;13:6684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11594471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39597828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards KH, Ahuja KD, Watson G, Dowling C, Musgrave H, Reyes J, Cherry J, Kitic CM. The influence of exercise intensity and exercise mode on gastrointestinal damage. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2021;46:1105&#x2013;1110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33725465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maillard F, Pereira B, Boisseau N. Effect of High-Intensity Interval Training on Total, Abdominal and Visceral Fat Mass: A Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. 2018;48:269&#x2013;288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29127602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parnell JA, Wagner-Jones K, Madden RF, Erdman KA. Dietary restrictions in endurance runners to mitigate exercise-induced gastrointestinal symptoms. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2020;17:32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7288429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32522222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson E. Nutritional implications for ultra-endurance walking and running events. Extrem Physiol Med. 2016;5:13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5117571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27895900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranchordas MK, Dawson JT, Russell M. Practical nutritional recovery strategies for elite soccer players when limited time separates repeated matches. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2017;14:35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5596842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28919844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanhauwaert E, Matthys C, Verdonck L, De Preter V. Low-residue and low-fiber diets in gastrointestinal disease management. Adv Nutr. 2015;6:820&#x2013;827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4642427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26567203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan T, Daly E, Ryan L. Exploring the Nutrition Strategies Employed by Ultra-Endurance Athletes to Alleviate Exercise-Induced Gastrointestinal Symptoms-A Systematic Review. Nutrients. 2023;15:4330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10610183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37892406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szilagyi A, Ishayek N. Lactose Intolerance, Dairy Avoidance, and Treatment Options. Nutrients. 2018;10:1994.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6316316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30558337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nehlig A. Effects of Coffee on the Gastro-Intestinal Tract: A Narrative Review and Literature Update. Nutrients. 2022;14:399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8778943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35057580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerksick CM, Arent S, Schoenfeld BJ, Stout JR, Campbell B, Wilborn CD, Taylor L, Kalman D, Smith-Ryan AE, Kreider RB, Willoughby D, Arciero PJ, VanDusseldorp TA, Ormsbee MJ, Wildman R, Greenwood M, Ziegenfuss TN, Aragon AA, Antonio J. International society of sports nutrition position stand: nutrient timing. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2017;14:33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5596471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28919842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vitale K, Getzin A. Nutrition and Supplement Update for the Endurance Athlete: Review and Recommendations. Nutrients. 2019;11:1289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6628334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31181616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez-Castillo &#xcd;M, Williams JA, L&#xf3;pez-Chicharro J, Mihic N, Rueda R, Bouzamondo H, Horswill CA. Compositional Aspects of Beverages Designed to Promote Hydration Before, During, and After Exercise: Concepts Revisited. Nutrients. 2023;16:17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10781183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38201848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong LE. Rehydration during Endurance Exercise: Challenges, Research, Options, Methods. Nutrients. 2021;13:887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8001428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33803421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau WY, Kato H, Nosaka K. Effect of oral rehydration solution versus spring water intake during exercise in the heat on muscle cramp susceptibility of young men. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2021;18:22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7962362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33722257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray D, Miller KC, Edwards JE. Does a Reduction in Serum Sodium Concentration or Serum Potassium Concentration Increase the Prevalence of Exercise-Associated Muscle Cramps? J Sport Rehabil. 2016;25:301&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25945453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anastasiou CA, Kavouras SA, Arnaoutis G, Gioxari A, Kollia M, Botoula E, Sidossis LS. Sodium replacement and plasma sodium drop during exercise in the heat when fluid intake matches fluid loss. J Athl Train. 2009;44:117&#x2013;123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2657026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19295955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Duvillard SP, Arciero PJ, Tietjen-Smith T, Alford K. Sports drinks, exercise training, and competition. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2008;7:202&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18607221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boytar AN, Skinner TL, Wallen RE, Jenkins DG, Dekker Nitert M. The Effect of Exercise Prescription on the Human Gut Microbiota and Comparison between Clinical and Apparently Healthy Populations: A Systematic Review. Nutrients. 2023;15:1534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10054511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36986264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gisolfi CV. Is the GI System Built For Exercise? News Physiol Sci. 2000;15:114&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11390892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racinais S, Alonso JM, Coutts AJ, Flouris AD, Girard O, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Alonso J, Hausswirth C, Jay O, Lee JK, Mitchell N, Nassis GP, Nybo L, Pluim BM, Roelands B, Sawka MN, Wingo J, P&#xe9;riard JD. Consensus recommendations on training and competing in the heat. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49:1164&#x2013;1173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4602249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26069301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sumi D, Nagatsuka H, Matsuo K, Okazaki K, Goto K. The Impact of Heat Acclimation on Gastrointestinal Function following Endurance Exercise in a Hot Environment. Nutrients. 2023;15:216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9823684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36615873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podlogar T, Wallis GA. New Horizons in Carbohydrate Research and Application for Endurance Athletes. Sports Med. 2022;52:5&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9734239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36173597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes DC, Ellefsen S, Baar K. Adaptations to Endurance and Strength Training. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med. 2018;8:a029769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5983157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28490537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x141;agowska K, Bajerska J, Kami&#x144;ski S, Del Bo' C. Effects of Probiotics Supplementation on Gastrointestinal Symptoms in Athletes: A Systematic Review of Randomized Controlled Trials. Nutrients. 2022;14:2645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9268154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35807826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiller LR, Santa Ana CA, Morawski SG, Fordtran JS. Mechanism of the antidiarrheal effect of loperamide. Gastroenterology. 1984;86:1475&#x2013;1480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6714575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiller R, Aziz Q, Creed F, Emmanuel A, Houghton L, Hungin P, Jones R, Kumar D, Rubin G, Trudgill N, Whorwell P Clinical Services Committee of The British Society of Gastroenterology. Guidelines on the irritable bowel syndrome: mechanisms and practical management. Gut. 2007;56:1770&#x2013;1798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2095723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17488783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg V, Narang P, Taneja R. Antacids revisited: review on contemporary facts and relevance for self-management. J Int Med Res. 2022;50:3000605221086457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8966100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35343261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji J, Jin W, Liu SJ, Jiao Z, Li X. Probiotics, prebiotics, and postbiotics in health and disease. MedComm (2020) 2023;4:e420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10625129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37929014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latif A, Shehzad A, Niazi S, Zahid A, Ashraf W, Iqbal MW, Rehman A, Riaz T, Aadil RM, Khan IM, &#xd6;zogul F, Rocha JM, Esatbeyoglu T, Korma SA. Probiotics: mechanism of action, health benefits and their application in food industries. Front Microbiol. 2023;14:1216674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10470842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37664108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr AE, Pugh J, O'Sullivan O, Black K, Townsend JR, Pyne DB, Wardenaar FC, West NP, Whisner CM, McFarland LV. Best Practices for Probiotic Research in Athletic and Physically Active Populations: Guidance for Future Randomized Controlled Trials. Front Nutr. 2022;9:809983.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8957944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35350412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaswala D, Shah S, Mishra A, Patel H, Patel N, Sangwan P, Chodos A, Brelvi Z. Can yoga be used to treat gastroesophageal reflux disease? Int J Yoga. 2013;6:131&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3734640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23930033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abegunde AT, Goyes D, Farooq U, Luke AH, Huggins E, Cooper RS, Dugas LR. The impact of physical exercise on health-related quality of life in inflammatory bowel disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2023;2023:CD014537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bianco A, Russo F, Franco I, Riezzo G, Donghia R, Curci R, Bonfiglio C, Prospero L, D'Attoma B, Ignazzi A, Campanella A, Osella AR. Enhanced Physical Capacity and Gastrointestinal Symptom Improvement in Southern Italian IBS Patients following Three Months of Moderate Aerobic Exercise. J Clin Med. 2023;12:6786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10648315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37959251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marttinen M, Ala-Jaakkola R, Laitila A, Lehtinen MJ. Gut Microbiota, Probiotics and Physical Performance in Athletes and Physically Active Individuals. Nutrients. 2020;12:2936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7599951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32992765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiorindi C, Russo E, Balocchini L, Amedei A, Giudici F. Inflammatory Bowel Disease and Customized Nutritional Intervention Focusing on Gut Microbiome Balance. Nutrients. 2022;14:4117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9572914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36235770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neil-Sztramko SE, Caldwell H, Dobbins M. School-based physical activity programs for promoting physical activity and fitness in children and adolescents aged 6 to 18. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2021;9:CD007651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8459921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34555181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen W, Li M, Li H, Lin Y, Feng Z. Tai Chi for fall prevention and balance improvement in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Front Public Health. 2023;11:1236050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10509476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37736087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts HC, Lim SER, Cox NJ, Ibrahim K. The Challenge of Managing Undernutrition in Older People with Frailty. Nutrients. 2019;11:808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6521101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30974825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou P, Chen C, Patil S, Dong S. Unveiling the therapeutic symphony of probiotics, prebiotics, and postbiotics in gut-immune harmony. Front Nutr. 2024;11:1355542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10881654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38389798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Victoria Obayomi O, Folakemi Olaniran A, Olugbemiga Owa S. Unveiling the role of functional foods with emphasis on prebiotics and probiotics in human health: A review. J Funct Foods. 2024;119:106337.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>