<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37129034</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1524-475X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Season>Jul-Aug</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Wound repair and regeneration : official publication of the Wound Healing Society [and] the European Tissue Repair Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Wound Repair Regen</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sex differences in the skin microbiome of burn scars.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>547</StartPage><EndPage>558</EndPage><MedlinePgn>547-558</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/wrr.13088</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Sex differences are observed in various spectrums of skin diseases, and there are differences in wound healing rate. Herein, sex differences were identified for the newly healed skin microbiome of burn patients. Fifty-two skin samples (26 normal skin, 26 burn scars) were collected from 26 burn patients (12 male, 14 female) and microbiota analysis was performed. The correlation between skin microbiota and biomechanical properties of burn scars was also investigated. There were no significant differences in clinical characteristics between male and female patients. Considering the biomechanical properties of burn scars and normal skin around it performed before sample collection, the mean erythema level of men's normal skin was significantly higher than that of women, whereas the mean levels of melanin, transepidermal water loss and skin hydration showed no significant sex differences. The erythrocyte sedimentation rate was significantly higher in females than that in males. Alpha diversity showed no significant differences between normal skin and burn scars in the male group. However, the scar was significantly higher than that of normal skin in the female group. Microbial network analysis revealed that the male group had more complex microbial network than the female group. Additionally, in the male group, the edge density and clustering coefficient were higher in burn scars when compared to normal skin, than the female group. There were sex differences in the results of microbiome of normal skin and burn scars. Some of the altered microbiota have been correlated with the biomechanical properties of burn scars. In conclusion, sex difference in the burn scar microbiome was confirmed. These results suggest that burn treatment strategies should vary with sex.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Wound Healing Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jung</LastName><ForeName>Yeongyun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Burn Institute, Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Hangang Sacred Heart Hospital, Hallym University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Hui Song</ForeName><Initials>HS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Burn Institute, Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Hangang Sacred Heart Hospital, Hallym University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Joo</LastName><ForeName>So Young</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Hangang Sacred Heart Hospital, Hallym University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Eun Kyung</ForeName><Initials>EK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Burn Institute, Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Hangang Sacred Heart Hospital, Hallym University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seo</LastName><ForeName>Cheong Hoon</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4091-6382</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Hangang Sacred Heart Hospital, Hallym University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cho</LastName><ForeName>Yoon Soo</ForeName><Initials>YS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9959-3285</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Hangang Sacred Heart Hospital, Hallym University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2020R1l1A3074150</GrantID><Agency>Basic Science Research Program through the National Research Foundation of Korea (NRF) funded by the Ministry of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Wound Repair Regen</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9310939</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1067-1927</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002921" MajorTopicYN="N">Cicatrix</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012727" MajorTopicYN="N">Sex Characteristics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014945" MajorTopicYN="N">Wound Healing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012867" MajorTopicYN="N">Skin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064307" MajorTopicYN="Y">Microbiota</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002056" MajorTopicYN="Y">Burns</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017439" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cicatrix, Hypertrophic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">burn</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">burn injury</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">burn rehabilitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">burn scar</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">scar biomechanical properties</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skin microbiome</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37129034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/wrr.13088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Stokes M, Johnson W. Burns in the third world: an unmet need. Ann Burns Fire Disasters. 2017;30:243-246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evers LH, Bhavsar D, Mail&#xe4;nder P. The biology of burn injury. Exp Dermatol. 2010;19:777-783.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logsetty S, Shamlou A, Gawaziuk JP, et al. Mental health outcomes of burn: a longitudinal population-based study of adults hospitalized for burns. Burns. 2016;42:738-744.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason SA, Nathens AB, Byrne JP, et al. Increased rate of long-term mortality among burn survivors: a population-based matched cohort study. Ann Surg. 2019;269:1192-1199.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone J, Gawaziuk JP, Khan S, et al. Outcomes in adult survivors of childhood burn injuries as compared with matched controls. J Burn Care Res. 2016;37:e166-e173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeschke MG, van Baar ME, Choudhry MA, Chung KK, Gibran NS, Logsetty S. Burn injury. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2020;6:1-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grice EA, Segre JA. The skin microbiome. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2011;9:244-253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrd AL, Belkaid Y, Segre JA. The human skin microbiome. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2018;16:143-155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shibagaki N, Suda W, Clavaud C, et al. Aging-related changes in the diversity of women's skin microbiomes associated with oral bacteria. Sci Rep. 2017;7:1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swaney MH, Kalan LR. Living in your skin: microbes, molecules, and mechanisms. Infect Immun. 2021;89:e00695-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knackstedt R, Knackstedt T, Gatherwright J. The role of topical probiotics on wound healing: a review of animal and human studies. Int Wound J. 2020;17:1687-1694.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Z, Ding J, Tredget EE. The molecular basis of hypertrophic scars. Burns. Dent Traumatol. 2016;4:4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corcione S, Lupia T, De Rosa FG, Host, Group MIS. Microbiome in the setting of burn patients: implications for infections and clinical outcomes. Burns. Dent Traumatol. 2020;8:8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plichta JK, Gao X, Lin H, et al. Cutaneous burn injury promotes shifts in the bacterial microbiome in autologous donor skin: implications for skin grafting outcomes. Shock. 2017;48:441-448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu SH, Huang YC, Chen LY, Yu SC, Yu HY, Chuang SS. The skin microbiome of wound scars and unaffected skin in patients with moderate to severe burns in the subacute phase. Wound Repair Regen. 2018;26:182-191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanjar F, Weaver AJ, Peacock TJ, Nguyen JQ, Brandenburg KS, Leung KP. Identification of metagenomics structure and function associated with temporal changes in rat (Rattus norvegicus) skin microbiome during health and cutaneous burn. J Burn Care Res. 2020;41:347-358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x105;browska M, Mielcarek A, Nowak I. Evaluation of sex-related changes in skin topography and structure using innovative skin testing equipment. Skin Res Technol. 2018;24:614-620.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen W, Mempel M, Traidl-Hofmann C, Al Khusaei S, Ring J. Gender aspects in skin diseases. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2010;24:1378-1385.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W, Han L, Yu P, Ma C, Wu X, Xu J. Nested PCR-denaturing gradient gel electrophoresis analysis of human skin microbial diversity with age. Microbiol Res. 2014;169:686-692.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dethlefsen L, McFall-Ngai M, Relman DA. An ecological and evolutionary perspective on human-microbe mutualism and disease. Nature. 2007;449:811-818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Findley K, Oh J, Yang J, et al. Topographic diversity of fungal and bacterial communities in human skin. Nature. 2013;498:367-370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J-H, Son S-M, Park H, et al. Taxonomic profiling of skin microbiome and correlation with clinical skin parameters in healthy Koreans. Sci Rep. 2021;11:1-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogai K, Nana BC, Lloyd YM, et al. Skin microbiome profile of healthy Cameroonians and Japanese. Sci Rep. 2022;12:1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ying S, Zeng D-N, Chi L, et al. The influence of age and gender on skin-associated microbial communities in urban and rural human populations. PloS One. 2015;10:e0141842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim M-J, Tagele SB, Jo H, et al. Effect of a bioconverted product of Lotus corniculatus seed on the axillary microbiome and body odor. Sci Rep. 2021;11:1-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolyen E, Rideout JR, Dillon MR, et al. Reproducible, interactive, scalable and extensible microbiome data science using QIIME 2. Nat Biotechnol. 2019;37:852-857.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peschel S, M&#xfc;ller CL, von Mutius E, Boulesteix A-L, Depner M. NetCoMi: network construction and comparison for microbiome data in R. Brief Bioinform. 2021;22:1-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lahti L, Shetty S. Tools for microbiome analysis in R. Microbiome package version 1.7. 21. Bioconductor. [Google Scholar]. http://microbiomegithub.com/microbiome 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham H, Fran&#xe7;ois R, Henry L, M&#xfc;ller K. dplyr: a grammar of data manipulation. R package version 04. 2015;3:p156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMurdie PJ, Holmes S. Phyloseq: an R package for reproducible interactive analysis and graphics of microbiome census data. PloS One. 2013;8:e61217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudis B. Hrbrthemes: Additional themes, theme components and utilities for &#x201c;ggplot2&#x201d; Hrbrthemes Documentation Accessed March 26, 2020. https://rdrrio/cran/hrbrthemes. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang W. Gcookbook: Data for &#x201c;R Graphics Cookbook&#x201d;. 2012 R package version.1:28. https://CRANR-project.org/package=gcookbook</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham H, Averick M, Bryan J, et al. Welcome to the Tidyverse. J Open Source Softw. 2019;4:1686.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bisanz JE. qiime2R: Importing QIIME2 artifacts and associated data into R sessions. Version 099. 2018. https://github.com/jbisanz/qiime2R</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Cui Y, Li X, Yao M. Microeco: an R package for data mining in microbial community ecology. FEMS Microbiol Ecol. 2021;97:fiaa255.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson MD, McCarthy DJ, Smyth GK. edgeR: a Bioconductor package for differential expression analysis of digital gene expression data. Bioinformatics. 2010;26:139-140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrell FE Jr, Harrell Jr MFE. Package &#x2018;hmisc&#x2019;. CRAN2018. 2019;2019:235-236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickham H. Data Analysis. ggplot2. Springer. 2016 189-201.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassambara A, Kassambara MA. Package &#x2018;ggpubr&#x2019;. R package version 01. 2020;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldman M, Sbong S. Is CRP, like ESR age and gender dependent? Rheumatology. 2014;4:134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firooz A, Sadr B, Babakoohi S, et al. Variation of biophysical parameters of the skin with age, gender, and body region. Sci World J. 2012;2012:1-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>SanMiguel A, Grice EA. Interactions between host factors and the skin microbiome. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2015;72:1499-1515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergquist M, Huss F, Fred&#xe9;n F, et al. Altered adrenal and gonadal steroids biosynthesis in patients with burn injury. Clin Mass Spectrom. 2016;1:19-26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavender-Bares J, Kozak KH, Fine PV, Kembel SW. The merging of community ecology and phylogenetic biology. Ecol Lett. 2009;12:693-715.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmieri G, Arciello S, Bimonte M, et al. The extraordinary resistance to UV radiations of a manganese superoxide dismutase of Deinococcus radiodurans offers promising potentialities in skin care applications. J Biotechnol. 2019;302:101-111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin SM, Baek CY, Jung J-H, et al. Antioxidant activities of an exopolysaccharide (DeinoPol) produced by the extreme radiation-resistant bacterium Deinococcus radiodurans. Sci Rep. 2020;10:1-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong W, Peng W, Liang R. Identification and genome analysis of Deinococcus actinosclerus SJTR1, a novel 17&#x3b2;-estradiol degradation bacterium. 3 Biotech. 2018;8:1-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majeed M, Majeed S, Nagabhushanam K, Lawrence L, Arumugam S, Mundkur L. Skin protective activity of LactoSporin-the extracellular metabolite from Bacillus coagulans MTCC 5856. Cosmetics. 2020;7:76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zouari R, Moalla-Rekik D, Sahnoun Z, Rebai T, Ellouze-Chaabouni S, Ghribi-Aydi D. Evaluation of dermal wound healing and in vitro antioxidant efficiency of Bacillus subtilis SPB1 biosurfactant. Biomed Pharmacother. 2016;84:878-891.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan L, Liu G, Zhao B, et al. Novel biomedical functions of surfactin A from Bacillus subtilis in wound healing promotion and scar inhibition. J Agric Food Chem. 2020;68:6987-6997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gontcharova V, Youn E, Sun Y, Wolcott RD, Dowd SE. A comparison of bacterial composition in diabetic ulcers and contralateral intact skin. Open Microbiol J. 2010;4:8-19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolcott RD, Hanson JD, Rees EJ, et al. Analysis of the chronic wound microbiota of 2,963 patients by 16S rDNA pyrosequencing. Wound Repair Regen. 2016;24:163-174.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guet-Revillet H, Coignard-Biehler H, Jais J-P, et al. Bacterial pathogens associated with hidradenitis suppurativa. France Emerg Infect Dis. 2014;20:1990-1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kay&#x131;ran MA, Sahin E, Ko&#xe7;o&#x11f;lu E, Sezerman OU, G&#xfc;rel MS, Karada&#x11f; AS. Is cutaneous microbiota a player in disease pathogenesis? Comparison of cutaneous microbiota in psoriasis and seborrheic dermatitis with scalp involvement. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol. 2022;88:738-748.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoch JJ, Monir RL, Satcher KG, Harris J, Triplett E, Neu J. The infantile cutaneous microbiome: a review. Pediatr Dermatol. 2019;36:574-580.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cogen A, Nizet V, Gallo R. Skin microbiota: a source of disease or defence? Br J Dermatol. 2008;158:442-455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sveen K. The capacity of lipopolysaccharides from Bacteroides, Fusobacterium and Veillonella to produce skin inflammation and the local and generalized Shwartzman reaction in rabbits. J Periodontal Res. 1977;12:340-350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loesche M, Gardner SE, Kalan L, et al. Temporal stability in chronic wound microbiota is associated with poor healing. J Invest Dermatol. 2017;137:237-244.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>