<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41227811</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>21</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>23</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of Steel Slag and Ethylenediaminetetraacetic Acid (EDTA) on Enhancing the CO<sub>2</sub> Sequestration Performance of Gangue-Based Cemented Backfill Materials.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4852</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma18214852</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>To enhance the support capacity of cemented paste backfill (CPB) in goaf areas and its ability to sequester CO<sub>2</sub>, steel slag and ethylenediaminetetraacetic acid (EDTA) were incorporated into gangue-based cemented backfill materials. A stress-carbonation-coupled reaction system was employed to carbonate the CPB, and the effects of steel slag and EDTA on compressive strength, CO<sub>2</sub> uptake, and microstructure were studied. The findings indicate that steel slag remarkably enhanced the performance of the CPB, with both strength and CO<sub>2</sub> uptake initially increasing before declining as steel slag content increased. The optimum performance was achieved at a steel slag content of 10%. The incorporation of EDTA further enhanced the compressive strength and CO<sub>2</sub> uptake, with the best results at 0.5 g/L. Microstructural analyses demonstrated that steel slag increased the availability of Ca<sup>2+</sup> and Mg<sup>2+</sup> in the cement paste system, while EDTA accelerated their leaching, promoted hydration products, and catalyzed carbonation via chelation. However, excessive steel slag or EDTA reduced hydration products and deteriorated material performance. This work may provide a reference for enhancing the properties of CPB and promoting the efficient utilization of coal-based solid wastes.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Xinying</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Deep Coal Resource Mining of Ministry of Education, School of Mines, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou 221116, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Dan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yankuang Energy Group Company Limited, Jining 273500, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Zejun</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Deep Coal Resource Mining of Ministry of Education, School of Mines, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou 221116, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Nan</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Deep Coal Resource Mining of Ministry of Education, School of Mines, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou 221116, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Jiangsu Key Laboratory for Clean Utilization of Carbon Resources, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou 221116, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Qian</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Deep Coal Resource Mining of Ministry of Education, School of Mines, China University of Mining and Technology, Xuzhou 221116, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023YFC3904304</GrantID><Agency>National Key R&amp;D Program of China</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023B01009</GrantID><Agency>Key R&amp;D Program of Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>BM2024007</GrantID><Agency>Research Project of Jiangsu Key Laboratory for Clean Utilization of Carbon Resources</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CO2 sequestration experiment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CO2 sequestration performance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cemented paste backfill</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">steel slag</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">strength</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Author Dan Kang was employed by the company Yankuang Energy Group Company Limited, but he declares that he has no known personal relationships or competing financial interests that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41227811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12609325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma18214852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma18214852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhu M., Liu L., Wang S., Wei B., Rong R., Zhang W., Zhuang D., Jia Q. Backfill-strip mining and CO2 mineralization sequestration in coal mine goaves: A synergetic method and its key technologies. Coal Geol. Explor. 2025;53:143&#x2013;155. doi: 10.12363/issn.1001-1986.25.02.0109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12363/issn.1001-1986.25.02.0109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Zhou N., Liu H., Xie Y., Sun Z., Ouyang S. Research progress and prospect of underground utilization of coal-based solid waste functional materials. Coal Sci. Technol. 2025;53:1&#x2013;28. doi: 10.12438/cst.2025-0605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12438/cst.2025-0605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiao Y., Lv B., Fan W., Li L., Wang M., Xing B. Preparation and application prospects of coal-based carbon materials: A comprehensive review. J. Alloys Compd. 2025;1016:178951. doi: 10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.178951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.178951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keskin T., Yilmaz E., Kasap T., Sari M., Cao S. Toward viable industrial solid residual waste recycling: A review of its innovative applications and future perspectives. Minerals. 2024;14:943. doi: 10.3390/min14090943.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/min14090943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang F. Study on mechanical properties and load-bearing failure characteristics of coal-based solid waste cemented backfill. Coal. 2025;34:100&#x2013;104. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1005-2798.2025.06.022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1005-2798.2025.06.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. China Coal Research Institute; Beijing, China: 2025. Experimental Study on Carbon Sequestration Slurry Materials for Goaf Backfilling and Reclamation.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bordoloi S., Afolayan O.D., Ng C.W.W. Feasibility of construction demolition waste for unexplored geotechnical and geo-environmental applications&#x2014;A review. Constr. Build. Mater. 2022;356:129230. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2022.129230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishna R.S., Shaikh F., Mishra J., Lazorenko G., Kasprzhitskii A. Mine tailings-based geopolymers: Properties, applications and industrial prospects. Ceram. Int. 2021;47:17826&#x2013;17843. doi: 10.1016/j.ceramint.2021.03.180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ceramint.2021.03.180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zajac M., Bremeier R., Deja J., Kr&#xf3;l M., Ben Haha M. Carbonation hardening of portland cement with recycled supplementary cementitious materials. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2025;157:105904. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2024.105904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2024.105904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves M.O., Nelson de Goes L.M., Simonelli G. Impact on greenhouse gas emissions in the ammonia production process by reusing heat in the CO2 absorption stage. Energy Convers. Manag. 2026;347:120534. doi: 10.1016/j.enconman.2025.120534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2025.120534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saletnik A., Saletnik B., Puchalski C. Coal as the world&#x2019;s dominant energy source and its role in the energy transformation and regulations of european green deal. J. Environ. Manag. 2025;392:126815. doi: 10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.126815.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2025.126815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40780162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L., Fang Z., Wang S., Gao G., Zhang B., Zhao Y., Zhu M., Liu Z., Wang J., Zhou J., et al. Theoretical basis and technical conception of backfill carbon fixation in coal mine. Coal Sci. Technol. 2024;52:292&#x2013;308. doi: 10.12438/cst.2023-1485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12438/cst.2023-1485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kusin F.M., Syed Hasan S.N.M., Molahid V.L.M., Soomro M.H. Dual adoption opportunities and prospects for mining and industrial waste recovery through an integrated carbon capture, utilization and storage. Sustain. Prod. Consum. 2024;48:181&#x2013;204. doi: 10.1016/j.spc.2024.05.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.spc.2024.05.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S., Niu D., Luo D., Wang Y. Activation of activator on steel slag-cement and its hydration mechanism. J. Harbin Inst. Tech. 2024;56:165&#x2013;172. doi: 10.11918/202302068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11918/202302068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biava G., Zacco A., Zanoletti A., Sorrentino G.P., Capone C., Princigallo A., Depero L.E., Bontempi E. Accelerated direct carbonation of steel slag and cement kiln dust: An industrial symbiosis strategy applied in the Bergamo&#x2013;Brescia area. Materials. 2023;16:4055. doi: 10.3390/ma16114055.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16114055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10254272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37297187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montoya D., Pistofidis N., Giannakopoulos G., Iacobescu R., Katsiotis M., Pontikes Y. Revisiting the iron-rich &#x201c;ordinary portland cement&#x201d; towards valorisation of wastes: Study of Fe-to-Al ratio on the clinker production and the hydration reaction. Mater. Struct. 2021;54:30. doi: 10.1617/s11527-020-01601-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1617/s11527-020-01601-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Guo M., Ling T. Review on CO2 curing of non-hydraulic calcium silicates cements: Mechanism, carbonation and performance. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2022;133:104641. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2022.104641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Na H., Wang Y., Zhang X., Li J., Zeng Y., Liu P. Hydration activity and carbonation characteristics of dicalcium silicate in steel slag: A review. Metals. 2021;11:1580. doi: 10.3390/met11101580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/met11101580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song X., Zhao C., Song Y., Guo Y., Kong X. Mineralization curing of steel slag-fly ash solid waste composite alkali-activated cementitious material. Clean Coal Tech. 2024;30:88&#x2013;98. doi: 10.13226/j.issn.1006-6772.CCUS24040101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13226/j.issn.1006-6772.CCUS24040101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen P., Boone M.A., Horckmans L., Snellings R., Quaghebeur M. Accelerated carbonation of steel slag monoliths at low CO2 pressure&#x2014;Microstructure and strength development. J. CO2 Util. 2020;36:124&#x2013;134. doi: 10.1016/j.jcou.2019.10.022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcou.2019.10.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jhatial A.A., Nov&#xe1;kov&#xe1; I., Gjerl&#xf8;w E. A review on emerging cementitious materials, reactivity evaluation and treatment methods. Buildings. 2023;13:526. doi: 10.3390/buildings13020526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings13020526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes V.A., Borges P.H.R. Recent advances in the reuse of steel slags and future perspectives as binder and aggregate for alkali-activated materials. Constr. Build. Mater. 2021;281:122605. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2021.122605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahami A., Issa C.A. Exploring the use of mixed waste materials (MWM) in concrete for sustainable construction: A review. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;398:132476. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang P., Wang W., Zheng Y., Hu S. Effect of recycled aggregate and slag as substitutes for natural aggregate and cement on the properties of concrete: A review. J. Renew. Mater. 2023;11:1853&#x2013;1879. doi: 10.32604/jrm.2023.024981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32604/jrm.2023.024981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W., Wang H., Liu Z., Li N., Zhao S., Hu S. Steel slag accelerated carbonation curing for high-carbonation precast concrete development. Materials. 2024;17:2968. doi: 10.3390/ma17122968.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17122968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11205995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38930337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosales J., Agrela F., Entrenas J.A., Cabrera M. Potential of stainless steel slag waste in manufacturing self-compacting concrete. Materials. 2020;13:2049. doi: 10.3390/ma13092049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma13092049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7254312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32353927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herki B.M.A., Ali A.I., Smail Y.S., Omer K.M. An innovative approach to enhancing concrete sustainability: Utilising unprocessed steel slag with low CaO and high SiO2 content. Buildings. 2025;15:1514. doi: 10.3390/buildings15091514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings15091514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu X., Wang Y., Sun D., Sun R. Macroscopic and microscopic characteristics of slag-steel slag ce-mentitious system under the action of composite activator. Coal Sci. Technol. 2025;53:375&#x2013;386.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Yang X., Yang J., Yin S., Bian W., Qi Y. Development of magnesium slag&#x2013;steel slag-based composite cementitious material and its backfilling application. Arch. Civ. Mech. Eng. 2025;25:194. doi: 10.1007/s43452-025-01226-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43452-025-01226-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sunkara Y., Vinod J.S., Kumari W.G.P., Saride S. Shear behaviour of basic oxygen furnace slag-granulated blast furnace slag mixtures: A laboratory investigation. Constr. Build. Mater. 2025;494:143443. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.143443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.143443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yi G., Tian W., Shi J., Guo J., Cheng X. CO2 mineralization curing steel slag-fly ash-portland cement ternary paste: Mechanical properties, microstructure and life cycle assessment. J. Cent. South Univ. 2025;32:2487&#x2013;2510. doi: 10.1007/s11771-025-6022-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11771-025-6022-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li N., Unluer C. A comparative study of ethylenediamine tetraacetic acid induced gas-solid and liquid-solid accelerated carbonation for enhancement of steel slag aggregates. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;400:132539. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.132539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le&#xe3;o A., Collin M., Ghodkhande S., Bouissonni&#xe9; A., Chen X., Malin B., Liu Y., Hovey G., Govindhakannan J., Plante E.L., et al. ZeroCAL: Eliminating carbon dioxide emissions from limestone&#x2019;s decomposition to decarbonize cement production. Acs Sustain. Chem. Eng. 2024;12:15762&#x2013;15787. doi: 10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c03193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c03193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11523464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39483210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jose V., Jose V., Kuruvilla E., Nesaraj A.S. Fabrication, phytotoxicity, and electrochemical performance of rare-earth metal-based mixed la&#x2013;ce cobaltite nanospheres: Applications in energy storage and environmental remediation. J. Phys. Chem. Solids. 2025;207:112935. doi: 10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.112935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.112935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parhizgar Keradeh M., Tabatabaei-Nezhad S.A. Investigation of the effect of diethylene triamine pentaacetic acid chelating agent as an enhanced oil recovery fluid on wettability alteration of sandstone rocks. Petrol. Explor. Dev. 2023;50:675&#x2013;687. doi: 10.1016/S1876-3804(23)60419-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1876-3804(23)60419-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu L., Deng J., Yuan H., Zhang X. Effect of ethylenediaminetetraacetic acid and its sodium salt on carbonation performance of steel slag block. Green Bulid. Mater. 2024;11:140&#x2013;145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S., Su Y., Yang M., Xu P., Yi C., Nie Y., Wang L. Preparation and activation of slag-blended cementitious materials: A study on the activation of cementitious activity. Met. Mine. 2022;57:252&#x2013;258. doi: 10.19614/j.cnki.jsks.202211033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19614/j.cnki.jsks.202211033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krevor S., de Coninck H., Gasda S.E., Ghaleigh N.S., de Gooyert V., Hajibeygi H., Juanes R., Neufeld J., Roberts J.J., Swennenhuis F. Subsurface carbon dioxide and hydrogen storage for a sustainable energy future. Nat. Rev. Earth Environ. 2023;4:102&#x2013;118. doi: 10.1038/s43017-022-00376-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s43017-022-00376-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Librandi P., Nielsen P., Costa G., Snellings R., Quaghebeur M., Baciocchi R. Mechanical and environmental properties of carbonated steel slag compacts as a function of mineralogy and CO2 uptake. J CO2 Util. 2019;33:201&#x2013;214. doi: 10.1016/j.jcou.2019.05.028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcou.2019.05.028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ababneh A., Al-Rousan R., Gharaibeh W., Abu-Dalo M. Recycling of pre-treated medical waste fly ash in mortar mixtures. J. Mater. Cycles Waste Manag. 2020;22:207&#x2013;220. doi: 10.1007/s10163-019-00928-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10163-019-00928-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T., Xue Y., Zhao X., Liu J. Effects of EDTA on the accelerated carbonation behavior of steel slag used as cementitious materials. J. Mater. Cycles Waste Manag. 2023;25:1498&#x2013;1508. doi: 10.1007/s10163-023-01622-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10163-023-01622-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katre S., Ochonma P., Mamidala A., Sahu S., Nair A.M., Ravi K., Gadikota G. Organic ligands and CO2 unlock the potential for energy relevant metals recovery and carbon mineralization from mafic rocks. Sci. Rep. 2025;15:10882. doi: 10.1038/s41598-025-94153-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-025-94153-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11954931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40157928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thumm A.K., Skerencak-Frech A., Gaona X., Altmaier M., Geckeis H. Uptake of cm (III) and eu (III) by c&#x2013;s&#x2013;h phases under saline conditions in presence of EDTA: A batch sorption and TRLFS study. Appl. Geochem. 2024;170:106087. doi: 10.1016/j.apgeochem.2024.106087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apgeochem.2024.106087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Shan J., Ma Z., Liu Z., Huang J., Fang Y. Effects of ethylenediaminetetraacetic acid on the properties of accelerated carbonated steel slag as supplementary cementitious materials. Constr. Build. Mater. 2025;487:142093. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.142093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2025.142093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Test Method of Cement Mortar Strength (ISO Method) National Cement Standardization Technical Committee; Beijing, China: 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Wu P., Liu X., Zhang Z., Ai X. The utilization of carbonated steel slag as a supplementary cementitious material in cement. Materials. 2024;17:4574. doi: 10.3390/ma17184574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17184574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11433562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39336314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng X., Tian W., Yuan Q., Chen W., Wan J., Guo J., Cai J. Effect of carbon dioxide mineralization curing on mechanical properties and microstructure of portland cement&#x2013;steel slag&#x2013;granulated blast furnace slag ternary paste. Constr. Build. Mater. 2024;431:136553. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2024.136553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C., Wang B., Li T., Wang Y., Li N. High volume steel slag powder-cement alkali excitation characteristics. China Powder Technol. 2023;29:55&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Ni W., Li J., Zhang S., Hitch M., Pascual R. Carbonation of steel slag and gypsum for building materials and associated reaction mechanisms. Cem. Concr. Res. 2019;125:105893. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huo B., Zhang J., Zhou N., Li M., Guo Q. Effect of sodium dodecyl sulfate on CO2 storage and rheological properties of alkali-activated coal gasification slag filling slurry. J. Min. Saf. Eng. 2024;41:1279&#x2013;1288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rui Y., Qian C., Zhang X., Ma Z. Different carbon treatments for steel slag powder and their subsequent effects on properties of cement-based materials. J. Clean. Prod. 2022;362:132407. doi: 10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.132407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclepro.2022.132407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian W., Wan J., Cheng X., Zhang J., Guo J. Synergistic carbon sequestration performance and microstructure of steel slag-base cementitious materials. J. Build. Mater. 2025;28:434&#x2013;441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J., Li Y., Yang J., Cao X., Wang J., Wang G., Sun L., Huang Q., Cheng W., Lyu Z. Preparation of slag-based foam concrete and its carbon dioxide sequestration performance. Int. J. Greenh. Gas Control. 2024;135:104156. doi: 10.1016/j.ijggc.2024.104156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijggc.2024.104156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngiwngam K., Chinvorarat S., Rachtanapun P., Auras R., Wittaya T., Tongdeesoontorn W. Effect of chemical and steam explosion pulping on the physical and mechanical properties of sugarcane straw pulp trays. Polymers. 2023;15:3132. doi: 10.3390/polym15143132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/polym15143132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10383716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37514521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saillio M., Baroghel-Bouny V., Pradelle S., Bertin M., Vincent J., d&#x2019;Espinose de Lacaillerie J. Effect of supplementary cementitious materials on carbonation of cement pastes. Cem. Concr. Res. 2021;142:106358. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2021.106358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2021.106358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Y., Aizenberg J. Effect of magnesium ions on oriented growth of calcite on carboxylic acid functionalized self-assembled monolayer. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2003;125:4032&#x2013;4033. doi: 10.1021/ja034094z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ja034094z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12670208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Mehdizadeh H., Ling T. Environmental, economic and engineering performances of aqueous carbonated steel slag powders as alternative material in cement pastes: Influence of particle size. Sci. Total Environ. 2023;903:166210. doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.166210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.166210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37574062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X., Zhang K., Wang B., Wu Z., Zhou M. Design and research on the preparation of pervious concrete using carbonized steel slag as a full component. Buildings. 2025;15:1526. doi: 10.3390/buildings15091526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/buildings15091526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li K., Zhu L., Wu Z., Wang X. Properties of cemented filling materials prepared from phosphogypsum-steel slag&#x2013;blast-furnace slag and its environmental effect. Materials. 2024;17:3618. doi: 10.3390/ma17143618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma17143618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11278685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39063909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Ma X., Guo H., Wang H., Qu Y., Jiao W., Ma Z. The influence mechanism of non-free calcium on the dissolution-polymerization reaction of coal gasification ash in alkaline environment. J. Fuel Chemis Tech. 2025;53:1416&#x2013;1426. doi: 10.1016/S1872-5813(25)60566-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1872-5813(25)60566-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao J., Zhou Z., Chen Z., Zhou Y., Wang J. Damage characterization and microscopic mechanism of steel slag-cemented paste backfill under uniaxial compression. Constr. Build. Mater. 2023;409:134175. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2023.134175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han J., Kim S., Lee Y., Hur D. Chemical cleaning of magnetite deposits on the flow mini-channels of a printed circuit heat exchanger in an EDTA-based solution. Materials. 2022;15:1471. doi: 10.3390/ma15041471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15041471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8874691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35208005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng J., Zhang D., Gu L., Yuan H., Zhang B. Enhanced carbonation of steel slag blocks using various chemical additives. J. Build. Eng. 2025;105:112518. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2025.112518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2025.112518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>