<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38147689</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1549-9626</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of chemical theory and computation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Chem Theory Comput</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Tuning Potential Functions to Host-Guest Binding Data.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>239</StartPage><EndPage>252</EndPage><MedlinePgn>239-252</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01050</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Software to more rapidly and accurately predict protein-ligand binding affinities is of high interest for early-stage drug discovery, and physics-based methods are among the most widely used technologies for this purpose. The accuracy of these methods depends critically on the accuracy of the potential functions that they use. Potential functions are typically trained against a combination of quantum chemical and experimental data. However, although binding affinities are among the most important quantities to predict, experimental binding affinities have not to date been integrated into the experimental data set used to train potential functions. In recent years, the use of host-guest complexes as simple and tractable models of binding thermodynamics has gained popularity due to their small size and simplicity, relative to protein-ligand systems. Host-guest complexes can also avoid ambiguities that arise in protein-ligand systems such as uncertain protonation states. Thus, experimental host-guest binding data are an appealing additional data type to integrate into the experimental data set used to optimize potential functions. Here, we report the extension of the Open Force Field Evaluator framework to enable the systematic calculation of host-guest binding free energies and their gradients with respect to force field parameters, coupled with the curation of 126 host-guest complexes with available experimental binding free energies. As an initial application of this novel infrastructure, we optimized generalized Born (GB) cavity radii for the OBC2 GB implicit solvent model against experimental data for 36 host-guest systems. This refitting led to a dramatic improvement in accuracy for both the training set and a separate test set with 90 additional host-guest systems. The optimized radii also showed encouraging transferability from host-guest systems to 59 protein-ligand systems. However, the new radii are significantly smaller than the baseline radii and lead to excessively favorable hydration free energies (HFEs). Thus, users of the OBC2 GB model currently may choose between GB cavity radii that yield more accurate binding affinities and GB cavity radii that yield more accurate HFEs. We suspect that achieving good accuracy on both will require more far-reaching adjustments to the GB model. We note that binding free-energy calculations using the OBC2 model in OpenMM gain about a 10&#xd7; speedup relative to corresponding explicit solvent calculations, suggesting a future role for implicit solvent absolute binding free-energy (ABFE) calculations in virtual compound screening. This study proves the principle of using host-guest systems to train potential functions that are transferrable to protein-ligand systems and provides an infrastructure that enables a range of applications.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Setiadi</LastName><ForeName>Jeffry</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Skaggs School of Pharmacy and Pharmaceutical Sciences, University of California San Diego, 9255 Pharmacy Lane, La Jolla, California 92093, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boothroyd</LastName><ForeName>Simon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3456-1872</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Boothroyd Scientific Consulting Ltd., London WC2H 9JQ, U.K.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Psivant Therapeutics, Boston, Massachusetts 02210, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Slochower</LastName><ForeName>David R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3928-5050</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vertex Pharmaceuticals, San Diego, California 92121, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dotson</LastName><ForeName>David L</ForeName><Initials>DL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Datryllic LLC, Phoenix, Arizona 85003, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Open Force Field Consortium, Open Molecular Software Foundation, Davis, California 95616, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thompson</LastName><ForeName>Matthew W</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Open Force Field Consortium, Open Molecular Software Foundation, Davis, California 95616, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wagner</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Open Force Field Consortium, Open Molecular Software Foundation, Davis, California 95616, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Lee-Ping</ForeName><Initials>LP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3072-9946</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chemistry Department, University of California Davis, Davis, California 95616, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gilson</LastName><ForeName>Michael K</ForeName><Initials>MK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3375-1738</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Skaggs School of Pharmacy and Pharmaceutical Sciences, University of California San Diego, 9255 Pharmacy Lane, La Jolla, California 92093, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 GM061300</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 GM132386</GrantID><Acronym>GM</Acronym><Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Chem Theory Comput</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101232704</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1549-9618</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008024">Ligands</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011506">Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012997">Solvents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008024" MajorTopicYN="N">Ligands</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011506" MajorTopicYN="Y">Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012984" MajorTopicYN="Y">Software</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011485" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Binding</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012997" MajorTopicYN="N">Solvents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013816" MajorTopicYN="N">Thermodynamics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056004" MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular Dynamics Simulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38147689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1957825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10838530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jctc.3c01050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gilson MK; Given JA; Bush BL; McCammon JA The Statistical-Thermodynamic Basis for Computation of Binding Affinities: A Critical Review. Biophysical Journal 1997, 72, 1047&#x2013;1069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1184492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9138555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boresch S; Tettinger F; Leitgeb M; Karplus M Absolute Binding Free Energies: A Quantitative Approach for their Calculation. Journal of Physical Chemistry B 2003, 107, 9535&#x2013;9551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woo HJ; Roux B Calculation of Absolute Protein&#x2013;Ligand Binding Free Energy from Computer Simulations. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 2005, 102, 6825&#x2013;6830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1100764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15867154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinzelmann G; Gilson MK Automation of Absolute Protein&#x2013;Ligand Binding Free Energy Calculations for Docking Refinement and Compound Evaluation. Scientific Reports 2021, 11, 1&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7806944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33441879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gapsys V; Yildirim A; Aldeghi M; Khalak Y; van der Spoel D; de Groot BL Accurate Absolute Free Energies for Ligand&#x2013;Protein Binding Based on Non-equilibrium Approaches. Communications Chemistry 2021, 4, 1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9814727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36697634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alibay I; Magarkar A; Seeliger D; Biggin PC Evaluating the Use of Absolute Binding Free Energy in the Fragment Optimization Process. Nature Communications Chemistry 2022, 5, 1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9814858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36697714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muddana HS; Fenley AT; Mobley DL; Gilson MK The SAMPL4 Host&#x2013;Guest Blind Prediction Challenge: An Overview. Journal of Computer-Aided Molecular Design 2014, 28, 305&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4053502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24599514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin J; Henriksen NM; Slochower DR; Shirts MR; Chiu MW; Mobley DL; Gilson MK Overview of the SAMPL5 Host&#x2013;Guest Challenge: Are We Doing Better? Journal of Computer-Aided Molecular Design 2017, 31, 1&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5241188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27658802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizzi A; Murkli S; McNeill JN; Yao W; Sullivan M; Gilson MK; Chiu MW; Isaacs L; Gibb BC; Mobley DL; Chodera JD Overview of the SAMPL6 Host&#x2013;Guest Binding Affinity Prediction Challenge. Journal of Computer-Aided Molecular Design 2018, 32, 937&#x2013;963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6301044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30415285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amezcua M; El Khoury L; Mobley DL SAMPL7 Host&#x2013;Guest Challenge Overview: Assessing the Reliability of Polarizable and Non-Polarizable Methods for Binding Free Energy Calculations. Journal of Computer-Aided Molecular Design 2021, 35, 1&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8121194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33392951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amezcua M; Setiadi J; Ge Y; Mobley DL An Overview of the SAMPL8 Host&#x2013;Guest Binding Challenge. Journal of Computer-Aided Molecular Design 2022, 36, 707&#x2013;734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9596595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36229622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henriksen NM; Gilson MK Evaluating Force Field Performance in Thermodynamic Calculations of Cyclodextrin Host&#x2013;Guest Binding: Water Models, Partial Charges, and Host Force Field Parameters. Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation 2017, 13, 4253&#x2013;4269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5606194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28696692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H; Yin C; Yan H; van der Spoel D Evaluation of Generalized Born Models for Large Scale Affinity Prediction of Cyclodextrin Host&#x2013;Guest Complexes. Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling 2016, 56, 2080&#x2013;2092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27626790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slochower D; Henriksen N; Wang LP; Chodera JD; Mobley DL; Gilson MK Binding Thermodynamics of Host&#x2013;Guest Systems with SMIRNOFF99Frosst 1.0.5 from the Open Force Field Initiative. Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation 2019, 15, 6225&#x2013;6242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7328435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31603667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park H; Zhou G; Baek M; Baker D; Dimaio F Force Field Optimization Guided by Small Molecule Crystal Lattice Data Enables Consistent Sub-Angstrom Protein&#x2013;Ligand Docking. Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation 2021, 17, 2000&#x2013;2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8218654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33577321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boothroyd S; Wang LP; Mobley DL; Chodera JD; Shirts MR Open Force Field Evaluator: An Automated, Efficient, and Scalable Framework for the Estimation of Physical Properties from Molecular Simulation. Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation 2022, 18, 3566&#x2013;3576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9245177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35507313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frenkel M; Chirico RD; Diky V; Dong Q; Marsh KN; Dymond JH; Wakeham WA; Stein SE; K&#xf6;nigsberger E; Goodwin AR XML-based IUPAC Standard for Experimental, Predicted, and Critically Evaluated Thermodynamic Property Data Storage and Capture (ThermoML)(IUPAC Recommendations 2006). Pure and Applied Chemistry 2006, 78, 541&#x2013;612.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobley DL; Guthrie JP FreeSolv: A Database of Experimental and Calculated Hydration Free Energies, with Input Files. Journal of Computer-Aided Molecular Design 2014, 28, 711&#x2013;720.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4113415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24928188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobley DL; Shirts M; Lim N; Chodera J; Beauchamp K; Wang LP
Mobleylab/Freesolv: Version 0.52. 2018; https://zenodo.org/record/1161245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang LP; Head-Gordon T; Ponder JW; Ren P; Chodera JD; Eastman PK; Martinez TJ; Pande VS Systematic Improvement of a Classical Molecular Model of Water. Journal of Physical Chemistry B 2013, 117, 9956&#x2013;9972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3770532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23750713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang LP; Martinez TJ; Pande VS Building Force Fields: An Automatic, Systematic, and Reproducible Approach. Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters 2014, 5, 1885&#x2013;1891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9649520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26273869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang LP; McKiernan KA; Gomes J; Beauchamp KA; Head-Gordon T; Rice JE; Swope WC; Mart&#xed;nez TJ; Pande VS Building a More Predictive Protein Force Field: A Systematic and Reproducible Route to AMBER-FB15. Journal of Physical Chemistry B 2017, 121, 4023&#x2013;4039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9724927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28306259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu Y; Smith DGA; Boothroyd S; Jang H; Hahn DF; Wagner J; Bannan CC; Gokey T; Lim VT; Stern CD; others, Development and Benchmarking of Open Force Field v1.0.0&#x2014;the Parsley Small-Molecule Force Field. Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation 2021, 17, 6262&#x2013;6280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8511297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34551262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin J; Henriksen NM; Muddana HS; Gilson MK Bind3P: Optimization of a Water Model Based on Host&#x2013;Guest Binding Data. Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation 2018, 14, 3621&#x2013;3632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6039243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29874074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin J; Fenley AT; Henriksen NM; Gilson MK Toward Improved Force-Field Accuracy through Sensitivity Analysis of Host&#x2013;Guest Binding Thermodynamics. Journal of Physical Chemistry B 2015, 119, 10145&#x2013;10155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4664157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26181208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onufriev AV; Case DA Generalized Born Implicit Solvent Models for Biomolecules. Annual Review of Biophysics 2019, 48, 275&#x2013;296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6645684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30857399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickstrom L; He P; Gallicchio E; Levy RM Large Scale Affinity Calculations of Cyclodextrin Host&#x2013;Guest Complexes: Understanding the Role of Reorganization in the Molecular Recognition Process. Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation 2013, 9, 3136&#x2013;3150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4137772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25147485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onufriev A; Bashford D; Case DA Exploring Protein Native States and Large-Scale Conformational Changes with a Modified Generalized Born Model. Proteins: Structure, Function and Genetics 2004, 55, 383&#x2013;394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15048829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mongan J; Simmerling C; McCammon JA; Case DA; Onufriev A Generalized Born Model with a Simple, Robust Molecular Volume Correction. Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation 2007, 3, 156&#x2013;169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2975579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21072141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen H; Roe DR; Simmerling C Improved Generalized Born Solvent Model Parameters for Protein Simulations. Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation 2013, 9, 2020&#x2013;2034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4361090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25788871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguilar B; Shadrach R; Onufriev AV Reducing the Secondary Structure Bias in the Generalized Born Model via R6 Effective Radii. Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation 2010, 6, 3613&#x2013;3630.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallicchio E; Levy RM AGBNP: An Analytic Implicit Solvent Model Suitable for Molecular Dynamics Simulations and High-Resolution Modeling. Journal of Computational Chemistry 2004, 25, 479&#x2013;499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14735568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallicchio E; Paris K; Levy RM The AGBNP2 Implicit Solvation Model. Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation 2009, 5, 2544&#x2013;2564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2857935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20419084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eastman P; Swails J; Chodera JD; McGibbon RT; Zhao Y; Beauchamp KA; Wang LP; Simmonett AC; Harrigan MP; Stern CD; Wiewiora RP; Brooks BR; Pande VS OpenMM 7: Rapid Development of High Performance Algorithms for Molecular Dynamics. PLOS Computational Biology 2017, 13, e1005659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5549999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28746339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawkins GD; Cramer CJ; Truhlar DG Pairwise Solute Descreening of Solute Charges from a Dielectric Medium. Chemical Physics Letters 1995, 246, 122&#x2013;129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaefer M; Bartels C; Karplus M Solution Conformations and Thermodynamics of Structured Peptides: Molecular Dynamics Simulation with an Implicit Solvation Model. Journal of Molecular Biology 1998, 284, 835&#x2013;848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9826519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiser J; Shenkin PS; Still WC Approximate Atomic Surfaces from Linear Combinations of Pairwise Overlaps (LCPO). Journal of Computational Chemistry 1999, 20, 217&#x2013;230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang H; Simmerling C Fast Pairwise Approximation of Solvent Accessible Surface Area for Implicit Solvent Simulations of Proteins on CPUs and GPUs. Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation 2018, 14, 5797&#x2013;5814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6600810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30303377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark Still W; Tempczyk A; Hawley RC; Hendrickson T Semianalytical Treatment of Solvation for Molecular Mechanics and Dynamics. Journal of the American Chemical Society 1990, 112, 6127&#x2013;6129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bondi A van der Waals Volumes and Radii. Journal of Physical Chemistry 1964, 68, 441&#x2013;451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velez-Vega C; Gilson MK Overcoming Dissipation in the Calculation of Standard Binding Free Energies by Ligand Extraction. Journal of Computational Chemistry 2013, 34, 2360&#x2013;2371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3932244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24038118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henriksen NM; Fenley AT; Gilson MK Computational Calorimetry: High-Precision Calculation of Host&#x2013;Guest Binding Thermodynamics. Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation 2015, 11, 4377&#x2013;4394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4614838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26523125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobley DL; Chodera JD; Dill KA On the use of Orientational Restraints and Symmetry Corrections in Alchemical Free Energy Calculations. Journal of Chemical Physics 2006, 125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3583553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16965052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldeghi M; Heifetz A; Bodkin MJ; Knapp S; Biggin PC Accurate Calculation of the Absolute Free Energy of Binding for Drug Molecules. Chemical Science 2016, 7, 207&#x2013;218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4700411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26798447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldeghi M; Heifetz A; Bodkin MJ; Knapp S; Biggin PC Predictions of Ligand Selectivity from Absolute Binding Free Energy Calculations. Journal of the American Chemical Society 2017, 139, 946&#x2013;957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5253712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28009512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham TT; Shirts MR Identifying Low Variance Pathways for Free Energy Calculations of Molecular Transformations in Solution Phase. Journal of Chemical Physics 2011, 135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21786994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizzi A Improving Efficiency and Scalability of Free Energy Calculations through Automatic Protocol Optimization. Ph.D. thesis, Weill Medical College of Cornell University, United States &#x2013; New York, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirts MR; Chodera JD Statistically Optimal Analysis of Samples From Multiple Equilibrium States. Journal of Chemical Physics 2008, 129, 124105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2671659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19045004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rekharsky MV; Mayhew MP; Goldberg RN; Ross PD; Yamashoji Y; Inoue Y
Thermodynamic and Nuclear Magnetic Resonance Study of the Reactions of <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline"><mml:mstyle mathvariant="normal"><mml:mi>&#x3b1;</mml:mi></mml:mstyle></mml:math>- and <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline"><mml:mstyle mathvariant="normal"><mml:mi>&#x3b2;</mml:mi></mml:mstyle></mml:math>-Cyclodextrin with Acids, Aliphatic Amines, and Cyclic Alcohols. Journal of Physical Chemistry B
1997, 101, 87&#x2013;100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellett K; Kantonen SA; Duggan BM; Gilson MK Toward Expanded Diversity of Host&#x2013;Guest Interactions via Synthesis and Characterization of Cyclodextrin Derivatives. Journal of Solution Chemistry 2018, 47, 1597&#x2013;1608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muddana HS; Varnado CD; Bielawski CW; Urbach AR; Isaacs L; Geballe MT; Gilson MK Blind Prediction of Host&#x2013;Guest Binding Affinities: A New SAMPL3 Challenge. Journal of Computer-Aided Molecular Design 2012, 26, 475&#x2013;487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3383923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22366955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moghaddam S; Yang C; Rekharsky M; Ko YH; Kim K; Inoue Y; Gilson MK New Ultrahigh Affinity Host&#x2013;Guest Complexes of Cucurbit[7]uril with Bicyclo[2.2.2]octane and Adamantane Guests: Thermodynamic Analysis and Evaluation of M2 Affinity Calculations. Journal of the American Chemical Society 2011, 133, 3570&#x2013;3581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3065999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21341773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ; Jeon WS; Ko YH; Kim K Inclusion of Methylviologen in Cucurbit[7]uril. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America 2002, 99, 5007&#x2013;5011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC122712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11917115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibb CL; Gibb BC Well-Defined, Organic Nanoenvironments in Water: The Hydrophobic Effect Drives a Capsular Assembly. Journal of the American Chemical Society 2004, 126, 11408&#x2013;11409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15366865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan H; Benjamin CJ; Gibb BC Nonmonotonic Assembly of a Deep-Cavity Cavitand. Journal of the American Chemical Society 2011, 133, 4770&#x2013;4773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21401093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xf6;ttcher J; Dilworth D; Reiser U; Neum&#xfc;ller RA; Schleicher M; Petronczki M; Zeeb M; Mischerikow N; Allali-Hassani A; Szewczyk MM; Li F; Kennedy S; Vedadi M; Barsyte-Lovejoy D; Brown PJ; Huber KV; Rogers CM; Wells CI; Fedorov O; Rumpel K; Zoephel A; Mayer M; Wunberg T; B&#xf6;se D; Zahn S; Arnhof H; Berger H; Reiser C; H&#xf6;rmann A; Krammer T; Corcokovic M; Sharps B; Winkler S; H&#xe4;ring D; Cockcroft XL; Fuchs JE; M&#xfc;llauer B; Weiss-Puxbaum A; Gerstberger T; Boehmelt G; Vakoc CR; Arrowsmith CH; Pearson M; McConnell DB Fragment-Based Discovery of a Chemical Probe for the PWWP1 Domain of NSD3. Nature Chemical Biology 2019, 15, 822&#x2013;829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31285596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray CW; Carr MG; Callaghan O; Chessari G; Congreve M; Cowan S; Coyle JE; Downham R; Figueroa E; Frederickson M; Graham B; McMenamin R; O&#x2019;Brien MA; Patel S; Phillips TR; Williams G; Woodhead AJ; Woolford AJ Fragment-Based Drug Discovery Applied to Hsp90. Discovery of Two Lead Series with High Ligand Efficiency. Journal of Medicinal Chemistry 2010, 53, 5942&#x2013;5955.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20718493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xe4;dler U; Schwarz D; Blaesse M; Leuthner B; Johnson TL; Bernard F; Jiang X; Marx A; Gilardone M; Lemoine H; Roche D; Jorand-Lebrun C Discovery of Novel Cyclophilin D Inhibitors Starting from Three Dimensional Fragments with Millimolar Potencies. Bioorganic and Medicinal Chemistry Letters 2019, 29, 126717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7195332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31635932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friberg A; Vigil D; Zhao B; Daniels RN; Burke JP; Garcia-Barrantes PM; Camper D; Chauder BA; Lee T; Olejniczak ET; Fesik SW Discovery of Potent Myeloid Cell Leukemia 1 (Mcl-1) Inhibitors Using Fragment-Based Methods and Structure-Based Design. Journal of Medicinal Chemistry 2013, 56, 15&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3646517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23244564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte Ramos Matos G; Kyu DY; Loeffler HH; Chodera JD; Shirts MR; Mobley DL Approaches for Calculating Solvation Free Energies and Enthalpies Demonstrated with an Update of the FreeSolv Database. Journal of Chemical and Engineering Data 2017, 62, 1559&#x2013;1569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5648357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29056756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiu Y; Smith DGA; Boothroyd S; Jang H; Wagner J; Bannan CC; Gokey T; Lim VT; Stern CD; Rizzi A; Lucas X; Tjanaka B; Shirts MR; Gilson MK; Chodera JD; Bayly CI; Mobley DL; Wang LP Development and Benchmarking of Open Force Field 2.0.0: The Sage Small Molecule Force Field. Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation 2023, 19, 3251&#x2013;3275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10269353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37167319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakalian A; Bush BL; Jack DB; Bayly CI Fast, Efficient Generation of High-Quality Atomic Charges. AM1-BCC Model: I. Method. Journal of Computational Chemistry 2000, 21, 132&#x2013;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12395429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakalian A; Jack DB; Bayly CI Fast, Efficient Generation of High-Quality Atomic Charges. AM1-BCC Model: II. Parameterization and Validation. Journal of Computational Chemistry 2002, 23, 1623&#x2013;1641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12395429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornak V; Abel R; Okur A; Strockbine B; Roitberg A; Simmerling C Comparison of Multiple Amber Force Fields and Development of Improved Protein Backbone Parameters. Proteins: Structure, Function and Bioinformatics 2006, 65, 712&#x2013;725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4805110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16981200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindorff-Larsen K; Piana S; Palmo K; Maragakis P; Klepeis JL; Dror RO; Shaw DE Improved Side-Chain Torsion Potentials for the Amber ff99SB Protein Force Field. Proteins: Structure, Function and Bioinformatics 2010, 78, 1950&#x2013;1958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2970904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20408171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maier JA; Martinez C; Kasavajhala K; Wickstrom L; Hauser KE; Simmerling C ff14SB: Improving the Accuracy of Protein Side Chain and Backbone Parameters from ff99SB. Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation 2015, 11, 3696&#x2013;3713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4821407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26574453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Case DA; Aktulga HM; Belfon K; Ben-Shalom IY; Berryman JT; Brozell SR; Cerutti DS; Cheatham TE; Cisneros GA; Cruzeiro VWD; Darden TA; Duke RE; Giambasu G; Gilson MK; Gohlke H; Goetz AW; Harris R; Izadi S; Izmailov SA; Kasavajhala K; Kaymak MC; King E; Kovalenko A; Kurtzman T; Lee TS; LeGrand S; Li P; Lin C; Liu J; Luchko T; Luo R; Machado M; Man V; Manathunga M; Merz KM; Miao Y; Mikhailovskii O; Monard G; Nguyen H; O&#x2019;Hearn KA; Onufriev A; Pan F; Pantano S; Qi R; Rahnamoun A; Roe DR; Roitberg A; Sagui C; Schott-Verdugo S; Shajan A; Shen J; Simmerling CL; Skrynnikov NR; Smith J; Swails J; Walker RC; Wang J; Wang J; Wei H; Wolf RM; Wu Y; Xiong Y; Xue Y; York DM; Zhao S; Kollman P Amber 2022, University of California, San Francisco. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumann HM; Gapsys V; De Groot BL; Mobley DL Challenges Encountered Applying Equilibrium and Nonequilibrium Binding Free Energy Calculations. Journal of Physical Chemistry B 2021, 125, 4241&#x2013;4261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8240641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33905257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou HX; Gilson MK Theory of Free Energy and Entropy in Noncovalent Binding. Chemical Reviews 2009, 109, 4092&#x2013;4107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3329805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19588959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>