<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40544624</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1095-7103</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>699</Volume><Issue>Pt 2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of colloid and interface science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Colloid Interface Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Co-hydrolyzed bio-inspired antifouling coatings for functional membranes in oily wastewater treatment.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>138197</StartPage><MedlinePgn>138197</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138197</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0021-9797(25)01588-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="HYPOTHESIS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The fast and unregulated bio-inspired Schiff base and Michael addition reactions between phenol- and amino-based materials often lead to the formation of uneven coatings with large aggregates, affecting the coating efficiency and various designed functionalities. Therefore, a co-hydrolysis strategy was proposed to modulate the phenol/amino reaction and the self-assembly coating process, achieving uniform and compact phenol/amino-based antifouling coating.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="EXPERIMENTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A uniform bio-inspired antifouling coating was fabricated by modulating the Schiff base and Michael addition reactions between tannic acid with amino groups within the co-hydrolyzed amino, zwitterionic, and fluorine-containing silane system. The surface morphology and underlying molecular interaction mechanism was probed by atomic force microscopy (AFM). The wettability of the coating was tuned through optimization of the coating composition and its interfacial antifouling performance was evaluated using quartz crystal microbalance (QCM) and optical photothermal infrared (O-PTIR) spectroscopy. The separation efficiency of the coated polyvinylidene difluoride (PVDF) membrane for treating oil-in-water emulsions was assessed using dead-end filtration tests.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Molecular force measurements and antifouling test results showed that incorporating zwitterionic and fluorine-containing silane not only regulated the Schiff base and Michael addition reaction rates, enabling the formation of a uniform surface coating, but also provided a stable hydration layer and low-surface-energy sites to enhance the fouling resistance and fouling release properties of the prepared antifouling surfaces. The proposed coating can be extended for membrane surface functionalization, showing enhanced water flux (over 5700 L m<sup>-2</sup> h<sup>-1</sup> bar<sup>-1</sup>) and excellent separation performance of oil-in-water emulsions even in the presence of additional bio-foulants, with a flux recovery ratio over 90&#xa0;%. This study proposes and validates a co-hydrolysis strategy that enables precise control over the structure and morphology of phenol/amino-based coating systems by modulating steric and hydration effects as well as electrostatic repulsion between reactive colloids. This strategy can be extended to other phenol/amino-based coating systems to modulate surface functionality and morphology through interfacial design.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Charley</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical and Materials Engineering, University of Alberta, Edmonton T6G 1H9 Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Pan</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical and Materials Engineering, University of Alberta, Edmonton T6G 1H9 Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Wenshuai</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zhongyuan Critical Metal Laboratory, Zhengzhou 450001, China; The Key Lab of Critical Metals Minerals Supernormal Enrichment and Extraction, Ministry of Education, Zhengzhou, Henan 450001, China. Electronic address: wenshuaiyang@zzu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Jifang</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cancer Center, The Fifth Affiliated Hospital, Guangzhou Medical University, 510700 Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Hongbo</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical and Materials Engineering, University of Alberta, Edmonton T6G 1H9 Alberta, Canada. Electronic address: hongbo.zeng@ualberta.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Colloid Interface Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0043125</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0021-9797</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antifouling coating</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bio-inspired</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Membrane oil/water separation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surface modulation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40544624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcis.2025.138197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0021-9797(25)01588-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>