<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38516768</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1478-5153</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nursing in critical care</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nurs Crit Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nursing experiences and knowledge of paediatric delirium: Analysing knowledge-practice gaps.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>923</StartPage><EndPage>930</EndPage><MedlinePgn>923-930</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nicc.13068</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Delirium commonly occurs in paediatric patients with acute critical illness and negatively affects clinical outcomes. Variations in delirium knowledge levels and its management have been noted among nurses.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIMS">This study investigated nurses' experiences and knowledge levels regarding paediatric delirium. Additionally, we aimed to assess the gap between knowledge levels and practical experiences with paediatric delirium.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN">This cross-sectional descriptive study conveniently sampled paediatric nurses from a university hospital in South Korea between September 2022 and March 2023. Nursing experiences with paediatric delirium and delirium knowledge levels were measured using structured survey questionnaires. Delirium knowledge was scored 0 to 47, and higher scores indicated higher levels of delirium-related knowledge. Data were analysed using descriptive statistics and presented as mean, standard deviation, frequency and percentage.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A total of 127 paediatric nurses participated in this study; 40.2% had experience with 1-5 delirium cases in the previous year, and 86.6% (n =&#x2009;110) had never used assessment tools for paediatric delirium assessment. The mean total delirium knowledge score was 34.45&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;5.4; the mean scores of knowledge regarding aetiology, signs and symptoms and nursing management of delirium were 8.93&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;1.31, 13.24&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.81 and 12.3&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;2.7, respectively. Interventions associated with a lower level of delirium-related knowledge and a lower performance rate included avoiding restraint use and maintaining hydration and electrolyte levels. Interventions associated with a higher level of delirium-related knowledge but a lower rate of performance comprised providing orientation, offering emotional support, allowing participants to stay with family members and administering medications to manage delirium.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Although nurses working in paediatric units exhibited high rate of delirium nursing care, there was the gap between their delirium-related knowledge and practice. Nurses need to be aware of the insufficient part of delirium care, and paediatric delirium education should be reinforced.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RELEVANCE TO CLINICAL PRACTICE">Preventing, assessing and systematically managing paediatric delirium is crucial, and considering the study results, delirium education among nurses is needed.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Authors. Nursing in Critical Care published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of British Association of Critical Care Nurses.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shon</LastName><ForeName>Soonyoung</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0571-2181</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, Keimyung University, Daegu, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Minkyung</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1105-1757</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, Ajou University, Suwon, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>20200602</GrantID><Agency>Bisa Research Grant of Keimyung University</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nurs Crit Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9808649</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1362-1017</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003693" MajorTopicYN="Y">Delirium</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000451" MajorTopicYN="N">nursing</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056910" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Republic of Korea</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002983" MajorTopicYN="Y">Clinical Competence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007722" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Knowledge, Attitudes, Practice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064648" MajorTopicYN="N">Critical Care Nursing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010371" MajorTopicYN="N">Pediatric Nursing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009741" MajorTopicYN="N">Nursing Staff, Hospital</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000193" MajorTopicYN="N">education</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knowledge</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neonate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nurse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">paediatric delirium</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">performance</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38516768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nicc.13068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>American Psychiatric Association D, Association AP. Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders: DSM&#x2010;5. Vol 5. American Psychiatric Association; 2013 [cited 2023 Dec 12]. Available from: https://www.academia.edu/download/38718268/csl6820_21.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thom RP, Levy&#x2010;Carrick NC, Bui M, Silbersweig D. Delirium. Am J Psychiatry. 2019;176(10):785&#x2010;793. doi:10.1176/appi.ajp.2018.18070893</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams SJ, Sprecher A. Delirium in the neonate. Clin Perinatol. 2022;49(1):1&#x2010;14. doi:10.1016/j.clp.2021.11.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel EJ, Traube C. Pediatric delirium: epidemiology and outcomes. Curr Opin Pediatr. 2020;32(6):743&#x2010;749. doi:10.1097/MOP.0000000000000960</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traube C, Silver G, Gerber LM, et al. Delirium and mortality in critically ill children: epidemiology and outcomes of pediatric delirium. Crit Care Med. 2017;45(5):891&#x2010;898. doi:10.1097/CCM.0000000000002324</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porter S, Holly C, Echevarria M. Infants with delirium: a primer on prevention, recognition, and management. Pediatr Nurs. 2016;42:223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semple D, Howlett MM, Strawbridge JD, Breatnach CV, Hayden JC. A systematic review and pooled prevalence of delirium in critically ill children. Crit Care Med. 2022;50(2):317&#x2010;328. doi:10.1097/CCM.0000000000005260</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bettencourt A, Mullen JE. Delirium in children: identification, prevention, and management. Crit Care Nurse. 2017;37(3):e9&#x2010;e18. doi:10.4037/ccn2017692</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siegel EJ, Groves AM, Silver G, Hojsak J, Lim CA, Traube C. Delirium in the NICU: a point prevalence study. Hosp Pediatr. 2021;11(11):e321&#x2010;e326. doi:10.1542/hpeds.2020&#x2010;005736</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amula V, Vener DF, Pribble CG, et al. Changes in anesthetic and postoperative sedation&#x2010;analgesia practice associated with early Extubation following infant cardiac surgery: experience from the pediatric heart network collaborative learning study. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2019;20(10):931&#x2010;939. doi:10.1097/PCC.0000000000002005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turkel SB. Pediatric delirium: recognition, management, and outcome. Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2017;19(12):101. doi:10.1007/s11920-017-0851-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traube C, Mauer EA, Gerber LM, et al. Cost associated with pediatric delirium in the ICU. Crit Care Med. 2016;44(12):e1175&#x2010;e1179. doi:10.1097/CCM.0000000000002004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalvas LB, Harrison TM. State of the science in pediatric ICU delirium: an integrative review. Res Nurs Health. 2020;43(4):341&#x2010;355. doi:10.1002/nur.22054</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sikich N, Lerman J. Development and psychometric evaluation of the pediatric anesthesia emergence delirium scale. Anesthesiology. 2004;100(5):1138&#x2010;1145. doi:10.1097/00000542&#x2010;200405000&#x2010;00015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staveski SL, Pickler RH, Lin L, et al. Management of Pediatric Delirium in pediatric cardiac intensive care patients: an international survey of current practices. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2018;19(6):538&#x2010;543. doi:10.1097/PCC.0000000000001558</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Castro REV, de Magalh&#xe3;es&#x2010;Barbosa MC, da Cunha AJLA, Cheniaux E, Prata&#x2010;Barbosa A. Delirium detection based on the clinical experience of pediatric intensivists. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2020;21(9):e869&#x2010;e873. doi:10.1097/PCC.0000000000002482</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konca C, Anil AB, K&#xfc;ll&#xfc;oglu EP, Luleyap D, Anil M, Tekin M. Evaluation of pediatric delirium awareness and management in pediatric intensive care units in Turkey. J Pediatr Intensive Care. 2022;11(2):130&#x2010;137. doi:10.1055/s&#x2010;0040&#x2010;1721507</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee YW, Kim CG, Kong ES, et al. A study of Nurses' knowledge level and assessment experience of delirium. J Korean Acad Adult Nurs. 2007;19(1):35&#x2010;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim EY. An Exploratory Study of Staff Nurse's Knowledge and Experience of Delirium in the Pediatric Intensive Care Unit [Master's thesis]. [Seoul, South Korea]: The Catholic University of Korea. doi:10.1002/smll.202400031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Kim DH, Kim HJ, Kim DH. Factors associated with pediatric delirium in the pediatric intensive care unit. Child Health Nurs Res. 2019;25(2):103&#x2010;111. doi:10.4094/chnr.2019.25.2.103</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schieveld JNM, Ista E, Knoester H, Molag ML. Pediatric delirium: a practical approach. IACAPAP e&#x2010;Textbook of Child and Adolescent Mental Health. International Association for Child and Adolescent Psychiatry and Allied Professions; 2015:1&#x2010;17. Available from: https://iacapap.org/_Resources/Persistent/24fc6273bb4a1fd3001cbe0bf65069b336420337/I.5&#x2010;DELIRIUM&#x2010;2015.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stenkjaer RL, Egerod I, Moszkowicz M, et al. Clinical application of &#x2018;Sophia observation withdrawal symptoms&#x2010;Paediatric delirium&#x2019; screening tool in Danish version: a feasibility study. Scand J Caring Sci. 2022;36(4):1027&#x2010;1036. doi:10.1111/scs.13073</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nam SY, Park KY, Choi SJ. The reliability and validity of the Korean version of the Cornell assessment of pediatric delirium. J Korean Clin Nurs Res. 2020;26(2):254&#x2010;264. doi:10.22650/JKCNR.2020.26.2.254</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nam SY, Choi SJ, Oh SR, Chio JE, Park KY. Effects of a multifaceted pediatric delirium education program for pediatric intensive care unit nurses on their delirium knowledge, self&#x2010;confidence in delirium nursing, and delirium assessment accuracy: a one group pretest&#x2010;posttest design. J Korean Crit Care Nurs. 2023;16(1):56&#x2010;70. doi:10.34250/jkccn.2023.16.1.56</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franken A, Sebbens D, Mensik J. Pediatric delirium: early identification of barriers to optimize success of screening and prevention. J Pediatr Health Care. 2019;33(3):228&#x2010;233. doi:10.1016/j.pedhc.2018.08.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demir Korkmaz F, Gok F, Yavuz KA. Cardiovascular surgery nurses' level of knowledge regarding delirium. Nurs Crit Care. 2016;21(5):279&#x2010;286. doi:10.1111/nicc.12184</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calandriello A, Tylka JC, Patwari PP. Sleep and delirium in pediatric critical illness: what is the relationship? Med Sci. 2018;6(4):90. doi:10.3390/medsci6040090</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azoulay E, Pochard F, Kentish&#x2010;Barnes N, et al. Risk of post&#x2010;traumatic stress symptoms in family members of intensive care unit patients. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2005;171(9):987&#x2010;994. doi:10.1164/rccm.200409&#x2010;1295OC</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stenkjaer RL, Herling SF, Egerod I, et al. Development of a non&#x2010;pharmacologic delirium management bundle in paediatric intensive care units. Nurs Crit Care. 2022;27(6):867&#x2010;876. doi:10.1111/nicc.12809</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo JB, Kim MJ, Cho SH, Shin YJ, Kim NC. The effects of pre&#x2010;operative visual information and parental presence intervention on anxiety, delirium, and pain of post&#x2010;operative pediatric patients in PACU. J Korean Acad Nurs. 2012;42(3):333&#x2010;341. doi:10.4040/jkan.2012.42.3.333</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silver G, Traube C. A systematic approach to family engagement: feasibility pilot of a pediatric delirium management and prevention toolkit. Palliat Support Care. 2019;17(1):42&#x2010;45. doi:10.1017/S1478951518000895</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray L, Snodin J, Carter B. Holding and restraining children for clinical procedures within an acute care setting: an ethical consideration of the evidence. Nurs Inq. 2015;22(2):157&#x2010;167. doi:10.1111/nin.12074</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ista E, Traube C, de Neef M, et al. Factors associated with delirium in children: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2023;24(5):372&#x2010;381. doi:10.1097/PCC.0000000000003196</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zainal Abidin H, Omar SC, Mazlan MZ, et al. Postoperative maladaptive behavior, preoperative anxiety and emergence delirium in children undergone general anesthesia: a narrative review. Glob Pediatr Health. 2021;8:2333794X211007975. doi:10.1177/2333794X211007975</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Tuijl SG, van Cauteren YJ, Pikhard T, Engel M, Schieveld JN. Management of pediatric delirium in critical illness: a practical update. Minerva Anestesiol. 2015;81(3):333&#x2010;341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kishk OA, Simone S, Lardieri AB, Graciano AL, Tumulty J, Edwards S. Antipsychotic treatment of delirium in critically ill children: a retrospective matched cohort study. J Pediatr Pharmacol Ther. 2019;24(3):204&#x2010;213. doi:10.5863/1551&#x2010;6776&#x2010;24.3.204</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyce C, Witcher R, Herrup E, et al. Evaluation of the safety of quetiapine in treating delirium in critically ill children: a retrospective review. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2015;25(9):666&#x2010;670. doi:10.1089/cap.2015.0093</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee G, Roh YS. Knowledge, barriers, and training needs of nurses working in delirium care. Nurs Crit Care. 2023;28(5):637&#x2010;644. doi:10.1111/nicc.12724</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park H&#x2010;m, Chang MY. Nurse's knowledge, confidence and performance on care for delirium. J Health Inform Stat. 2016;41(4):359&#x2010;368. doi:10.21032/jhis.2016.41.4.359</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simone S, Edwards S, Lardieri A, et al. Implementation of an ICU bundle: an interprofessional quality improvement project to enhance delirium management and monitor delirium prevalence in a single PICU. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2017;18(6):531&#x2010;540. doi:10.1097/PCC.0000000000001127</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>