<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38634162</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-8137</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>243</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The New phytologist</Title><ISOAbbreviation>New Phytol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Harnessing photosynthetic C<sup>18</sup>O<sup>16</sup>O discrimination dynamics under leaf water nonsteady state to estimate mesophyll conductance: a new, regression-based method.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2102</StartPage><EndPage>2114</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2102-2114</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nph.19767</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Mesophyll conductance (g<sub>m</sub>) is a crucial plant trait that can significantly limit photosynthesis. Measurement of photosynthetic C<sup>18</sup>O<sup>16</sup>O discrimination (&#x394;<sup>18</sup>O) has proved to be the only viable means of resolving g<sub>m</sub> in both C<sub>3</sub> and C<sub>4</sub> plants. However, the currently available methods to exploit &#x394;<sup>18</sup>O for g<sub>m</sub> estimation are error prone due to their inadequacy in constraining the degree of oxygen isotope exchange (&#x3b8;) during mesophyll CO<sub>2</sub> hydration. Here, we capitalized on experimental manipulation of leaf water isotopic dynamics to establish a novel, nonsteady state, regression-based approach for simultaneous determination of g<sub>m</sub> and &#x3b8; from online &#x394;<sup>18</sup>O measurements. We demonstrated the methodological and theoretical robustness of this new &#x394;<sup>18</sup>O-g<sub>m</sub> estimation approach and showed through measurements on several C<sub>3</sub> and C<sub>4</sub> species that this&#xa0;approach can serve as a benchmark method against which to identify previously-unrecognized biases of the existing &#x394;<sup>18</sup>O-g<sub>m</sub> methods. Our results highlight the unique value of this nonsteady state-based approach for contributing to ongoing efforts toward quantitative understanding of mesophyll conductance for crop yield improvement and carbon cycle modeling.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Author(s). New Phytologist &#xa9; 2024 New Phytologist Foundation.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rao</LastName><ForeName>Sen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8754-7858</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Life Sciences and Oceanography, Shenzhen University, Shenzhen, 518060, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Optoelectronic Devices and Systems of Ministry of Education and Guangdong Province, College of Optoelectronic Engineering, Shenzhen University, Shenzhen, 518060, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Tao</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6450-9111</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Resources, Sichuan Agricultural University, Chengdu, 611130, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cernusak</LastName><ForeName>Lucas A</ForeName><Initials>LA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7575-5526</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Science and Engineering, James Cook University, Cairns, Qld, 4878, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Xin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8513-3595</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Life Sciences and Oceanography, Shenzhen University, Shenzhen, 518060, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023DF005</GrantID><Agency>Research Team Cultivation Program of Shenzhen University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023JCT002</GrantID><Agency>Research Team Cultivation Program of Shenzhen University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>42177048</GrantID><Agency>National Natural Science Foundation of China</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>New Phytol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9882884</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0028-646X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010103">Oxygen Isotopes</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>142M471B3J</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002245">Carbon Dioxide</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058503" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mesophyll Cells</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010788" MajorTopicYN="Y">Photosynthesis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010103" MajorTopicYN="Y">Oxygen Isotopes</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="Y">Water</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018515" MajorTopicYN="Y">Plant Leaves</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012044" MajorTopicYN="N">Regression Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002245" MajorTopicYN="N">Carbon Dioxide</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">C4 plants</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">carbonic anhydrase</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">leaf water</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mesophyll conductance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxygen isotopes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">photosynthetic discrimination</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38634162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nph.19767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Barbour MM, Evans JR, Simonin KA, von Caemmerer S. 2016. Online CO2 and H2O oxygen isotope fractionation allows estimation of mesophyll conductance in C4 plants, and reveals that mesophyll conductance decreases as leaves age in both C4 and C3 plants. New Phytologist 210: 875&#x2013;889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickford CP, Mcdowell NG, Erhardt EB, Hanson DT. 2009. High&#x2010;frequency field measurements of diurnal carbon isotope discrimination and internal conductance in a semi&#x2010;arid species, Juniperus monosperma. Plant, Cell &amp; Environment 32: 796&#x2013;810.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busch FA, Holloway&#x2010;Phillips M, Stuart&#x2010;Williams H, Farquhar GD. 2020. Revisiting carbon isotope discrimination in C3 plants shows respiration rules when photosynthesis is low. Nature Plants 6: 245&#x2013;258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Caemmerer S. 2021. Updating the steady&#x2010;state model of C4 photosynthesis. Journal of Experimental Botany 72: 6003&#x2013;6017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cano FJ, Sharwood RE, Cousins AB, Ghannoum O. 2019. The role of leaf width and conductances to CO2 in determining water use efficiency in C4 grasses. New Phytologist 223: 1280&#x2013;1295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cernusak LA, Farquhar GD, Wong SC, Stuart&#x2010;Williams H. 2004. Measurement and interpretation of the oxygen isotope composition of carbon dioxide respired by leaves in the dark. Plant Physiology 136: 3350&#x2013;3363.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cousins AB, Badger MR, von Caemmerer S. 2006. A transgenic approach to understanding the influence of carbonic anhydrase on C18OO discrimination during C4 photosynthesis. Plant Physiology 142: 662&#x2013;672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cousins AB, Badger MR, von Caemmerer S. 2008. C4 photosynthetic isotope exchange in NAD&#x2010;ME&#x2010; and NADP&#x2010;ME&#x2010;type grasses. Journal of Experimental Botany 59: 1695&#x2013;1703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cousins AB, Baroli I, Badger MR, Ivakov A, Lea PJ, Leegood RC, von Caemmerer S. 2007. The role of phosphoenolpyruvate carboxylase during C4 photosynthetic isotope exchange and stomatal conductance. Plant Physiology 145: 1006&#x2013;1017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cousins AB, Mullendore DL, Sonawane BV. 2020. Recent developments in mesophyll conductance in C3, C4, and crassulacean acid metabolism plants. The Plant Journal 101: 816&#x2013;830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crawford JD, Cousins AB. 2022. Limitation of C4 photosynthesis by low carbonic anhydrase activity increases with temperature but does not influence mesophyll CO2 conductance. Journal of Experimental Botany 73: 927&#x2013;938.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiMario RJ, Clayton H, Mukherjee A, Ludwig M, Moroney JV. 2017. Plant carbonic anhydrases: structures, locations, evolution, and physiological roles. Molecular Plant 10: 30&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubbert M, K&#xfc;bert A, Werner C. 2017. Impact of leaf traits on temporal dynamics of transpired oxygen isotope signatures and its impact on atmospheric vapor. Frontiers in Plant Science 8: 5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ermakova M, Osborn H, Groszmann M, Bala S, Bowerman A, McGaughey S, Byrt C, Alonso&#x2010;cantabrana H, Tyerman S, Furbank R et&#xa0;al. 2021. Expression of a CO2&#x2010;permeable aquaporin enhances mesophyll conductance in the C4 species Setaria viridis. eLife 10: e70095.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans JR, von Caemmerer S. 2013. Temperature response of carbon isotope discrimination and mesophyll conductance in tobacco. Plant, Cell &amp; Environment 36: 745&#x2013;756.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans JR, Sharkey TD, Berry JA, Farquhar GD. 1986. Carbon isotope discrimination measured concurrently with gas exchange to investigate CO2 diffusion in leaves of higher plants. Functional Plant Biology 13: 281&#x2013;292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farquhar GD, Cernusak LA. 2012. Ternary effects on the gas exchange of isotopologues of carbon dioxide. Plant, Cell &amp; Environment 35: 1221&#x2013;1231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farquhar GD, Cernusak LA, Barnes B. 2007. Heavy water fractionation during transpiration. Plant Physiology 143: 11&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farquhar GD, Griffani DS, Barbour MM. 2021. The effects on isotopic composition of leaf water and transpiration of adding a gas&#x2010;exchange cuvette. Plant, Cell &amp; Environment 44: 2844&#x2013;2857.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farquhar GD, Lloyd J. 1993. Carbon and oxygen isotope effects in the exchange of carbon dioxide between terrestrial plants and the atmosphere. In: Ehleringer JR, Hall AE, Farquhar GD, eds. Stable isotopes and plant carbon&#x2013;water relations. San Diego, CA, USA: Academic Press, 47&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farquhar GD, Lloyd J, Taylor JA, Flanagan LB, Syvertsen JP, Hubick KT, Wong SC, Ehleringer JR. 1993. Vegetation effects on the isotope composition of oxygen in atmospheric CO2. Nature 363: 439&#x2013;443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flexas J, Barbour MM, Brendel O, Cabrera HM, Carriqu&#xed; M, D&#xed;az&#x2010;Espejo A, Douthe C, Dreyer E, Ferrio JP, Gago J et&#xa0;al. 2012. Mesophyll diffusion conductance to CO2: an unappreciated central player in photosynthesis. Plant Science 193&#x2013;194: 70&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillon J, Yakir D. 2001. Influence of carbonic anhydrase activity in terrestrial vegetation on the 18O content of atmospheric CO2. Science 291: 2584&#x2013;2587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillon JS, Yakir D. 2000a. Internal conductance to CO2 diffusion and C18OO discrimination in C3 leaves. Plant Physiology 123: 201&#x2013;214.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillon JS, Yakir D. 2000b. Naturally low carbonic anhydrase activity in C4 and C3 plants limits discrimination against C18OO during photosynthesis. Plant, Cell &amp; Environment 23: 903&#x2013;915.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatch MD, Burnell JN. 1990. Carbonic anhydrase activity in leaves and its role in the first step of C4 photosynthesis. Plant Physiology 93: 825&#x2013;828.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helliker BR, Griffiths H. 2007. Toward a plant&#x2010;based proxy for the isotope ratio of atmospheric water vapor. Global Change Biology 13: 723&#x2013;733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holloway&#x2010;Phillips M, Cernusak LA, Stuart&#x2010;Williams H, Ubierna N, Farquhar GD. 2019. Two&#x2010;source &#x3b4;18O method to validate the CO18O&#x2010;photosynthetic discrimination model: implications for mesophyll conductance. Plant Physiology 181: 1175&#x2013;1190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knauer J, Cuntz M, Evans JR, Niinemets &#xdc;, Tosens T, Veromann&#x2010;J&#xfc;rgenson LL, Werner C, Zaehle S. 2022. Contrasting anatomical and biochemical controls on mesophyll conductance across plant functional types. New Phytologist 236: 357&#x2013;368.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kodama N, Cousins A, Tu KP, Barbour MM. 2011. Spatial variation in photosynthetic CO2 carbon and oxygen isotope discrimination along leaves of the monocot triticale (Triticum &#xd7; Secale) relates to mesophyll conductance and the P&#xe9;clet effect. Plant, Cell &amp; Environment 34: 1548&#x2013;1562.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehmann MM, Goldsmith GR, Schmid L, Gessler A, Saurer M, Siegwolf RT. 2018. The effect of 18O&#x2010;labelled water vapour on the oxygen isotope ratio of water and assimilates in plants at high humidity. New Phytologist 217: 105&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T, Barbour MM, Yu D, Rao S, Song X. 2022. Mesophyll conductance exerts a significant limitation on photosynthesis during light induction. New Phytologist 233: 360&#x2013;372.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loucos KE, Simonin KA, Barbour MM. 2017. Leaf hydraulic conductance and mesophyll conductance are not closely related within a single species. Plant, Cell &amp; Environment 40: 203&#x2013;215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Momayyezi M, McKown AD, Bell SC, Guy RD. 2020. Emerging roles for carbonic anhydrase in mesophyll conductance and photosynthesis. The Plant Journal 101: 831&#x2013;844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Og&#xe9;e J, Wingate L, Genty B. 2018. Estimating mesophyll conductance from measurements of C18OO photosynthetic discrimination and carbonic anhydrase activity. Plant Physiology 178: 728&#x2013;752.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathare VS, DiMario RJ, Koteyeva N, Cousins AB. 2022. Mesophyll conductance response to short&#x2010;term changes in pCO2 is related to leaf anatomy and biochemistry in diverse C4 grasses. New Phytologist 236: 1281&#x2013;1295.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathare VS, Koteyeva N, Cousins AB. 2020. Increased adaxial stomatal density is associated with greater mesophyll surface area exposed to intercellular air spaces and mesophyll conductance in diverse C4 grasses. New Phytologist 225: 169&#x2013;182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pons TL, Flexas J, von Caemmerer S, Evans JR, Genty B, Ribas&#x2010;Carbo M, Brugnoli E. 2009. Estimating mesophyll conductance to CO2: methodology, potential errors, and recommendations. Journal of Experimental Botany 60: 2217&#x2013;2234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shrestha A, Song X, Barbour MM. 2019. The temperature response of mesophyll conductance, and its component conductances, varies between species and genotypes. Photosynthesis Research 141: 65&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonin KA, Roddy AB, Link P, Apodaca R, Tu KP, Hu J, Dawson TE, Barbour MM. 2013. Isotopic composition of transpiration and rates of change in leaf water isotopologue storage in response to environmental variables. Plant, Cell &amp; Environment 36: 2190&#x2013;2206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonawane BV, Cousins AB. 2019. Uncertainties and limitations of using carbon&#x2010;13 and oxygen&#x2010;18 leaf isotope exchange to estimate the temperature response of mesophyll CO2 conductance in C3 plants. New Phytologist 222: 122&#x2013;131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonawane BV, Cousins AB. 2020. Mesophyll CO2 conductance and leakiness are not responsive to short&#x2010; and long&#x2010;term soil water limitations in the C4 plant Sorghum bicolor. The Plant Journal 103: 1590&#x2013;1602.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonawane BV, Koteyeva NK, Johnson DM, Cousins AB. 2021. Differences in leaf anatomy determines temperature response of leaf hydraulic and mesophyll CO2 conductance in phylogenetically related C4 and C3 grass species. New Phytologist 230: 1802&#x2013;1814.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song X, Simonin KA, Loucos KE, Barbour MM. 2015. Modelling non&#x2010;steady&#x2010;state isotope enrichment of leaf water in a gas&#x2010;exchange cuvette environment. Plant, Cell &amp; Environment 38: 2618&#x2013;2628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tazoe Y, von Caemmerer S, Estavillo GM, Evans JR. 2011. Using tunable diode laser spectroscopy to measure carbon isotope discrimination and mesophyll conductance to CO2 diffusion dynamically at different CO2 concentrations. Plant, Cell &amp; Environment 34: 580&#x2013;591.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ubierna N, Gandin A, Boyd RA, Cousins AB. 2017. Temperature response of mesophyll conductance in three C4 species calculated with two methods: 18O discrimination and in vitro Vpmax. New Phytologist 214: 66&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ubierna N, Gandin A, Cousins AB. 2018. The response of mesophyll conductance to short&#x2010;term variation in CO2 in the C4 plants Setaria viridis and Zea mays. Journal of Experimental Botany 69: 1159&#x2013;1170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Good SP, Caylor KK, Cernusak LA. 2012. Direct quantification of leaf transpiration isotopic composition. Agricultural and Forest Meteorology 154: 127&#x2013;135.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>