<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41256069</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1642-395X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Postepy dermatologii i alergologii</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Postepy Dermatol Alergol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Regeneration of the skin of oncology patients after radiation therapy using upcycled fish collagen.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>502</StartPage><EndPage>506</EndPage><MedlinePgn>502-506</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5114/ada.2025.154820</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Oncological therapy is a very complex process. An accurate diagnosis is the first and most important stage of therapy for the patient as it allows the medical staff to determine what treatment is necessary and how to plan it. Cancer treatment is now widely recognized as holistic, in which the body is viewed as one interconnected system. Cancer therapy should not focus on just one area of care, but should also include treatment support such as proper nutrition, pain management, psychological care, rehabilitation and nursing. Cancer therapy, despite its effectiveness, has a number of negative effects felt mainly in the area of the skin subjected to irradiation. Side effects significantly affect the patient's quality of life through pain, discomfort and a negative impact on the aesthetic value of the skin.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The aim of the article was to confirm the level of hydration, limit excessive water loss and regulate the pH value of the skin of patients after cancer treatment who were administered fish collagen.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIAL AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The cosmetic preparation collagen laminate obtained by ultrafiltration was tested on patients who underwent therapy at the University Hospital in Zielona Gora and who underwent radiotherapy. Patients are currently no longer undergoing treatment. The research group of 50 women suffered from breast cancer (<i>n</i> = 50). Before the experiment, the patients' skin was examined to diagnose its condition (zero condition). The study was conducted with the consent of the Bioethics Committee in Poznan (consent number 692/23). Each participant received a commercial cosmetic preparation. People who underwent radiotherapy applied the cosmetic to the area exposed to radiation, i.e., their breasts. Patients used the preparation twice a day, in the morning and in the evening. The preparation was used to eliminate skin reactions to oncological treatment. The study lasted 6 months. Then, digital measurements were performed monthly using a Courage + Khazaka Electronic GmbH device to measure hydration, transepidermal water loss (TEWL) and pH value.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Already after the first use, the device's skin hydration level increases by 5 a.u. In the next month it increased by 15 a.u. and in the fourth month it increased by 30 IU. Staff skin hydration levels increased linearly over time. After 5 parameters enabling 55 [a.u.] and after 6 a.m., another one until 6 a.m. [a.u.]. The average TEWL value measured in patients after radiotherapy was 40 g/m<sup>2</sup>/h. With the duration of the study/During the study, the TEWL parameter gradually improved, oscillating after 6 months of study at an average level of 6 g/m<sup>2</sup>/h. X-ray therapy also has an adverse effect on the condition of the skin, increasing the normal slightly acidic reaction on the skin surface. Based on the research, it was found that the longer the time since the end of the therapy, the less alkaline the pH became.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">It was confirmed that the product tested for an oncological patient has an appropriate level of skin hydration, supports the reconstruction of the skin and its energy barrier by reducing transepidermal water loss and restoring appropriate pH values.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2025 Termedia Sp. z o. o.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Igielska-Kalwat</LastName><ForeName>Joanna</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Food Technology of Plant Orgin, Faculty of Food Science and Nutrition, Poznan University of Life Sciences, Poznan, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Education and Therapy, Poznan, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Poland</Country><MedlineTA>Postepy Dermatol Alergol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101168357</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1642-395X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">collagen</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oncological skin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">radiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">upcycling</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41256069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12621205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5114/ada.2025.154820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">56874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>McKay J, Hirano N. Chemioterapia radioterapia. Gda&#x144;skie Wydawnictwo Psychologiczne, Gda&#x144;sk: 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autier J, Mateus C, Wechsler L. Cutaneous side effects of sorafenib and sunitinib. Ann Dermatol Venereol 2008; 135: 148-53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18342102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergonie J, Tribondeau L. L&#x2019;interpretation de quelques resultants de la radiotherapie et essai de fixation d&#x2019;une technique rationnelle. CR Seances Acad Sci 1996; 143: 983-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McQuestion M. Evidence-based skin care management in radiation therapy. Semin Oncol Nurses 2006; 22: 163-73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16893745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wi&#x15b;niewski M, Graczyk M, Szpinda M, Brzozowska-Ma&#x144;kowska S. Popromienne zapalenie sk&#xf3;ry &#x2013; zasady post&#x119;powania. Palliat Med Pract 2013; 7: 41-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michalewska J. Odczyny popromienne w radioterapii oraz popromienne zapalenie sk&#xf3;ry. Lett Oncol Sci 2017; 14: 104-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escudier B, Eisen T, Stadler WM. Sorafenib for treatment of renal cell carcinoma: final efficacy and safety results of the phase III treatment approaches in renal cancer global evaluation trial. J Clin Oncol 2009; 27: 3312-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19451442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martini MC. Kosmetologia i farmakologia sk&#xf3;ry. PZWL Wydawnictwo Lekarskie, Warsaw: 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan CW, Goldman BH, Lara PN Jr. Sorafenib with interferon alfa-2b in first-line treatment of advanced renal carcinoma: a phase II study of the Southwest Oncology Group. J Clin Oncol 2007; 25: 3296-301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17664477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong PY, Ohtake T, Brandt C, et al. Endogenous antimicrobial peptides and skin infections in atopic dermatitis. N Engl J Med 2002; 347: 1151-60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12374875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawlings AV, Matts PJ, Anderson CF, Roberts MS. Skin biology, xerosis, barrier repair and measurement. Drug Discov Today Dis Mech 2008; 5: 127-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatala M, Janowski K, Wa&#x142;achowska K, et al. Jako&#x15b;&#x107; &#x17c;ycia u kobiet w aspekcie prze&#xbf;ywania choroby nowotworowej gruczo&#x142;u piersiowego. Horyzonty Psychologii 2013; 3: 163-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lod&#xe9;n M. The skin barrier and use of moisturizers in atopic dermatitis. Clin Dermatol 2003; 21: 145-57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12706332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darlenski R, Sassning S, Tsankov N, Fluhr JW. Non-invasive in vivo methods for investigation of the skin barrier physical properties. Eur J Pharm Biopharm 2009; 72: 95-303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19118626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loden M, Maibach HI. Dry Skin and Moisturizers. Chemistry and Function. CRC Press, London, New York, Washington: 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacalak-Rzepka A, Bielecka-Grzela S, Klimowicz A, et al. Sucha sk&#xf3;ra jako problem dermatologiczny i kosmetyczny. Int J Adv Integr Med Sci 2008; 54: 54-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19839512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Igielska-Kalwat J, Kilian-Pi&#x119;ta E, Po&#x142;ocza&#x144;ska-Godek S. Trends in the manufacture and design of sustainable cosmetics. Clin Dermatol Open Access J 2023; 8: 000297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Igielska-Kalwat J, Kilian-Pi&#x119;ta E, Po&#x142;ocza&#x144;ska-Godek S. The use of biodegradable polymers obtained from fish waste in hair. Polymers 2022; 14: 749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8876148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35215659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>