<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38737042</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2470-1343</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>18</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ACS omega</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ACS Omega</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mud Cake Improver Mul-GX with Lubrication and Interface Enhancement Effect and Its Action Mechanism.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>20223</StartPage><EndPage>20230</EndPage><MedlinePgn>20223-20230</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acsomega.4c00462</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In view of the problems in which the solid content of drilling fluid increases in the middle and late stages of horizontal well drilling, the lubricity of mud cakes on the borehole wall decreases, and the friction of pipe string increases due to the gradual thickening of mud cakes, which leads to the sticking and the obvious decrease of cementing strength at the second interface, a mud cake improver Mul-GX with lubrication and interface enhancement effect was studied in this paper. Based on the hydration and filling mechanism, the lubricity of the mud cake was improved, its thickness was reduced, and its strength was improved through synergistic effects of solvated water film lubrication and buffering, hardening and crystallization of gelled substances, and filling and dispersion of elastic particles. The mud cake improver Mul-GX is composed of the metasilicate GX-ZQ, polymer copolymer GX-JB, and polymer GX-TX, and the mass ratio of each component was GX-ZQ: GX-JB: GX-TX = 15:1:0.5. The effect of Mul-GX was evaluated through the performance determination of the mud cake and interface cementing simulation experiments. In addition, the microscopic characterization by SEM and XRD were carried out to analyze the mechanism of Mul-GX. The experimental results showed that when Mul-GX was added to the water-based drilling fluid with the 1.0%-1.5% adding quantity, the mud cake lubricity improved by more than 60%, its thickness reduced by 53.9% on average, and its strength increased by 54.3% on average. At the same adding quantity, the interfacial bonding strength was 4.4 times more than the data before adding Mul-GX. All of the results showed that Mul-GX has obvious mud cake lubrication effect and interface enhancement effect.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Authors. Published by American Chemical Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Jianwei</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ministry of Education of China on Enhanced Oil and Gas Recovery, Northeast Petroleum University, Daqing, Heilongjiang 163318, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liang</LastName><ForeName>Mengna</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-6848-6678</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ministry of Education of China on Enhanced Oil and Gas Recovery, Northeast Petroleum University, Daqing, Heilongjiang 163318, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feng</LastName><ForeName>Fuping</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-9077-1009</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ministry of Education of China on Enhanced Oil and Gas Recovery, Northeast Petroleum University, Daqing, Heilongjiang 163318, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Reservoir Stimulation, China National Petroleum Corporation, Daqing, Heilongjiang 163311, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Yang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PetroChina Jilin Oilfield Company, China National Petroleum Corporation, Songyuan, Jilin 138000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Kun</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Drilling Engineering Technology Research Institute, Daqing Oilfield Drilling Engineering Company, Daqing, Heilongjiang 163413, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>Xu</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Ministry of Education of China on Enhanced Oil and Gas Recovery, Northeast Petroleum University, Daqing, Heilongjiang 163318, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>ACS Omega</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101691658</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2470-1343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing financial interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38737042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11080020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.4c00462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Qun L.; Yun X.; Bo C.; Baoshan G.; Xin W.; Guoqiang B.; Hui L.; Shuai L. I.; Bin D.; Haifeng F.; Zheng T.; Tao L.; Haoyu Z. Progress and prospects of horizontal well fracturing technology for shale oil and gas reservoirs. Pet. Explor. Dev. 2022, 49 (1), 191&#x2013;199. 10.1016/S1876-3804(22)60015-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1876-3804(22)60015-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie S.; Li H.; Hu Z.; Wen M.; Gao S.; Zhang H.; Luo H.; Zhang L. A review of the research status and development prospects for gravel packing sand control in horizontal wells. Geoenergy Sci. Eng. 2023, 229, 212152. 10.1016/j.geoen.2023.212152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geoen.2023.212152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X. M.; Fan Y.; Li J.; Su X.; Zhan S.; Hu G.; He Y.; Zhang M. Research on the Influence of a Cuttings Bed on Drill String Friction Torque in Horizontal Well Sections. Processes 2022, 10 (10), 2061. 10.3390/pr10102061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pr10102061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pakdaman E.; Osfouri S.; Azin R.; Niknam K.; Roohi A. Improving the rheology, lubricity, and differential sticking properties of water-based drilling muds at high temperatures using hydrophilic Gilsonite nanoparticles. Colloids Surf., A 2019, 582, 123930. 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2019.123930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2019.123930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan L.; Congjun L.; Zhang Z.; Wang J.; Xianguang X.; Sun J.; Yinao S.. Successful Application of Unique High-Density Water-Based Drilling Fluid Used in Zhaotong Shale Gas Horizontal Wells. In Paper presented at the SPE/IATMI Asia Pacific Oil &amp; Gas Conference and Exhibition; OnePetro: Nusa Dua, Bali, Indonesia, 2015;pp 176428. DOI: 10.2118/176428-MS.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2118/176428-MS</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isambourg P.; Ottesen S.; Benaissa S.; Marti J.. Down-Hole Simulation Cell for Measurement of Lubricity and Differential Pressure Sticking. In Paper presented at the SPE/IADC Drilling Conference; OnePetro: Amsterdam, Netherlands, 1999; pp 52816. DOI: 10.2118/52816-MS.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2118/52816-MS</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalil A. A.; Sadeq Adnan M.; Asad M. S.; Alfarge D. Decreasing the stick-slip vibration during drilling wells using water and polymer drilling mud modified with NanoSiO2 particles. Kuwait J. Sci. 2024, 51 (2), 100178. 10.1016/j.kjs.2024.100178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.kjs.2024.100178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao C. J.; Li J.; Liu G.; Zhang X. Analysis of the influence of cement sheath failure on sustained casing pressure in shale gas wells. J. Nat. Gas Sci. Eng. 2019, 66, 244&#x2013;254. 10.1016/j.jngse.2019.04.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jngse.2019.04.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu H. Y.; Deng J. G.; Zhao J.; Zhao H.; Liu H. L.; Wang T. Cementing failure of the casing-cement-rock interfaces during hydraulic fracturing. Computers Concrete 2014, 14 (1), 91&#x2013;107. 10.12989/cac.2014.14.1.091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12989/cac.2014.14.1.091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jing W. Exploration of Key Technologies for Cementing Large Displacement Wells. Western Exploration Engineering 2019, 31 (10), 107&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jindong W. Research on Cementing Quality of High Permeability and Low Pressure Layers in Zone 3/7 of South Sudan. Western Exploration Engineering 2019, 31 (3), 59&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jianwei Z.; Jian W.; Xin L.; Qingming M.; Baodong Z. Mud cake quality improvers and their impact on cementing quality. Silicate Bulletin 2016, 35 (2), 623&#x2013;627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhiqiang W.; Jianliang Z.; Yong J.; Hongsheng Z. Analysis of Difficulties and Technical Countermeasures for Gas Layer Sealing in Shale Gas Horizontal Wells. Petroleum Drilling Prod. Technol. 2012, 34 (S1), 26&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin G.; Xu M.; He M.; Chen K.; et al. Synergistic Effect of Polyaspartate and Polyethylene Glycol on Lubrication Performance of the Water-Based Drilling Mud. ACS Omega 2021, 6 (21), 13817&#x2013;13830. 10.1021/acsomega.1c01361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.1c01361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8173554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34095674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shuming Y.; Qiang L.; Huaizhen Z. Research on High Temperature and High Density Drilling Fluid Lubrication Technology. Chem. Ind. Eng. Technol. 2019, (3), 40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S.-S.; Song J.-J.; Xu P.; He M.; Xu M.-B.; You F.-C. A review on tribology, characterization and lubricants for water-based drilling fluids. Geoenergy Sci. Eng. 2023, 229, 212074. 10.1016/j.geoen.2023.212074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.geoen.2023.212074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf6;nmez A.; Kok M. V.; &#xd6;zel R. Performance analysis of drilling fluid liquid lubricants. J. Pet. Sci. Eng. 2013, 108, 64&#x2013;73. 10.1016/j.petrol.2013.06.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2013.06.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saffari H. R. M.; Soltani R.; Alaei M.; Soleymani M. Tribological properties of water-based drilling fluids with borate nanoparticles as lubricant additives. J. Pet. Sci. Eng. 2018, 171, 253&#x2013;259. 10.1016/j.petrol.2018.07.049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2018.07.049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bukhawwah M.; Alrammah S.. Laboratory Evaluation Comparison Study Between the Performance of Fatty Acid Solid Lubricant and Liquid Lubricant. In Paper presented at the International Petroleum Technology Conference; OnePetro: Riyadh, Saudi Arabia, 2022. DOI: 10.2523/IPTC-22590-MS.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2523/IPTC-22590-MS</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zain Z. M.; Sharma M. M. Mechanisms of Mudcake Removal During Flowback. SPE Drill. Completion 2001, 16 (4), 214&#x2013;220. 10.2118/74972-PA.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2118/74972-PA</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao N.; Xiaodong B.; Xuepeng Z.; Xuepeng Z.; Yuqian X.; Xuemei Y.; Yuemei L.; Song Z. Solidification technology and mechanism analysis of improving the interface cementation quality of mud cake and rock.. Chem. Ind. Oil Gas 2020, 49 (5), 76&#x2013;81+86. 10.3969/j.issn.1007-3426.2020.05.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1007-3426.2020.05.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X. Y.; Nair S.; Aughenbaugh K.; van Oort E. Mud-to-cement conversion of non-aqueous drilling fluids using alkali-activated fly ash. J. Pet. Sci. Eng. 2019, 182, 106242. 10.1016/j.petrol.2019.106242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.petrol.2019.106242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jinying Y. Research on the treatment process of oilfield drilling waste mud. Petrochem. Technol. 2022, 29 (5), 233&#x2013;234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jun G.; Yaxin Y.; Pengwei Z.; Pengwei Z.; Yutang G.; Yanwei L.; Sanyue Y. Principle of Anti-Channeling Cementing Technology with MTA Method and Field Applications in Daqing/Shengli/Henan Oilfields. Pet. Drill. Tech. 2012, 40 (1), 17&#x2013;21. 10.969/j.issn.1001-0890.2012.01.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.969/j.issn.1001-0890.2012.01.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong Y.; Wang J.; Zhongxian L.; YijunYang J. H.; Jun G. Haiyang Hao. Mud Cake Solidification Reaction at Cement-Formation Interface. J. Oilfield Chem. 2015, 32 (4), 485&#x2013;489. 10.19346/j.cnki.1000-4092.2015.04.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.19346/j.cnki.1000-4092.2015.04.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y.; Xu P.; Xu M.; Pu L.; Wang X. Properties of Bentonite Slurry Drilling Fluid in Shallow Formations of Deepwater Wells and the Optimization of Its Wellbore Strengthening Ability While Drilling.. ACS Omega 2022, 7 (44), 39860&#x2013;39874. 10.1021/ACSOMEGA.2C03986.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ACSOMEGA.2C03986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9647726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36385803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J.; Wang D.; Su H.; Zhu B.; Meng Q.; et al. A cement interface enhancer and its action mechanism. Arab J. Geosci. 2015, 8 (10), 7869&#x2013;7877. 10.1007/s12517-015-1847-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12517-015-1847-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y.; Kumar Narayanan Nair A.; Sun S.; et al. Layer Charge Effects on Adsorption and Diffusion of Water and Ions in Interlayers and on External Surfaces of Montmorillonite. ACS Earth Space Chem. 2019, 3 (11), 2635&#x2013;2645. 10.1021/acsearthspacechem.9b00236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsearthspacechem.9b00236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen W. L.; Chen W. L.; Grabowski R. C.; Grabowski R. C.; Goel S.; Goel S. Clay Swelling: Role of Cations in Stabilizing/Destabilizing Mechanisms. ACS Omega 2022, 7 (4), 3185&#x2013;3191. 10.1021/acsomega.1c04384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.1c04384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8811774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35128231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>