<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37924888</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-1026</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>908</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Science of the total environment</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Total Environ</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The predictive machine learning model of a hydrated inverse vulcanized copolymer for effective mercury sequestration from wastewater.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>168034</StartPage><MedlinePgn>168034</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.168034</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0048-9697(23)06661-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Inverse vulcanized polysulfides (IVP) are promising sulfur-enriched copolymers with unconventional properties irresistible for diverse applications like Hg<sup>2+</sup> remediation. Nevertheless, due to their inherent hydrophobic nature, these copolymers still offer low Hg<sup>2+</sup> uptake capacity. Herein, we reported the synthesis of IVP by reacting molten sulfur with 4-vinyl benzyl chloride, followed by their functionalization using N-methyl D-glucamine (NMDG) to increase the hydration of the developed IVP. The chemical composition and structure of the functionalized IVP were proposed based on FTIR and XPS analysis. The functionalized IVP demonstrated a high mercury adsorption capacity of 608&#xa0;mg/g (compared to &lt;26&#xa0;mg/g for common IVP) because of rich sulfur and hydrophilic regions. NMDG functionalized IVP removed 100&#xa0;% Hg<sup>2+</sup> from a low feed concentration (10-50&#xa0;mg/l). A predictive machine learning model was also developed to predict the amount of mercury removed (%) using GPR, ANN, Decision Tree, and SVM algorithms. Hyperparameter and loss function optimization was also carried out to reduce the prediction error. The optimized GPR algorithm demonstrated high R<sup>2</sup> (0.99 (training) and 0.98 (unseen)) and low RMSE (2.74 (training) and 2.53 (unseen)) values indicating its goodness in predicting the amount of mercury removed. The produced functionalized IVP can be regenerated and reused with constant Hg<sup>2+</sup> uptake capacity. Sulfur is the waste of the petrochemical industry and is abundantly available, making the functionalized IVP a sustainable and cheap adsorbent that can be produced for high-volume Hg<sup>2+</sup> remediation. ENVIRONMENTAL IMPLICATION: This research effectively addresses the removal of the global top-priority neurotoxic pollutant mercury, which is toxic even at low concentrations. We attempted to remove the Hg<sup>2+</sup> utilizing an inexpensive adsorbent developed by NMDG functionalized copolymer of molten sulfur and VBC. A predictive machine learning model was also formulated to predict the amount of mercury removal from wastewater with only a 0.05&#xa0;% error which shows the goodness of the developed model. This work is critical in utilizing this low-cost adsorbent and demonstrates its potential for large-scale industrial application.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ghumman</LastName><ForeName>Ali Shaan Manzoor</ForeName><Initials>ASM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chemical Engineering Department, Universiti Teknologi PETRONAS, 32610 Bandar Seri Iskandar, Perak Darul Ridzuan, Malaysia; HICoE, Centre for Biofuel and Biochemical Research (CBBR), Institute of Self-Sustainable Building, Universiti Teknologi PETRONAS, 32610 Seri Iskandar, Perak, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shamsuddin</LastName><ForeName>Rashid</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chemical Engineering Department, Universiti Teknologi PETRONAS, 32610 Bandar Seri Iskandar, Perak Darul Ridzuan, Malaysia; HICoE, Centre for Biofuel and Biochemical Research (CBBR), Institute of Self-Sustainable Building, Universiti Teknologi PETRONAS, 32610 Seri Iskandar, Perak, Malaysia. Electronic address: mrashids@utp.edu.my.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abbasi</LastName><ForeName>Amin</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Technology University of the Shannon (TUS), Athlone, County Westmeath, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmad</LastName><ForeName>Mohaira</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, National University of Sciences and Technology (NUST), Islamabad 44000, Pakistan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoshida</LastName><ForeName>Yoshiaki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Engineering, Department of Material Science, Kyushu Institute of Technology, 1-1, Sensui-Cho, Tobata-ku, Kitakyushu-shi 804-8550, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sami</LastName><ForeName>Abdul</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chemical Engineering Department, Universiti Teknologi PETRONAS, 32610 Bandar Seri Iskandar, Perak Darul Ridzuan, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almohamadi</LastName><ForeName>Hamad</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, Islamic University of Madinah, Madinah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Total Environ</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0330500</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0048-9697</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hyperparameter optimization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inverse vulcanized copolymers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mercury(II) remediation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">N-methyl D-glucamine functionalization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Predictive model</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sulfur</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37924888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.168034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0048-9697(23)06661-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>