<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39962588</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1754-1611</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>19</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of biological engineering</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Biol Eng</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The stability and self-assembly of tri-calcium silicate and hydroxyapatite scaffolds in bone tissue engineering applications.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>16</StartPage><MedlinePgn>16</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">16</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13036-025-00481-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The fabrication of scaffolds for bone tissue engineering (BTE) applications often involves the utilization of two distinct categories of biomaterials, namely calcium phosphates and calcium silicates. The selection of these materials is based on their biocompatibility, bioactivity, and mechanical characteristics that closely resemble those of natural bone. The present research examined the utilization of hydroxyapatite (HAP) and tri-calcium silicate (TCS), which are among the most commonly utilized materials in calcium phosphates and calcium silicates, in the context of bone scaffolding applications. A molecular dynamics simulation was conducted to investigate the impact of different concentrations of ceramic nanoparticles, when combined with sodium alginate (SA) hydrogel, on the fabrication of bone scaffolds.The stability and self-assembly were assessed through several parameters, such as the solvent-accessible surface area (SASA), radius of gyration (Rg), radial distribution function (g(r)), root-mean-square deviation (RMSD), root-mean-square fluctuation (RMSF), hydrogen bonding, van der Waals, electrostatic, and total energies. The findings indicate that the addition of 10 wt% HAP and TCS to the SA hydrogel matrix results in a more compact, stable, and potentially less hydrated structure. Accordingly, the experimental validation of these simulation approved our in silico findings. Experimental rheology and mechanical properties evaluation validate our simulation results, indicating a superior characteristic of TCS10 and HAP10 inks and 3D-printed scaffolds among other composition ratios. This could potentially benefit the in vitro and in vivo performance of the scaffold and its interaction with cells. The aforementioned traits are considered fundamental for the successful execution of the scaffold in the field of BTE. The findings indicate that TCS samples exhibit superior properties when compared to HAP samples, specifically in terms of composition with SA hydrogel.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beheshtizadeh</LastName><ForeName>Nima</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Tissue Engineering, Faculty of Advanced Medical Sciences, Tabriz University of Medical Sciences, Tabriz, Iran. n.beheshtizadeh@tbzmed.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Regenerative Medicine Group (REMED), Universal Scientific Education and Research Network (USERN), Tehran, Iran. n.beheshtizadeh@tbzmed.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seraji</LastName><ForeName>Amir Abbas</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mechanical and Industrial Engineering, University of Toronto, Toronto, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Polymer Engineering and Color Technology, Amirkabir University of Technology, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azadpour</LastName><ForeName>Behnam</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemical Engineering, Brigham Young University, Provo, UT, 84602, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rezvantalab</LastName><ForeName>Sima</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Renewable Energies Department, Faculty of Chemical Engineering, Urmia University of Technology, Urmia, 57166&#x2011;419, Iran. s.rezvantalab@uut.ac.ir.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>73575</GrantID><Agency>Tabriz University of Medical Sciences</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Biol Eng</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101306640</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1754-1611</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bone scaffolds</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Calcium phosphate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Calcium silicate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hydroxyapatite</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular dynamics simulations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rheology performance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This article does not contain any studies with human participants or animals performed by any of the authors. Research was approved by ethical committee of Tabriz University of Medical Sciences [ethics code: IR.TBZMED.VCR.REC.1403.220]. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39962588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11834295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13036-025-00481-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13036-025-00481-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sun W, Lal P. Recent development on computer aided tissue engineering &#x2014; a review. Comput Methods Programs Biomed. 2002;67(2):85&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0169-2607(01)00116-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11809316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Liu Y, Kang S, Sun D, Liu Y, Wang X, Lu L. Peripheral nerve injury repair by electrical stimulation combined with graphene-based scaffolds. Front Bioeng Biotechnol 12 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10933080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38481574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue R, Yuan P, Zhao B, Jing F, Kou X, Yue W, wang Y, Wang D, Sewvandi GA, Hu D. DLP printing of BT/HA nanocomposite ceramic scaffolds using low refractive index BT crystals. J Materiomics. 2024;10(5):1036&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmat.2023.11.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahdavi H, Rezaei M, Ahmadian-Alam L, Amini MM. A novel ternary Pd-GO/N-doped TiO2 hierarchical visible-light sensitive photocatalyst for nanocomposite membrane. Korean J Chem Eng. 2020;37(6):946&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11814-020-0533-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aghdam HA, Sanatizadeh E, Motififard M, Aghadavoudi F, Saber-Samandari S, Esmaeili S, Sheikhbahaei E, Safari M, Khandan A. Effect of calcium silicate nanoparticle on surface feature of calcium phosphates hybrid bio-nanocomposite using for bone substitute application. Powder Technol. 2020;361:917&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.powtec.2019.10.111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joyce M, Hodgkinson T, Lemoine M, Gonz&#xe1;lez-V&#xe1;zquez A, Kelly DJ, O&#x2019;Brien FJ. Development of a 3D-printed bioabsorbable composite scaffold with mechanical properties suitable for treating large, load-bearingarticular cartilage defects. Eur Cell Mater. 2023;45:158&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22203/eCM.v045a11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37382477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y, Zhang F, Zhai W, Cheng S, Li J, Wang Y. Unraveling of Advances in 3D-Printed Polymer-Based Bone Scaffolds, Polymers, 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8840342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35160556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hao X, Jiang B, Wu J, Xiang D, Xiong Z, Li C, Li Z, He S, Tu C, Li Z. Nanomaterials for bone metastasis. J Controlled Release. 2024;373:640&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jconrel.2024.07.067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39084467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dejob L, Toury B, Tadier S, Gr&#xe9;millard L, Gaillard C, Salles V. Electrospinning of in situ synthesized silica-based and calcium phosphate bioceramics for applications in bone tissue engineering: a review. Acta Biomater. 2021;123:123&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actbio.2020.12.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33359868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pupilli F, Ruffini A, Dapporto M, Tavoni M, Tampieri A, Sprio S. Design strategies and biomimetic approaches for calcium phosphate scaffolds in bone tissue regeneration. Biomimetics. 2022;7(3):112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biomimetics7030112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9397031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35997432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prati C, Gandolfi MG. Calcium silicate bioactive cements: biological perspectives and clinical applications. Dent Mater. 2015;31(4):351&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dental.2015.01.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25662204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Zhang G, Ding Q, Yan P, Li Y. Microstructural evolution and degradation mechanisms of tricalcium silicate and tricalcium aluminate composite pastes under sulfate exposure. Case Stud Constr Mater. 2024;21:e04050.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duarte MAH, Marciano MA, Vivan RR, Tanomaru Filho M, Tanomaru JMG, Camilleri J. Tricalcium silicate-based cements: properties and modifications. Brazilian oral Res 32 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30365611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao W, Chang J, Zhai W. Self-setting properties and in vitro bioactivity of Ca3SiO5/CaSO4&#x22c5;1/2H2o composite cement. J Biomedical Mater Res Part A. 2008;85A(2):336&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jbm.a.31523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17688248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pei P, Qi X, Du X, Zhu M, Zhao S, Zhu Y. Three-dimensional printing of tricalcium silicate/mesoporous bioactive glass cement scaffolds for bone regeneration. J Mater Chem B. 2016;4(46):7452&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C6TB02055K</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32263745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazehara-Kunitomo Y, Hara ES, Ono M, Aung KT, Komi K, Pham HT, Akiyama K, Okada M, Oohashi T, Matsumoto T, Kuboki T. Acidic Pre-conditioning enhances the stem cell phenotype of human bone marrow Stem/Progenitor cells. International Journal of Molecular Sciences; 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6429188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30836626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh SH, Lee JH. Hydrophilization of synthetic biodegradable polymer scaffolds for improved cell/tissue compatibility. Biomed Mater. 2013;8(1):014101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1748-6041/8/1/014101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23472257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maximova T, Moffatt R, Ma B, Nussinov R, Shehu A. Principles and overview of sampling methods for modeling Macromolecular structure and Dynamics. PLoS Comput Biol. 2016;12(4):e1004619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pcbi.1004619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4849799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27124275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira LG, Dos Santos RN, Oliva G, Andricopulo AD. Molecular docking and structure-based drug design strategies. Molecules. 2015;20(7):13384&#x2013;421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules200713384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6332083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26205061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X, Chang L, Zhao H, Cai Z. Study on craniocerebral dynamics response and helmet protective performance under the blast waves. Mater Design. 2022;224:111408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.matdes.2022.111408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hospital A, Go&#xf1;i JR, Orozco M, Gelp&#xed; JL. Molecular dynamics simulations: advances and applications. Adv Appl Bioinform Chem. 2015;8:37&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4655909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26604800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi YK, Kern NR, Kim S, Kanhaiya K, Afshar Y, Jeon SH, Jo S, Brooks BR, Lee J, Tadmor EB, Heinz H, Im W. CHARMM-GUI nanomaterial modeler for modeling and Simulation of Nanomaterial systems. J Chem Theory Comput. 2022;18(1):479&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jctc.1c00996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8752518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34871001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Lee J, Jo S, Brooks Iii CL, Lee HS, Im W. CHARMM-GUI ligand reader and modeler for CHARMM force field generation of small molecules. J Comput Chem. 2017;38(21):1879&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcc.24829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5488718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28497616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks BR, Bruccoleri RE, Olafson BD, States DJ, Swaminathan S, Karplus M. CHARMM: a program for macromolecular energy, minimization, and dynamics calculations. J Comput Chem. 1983;4(2):187&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcc.540040211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kern NR, Lee J, Choi YK, Im W. CHARMM-GUI multicomponent assembler for modeling and simulation of complex multicomponent systems. Biophys J. 2022;121(3):529a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bpj.2021.11.2789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11211406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38937468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Essmann U, Perera L, Berkowitz ML, Darden T, Lee H, Pedersen LG. A smooth particle mesh Ewald method. J Chem Phys. 1995;103(19):8577&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.470117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parrinello M, Rahman A. Polymorphic transitions in single crystals: a new molecular dynamics method. J Appl Phys. 1981;52(12):7182&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.328693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hess B, Bekker H, Berendsen HJ, Fraaije JG. LINCS: a linear constraint solver for molecular simulations. J Comput Chem. 1997;18(12):1463&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1096-987X(199709)18:12&lt;1463::AID-JCC4&gt;3.0.CO;2-H</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humphrey W, Dalke A, Schulten K. VMD: visual molecular dynamics. J Mol Graph. 1996;14(1):33&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0263-7855(96)00018-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8744570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beheshtizadeh N, Farzin A, Rezvantalab S, Pazhouhnia Z, Lotfibakhshaiesh N, Ai J, Noori A, Azami M. 3D printing of complicated GelMA-coated Alginate/Tri-calcium silicate scaffold for accelerated bone regeneration. Int J Biol Macromol. 2023;229:636&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2022.12.267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36586652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ram&#xe9;zani H, Ellien I, El Oufir Z, Mathieu N, Delpeux S, Bhatia SK. Clustering of caffeine in water and its adsorption in activated carbon: molecular simulations and experiments. Colloids and Surfaces A: physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. 2023;673:131645. 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2023.131645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell EW, Zhang Y. DockRMSD: an open-source tool for atom mapping and RMSD calculation of symmetric molecules through graph isomorphism. J Cheminform. 2019;11(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13321-019-0362-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6556049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31175455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamal GA, Jahangirian E, Hamblin MR, Tarrahimofrad H, Alikowsarzadeh N. A structural and biochemical approach to effect of temperature and pH on the molten globule phenomenon in a thermophilic protease: molecular dynamics simulation, fluorescence spectroscopy and circular dichroism. J Mol Struct. 2024;1318:139204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molstruc.2024.139204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grabowski SJ. Understanding hydrogen bonds: theoretical and experimental views. Royal Society of Chemistry; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallipeddi PL, Zhang Y, Li H, Markowitz SD, Posner B. Structural insights into Novel 15-Prostaglandin dehydrogenase inhibitors. Molecules. 2021;26(19):5903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules26195903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8512612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34641449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jindal A, Arunachalam V, Vasudevan S. Search for H-Bonded motifs in Liquid Ethylene Glycol using a machine learning strategy. J Phys Chem B. 2021;125(22):5909&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.jpcb.1c01308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34060849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vao-soongnern V, Jamornsuriya S. Molecular simulation of structural and surface properties of poly (ethylene-ran-propylene) thin films. J Polym Res. 2021;28(9):340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10965-021-02704-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuel H, Nweke-Mariazu U, Etim E. Understanding intermolecular and intramolecular hydrogen bonds: spectroscopic and computational approaches. J Chem Reviews. 2023;5(4):439&#x2013;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuzmanic A, Pannu NS, Zagrovic B. X-ray refinement significantly underestimates the level of microscopic heterogeneity in biomolecular crystals. Nat Commun. 2014;5(1):3220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms4220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3926004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24504120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Hou T. Develop and test a solvent accessible surface area-based model in conformational entropy calculations. J Chem Inf Model. 2012;52(5):1199&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ci300064d</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3360827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22497310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>