<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37687745</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>17</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Preparation of High-Ductility Cement-Calcined Coal-Gangue-Powder-Composite-Based Rapid Repair Material.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">6049</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma16176049</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Coal gangue is a kind of solid waste. A high-ductility cement-calcined coal-gangue-powder-composite-based rapid repair material (HD-RRM) was prepared by partially replacing cement with calcined coal gangue powder (CCGP) for achieving high ductility and rapid hardening and conforming to the strength requirements of pavement layers. First, the physical and chemical properties and the reactivity of the CCGP were investigated. Second, HD-RRM material was prepared, and its tensile performance characteristic parameters were investigated. Lastly, the hydration products and microstructure of HD-RRM were characterized through tests (e.g., non-evaporable water content, scanning electron microscopy (SEM), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and comprehensive thermogravimetric analysis and differential scanning calorimetry (TG-DSC)). As indicated by the experimental results, the CCGP with a particle size of 1250 mesh exhibited the maximum potential reactivity. The optimal mixing ratio for HD-RRM in the experiments comprised a water-cement ratio of 0.27, a sand-cement ratio of 0.3, a fiber volume fraction of 2%, a cement content of 70%, a CCGP content of 20%, a fly ash (FA) content of 10%, and a superplasticizer content of 0.1%. Using the abovementioned mix design, the prepared HD-RRM was endowed with a 6 h ultimate elongation of 2.75%, an ultimate tensile strength of 7.58 MPa, a compressive strength of 45.4 MPa, and an average crack width of 125.53 &#x3bc;m, which meets the requirements of repair materials and provides a design method for CCGP resource utilization and asphalt concrete road and bridge deck repair.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Biaokun</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil Engineering, Taiyuan University of Technology, Taiyuan 030024, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chai</LastName><ForeName>Lijuan</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil Engineering, Taiyuan University of Technology, Taiyuan 030024, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Yuanzhen</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1531-5091</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil Engineering, Taiyuan University of Technology, Taiyuan 030024, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yangkai</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Civil Engineering, Taiyuan University of Technology, Taiyuan 030024, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>No. CPCSME2022-09</GrantID><Agency>Southeast University, Key Laboratory of Concrete and Pre-stressed Concrete Structures of Ministry of Education</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 20211B01</GrantID><Agency>Guangdong Key Laboratory of Modern Civil Engineering Technology</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>No. 20210302124011</GrantID><Agency>Shanxi Province Applied Basic Research Plan for Youths</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">calcined coal gangue powder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high ductility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rapid repair</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tensile performance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37687745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10488730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma16176049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ma16176049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lu K.Y. Analysis and prospect of comprehensive utilization of coal solid waste. Coal Process. Compr. Util. 2016;7:3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang A., Liu P., Mo L., Liu K., Ma R., Guan Y., Sun D. Mechanism of thermal activation on granular coal gangue and its impact on the performance of cement mortars. J. Build. Eng. 2022;45:103616. doi: 10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jobe.2021.103616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J., Shui Z.H., Sun T., Gao X., Song Q., Guo C. Early hydration kinetics research of calcined coal gangue in cement-based materials. Bull. Chin. Ceram. Soc. 2019;38:1983&#x2013;1990. doi: 10.16552/j.cnki.issn1001-1625.2019.07.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16552/j.cnki.issn1001-1625.2019.07.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J., Su Y., He X., Tan H., Jiang Y., Zeng L., Strnadel B. Pore structure evaluation of cementing composites blended with coal by-products: Calcined coal gangue and coal fly ash. Fuel Process. Technol. 2018;181:75&#x2013;90. doi: 10.1016/j.fuproc.2018.09.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fuproc.2018.09.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou M., Qu H.L., Zhao H.M. Effect of Calcined Coal Gangue Powder on Workability and Strength of Concrete. Bull. Chin. Ceram. Soc. 2015;34:273&#x2013;279. doi: 10.16552/j.cnki.issn1001-1625.2015.01.048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16552/j.cnki.issn1001-1625.2015.01.048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y., Hou M., Yu J., Xu S., Yu K., Zhang Z. Experimental study on mechanical properties of ultra-high ductile cementitious composites. Mater. Rep. 2018;32:3535&#x2013;3540.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li-li K.A.N., Zhi Z., Li Z., Wei-dong L.I.U. A dynamic constitutive model of ultra high toughness cementitious composites. J. Zhe Jiang Univ. Sci. 2020;21:939&#x2013;960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kan L.L., Zhang Z., Zhang L., Wei-dong L. Effect of low-cost PVA fibers on the mechanical properties of engineered cementitious composites. Eng. Mech. 2019;36:121&#x2013;129+182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smail M.K., Sherir M.A., Siad H., Hassan A.A., Lachemi M. Properties of self-consolidating engineered cementitious composite modified with rubber. J. Mater. Civ. Eng. 2018;30:04018031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan F., Chen M.C., Pan J.H. Flexural strengthening of reinforced concrete beams with high-strength steel wire and engineered cementitious composites. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;254:119284. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo L.P., Yang Y.N., Chen B. A uniaxial tensile constitutive equation of high-ductility cementitious composites. J. Southeast Univ. 2019;35:476&#x2013;481.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo L.P., Wang M., Ding C., Cai L.J. Effect of incorporating reclaimed asphalt pavement on macroscopic and microstructural properties of high ductility cementitious composites. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;260:119956. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.119956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J.X., Weng J., Yang E.H. Stochastic model of tensile behavior of strain-hardening cementitious composites (SHCCs) Cem. Concr. Res. 2019;124:105856. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconres.2019.105856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z.B., Zhang J., Wang Q. Mechanical behavior and crack width control of hybrid fiber reinforced ductile cementitious composites. J. Build. Mater. 2018;21:216&#x2013;221+227. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1007-9629.2018.02.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1007-9629.2018.02.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu H., Yu K., Li V.C. Sprayable engineered cementitious composites (ECC) using calcined clay limestone cement (LC3) and PP fiber. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2021;115:103868. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2020.103868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2020.103868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng H., Chen G., Hadi M.N., Sheikh M.N., Zhou B. Mechanical behaviour of micro-fine steel fibre reinforced sulphoaluminate cement composite. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;170:91&#x2013;100. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.03.065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.03.065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv L., Hong X., Ding Z., Ma X., Li H. Preparation and characterization of calcium sulfoaluminate based engineered cementitious composites for rapid repairing of concrete member. Front. Mater. 2020;7:282. doi: 10.3389/fmats.2020.00282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmats.2020.00282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Technical Specifications of Cement Concrete Pavement Maintenance for Highway. China Communication Press; Beijing, China: 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Specification of Cement Concrete Pavement Design for Highway. China Communication Press; Beijing, China: 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulphoaluminate Cement. National Standard of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China; Beijing, China: 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chai L.J., Guo L.P., Chen B., Xu Y.H. Interactive effects of freeze-thaw cycle and carbonation on tensile property of ecological high ductility cementitious composites for bridge deck link slab. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;186:773&#x2013;781. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.07.248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.07.248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Method of Testing Cements&#x2014;Determination of Strength. National Standard of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China; Beijing, China: 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fly Ash Used for Cement and Concrete. National Standard of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China; Beijing, China: 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standard Test Method for the Mechanical Properties of Ductile Fiber Reinforced Cementitious Composites. Building Materials Industry Standard of the People&#x2019;s Republic of China; Beijing, China: 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao H.S., Zhang X., Cao J. Grey related analysis on the relationship between the particle size distribution of coal gangue and its activity. Cem. Eng. 2004:23&#x2013;26+32. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1007-0389.2004.02.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1007-0389.2004.02.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei J., Gencturk B., Jain A., Hanifehzadeh M. Mitigating alkali-silica reaction induced concrete degradation through cement substitution by metakaolin and bentonite. Appl. Clay Sci. 2019;182:105257. doi: 10.1016/j.clay.2019.105257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clay.2019.105257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li W., Hua L., Shi Y., Wang P., Liu Z., Cui D., Sun X. Influence of metakaolin on the hydration and microstructure evolution of cement paste during the early stage. Appl. Clay Sci. 2022;229:183&#x2013;193. doi: 10.1016/j.clay.2022.106674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clay.2022.106674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y.T., Zhang Y.S., Wu Z.T., Liu N.D., Yuan T.F. Ptimization Design and Properties of Glass Fiber Reinforced Cementitious Composities. Mater. Rev. 2019;33:2331&#x2013;2336. doi: 10.11896/cldb.18070194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11896/cldb.18070194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han J.G., Yan P.Y. Influence of Lithium Carbonate on Hydration Characteristics and Strength Development of Suiphoaluminate Cement. J. Build. Mater. 2011;14:6&#x2013;9. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1007-9629.2011.01.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1007-9629.2011.01.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T., Ren B., Wang Z., Meng X., Ning Y., Lv Y. Effect of early strength agent on the hydration of geopolymer mortar at low temperatures. Case Stud. Constr. Mater. 2022;17:e01419. doi: 10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cscm.2022.e01419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafieizonooz M., Mirza J., Salim M.R., Hussin M.W., Khankhaje E. Investigation of coal bottom ash and fly ash in concrete as replacement for sand and cement. Constr. Build. Mater. 2016;116:15&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.04.080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.04.080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang H., Guo M.X., Zhang W. Mechanical property and microstructure of geopolymer concrete based on fly ash and slag. J. Harbin Inst. Technol. 2022;54:74&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia Y.T. Master&#x2019;s Thesis. Jiangsu Southeast University; Nanjing, China: 2005. Study on hydration mechanism of slag and fly ash cement-based materials.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7666/d.y790771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Jazairi B., Illston J.M. A simultaneous semi-isothermal method of thermogravimetry and derivative thermogravimetry, and its application to cement pastes. Cem. Concr. Res. 1977;7:247&#x2013;257. doi: 10.1016/0008-8846(77)90086-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0008-8846(77)90086-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor H.F.W., Mohan K., Moir G.K. Analytical Study of Pure and Extended Portlan Cement Pastes: II, Fly Ash-and Slag-Cement Pastes. J. Am. Ceram. Soc. 1985;68:685&#x2013;690. doi: 10.1111/j.1151-2916.1985.tb10125.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1151-2916.1985.tb10125.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanda T., Lin Z., Li V.C. Tensile stress-strain modeline of pseudo strain hardening cementitious composites. J. Mater. Civ. Eng. 2011;12:147&#x2013;156. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)0899-1561(2000)12:2(147).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)0899-1561(2000)12:2(147)</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M., Zhi X.L., Yao A.L. Study on Slag Based Cement Concrete Pavement Repair Material. Mater. Rev. 2014;28:124&#x2013;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song L.X., Hao X.F., Duan P., Huang M., Zhang H. Preparation of Solid Waste Geopolymer Pavement Repairing Material and Performance Study. J. Hubei Univ. Educ. 2022;39:25&#x2013;31. doi: 10.3969/j.issn.1674-344X.2022.02.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1674-344X.2022.02.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H.L., Luo Y.J., Peng G.Y., Sun X., Ying Q. Effect of Admixtures on Tensile Behavior of Fiber Reinfbrced Cementitious Composites. J. Southwest Jiao Tong Univ. 2017;52:61&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>