<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41599317</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1420-3049</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>13</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Molecules (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Molecules</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Molecular Simulation Study of Water-Rock Interfaces During Supercritical CO<sub>2</sub> Sequestration.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">268</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/molecules31020268</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Understanding how supercritical CO<sub>2</sub> and water interact with mineral surfaces is essential for predicting the stability and sealing performance of geological storage formations. Yet, the combined effects of mineral surface chemistry and confined pore geometry on interfacial structure and fluid dynamics remain insufficiently resolved at the molecular scale. In this study, molecular dynamics simulations were employed to quantify how methylated SiO<sub>2</sub>, hydroxylated SiO<sub>2</sub>, and kaolinite regulate CO<sub>2</sub>-H<sub>2</sub>O interfacial behavior through variations in wettability and electrostatic interactions. The results show a clear hierarchy in water affinity across the three minerals. On methylated SiO<sub>2</sub>, the water cluster remains spherical and poorly anchored, with a contact angle of ~140&#xb0;, consistent with the weakest water-surface Coulomb attractions (only -400 to -1400 kJ/mol). Hydroxylated SiO<sub>2</sub> significantly enhances hydration, forming a cylindrical water layer with a reduced contact angle of ~61.3&#xb0; and strong surface-water electrostatic binding (~-18,000 to -20,000 kJ/mol). Kaolinite exhibits the highest hydrophilicity, where water forms a continuous bridge between the two walls and the contact angle further decreases to ~24.5&#xb0;, supported by the strongest mineral-water electrostatic interactions (-23,000 to -25,000 kJ/mol). Meanwhile, CO<sub>2</sub>-water attractions remain moderate (typically -2800 to -3500 kJ/mol) but are sufficient to influence CO<sub>2</sub> distribution within the confined domain. These findings collectively reveal that surface functionalization and mineral type govern interfacial morphology, fluid confinement, and electrostatic stabilization in the sequence methylated SiO<sub>2</sub> &lt; hydroxylated SiO<sub>2</sub> &lt; kaolinite. This molecular-level understanding provides mechanistic insight into how mineral wettability controls CO<sub>2</sub> trapping, fluid segregation, and pore-scale sealing behavior in subsurface carbon-storage environments.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yan</LastName><ForeName>Yuanzi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Shaanxi Key Laboratory of Higher Education Institutions for Intelligent Prevention and Control of Coal Mine Disasters, Shaanxi Energy Institute, Xianyang 712000, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fan</LastName><ForeName>Yunfeng</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Geology Research Institute, China National Logging Corporation, Xi'an 710077, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Peng</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CCTEG Xi'an Research Institute (Group) Co., Ltd., Xi'an 710077, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2023-JC-QN-0373</GrantID><Agency>General Project of Natural Science Basic Research Program of Shaanxi Province (for Young Scholars)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Molecules</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100964009</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1420-3049</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">confined water structure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interfacial electrostatic interactions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mineral wettability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">molecular dynamics simulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">supercritical CO2 sequestration</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Author Yunfeng Fan was employed by China National Logging Corporation and author Peng Zhang was employed by CCTEG Xi&#x2019;an Research Institute (Group) Co., Ltd. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41599317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12843969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules31020268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">molecules31020268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang W., Li X., Wei Z., Xin Y., Xiao R., Yang H., Chen X. Effect of CO2&#x2013;Brine&#x2013;Rock Interactions on the Pore Structure of the Tight Sandstone during CO2 Flooding: A Case Study of Chang 7 Member of the Triassic Yanchang Formation in the Ordos Basin, China. ACS Omega. 2023;8:3998&#x2013;4009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9893740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36743022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng H., Yang J., Peng J., Pu J., Liu Q., Su J., Liu J. Experimental investigation of the mechanism of supercritical CO2 interaction with tight sandstone. Front. Energy Res. 2022;10:984144. doi: 10.3389/fenrg.2022.984144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fenrg.2022.984144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan M.N., Siddiqui S., Thakur G.C. Recent advances in geochemical and mineralogical studies on CO2&#x2013;brine&#x2013;rock interaction for CO2 sequestration: Laboratory and simulation studies. Energies. 2024;17:3346</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang K., Zhou J., Xian X., Zhang C., Gan Q., Dong Z. Effect of supercritical CO2-water-shale interaction on mechanical properties of shale and its implication for carbon sequestration. Gas Sci. Eng. 2023;111:204930.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo Q., Zhang Y., Zhang M., Ju B., Ning W., Deng X., Pang C. Numerical Simulation of CO2 Dissolution and Mineralization Storage Considering CO2-Water-Rock Reaction in Aquifers. ACS Omega. 2024;9:45983&#x2013;45995. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.4c05620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.4c05620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11579739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39583665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M., Kortunov P., Lee A., Marica F., Balcom B. Sandstone wettability in supercritical CO2-brine-rock interactions evaluated with 13C and 1H magnetic resonance. Chem. Eng. J. 2024;500:157100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu D., Zhai W., Liu X., Xiao X., Xu J., Jia N., Miao F. The permeability of shale exposed to supercritical carbon dioxide. Sci. Rep. 2023;13:6734. doi: 10.1038/s41598-023-33702-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-33702-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10130032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37185792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai B., Ni H.J., Shi X., Guo X., Ding L. The experimental investigation of effect of supercritical CO2 immersion on mechanical properties and pore structure of shale. Energy. 2021;228:120663. doi: 10.1016/j.energy.2021.120663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.energy.2021.120663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medina B.X., Kohli A., Kovscek A.R., Alvarado V. Effects of supercritical CO2 injection on the shale pore structures and mass transport rates. Energy Fuels. 2022;37:1151&#x2013;1168. doi: 10.1021/acs.energyfuels.2c02254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.energyfuels.2c02254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Z., Wang Y., Chang C., Song H., Lu X., Cheng F. Synergistic gas&#x2013;slag scheme to mitigate CO2 emissions from the steel industry. Nat. Sustain. 2025;8:763&#x2013;772. doi: 10.1038/s41893-025-01572-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41893-025-01572-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma X., Du Y., Fu C., Fang H., Wei H., Pan Z., Zhang J. Effects of supercritical CO2 on the pore structure complexity of high-rank coal with water participation and the implications for CO2 ECBM. ACS Omega. 2023;8:18964&#x2013;18980. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.3c01486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.3c01486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10233688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37273609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyu Q., Tan J., Li L., Ju Y., Busch A., Wood D.A., Hu R. The role of supercritical carbon dioxide for recovery of shale gas and sequestration in gas shale reservoirs. Energy Environ. Sci. 2021;14:4203&#x2013;4227. doi: 10.1039/D0EE03648J.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/D0EE03648J</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang H., Sun Q., Yang D., Geng J., Zhang L., Pan Y. Effects of CO2&#x2013;water&#x2013;rock cycling cycles on sandstone pore structure. Front. Energy Res. 2024;12:1485241. doi: 10.3389/fenrg.2024.1485241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fenrg.2024.1485241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Sun X., Guo X., Zheng L., Luo P. Study on the influence of supercritical CO2 with high temperature and pressure on pore-throat structure and minerals of shale. ACS Omega. 2024;9:15259&#x2013;15270. doi: 10.1021/acsomega.3c09698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsomega.3c09698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10993383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38585050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Tan J., Wang Q., Li H., Han G., Ding Y., Hua S. Surface morphologic changes and mineral transformation mechanisms after CO2-brine-rock reaction in organic matter-rich ferroan shale. Chem. Eng. J. 2024;498:155130. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2024.155130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2024.155130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Xiong Y., Zhang Y., Lan K. A novel self-healing and degradable plugging material for high temperature gas well. J. Mol. Liq. 2023;376:121473. doi: 10.1016/j.molliq.2023.121473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molliq.2023.121473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazra B., Chandra D., Vishal V., Ostadhassan M., Sethi C., Saikia B.K., Varma A.K. Experimental study on pore structure evolution of thermally treated shales: Implications for CO2 storage in underground thermally treated shale horizons. Int. J. Coal Sci. Technol. 2024;11:61. doi: 10.1007/s40789-024-00717-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40789-024-00717-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seisenbayev N., Absalyamova M., Alibekov A., Lee W. Reactive transport modeling and sensitivity analysis of CO2&#x2013;rock&#x2013;brine interactions at Ebeity Reservoir, West Kazakhstan. Sustainability. 2023;15:14434. doi: 10.3390/su151914434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su151914434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z., Hu M., Steefel C. Pore-scale modeling of reactive transport with coupled mineral dissolution and precipitation. Water Resour. Res. 2024;60:e2023WR036122. doi: 10.1029/2023WR036122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1029/2023WR036122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J., Yang Y., Li Y., Song H., Sun H., Zhang L., Yao J. Multi-mineral dissolution in 3D natural rock: Pore-scale reactive transport modeling for geological carbon storage. Chem. Eng. Sci. 2025;320:122507. doi: 10.1016/j.ces.2025.122507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ces.2025.122507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neil C.W., Yang Y., Nisbet H., Iyare U.C., Boampong L.O., Li W., Viswanathan H.S. An integrated experimental&#x2013;modeling approach to identify key processes for carbon mineralization in fractured mafic and ultramafic rocks. PNAS Nexus. 2024;3:pgae388. doi: 10.1093/pnasnexus/pgae388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/pnasnexus/pgae388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11416041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39308890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moslehi S., Fazeli H., Doster F., Kord S. Development of a reactive transport solver in MATLAB Reservoir Simulation Toolbox using the fully-implicit sequential iterative approach. Adv. Geo-Energy Res. 2025;16:114&#x2013;130. doi: 10.46690/ager.2025.05.04.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46690/ager.2025.05.04</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazaheri A.H., Muhamad M.R., Faiz M.K., Yusof F., Zulkifli M.F., Hassan Z.F.A., Asemi A. Carbon capture and storage (CCS): CO2 basaltic mineralization through the phase transition from gas-solid to aqueous under low reaction kinetics. Environ. Earth Sci. 2025;84:464. doi: 10.1007/s12665-025-12455-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12665-025-12455-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen Y., Clennell B., Zhang J., Tang M., Ahmed S. Reactive transport modelling of in-situ CO2 mineralization in basalt formations. Capillarity. 2024;13:37&#x2013;46. doi: 10.46690/capi.2024.11.02.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46690/capi.2024.11.02</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao Z., Jia J., Liang Y., Cui W., Jo G., Usui K., Tsuji T. Surface Reaction of CO2 with Basaltic Minerals as a Mechanism for Carbon Mineralization. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2025;59:14410&#x2013;14418. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.5c03416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.5c03416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12288057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40623956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fentaw J.W., Emadi H., Hussain A., Fernandez D.M., Thiyagarajan S.R. Geochemistry in geological CO2 sequestration: A comprehensive review. Energies. 2024;17:5000. doi: 10.3390/en17195000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/en17195000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen T., Miller Q.R., Lahiri N., Terry O., Owen A.T., Kou Z., Kelly S.A. Multiphase flow regime controls carbonate precipitation morphologies during CO2 injection in subsurface basalts. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2025;59:20345&#x2013;20356. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.5c03397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.5c03397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40956933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue X., Fang H., Wang L., Liu S., Zhang H., Feng F., Lu X. Molecular Simulation of Carbon Dioxide Sequestration in High-Water Intergranular Pores of Shale. Colloids Surf. A Physicochem. Eng. Asp. 2025;719:137002. doi: 10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.137002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.colsurfa.2025.137002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M., Jin Z. Molecular simulation on CO2 adsorption in partially water-saturated kaolinite nanopores in relation to carbon geological sequestration. Chem. Eng. J. 2022;450:138002. doi: 10.1016/j.cej.2022.138002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cej.2022.138002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang W., Lv W., Jia N., Lu X., Wang L., Wang K., Mei Y. Study on the effects of wettability and pressure in shale matrix nanopore imbibition during shut-in process by molecular dynamics simulations. Molecules. 2024;29:1112. doi: 10.3390/molecules29051112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules29051112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10934049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38474624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes P.E., Murashov V., Tazi M., Demchuk E., MacKerell A.D. Development of an empirical force field for silica. Application to the quartz-water interface. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2006;110:2782&#x2013;2792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2531191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16471886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pang J., Liang Y., Mi F., Jiang G., Tsuji T., Ning F. Nanoscale understanding on CO2 diffusion and adsorption in clay matrix nanopores: Implications for carbon geosequestration. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2024;58:20401&#x2013;20411. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.4c08158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.4c08158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39381980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiga M., Morishita T., Sorai M. Interfacial tension of carbon dioxide-water under conditions of CO2 geological storage and enhanced geothermal systems: A molecular dynamics study on the effect of temperature. Fuel. 2023;337:127219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlcek L., Chialvo A.A., Cole D.R. Optimized unlike-pair interactions for water&#x2013;carbon dioxide mixtures described by the SPC/E and EPM2 models. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2011;115:8775&#x2013;8784. doi: 10.1021/jp203241q.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp203241q</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21644504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan X., Huang X., Deng N. Short-Chain Carboxylic Acids Influencing Mineralization Mechanisms of Ferrihydrite Transformation to Hematite and Goethite. Environ. Sci. Technol. 2025;59:12910&#x2013;12919. doi: 10.1021/acs.est.5c00455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.5c00455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40526414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>